<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650522-16">
               <interp inst="t17650522-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-16" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-16" type="date" value="17650522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-16-off92-c147" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-defend175 t17650522-16-off92 t17650522-16-verdict100"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-16-off93-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-defend179 t17650522-16-off93 t17650522-16-verdict102"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-16-off95-c151" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-defend181 t17650522-16-off95 t17650522-16-verdict104"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-16-off96-c153" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-defend184 t17650522-16-off96 t17650522-16-verdict104"></join>
         
               <p>309, 310, 311, 312. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-16-defend175" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Gammon 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend175" type="surname" value="Gammon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend175" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend175" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             was indicted, <rs id="t17650522-16-off92" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-off92" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-off92" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               together with 
                     <persName id="t17650522-16-person176">
                        John 
                        Magennes 
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person176" type="surname" value="Magennes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-16-person176" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650522-16-person176" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not taken, for stealing 70 lawn handkerchiefs, value 10 l. 48 linen handkerchiefs, value 3 l. 12 s. 60 pair of worsted stockings, value 9 l. 40 yards of lawn, value 6 l. 7 yards of printed cotton, value<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220014"></xptr> 17 s. 3 yards of printed Russia cloth, value 5 s., 3 pair of leather gloves, 3 pair of worsted gloves, 3 worsted caps. and 15 yards of flowered gause
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-16-victim178" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Short 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-16-victim178" type="surname" value="Short"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-victim178" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-victim178" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            : and 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-defend179" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Elizabeth 
                     Holmes 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17650522-16-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-defend179 t17650522-16-alias-3"></join>Truby</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend179" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend179" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend179" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for <rs id="t17650522-16-off93" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-off93" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-off93" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving 16 lawn handkerchiefs, 48 linen handkerchiefs, 56 pair of stockings, and 7 yards of printed cotton, part of the said goods
            </rs>; and 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-defend181" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Ann 
                     Wilder 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17650522-16-alias-4" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-defend181 t17650522-16-alias-4"></join>
                     Ann 
                     <rs id="t17650522-16-deflabel94" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-defend181 t17650522-16-deflabel94"></join> of 
                        <persName id="t17650522-16-person183">
                           John 
                           Howard 
                        <interp inst="t17650522-16-person183" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17650522-16-person183" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17650522-16-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        </persName>
                     
                     </rs>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend181" type="surname" value="Wilder Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend181" type="given" value="Ann Ann John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend181" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for <rs id="t17650522-16-off95" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-off95" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-off95" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving 3 pair of worsted gloves, 3 worsted caps, and 15 yards of flowered gauze, part of the said goods
            </rs>; and 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-defend184" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Ablet 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend184" type="surname" value="Ablet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend184" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-defend184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , for <rs id="t17650522-16-off96" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-off96" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-off96" type="offenceSubcategory" value="receiving"></interp>
               receiving 4 linen handkerchiefs, part of the said goods; each well knowing the said goods to have been stolen
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650522-16-cd97" type="crimeDate">April 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-off92 t17650522-16-cd97"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-off93 t17650522-16-cd97"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-off95 t17650522-16-cd97"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-off96 t17650522-16-cd97"></join> +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-16-person185">
                  Robert 
                  Short 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person185" type="surname" value="Short"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person185" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17650522-16-crimeloc98">Gray's-inn-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-16-crimeloc98" type="placeName" value="Gray's-inn-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-16-crimeloc98" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-off92 t17650522-16-crimeloc98"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-off93 t17650522-16-crimeloc98"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-off95 t17650522-16-crimeloc98"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-off96 t17650522-16-crimeloc98"></join>, and <rs id="t17650522-16-viclabel99" type="occupation">keep a shop in the linen and haberdashery way</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-victim178 t17650522-16-viclabel99"></join>: on the 24th of April, about nine at night, my shutters were shut; my wife was gone into the parlour to an old woman that was laying ill there, and in that time the goods mentioned in the indictment, (mentioning them by name) were stolen: I went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person186">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person186" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person186" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and got hand bills delivered about, by which means I found out the prisoners, and got a few of the things again; the robbery was on the Wednesday evening, and the evidence was taken on the Friday. I found two odd stockings in Field lane, at one Mrs. Norfolk's, and about a yard and half of lawn: I found 23 linen handkerchiefs in two parcels, in a place called Brown's Gardens, by Monmouth-street; (produced in court.) I can swear to the handkerchiefs to be my property. There were also a pair of stockings found at the house of Wilder, the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-16-person187">
                  Jonathan 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person187" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person187" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person188">
                  Richard 
                  Gammon 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person188" type="surname" value="Gammon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person188" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I, and Magennes stole these things.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Gammon?</p>
               <p>Parker. I have known him about eleven months: I am a gentleman's servant out of place: I lived at Mr. Penyman's, a sadler in Holbourn, as an errand boy; and after that I lived in Leicester-fields. I was born in Berkshire: I got acquainted with Gammon in St. Sepulchre's church-yard; he is about 16 years of age, and I 18: Magennes, he and I were playing at skittles at the King's arms in St. Giles's; that night, when it came to be dusk, we all came together, to see what we could get, down Holbourn, and up Gray's-inn-lane; we saw the prosecutor's door was open, and nobody in the shop; Magennes and I went in; Gammon stood and received the things of us at the door: I went in twice, and Magennes once: we went and put them behind a parcel of tember in a lane just by; then we went back, and I went in; and Magennes took the things of me at the door; we went and carried them to the rest: then we sent Gammon by the door to see if any body was near it; we went another way; and he was to meet us at the corner of a street; but Gammon went back to the timber again; Magennes and I were going by the door; I was going in again, and we saw a light through the door; Magennes said, do not go in any more, for the pitcher never goes to the well so often, but it comes home broke at last; so he would not let me go in: then we went to the goods, where we found Gammon watching them; we took each a bundle, and carried them to Holmes's house; she lodged up two pair of stairs, in Field-lane; there we opened the goods; there was about seven yards of printed cotton, a piece of Russia cloth, about three yards and a half; about five dozen and a half of lawn handkerchiefs, and about four dozen and a half of linen ones, about 50 pair of stockings or upwards, and some childrens stockings; I believe in all there were 60 pair; six pieces of plain lawn, three pair of leather gloves, three other pair, and three caps; there were two or three pieces of figured gauzes, about ten or a dozen yards.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Mrs. Holmes?</p>
               <p>Parker. I have known her about two months; she buys old cloaths, and sells them again at Monmouth-street and Rag-fair: it might want about a quarter of 10 o'clock when we got there: she bought the seven yards of cotton for a gown, and two small children's pocket handkerchiefs, for 11 s. and two pair of stockings for her maid for 2 s. one black ribb'd, four thread, and the other crimson coloured: we left all the things with her that night; she asked us where we got them, because she wanted to know where to go to sell them; we told her we got them in Gray's-inn-lane: I was recommended to her by others that had employed her to sell such things; we were to have gone to her in the morning, to sell her more things, as she chose to buy them at different times, and bring the money as she sold them: Magennes and I lodged that night at Mrs. Wilder's, in Black Boy-alley: Gammon lived in St. Giles's: we went home directly; Mrs. Wilder was suspicious that we had got some things: Mrs. Holmes came and told Mrs. Wilder there were constables about near her lodging and she was afraid they would searched her room; she brought the things in her lap, all but what she had bought; this was about seven the next morning; she said, the constables had said there were nothing but a parcel of thieves lived there: I and Magennes took the things of her; Mrs. Wilder said, there will be a search about here: she took the things and put<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220015"></xptr> them into a wheel barrow, and wheeled it out upon the dunghill, and put two other barrows by them, and covered them up; and said they would not think to search there: we then sold Holmes a few stockings for half a guinea; and a parcel of lawn handkerchiefs for another half guinea; which she took away with her; we trusted to her honour: in about two hours and a half after she came again, we wheeled the barrow into the room and took the lawn out, and let her have six small pieces and some gauze for half a guinea; she had all the lawn but one piece of about seven yards, which Mrs. Norfolk had: after she brought the money, she had some more lawn handkerchiefs for half a guinea; then she had a piece of 16 handkerchiefs, for which she gave us 8 s. Mrs. Wilder saw her buy all these. On the Thursday morning we disposed of all the things, except the two parcels of handkerchiefs that are produced here: Mrs. Holmes met us at the King's arms St. Giles, and paid us the last of the money, about three in the afternoon: we asked if the things would be safe if we should be taken up; she said, yes; for she sold them to a schoolmaster, and we should be very safe; for they were washed, ironed, and hemmed, before she parted with them: Mrs. Wilder would not let us stay at her apartment any longer, because we would not give her some gauze to make her caps; she said, if we did not take the things away she would throw them out at the door: I carried them under my arm to Mrs. Norfolk's, and asked her to let us leave them there till night; which she did: when we came she was not at home; her husband gave them us: we carried them to St. Giles's, to Gammon's: Gammon took them to the King's arms, and called a young woman out and desired her to carry them home: she told us after, she went and opened her bed and sowed them up in it. That night we all three went to the White Swan, at Black Friars, and lay there: we lay at the young woman's lodging on the Thursday night; and on the Friday we went to the Fox and Hounds, in Tottenham-court road, and sent for the young woman; we had three pints of half-and-half; the young woman went to see for Mrs. Holmes, to come to buy the handkerchiefs; she did not come. Then Ablet came, and said Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person189">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person189" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person189" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's men were after us; we left the handkerchiefs there, and ran away: we left the handkerchiefs with him and the young woman, named 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person190">
                  Jenny 
                  Bull 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person190" type="surname" value="Bull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person190" type="given" value="Jenny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person190" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; we all ran down Tottenham-court road, and desired them to meet us at the One Tun in Field-lane; we went there; they were not there; Magennes and Gammon staid in Union-court; when they came, we went in and had some beer and salmon, at the Angel and Crown there; then we sent 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person191">
                  Jenny 
                  Bull 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person191" type="surname" value="Bull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person191" type="given" value="Jenny"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person191" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for Mrs. Holmes; she came; there were 16 handkerchiefs; she was to give us 16 s. also for them; she paid us the other 8 s. she staid and drank part of a pot of beer, and carried them home; she took them away under pretence they were foul linen, for a blind: she was to meet us again at the One Tun on the Saturday night, but she did not come: when she was with us in Union-court, she desired us by all means to keep from her lodging, fearing we should be taken up: then we took a walk into the fields, and went down to the White Swan, and lay there again that night: this was Saturday night: the next day Magennes and Gammon said they would not stay in London, fearing they should be taken up; I said, if you are afraid of that, I'll take it all upon myself, let Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person192">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person192" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person192" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             do what he will with me: we went together to the bottom of Gray's-inn-lane, on the Sunday morning, and met a milk-man; we drank some milk there; we all shook hands and parted: I thought they were going into the country: then Ablet and I went up to the King's arms, St. Giles's; there I saw one of Mr. Fielding's men; he took and charged me with this thing: then I said I would confess it all. I had denied it a little at first: then I put him off, and said, I would tell him to-morrow; he trusted to my honour: the next morning I came to the same house again; he said, tell me where the things are, that is all I want: then I told him; then he came up to me and told me Magennes was taken, and had made himself an evidence: then I said, if he is not admitted I'll go along with you; I went with him and told every thing. I knew: I know nothing against Ablet.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-16-person193">
                  Jane 
                  Bull 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person193" type="surname" value="Bull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person193" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person193" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Maynard-street, St. Giles's: I have one that keeps me without business: Magennes brought me the handkerchiefs about 10 o'clock on a Thursday night, and desired me to keep them till the morning; Parker and Gammon were with him: I was at the King's arms; Gammon came and said he wanted to speak with me: I have known him about a year and a half: he asked me if he might leave these things in my room till morning: I took them from Magennes, and took them home: they were these two pieces of handkerchiefs here produced. I kept them till morning; then I brought them to them at the Fox and Hounds in Tottenham-court road on the Friday morning; there were Magennes, Parker, and Gammon; they desired me to go and wait for Mrs. Holmes at the King's Arms: when she came I sent her up to them: she had promised to come there by two o'clock; she did<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220016"></xptr> not come: I went up to the Fox and Hounds along with Ablet, he used that house; he seeing some of Justice Fielding's men come by, he said, if he knew where they were, he would go and send them out of the way; he had heard about the hand bills being given about: I told him I knew where they were; then he went with me; he told them of the men; they all ran out of the house, and left word where they would be: Ablet used to go by the name of 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person194">
                  John 
                  Frick 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person194" type="surname" value="Frick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person194" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : they said they would be at the One Tun, the corner of Field-lane, that same day: they left the handkerchiefs on the table; Ablet and I took and carried them down Holbourn: I carried them part of the way: We called at the Three Tuns, in Berwick-street, going along; there Ablet cut off two handkerchiefs from each piece: then we went to the One Tun in Field-lane; they were not there; but we met Parker; after that we went to the Angel, in Union-court; Parker went with us; there were Magennes and Gammon waiting in the court; we all went in at the alehouse together; I went along with Magennes to Mrs. Holmes's; she was not at home: I went a second time; she then came with me, and took the handkerchiefs from them at the Angel. When she went out, Magennes went out with her, and said, mind and take care to wash my shirt and stockings clean; that the people of the house should not suspect them: then I went home. I saw Mrs. Holmes pay 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person195">
                  Parker
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person195" type="given" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             some money at the King's Arms, on the Thursday morning; but do not know how much, or for what; her maid was along with her.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Porter. I live at the King's Arms, in Maynard-street: I have seen Parker, Gammon, and Holmes drinking together in my house: I have also seen 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person196">
                  Jane 
                  Bull 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person196" type="surname" value="Bull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person196" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person196" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             drinking there with them in other company. I have seen Ablet at our house, but not in particular with them.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-16-person197">
                  Mary 
                  Dupree 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person197" type="surname" value="Dupree"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person197" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw Gammon but once: I lived servant with 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person198">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person198" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person198" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person198" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person199">
                  Jonathan 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person199" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person199" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             brought a parcel of things, either on the Wednesday or Thursday night, a month ago this week: he said, if she had money she might get money; she might have things cheap: Magennes was along with him: she said, she had but half a guinea; there were some things opened; cotton and handkerchiefs; she said, if he would take half a guinea for the piece of cotton, she would give it him; I do not know what quantity there was of it; she said, it was as much as she could afford to give; they told her, if it was for her own wear she should have it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ask how they came by them?</p>
               <p>Dupree. No, she did not: she had the piece, and gave them half a guinea for it; I saw her pay it: she also gave six-pence to them for two small handkerchiefs: Parker desired she would left all the things lie in her apartment that night; she refused it, fearing the house should be searched; they then desired her to let them stay till they came again in a quarter of an hour; she agreed to it, but they did not come: I believe she bought a pair of black stockings, and another of purple, but they were too little for me: the next morning she carried them from her apartment, about nine or ten o'clock, to where Parker lodged, and said, she would have no more to do with them.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. When Mrs. Holmes was taken up, she told me she could help me to some of my things again; I went with her and one of Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person200">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person200" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person200" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person200" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's men in a coach, to where she owned she had carried them, in Brown's Gardens; she then brought me under an obligation that I should not speak one word when we were in the house about the things being stolen; I was to go as if I was to buy goods: when I got there I saw three or four more of my handkerchiefs hanging up, but upon account of my promise I did not then take any notice: afterwards I went there again, but the things were not to be found: we went to Norfolk's house. Parker said, my life is at stake; allow me to manage as I think proper: he went to the maid, and talked with her about five minutes; after that we went into the house, and there we found some stockings, and this piece of lawn.</p>
               <p>Mr. Bailey. I keep the Three Tuns in Brewick-street: as I pass'd and repass'd my cellar with beer, I saw some people, and some handkerchiefs lying before them, resembling these red and white one's here: I think one of them had a pair of scissars in their hand, but whether it was a man or a woman I cannot tell, I took so little notice.</p>
               <p>Isabella Goldsborough. I keep the Angel, in Union-court; there were three young men and a young woman at my house about a month ago; I believe it was on a Thursday: I can swear to none of them but 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person201">
                  Jane 
                  Bull 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person201" type="surname" value="Bull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person201" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person201" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; they had got some salmon; they drank about two pots of half-and-half: they swore so very bad, I said they should not swear in my house: there came in Holmes, the prisoner; one of the young men called her mother; I thought she had got a very unhappy son: they went away upon my speaking to them.</p>
               <p>Gammon's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all about the affair: I had been of an errand for my father beyond Monmouth-street;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220017"></xptr> somebody slipt out of a house and called me in; there was Parker; I went up to the King's Arms with him; there we had two pots of beer; Holmes came in; she gave Parker and Magennes some money, how much I can't tell: we drank there about two hours; then we went to take a walk in the fields; we staid out till 11 o'clock; I said, if I went home to my father I could not get in: so we went to the Swan, at Black Friars, and lay there all night: the next morning we went to the King's Arms: they desired me to go and call the young woman out. I being acquainted with her; I went and desired he to bring the handkerchiefs, and she brought them to the Fox and Hounds: there they heard of people coming; they ran out; I said, they can't hurt me: then they said come along; for if you are taken up you will be hanged; then I went with them, and we went to the Angel and Crown.</p>
               <p>Holmes's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw one of these people three times since I was born: I am innocent; I know them not: Bull came to me and desired me to go to 
               <persName id="t17650522-16-person202">
                  Jonathan 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17650522-16-person202" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person202" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : I formerly did wash for the woman he called his wife: I went to the Angel to him; he said, mother Holmes, will you wash these things; they are a shirt and two pair of stockings: I never sat down: when I came home I opened the parcel; then I saw they were handkerchiefs; I said, the Lord bless me, these are not washing cloaths; these are stolen goods: I took them to a friend's house: I came back to the Angel to give them the things, and they were gone.</p>
               <p>Wilder's Defence.</p>
               <p>They lay at my house; what they brought I never saw: when I saw these things, I took and kicked them out at the door: and because I turned them out, they have sworn this against me.</p>
               <p>Ablet's Defence.</p>
               <p>I had the handkerchiefs to keep for them; but did not know they were stolen.</p>
               <p>Gammon, <rs id="t17650522-16-verdict100" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-verdict100" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650522-16-punish101" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-punish101" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-defend175 t17650522-16-punish101"></join>
               T
            </rs>. </p>
               <p>Holmes, <rs id="t17650522-16-verdict102" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-verdict102" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650522-16-punish103" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-punish103" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-16-defend179 t17650522-16-punish103"></join>
               T. 14
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Wilder and Ablet, <rs id="t17650522-16-verdict104" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-16-verdict104" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See Parker, the evidence, tried, and Gammon evidence against him, No. 135. in this mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
