<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-55">
               <interp inst="t17610916-55" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-55" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-55" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-55" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-55-off288-c413" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-55-defend508 t17610916-55-off288 t17610916-55-verdict292"></join>
         
               <p>275. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-55-defend508" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Steel 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-55-defend508" type="surname" value="Steel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-55-defend508" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-55-defend508" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for <rs id="t17610916-55-off288" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-55-off288" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-55-off288" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610916-55-victim510" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Benson 
                        <interp inst="t17610916-55-victim510" type="surname" value="Benson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-55-victim510" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-55-victim510" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-55-off288 t17610916-55-victim510"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17610916-55-viclabel289" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-55-victim510 t17610916-55-viclabel289"></join>; did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life; one silver watch, value 10 l. and four guineas, his property<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160057"></xptr> property, from his person, and against his will, did steal, take, and carry away
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610916-55-cd290" type="crimeDate">June 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-55-off288 t17610916-55-cd290"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-55-person511">
                  James 
                  Benson 
               <interp inst="t17610916-55-person511" type="surname" value="Benson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-55-person511" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-55-person511" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 13th of June, I was travelling in a post chaise with Mr. Smith, in the road from Tyburn to Ealing. I remember it was the night we had the account of the taking of Bellersle: near the turnpike behind <placeName id="t17610916-55-crimeloc291">Kensington-gardens</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-55-crimeloc291" type="placeName" value="Kensington-gardens"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-55-crimeloc291" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-55-off288 t17610916-55-crimeloc291"></join>, about 11 at night, I was asleep, and was awaked by a person on horseback. I asked what was the matter; Mr. Smith said, do not be affrighted, it is only a highway-man. When I looked up. I saw a man on horse-back, with a mask on the upper part of his face, which came down as low as his mouth. He was mounted on a chesnut or brown-horse, it was a very moonlight night, I think the horse had a light face, he was on the right side of the chaise next me. The head of his horse was turned towards the chaise. he had a short pistol in his right-hand. He said, Your watches and money, do not be alarmed, gentlemen, I shall not hurt you, your watches and money. Mr. Smith reply'd, do not hurt us, you shall have them Sir. He gave him his purse, and then I gave him mine. Then he took Mr. Smith's watch, and then mine. Mr. Smith asked him for his seal, he told him he might take it. Mr. Smith reach'd and took it off.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use any threatning words?</p>
               <p>Benson. No, he did not; he was extremely civil, he bid us not be frighted, and said, he was a poor unhappy man, reduced to that way of supporting his wife and six small children.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of watches were they?</p>
               <p>Benson. Mr. Smith gave him a metal watch, with a shagreen case, and mine was a horizontal silver repeating watch. I cannot exactly tell what money I had, I know it was about four guinea, or four guineas and a half.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give him your money and watch, under any terror or apprehensions of danger?</p>
               <p>Benson. I would not have given him them, if I could have avoided it. Mr. Smith asking him for his seal, led into conversation between them; at that time I look'd under the horse's neck to observe his feet and discovered, that the highway man's toe of the right leg, turned out towards the horse's flank. I found it was a withered leg. I saw the prisoner since at justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>[ The prisoner is ordered from the bar, into the body of the court. ]</p>
               <p>Q. look at his legs?</p>
               <p>Benson. I do, I have great reason to believe, that is the leg that I see that night. After about 10 or 15 minutes conversation, he rode off. He represented his case to us, as though he was a very unfortunate man. He said, he had been a bankrupt, about a year and half ago, and that he had entered into security for an uncle, for about 15 hundred pounds; this was on a Saturday night, and I gave information of it before Mr. Fielding, on the Tuesday following. I then described the person to have a withered leg. About three weeks after, Mr Fielding sent for me, the man at the bar was taken up, upon some other robbery. I looked at the prisoner's leg, and told the justice, from the circumstance of the leg, I had reason to believe that was the man?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever meet with your watch again.</p>
               <p>Benson. No, I never did. I advertized it, but never had any information of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion of the prisoner now?</p>
               <p>Benson. I can form no opinion of this to be the man by any thing, but only by the circumstance of his leg.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe his voice?</p>
               <p>Benson. He spoke to us with a very particular voice, I can form no certainty from that?</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. At this time, I believe when you was robbed, you, according to what I heard before the justice, came and laid an information, that you had been so robbed?</p>
               <p>Benson. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Was not there an advertisement in the Publick Advertiser?</p>
               <p>Benson. Yes, Mr. Fielding put in an advertisement, agreeable to the information.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Do you think he put it in according to your description given?</p>
               <p>Benson. I suppose Mr. Fielding put in such advertisement, as was proper on such an occasion.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. I would be glad, if you would be kind enough to give the real information you gave to Mr. Fielding?</p>
               <p>Benson. The information I gave Mr. Fielding was the same I have given now.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have the Advertisement here.</p>
               <p>Benson. It was near the same I have given here, in substance almost the same.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. From the best recollection I have, you said, the man's jaws were thin, that this was a man of a thin hollow visage, and upon your oath, you say, he had a mask down to his mouth.</p>
               <p>Court. That was a near description to you, for you are such, and that might be seen if the mask came no lower than the mouth.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160058"></xptr>Q. from Prisoner. Did not you at that time observe, that this man had spatterdashes on?</p>
               <p>Benson. I did observe, that the withered leg had a spatterdash on; I mentioned it to Mr Smith, after the robbery, that the man had an unfortunate mark about him, to be a highway-man, and told him of the withered leg.</p>
               <p>Prisoner At that time you advertized, or at least, gave information to Mr. Fielding, that this man had either a cue wig, or his own hair. I believe you to be much of a gentleman, and you will allow me to ask some questions in defence of my life.</p>
               <p>Benson. Yes, I told Mr. Fielding, he was as the prisoner is, in his hair, or a cue wig.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Did not you talk something of a letter?</p>
               <p>Benson. Mr. Smith asking for his seal, the man said, gentlemen, you shall have your watches, as well as your seals, if you will advertize two guineas each for them. I said, I will give you five for mine; but why need we advertize; do you name a place where they shall be left, and the money shall be ready. Then the man said, let it be the Rummer Tavern, Charing Cross; there we were to apply, to get our watches again, upon paying two guineas each.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. I think just now you was saying, the man that robbed you, told you, he was a bankrupt about a year and half ago.</p>
               <p>Benson. About a year and half before that time.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You said before justice Fielding, it was about four months before that time?</p>
               <p>Benson. I cannot exactly recollect that, I know he told me had been a bankrupt.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Then you cannot tell, whether it was a year and half, or a year and four months, or four months.</p>
               <p>Benson. No, I cannot be certain.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Do you know any thing of a letter, or parcel, (then produced) I know you read a letter?</p>
               <p>Benson. Mr Smith and I went to the Rummer about 10 o'clock, to inquire for our watches, agreeable to his information. I did expect, in consequence of his appointment (as he seem to be very exact) that he would have sent our watches. We inquired if a parcel had been left directed for Mr. Smith and Mr Benson, a woman there said, she knew nothing of the matter; but a servant said, there was a small parcel, it was delivered to us. There was in some cotton, my seal, and the block of Mr. Smith's seal, which he had left to the watch, as he could not get it off. There was no money asked; but upon the out side of the letter or parcel, was wrote value 2 l. 2 s. It was brought there by the penny-post.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. How do you know they came by the penny post?</p>
               <p>Benson. By the penny post mark upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it put in?</p>
               <p>Benson. It was mark'd in Bond-street. Mr. Fielding's man went to the place, and can inform the court of all that, if needful.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner Did you never make inquiry at any post-office about it?</p>
               <p>Benson. No, I did not</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Because the advertisement says, the man was in a fustian frock, and seemed to be a gentleman's servant</p>
               <p>Q. What do you say to the prisoner's voice now; you was a little dubious at the first part of your evidence?</p>
               <p>Benson. He rather spoke in a theatrical way, as if he had been bred at a spouting club. He said, 'O my conscience, my conscience,' and would seem grievously tormented with a guilty conscience, for what he was committing. From the circumstance of voice, I will not take upon me to say, he is the man. The prisoner said with great resolution before the justice, that he was in bed before ten o'clock that night; and I am sure it was after that when we were robbed, and I wish he can prove he was so in bed.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. I have one question more. At the time you gave the information before justice Fielding, you said, you was robbed between 10 and 11.</p>
               <p>Benson. I believe I said so, I say so now.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You said, the horse was a brown, or chesnut horse.</p>
               <p>Benson. To the best of my knowledge it was.</p>
               <p>Mr. Smith. On the 13th of June, near the turnpike, behind Kensington gardens, I was in a post-chaise with Mr. Benson, a highwayman stopped the chaise, and demanded our money and watches; I was on the farther side from the highway-man, I did not observe any thing circumstantially, I have little more to say, than that I was robbed there about 11 o'clock, by a highway man; that he presented a pistol, and demanded our money and watches, which we delivered him. He was turning away; Sir, said I, I should be obliged to you, if you will let me have my seal. Said he, is it a valuable one? I said, nothing more than my name in a cypher. He handed my watch over to me, I could not take it. I returned it to him, and desired he would take it off. He said, gentlemen, you need not be uneasy for your seals or watches, you shall<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160059"></xptr> have them by advertizing two guineas each. I called him back again, and said, there was no need to advertize, he might let us know where to meet with them and the money should be paid. He asked us we were officers, we told him we were merchants; he seemed to be sorry to rob merchants. He asked us where he could bring them. He said, if you will not hurt me, I will bring them myself. I said, Sir you may happen to change your mind. Then he fixed upon the Rummer-tavern, Charing-cross. We went there by 10 o'clock, we found our seals packed up in some cotton, inclosed with a direction for Mess. Benson and Smith, merchants. The letter, by the contents of it, seemed to be wrote by his wife, it was in this manner [ My unfortunate husband promised to send you your watches; it was not his fault, but my fear; I hope you will excuse it, and be never will commit another robbery, or follow such practice hereafter. I am a poor woman, and have a number of children, and hope you will never advertize them.]</p>
               <p>Q. What do you say to the prisoner's voice?</p>
               <p>Smith. I cannot swear to his voice.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion?</p>
               <p>Smith. I think it will not be right to give my opinion about it, as I cannot swear to it; I cannot say it is the same voice.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his legs?</p>
               <p>Smith. No, I did not; I did look a little at his face, but not so as to say this is the man. I discovered his body was thin, and his face was thin, ( such was the prisoner,) but cannot pretend to say, that is the man. Mr. Benson told me immediately after the robbery, about his leg, and I was surprized to think he could describe it so punctual to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Smith It was a very moon-light night, and Mr Benson did look down at the horse's feet, I had a great deal of conversation with the man about his being a bankrupt; he also talked of having a wife and six children.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Was you before justice Fielding at the time Mr Benson was?</p>
               <p>Smith. Yes, I was</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Did you not say you could not swear to the man that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Smith. I say so now.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. You said there, you was surprised how he could see this leg so narrowly?</p>
               <p>Smith. I say so now.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. You said, a chesnut-horse.</p>
               <p>Smith. I say so now. I believe he was.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. You never observed any spatterdashes on the man's leg, or any thing of that kind?</p>
               <p>Smith. No.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Did you observe a pistol?</p>
               <p>Smith. I saw something that I thought to be a pistol; I saw the person produce a pistol before Mr. Benson was awake.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. At this time you was robbed, you was in a post-chaise, I think Mr. Benson says Which sat next the highway-man?</p>
               <p>Smith Mr. Benson did.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. What time do you suppose it to be?</p>
               <p>Smith. Rather full 11, or a little before 11.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-55-person512">
                  Elizabeth 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17610916-55-person512" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-55-person512" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-55-person512" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodg'd a fortnight in my house, he came to me the 7th of June, and went away on the 24th, he was not well, he was sick, and was not out from the time he came to me, which was on a Sunday, till the Saturday following, which was the 13th, he was taking medicines the whole fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>E. White. I live at Marybone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not go out at all till the 13th?</p>
               <p>E. White. He walked out in the garden at times, he was not confined to the house, but he was no farther than the garden. On the 13th he hired a horse of a neighbour, and rode out, he sent my servant to know if he could have a horse, she brought word back, he might have one. I saw the horse brought to the door, and saw him get upon him.</p>

               <p>Q. What sort of a horse was it, what colour?</p>
               <p>E. White. I did not take notice of the horse, I do not know what colour; it was something of a brownish colour; but I am not judge enough to know the colour of a horse.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he get on horseback?</p>
               <p>E. White. I believe it was between four and five in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he come home?</p>
               <p>E. White. He came home between 11 and 12 night.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Benson. How far from Marybone was it you was robbed?</p>
               <p>Benson. I believe it was about a mile and half from Tyburn</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. I believe, madam, you was before Mr. Fielding, and the information you gave upon oath was read to me?</p>
               <p>E. White. Yes, it was.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. I think there you said, I returned about 11 o'clock.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160060"></xptr>E. White. I think I said after 11.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Do you remember what kind of a wig I had on, when I went out?</p>
               <p>E. White. To my knowledge, it was such a one as you have now.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. What wig did I come home in?</p>
               <p>E. White. The same.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Had I spatterdashes on my legs?</p>
               <p>E. White. No, they were boots.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. And the same when I returned?</p>
               <p>E. White. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Do you remember I had it in my power, to have taken any of your property, if I had been a bad man?</p>
               <p>E. White. You might; but I had a very good character with you by very substantial people in Bond-street.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. I never did rob you?</p>
               <p>E. White. No</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Did you ever see any thing in my behaviour, like a highway-man or a villain?</p>
               <p>E. White. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. What might I have taken from you, had I mind to have been a villain?</p>
               <p>E. White. There were plate, and a gold watch, and other things. The prisoner paid me on the Sunday, and went away on the Monday morning, and did not return any more.</p>
               <p>Samuel Watkins. I know the prisoner, he hired a horse of me on the 13th of June</p>
               <p>Q. What colour was your horse?</p>
               <p>Watkins. Betwixt a bay and a chesnut colour, two feet white behind.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he return to you that night?</p>
               <p>Watkins. About 11 o'clock. I know it was very late, because I sat up for him myself; it was rather after 11 than any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour is the mane and tail?</p>
               <p>Watkins. a little flaxen.</p>
               <p>Q. Who brought the horse home?</p>
               <p>Watkins. The prisoner did himself to my door.</p>
               <p>Q. Who came for him?</p>
               <p>Watkins. Mrs. White's servant did; and said, a gentleman wanted one.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your horse seem to be hard rode?</p>
               <p>Watkins. No, he did not at all; I turned him out to grass that night.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Which way did I ride?</p>
               <p>Watkins. I cannot tell that. I know you hired him to go to Highgate, or Hampstead, out for a ride in the air.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. What heighth is this horse?</p>
               <p>Watkins. He is upwards of 14 hands.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. What kind of a horse?</p>
               <p>Watkins. A square made horse, a cut full tail.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Describe the colour?</p>
               <p>Watkins. He is a sort of chesnut brown bay.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Take care what you say, I think you are mistaken; I take him to be a light bay; but that is not material my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Has he a particular white face?</p>
               <p>Watkins. He has a pretty deal of white in his face; the prisoner had him twice, the 13th, and the 19th.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice, whether he had spatterdashes on?</p>
               <p>Watkins. I did not take notice of that, he was off the horse when he brought him to my door.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Benson. Can you recollect, whether the man that robbed you had spatterdashes on, or boots?</p>
               <p>Benson. To the best of my recollection, he had a spatterdash on the right leg, and not on the other.</p>
               <p>Q. to E. White. did you observe a spatterdash on one of the prisoner's legs that time?</p>
               <p>E. White. There was a boot on each leg.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mr. Benson. Did you observe, so as to distinguish whether he had a boot or shoe on that leg?</p>
               <p>Benson. By the smallness of the foot, I judged it was a shoe.</p>
         
               <p>*** The Last Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17610916-55">
                  <interp inst="t17610916-55" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-55" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-55" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-55" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160061"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 16th, Thursday the 17th. Friday the 18th, Saturday the 19th, and Monday the 21st of SEPTEMBER.</p>
                  <p>In the first Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Seventh SESSION in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17610916-55-person513">
                     Matthew 
                     Blakiston 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-55-person513" type="surname" value="Blakiston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-55-person513" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-55-person513" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER VII. PART IV. for the YEAR 1761.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. SCOTT, at the Black-Swan, in Pater-noster Row.</p>
                  <p>M. DCC. LXI.</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160062"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17610916-55-person514">
                  Elizabeth 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17610916-55-person514" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-55-person514" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-55-person514" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>WAS it visible that he had a withered leg?</p>
               <p>E. White. It was very visible, he went very lame.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>As to any part of the charge, I have no occasion to repeat any of the evidence again, that has been already mentioned. This horse, it appears from the evidence, I hired of Mr Watkins to go to Highgate; and I did accordingly set out, I believe between four and five in the afternoon, for a ride for the air, as has appeared already, that the air might be of service to me. Mrs. White, I believe, can tell which way I went, when I set out from Marybone, from her house: her house is just in the middle of Marybone, please to ask her that question?</p>
               <p>Mrs. White to the Question. He went up to the New road.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That is the way to Highgate; I did go to Highgate, merely for a ride; and at the inn, under the gateway, I called for a gill of wine, and drank it. Then I went down the road to go to the Spaniard's, I had heard of some things to be seen there, some curiosities; there I alighted, and put up my horse. From thence I went to a place called Georgia, to see the curiosities there. There I saw different curiosities. Then I came back again to this publick-house, or tavern, or something of that kind, where some gentlemen were drinking; and I being fatigued, by not being well, I put in sixpence with them, and we had some punch, and drank it; and in the interim, at about half an hour after nine, there came the news of the surrender of Belleisle; upon which we drank several loyal healths. As I was always a loyal man for my country, I did consent to have another half-crown bowl of punch to be called for. We sat 'till we drank that, and I believe it might be half an hour after ten o'clock when I came from that place. I came directly to Marybone; and after I was at home, in particular I mentioned to Mrs. White, of my seeing the rockets and lights as I was coming from the new-road to Tottenham-court road. I came very softly all the way, as appears from Mr. Watkins; he says the horse was very cool. I suppose I might be the best part of an hour in coming from the Spaniard's. I believe it was eleven o'clock. I dare say it was, when I got home. I remember seeing the lights and rockets from a sort of a hill, it looks over the buildings; seeing them, confirmed me in the good news that I had heard. From the different advertisements set forth in the papers, concerning what a notorious highway man I have been, has given my friends the opinion that I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160063"></xptr> must be convicted of this offence, or some other. I have wrote to them several times, but they have not appeared in it all, supposing my case to be very desparate; and here are those advertisements, which, if your lordship thinks necessary, I beg they may be read. They are advertisements of robberies committed in Middlesex, which have been the occasion of my friends not coming to appear at all for me. My name is inserted at full length. I have been six times before justice Fielding, for people to see me, when nobody could swear to my person at all; and since I have been in prison I have had but a trifle of money, and I dare say the court will consider it; when a man has such a charge against him, people are all very cautious in coming without being subpoena's. I dare say if I had had money to have sent subpoena's to the Spaniard's, the people would have remembered it, being so remarkable a man as I am; but having no attorney, nor nobody to apply to, having no money at all, I could not get them to come; and I hope your lordship, and the jury, will be kind enough to consider right upon it; this is all I have to say.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-55-verdict292" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-55-verdict292" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was detained to be sent to the county-goal in Surrey, he having detainers against him for highway robberies in that county.</p>
            </div1>
