<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17671209-26">
               <interp inst="t17671209-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-26" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17671209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-26" type="date" value="17671209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671209-26-off130-c155" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-defend200 t17671209-26-off130 t17671209-26-verdict138"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671209-26-off130-c156" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-defend202 t17671209-26-off130 t17671209-26-verdict138"></join>
         
               <p>31, 32. (M) 
               <persName id="t17671209-26-defend200" type="defendantName">
                  
                        
                           <persName id="t17671209-26-defend202" type="defendantName">
                              Richard 
                              Griffiths 
                           <interp inst="t17671209-26-defend202" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-defend202" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-defend202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                         
                     , and Mary
                   his 
                  <rs id="t17671209-26-deflabel128" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-defend200 t17671209-26-deflabel128"></join>, otherwise <rs id="t17671209-26-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-defend200 t17671209-26-alias-2"></join>Mary Pitt</rs>, <rs id="t17671209-26-deflabel129" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-defend200 t17671209-26-deflabel129"></join>, otherwise <rs id="t17671209-26-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-defend200 t17671209-26-alias-3"></join>Anne Taylor</rs>, spinster<interp inst="t17671209-26-defend200" type="surname" value="Griffiths"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-defend200" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-defend200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17671209-26-off130" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-off130" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-off130" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               burglariously breaking and entering the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17671209-26-victim204" type="victimName">
                           Anne 
                           Nevell 
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim204" type="surname" value="Nevell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim204" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim204" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17671209-26-viclabel131" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-victim204 t17671209-26-viclabel131"></join>, on the <rs id="t17671209-26-cd132" type="crimeDate">11th of October</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-off130 t17671209-26-cd132"></join>, about the hour of four in the night, and stealing a brilliant diamond ring, set in gold, value 15 l. a rose diamond ring, set in gold, value 5 l. a ring with diamond sparks and green stones, value 10 s. a cotton counterpane, value 15 s. a linen table-cloth, value 4 s. a linen napkin, value 6 d. a pillowbear, value 6 d. two silver spoons, value 4 s. a pair of linen sheets, a pair of muslin ruffles, worked, a muslin apron, a dimitty petticoat, two shirts, and a coloured silk handkerchief, the property of the said 
                     <persName id="t17671209-26-person205">
                        Anne 
                        Nevell 
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person205" type="surname" value="Nevell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-person205" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-person205" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , widow; one flowered cotton gown, two shifts, a pair of cotton stockings, a worked muslin apron, a worked muslin handkerchief, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17671209-26-victim207" type="victimName">
                           Martha 
                           Ellis 
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim207" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim207" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17671209-26-viclabel133" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-victim207 t17671209-26-viclabel133"></join>; one muslin handkerchief, two shifts, a pair of laced russles, and a worked muslin apron, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17671209-26-victim208" type="victimName">
                        Moreal 
                        Nevell 
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim208" type="surname" value="Nevell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim208" type="given" value="Moreal"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , <rs id="t17671209-26-viclabel134" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-victim208 t17671209-26-viclabel134"></join>; a muslin apron, a pair of muslin double ruffles, a shift, a muslin handkerchief, and a muslin apron, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17671209-26-victim210" type="victimName">
                           Anne 
                           Nevell 
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim210" type="surname" value="Nevell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim210" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim210" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17671209-26-viclabel135" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-victim210 t17671209-26-viclabel135"></join>; a silk handkerchief, and a shift, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17671209-26-victim212" type="victimName">
                           Susanna 
                           Julian 
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim212" type="surname" value="Julian"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim212" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim212" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17671209-26-viclabel136" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-victim212 t17671209-26-viclabel136"></join>; a striped muslin apron, three quarters of a yard of new muslin, a silk handkerchief, half a guinea, a quarter guinea, and 2 s. and 3 d. in money numbered, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17671209-26-victim213" type="victimName">
                        Susannh 
                        Warnham 
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim213" type="surname" value="Warnham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim213" type="given" value="Susannh"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-victim213" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   , in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17671209-26-person214">
                        Anne 
                        Nevell 
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person214" type="surname" value="Nevell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-person214" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-26-person214" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-26-person215">
                  Susannah 
                  Warnham 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person215" type="surname" value="Warnham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person215" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person215" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17671209-26-person216">
                  Anne 
                  Nevell 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person216" type="surname" value="Nevell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person216" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person216" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 11th of October there were only I and 
               <persName id="t17671209-26-person217">
                  Susanna 
                  Julian 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person217" type="surname" value="Julian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person217" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person217" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at our house in <placeName id="t17671209-26-crimeloc137">Park-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17671209-26-crimeloc137" type="placeName" value="Park-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17671209-26-crimeloc137" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-26-off130 t17671209-26-crimeloc137"></join>, Mrs. Nevell was then in the country, and had been about a fortnight; on that Sunday evening we fastened the house, we double locked the fore door and chained it, the kitchen window was secured as usual, the closet in the parlour was locked; we went to bed between nine and ten. We<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176712090014"></xptr> lay backwards next the Park in a garret; 
               <persName id="t17671209-26-person218">
                  Richard 
                  Knot 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person218" type="surname" value="Knot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person218" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : knocked at the door about seven the next morning, I came down to him; he asked who we had in the house all night; I said, nobody but my fellow servant and myself; then he said, I am afraid your house has been robbed, for I saw a man and a woman with a child go out of your house about half an hour after six; I begged if him to run after them, he and another man did; then I and my fellow servant went to search about the house; we found the kitchen window open, the sash frame cut away, and the sash up, the bolt on the inside was forced; this was a window fronting the street; it is in the area part of the window, is rather higher than the ground. I ran down into the kitchen first, there were two chairs thrown down; the kitchen was wet with two bottles of wine broke, one had red and the other white; there lay two large tallow candles; we had none in the house but what were locked in a candle chest, we used a bit of a wax one to light us to bed. I missed a new striped muslin apron, and three quarters of new striped muslin, and about 18 s. in money, which I left locked in a little trunk when I went to bed; then we went up into the dining-room, there we found a great deal of linen scattered about that had been in baskets, and there was a great deal missing. There was missing out of my mistress's room eight or nine shifts, a pair of sheets, a counterpane, a cotton gown, a table cloth, napkin, pillowbear, a petticoat, aprons, and a great deal of small linen; the lock seemed as if it had been forced.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-26-person219">
                  Susanna 
                  Julian 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person219" type="surname" value="Julian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person219" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave the same account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-26-person220">
                  Richard 
                  Knot 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person220" type="surname" value="Knot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person220" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 12th of October I was at work at a public pump in Park-street, about twelve yards from Mrs. Nevell's house; that pump drains the water from the kitchens of all the houses there; the pump is in the street against a wall that divides Queen's-square; I could see a little way into Mrs. Nevell's door when it opens from there; I went to pump as the clock struck six, and in about half an hour after I saw a man and a tall woman come out of Mrs. Nevell's house, the woman came out first, and the man after her; the woman turned and pulled the door to; I did not see the woman's face, but I can swear to her habit; she had a blue and a white striped silk gown, a little draggled up the tail, a black cardinal, and a black hat; she had a large bundle under her right arm, the outside like a white counterpane; the man was a short man, in a sort of a fustian frock, the stocking down of his right leg; he had dark brown hair tied behind in a club; he had a child lay cross his two arms, I saw it move; I kept pumping till about seven o'clock; I went to get a penny worth of purl, and saw Mrs. Nevell's door a-jar; I went and knocked at the door, and the first evidence came to me, she clapped her hands together, and said, Lord, Richard, how came the door open; I desired her to shut the door and fasten it, and I and a carpenter that was in the street went to see for the man and woman, but we missed them. When I saw the prisoner's two days after, I knew them again, and followed the man, he had lived at Mrs. Nevell's; I knew him, and have drunk with him when he lived there, but he was got so far out of my knowledge that I did not recollect him then; he has been discharge from thence about a year, I believe; I saw his face very plain as he came out of the house, but it did not strike me that it was he. I was sent for to the lady after she came to town, and described the man and woman; the prisoners were suspected from my information; I was informed they lodged somewhere in Peter-street; I went to the house, and asked if such people lodged in the house; the woman of the house said yes; I said I should be glad to speak with the woman; the woman at the bar came down; I said, pray madam, is your husband at home; she said, yes, pray walk up; she had the same gown on as she had the morning when she came out of Mrs. Nevell's house; I went up stairs, and desired the coachman who was with me to follow me; there was the man at the bar; I clapped my hand on his shoulder, and said, you are the man, I want and said the same to the woman; the coachman and I took them in custody; the woman knowing the coachman said, Lord, Phil, what is the matter: we took them before Justice Miller; they took the child with them: they denied the charge there; I told the Justice I would not swear downright, but to the best of my knowledge they are the people; they were discharged, not finding any of the things upon them. The next morning we searched their lodgings, but found nothing; they were taken before Sir 
               <persName id="t17671209-26-person221">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person221" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person221" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; there their landlady came and took her oath they were in their lodgings the night this happened, from ten at night to nine the next morning; they were then discharged again. Some time about the 29th of October I was sent for to Mrs. Nevell's; she told me to be at Sir 
               <persName id="t17671209-26-person222">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person222" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person222" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's by 11 o'clock; I went; I was asked whether I knew them; I said I did; then I swore positively they were the people, and that I knew them well; then they were committed, the woman to Tothill-fields Bridewell,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176712090015"></xptr> and the man to New Prison. I am very clear as to the man, the woman by her height and clothes I can swear to.</p>
               <p>Q How came you to be uncertain twice before. and yet to be certain a fortnight after?</p>
               <p>Knot. Because of the ring being found upon the woman, and the man grows more and more in my knowledge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-26-person223">
                  William 
                  Masters 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person223" type="surname" value="Masters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person223" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pawnbroker, and live in Holbourn. On the 24th of October the woman at the bar brought this diamond ring (holding one in his hand) to me, and asked 18 s. upon it; she told me she brought it from one Mrs. Smithfield her mistress, that lived in Red Lion-street, Holbourn; I asked her her own name; she said it was 
               <persName id="t17671209-26-person224">
                  Anne 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person224" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person224" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I desired to have an opportunity to see her mistress; she said, her mistress desired nobody might come home with her, she was not very well, she went away and left the ring; she came back in about eight or ten minutes, and told me her master was come home in liquor, and desired I would let her have the ring again, and when he was gone to bed or the tavern, I might have an opportunity of seeing her mistress; this was about six in the evening; I refused to give it her; she went away. I waited till the Thursday following to see if such a ring was advertised; finding none between Wednesday and Saturday, I advertised it in the Daily and Public Advertisers, and Gazetteer, and on Saturday the 31st of October Mrs. Nevell applied to see the ring; I shewed it her; she said she believed it to be her ring, her daughter was with her; she seemed more clear in it; Mrs. Nevell told me she had a suspicion of two people that had lived in her house; I took the woman up; she then denied knowing any thing of the ring.</p>
               <p>Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17671209-26-person225">
                  Anne 
                  Nevell 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person225" type="surname" value="Nevell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person225" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person225" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Epsom on the 11th of October; I left my two maids which have been examined, in my house in Park-street, (she takes the ring in her hand) I am very sure this is my ring which was missing out of a drawer, when the things mentioned in the indictment were missing; I had the key of my bureau in which it was with me in the country; I came to town the very night after I heard of my house being broke open; I found my house in great disorder, as my maids have given an account; the two prisoners had both lived in my house.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Ellis. I am brother to Mrs. Nevell; this ring (taking it in his hand) was in my possession 35 years ago; I parted with it to my sister 
               <persName id="t17671209-26-person226">
                  Martha 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person226" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person226" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person226" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             about nine years ago.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Nevell. My sister 
               <persName id="t17671209-26-person227">
                  Martha 
                  Ellis 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person227" type="surname" value="Ellis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person227" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             gave it me about five years ago.</p>
               <p>Mr. Ellis. I described it particularly to the pawnbroker before I saw it; there is a particular flaw in the middle stone, by which I am sure.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-26-person228">
                  Richard 
                  Griffith 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person228" type="surname" value="Griffith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person228" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's defence.</p>
               <p>I never was within Mrs. Nevell's house not near it for the last six months, no nearer than Dartmouth-street.</p>
               <p>Mary Griffiths's defence.</p>
               <p>I never was in a pawnbroker's shop in Holbourn in my life; I know nothing of the ring.</p>
               <p>Masters. I am sure this woman is the same that brought the ring to me.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-26-person229">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Bartlet 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person229" type="surname" value="Bartlet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person229" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person229" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoners lodged with me; they came about five weeks before the 12th of October; they are the man and wife; they have one child about seven months old.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing particular on the 11th of October.</p>
               <p>E. Bartlet. No, nothing, unless they were in our house; they always kept good hours.</p>
               <p>Q. Where they both in your house that Sunday?</p>
               <p>E. Bartlet. I believe they were.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go to bed that Sunday night?</p>
               <p>E. Bartlet. About eight o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they in your house then?</p>
               <p>E. Bartlet. I really believe they were, but I did not see them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not swear before Justice Fielding, that they were in your house all that night?</p>
               <p>E. Bartlet. No; I swore they were to the best of my knowledge; I should be very loth to take an oath of that I was not sure of.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thing of them on Monday morning?</p>
               <p>E. Bartlet. I saw them come down stairs on that morning about eight o'clock; they behaved well while with us.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-26-person230">
                  William 
                  Bartlet 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person230" type="surname" value="Bartlet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person230" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoners lodged with us.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether the two prisoners were at home that Sunday night?</p>
               <p>Bartlet. I believe they might, but I was in bed before nine; I did not see them in the morning, for I went out to the market; I believe them to be very honest people.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-26-person231">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17671209-26-person231" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person231" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a lodger in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether they were out of the house that Sunday night?</p>
               <p>Davis. I do not know whether they were out or in; I never trouble my head with any lodgers;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176712090016"></xptr> when the pawnbroker came to take the woman, he said she did not answer the description of the woman that came to pawn the ring.</p>
               <p>Masters. When I went up to the woman's room, I said to her, my dear, do you know me; she said, no, Sir; I shewed her the ring, and asked her if she did not bring that to me; she said, no; I said, that the time she came she appeared paler than she did then, but I expressed no doubt about her; I gave order to the constable to take her into custody, knowing she was absolutely the same woman.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17671209-26-verdict138" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671209-26-verdict138" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
