<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651211-45">
               <interp inst="t17651211-45" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-45" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-45" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651211"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651211-45" type="date" value="17651211"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651211-45-off271-c315" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-45-defend416 t17651211-45-off271 t17651211-45-verdict277"></join>
         
               <p>51. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17651211-45-defend416" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Bonson 
                  <interp inst="t17651211-45-defend416" type="surname" value="Bonson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-defend416" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-defend416" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that he, on the <rs id="t17651211-45-cd270" type="crimeDate">25th of October</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-45-off271 t17651211-45-cd270"></join>, <rs id="t17651211-45-off271" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-off271" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-off271" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               about the hour of one in the night of the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17651211-45-victim418" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Wood 
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim418" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim418" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim418" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and stealing 2 linen curtains, value 10 s. 1 linen head-cloth, value 2 s. 1 linen tester-cloth, value 2 s. 6 linen valences, value 2 s. 2 looking-glasses, value 4 s. 1 wooden tea-chest, with 2 tin canisters, the property of 
                     <persName id="t17651211-45-person419">
                        William 
                        Wood 
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person419" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-person419" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-person419" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  : one feather-bed;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110029"></xptr> value 10 s. 1 mattrass, 1 pillow, 1 woollen blanket, 1 quilt, 1 copper tea-kettle, and 2 brass candlesticks, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17651211-45-victim421" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Stockdale 
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim421" type="surname" value="Stockdale"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim421" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim421" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; 1 looking-glass in a wooden frame, 7 aprons, 4 pair of linen sleeves, 1 yard of linen cloth, a cotton gown, 3 linen caps, a pair of thread stockings, and 2 pieces of green baize, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17651211-45-victim423" type="victimName">
                           Anne Adamson 
                           Weston 
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim423" type="surname" value="Weston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim423" type="given" value="Anne Adamson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim423" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , <rs id="t17651211-45-viclabel272" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-45-victim423 t17651211-45-viclabel272"></join>; a copper saucepan and cover, a brass saucepan, a tin saucepan, a tin boiler, 2 wooden tea-chests with 3 tin cannisters, a looking-glass with a wooden frame, a pillow, 3 blankets, a copper warming-pan, a brass candlestick, a linen napkin, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17651211-45-victim425" type="victimName">
                           Francis 
                           Snell 
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim425" type="surname" value="Snell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim425" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; 1 feather-bed, 1 pillow, 2 woollen blankets, a quilt, 6 china cups, 6 china saucers, a copper saucepan and cover, a copper tea-kettle, a brass fender, an iron poker, and iron shovel, a pair of iron tongs, 1 serge curtain, and 1 serge valence, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17651211-45-victim427" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Clain 
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim427" type="surname" value="Clain"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim427" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17651211-45-victim427" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the said dwelling-house
            </rs>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-45-person428">
                  William 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17651211-45-person428" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person428" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person428" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17651211-45-crimeloc273">Castle-street on the back of Long-acre</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-45-crimeloc273" type="placeName" value="Castle-street on the back of Long-acre"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17651211-45-crimeloc273" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-45-off271 t17651211-45-crimeloc273"></join>. My house was broke open between the 20th and 26th of October last, but what day I cannot justly tell: I left it late on the Sunday, and on the Saturday after I sent my daughter to the garden to get some parsley; she returned and told me it had been broke open. I let it out in lodgings, these people here are tenants to me; I have an apartment to myself in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is this house?</p>
               <p>Wood. It is joining to Tottenham turnpike in Islington road: I lodge there in the summer time, but very seldom in the winter. Mr. Clain, Mr. Stockdale, and Mr. Snell, lodge there; the woman is a <rs id="t17651211-45-viclabel274" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-45-victim423 t17651211-45-viclabel274"></join>. I went there on Sunday the 27th, and found the thief had got in at the back window, by wrenching the bar off. I missed two linen curtains, a head-cloth, a tester-cloth, 6 valences, 2 looking-glasses, and a tea-chest: I lost more since, but these things I have found again; they were at one Crofts's, a broker, at the Bell in Drury-lane. (Produced and deposed to.) I have matched the tester-cloth with the piece they left behind where they cut it off, and it matched exactly. It is entirely new.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Wood. I am a <rs id="t17651211-45-viclabel275" type="occupation">broker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-45-victim418 t17651211-45-viclabel275"></join>. I saw the prisoner at Justice Fielding's about the 5th of November; he there acknowledged the taking these things away, but said he was not in the house. He was asked how he conveyed the things away from Tottenham-court: his answer was,</p>
               <p>"We carried them away on our backs."</p>
               <p>Q. Does the house stand alone?</p>
               <p>Wood. It does; and the furniture of the house belonged to us: the prisoner owned he was in the garden, and they carried them upon the rising ground, and put them over the pales.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say who did break the house?</p>
               <p>Wood. I cannot say he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Crofts here?</p>
               <p>Wood. No, he is not; he was not bound over.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-45-person429">
                  Anne 
                  Adamson 
               <interp inst="t17651211-45-person429" type="surname" value="Adamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person429" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person429" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             Weston. I am servant to Mr. Stockdale; my box was broke open in that house, and all that was in it was taken out; it was full of linen; there were ten guineas in a purse taken away. I was in London at the time the house was broke, at my master's house in Green-street, by Leicester-fields. I was in the house about a fortnight before the house was broke; and I expected my box to come to town the very day the house was broke. I found a shift body, a cotton gown, some sleeves, 7 aprons, a pair of white stockings, and some green cloth, at the prisoner's house: he <rs id="t17651211-45-deflabel276" type="occupation">kept a chandler's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-45-defend416 t17651211-45-deflabel276"></join> in Parker's-lane. These were taken out of my box which stood in the kitchen. There was nobody left in the house when I went from it, as I know of. I heard the prisoner say, he only received the bundle as it was thrown out at the window; he never was in the house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-45-person430">
                  Francis 
                  Snell 
               <interp inst="t17651211-45-person430" type="surname" value="Snell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person430" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have a room at this house: I went there on Sunday the 20th of October, in order to bring some of my things away. I left bed, bedding, and several things in the room. I heard the house was broke open on the 26th. I went there at night, between the hours of 7 and 8. I found my apartment broke open, a stock-lock and pad-lock to the door were both broke: I was the last person in the house on that Sunday, and I fastened it when I went away. I missed bed, bedding, 3 blankets, a quilt, a mattrass, a pair of sheets, 2 pillows, a bolster, a copper warming-pan, and a brass candlestick: I have found some again; the brass candlestick, copper warming-pan, and a blanket, at the prisoner's house; the blanket was on his bed. (Produced and deposed to.) I saw the prisoner in Newgate, and there heard him say he and 
               <persName id="t17651211-45-person431">
                  Evan 
                  Parry 
               <interp inst="t17651211-45-person431" type="surname" value="Parry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person431" type="given" value="Evan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person431" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (not taken) began about 7 o'clock (but did not mention the day); that they carried 5 beds out of the house all on their backs; that they went 6 or 7 times each, and deposited them near Lord Baltimore's house, and carried them all home before day-light but one bundle; and when they came back for that, somebody had carried it away for them.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he say his house was?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176512110030"></xptr>Snell. I knew he lived in Parker's-lane: he said he staid in the garden while the other man bundled them up, and threw them out to him. I saw the window was wrenched open, as Mr. Wood has mentioned; there were five locks in the house broke.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-45-person432">
                  Thomas 
                  Clain 
               <interp inst="t17651211-45-person432" type="surname" value="Clain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person432" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in this house; I lost a bed-bolster, 2 pillows, 4 blankets, a quilt, curtains to a four-post bedstead, 6 cups and saucers, a blue surtout coat, a waistcoat, a brass sender, shovel, and tongs. I found a good many of my things at Crofts's the broker; I found two of my curtains in the prisoner's house, (produced and deposed to.) I heard the prisoner say the same as Mr. Snell has mentioned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-45-person433">
                  Terence
                   M'Ginnis
               <interp inst="t17651211-45-person433" type="surname" value="M'Ginnis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person433" type="given" value="Terence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. On the 4th of November, I went to the prisoner's and Crofts's houses, and found the things produced here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651211-45-person434">
                  Thomas 
                  Stockdale 
               <interp inst="t17651211-45-person434" type="surname" value="Stockdale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person434" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Wood let me know the house was broke open, on the 26th of October; I went there and found my door unlocked, and the two bolts unbolted; the lock of 
               <persName id="t17651211-45-person435">
                  Anne Adamson 
                  Weston 
               <interp inst="t17651211-45-person435" type="surname" value="Weston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person435" type="given" value="Anne Adamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-person435" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's box broke, and entirely empty. I found a bed tied up ready to be taken away. I missed a bed, mattrass, pillow, and 2 blankets, a copper tea-kettle, a quilt, and 2 brass candlesticks. I had word the prisoner was taken, and I went to Parker's-lane to his house; there I found the feather-bed, mattrass, 2 blankets, and the copper tea-kettle. I went to him in Clerkenwell-prison. I asked him about the things; he told me Mr. Crofts had bought near 13 beds of him: he told me Parry went into the house, and he stood without to receive them, and there is a little mount in the garden, from which he put them over the pales.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you how he got into the house?</p>
               <p>Stockdale. I think he said he went in at a window, and over a lumber-room; I found the bar to the back window had been wrenched.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never sold any of them things to Mr. Crofts; neither was I ever in the prosecutor's house; if Mr. Crofts was here, I dare say he would say who he bought them of. I lived with one gentleman 7 years, and with another 2. My last master was a bankrupt, then I left him, and became acquainted with Mr. Parry.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651211-45-verdict277" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-verdict277" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17651211-45-punish278" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651211-45-punish278" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651211-45-defend416 t17651211-45-punish278"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There were 14 other indictments against him.</p>
            </div1>
