<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650918-3">
               <interp inst="t17650918-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-3" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650918"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-3" type="date" value="17650918"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650918-3-off17-c67" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-3-defend73 t17650918-3-off17 t17650918-3-verdict20"></join>
         
               <p>418. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650918-3-defend73" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Rook 
                  <interp inst="t17650918-3-defend73" type="surname" value="Rook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-3-defend73" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-3-defend73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17650918-3-off17" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-3-off17" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-3-off17" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the King's high-way, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650918-3-victim75" type="victimName">
                           Benjamin 
                           Tomlinson 
                        <interp inst="t17650918-3-victim75" type="surname" value="Tomlinson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-3-victim75" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-3-victim75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-3-off17 t17650918-3-victim75"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person a silver watch, value 40 s. his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650918-3-cd18" type="crimeDate">July 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-3-off17 t17650918-3-cd18"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-3-person76">
                  Benjamin 
                  Tomlinson 
               <interp inst="t17650918-3-person76" type="surname" value="Tomlinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-3-person76" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-3-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in Brokers-Row: I had been at Vauxhall on the 19th of July, and coming back, in <placeName id="t17650918-3-crimeloc19">Bow-street, Covent-Garden</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-3-crimeloc19" type="placeName" value="Bow-street, Covent-Garden"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-3-crimeloc19" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-3-off17 t17650918-3-crimeloc19"></join>, past twelve at night, a little boy, named Mackrell, attempted to pick my pocket: I prevented him: after which the prisoner came up, pretending to be drunk, and jostled against me, and whip'd out my watch, and took to his heels.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he put you in fear?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176509180007"></xptr>Tomlinson. I was afraid when he jostled me; it was done almost in an instant.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Tomlinson. No, not a word.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he present any pistol or instrument to you?</p>
               <p>Tomlinson. No. In the morning I went to Justice Fielding, and got it advertised, Number forgot.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you had it in your pocket at the time the prisoner came up to you?</p>
               <p>Tomlinson. I am sure I had, and I felt it go from me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Clay. The boy Mackrell was in custody before Justice Girdler for robbing a till; the justice sent for me; I heard the low declare by had been concerned with the prisoner. Queen, and Parker, in robbing several talk: he denied to be admitted an evidence, and said he could a good many of them: he gave an account of this robbery, and informed us where his companions were to be found. I, with the assistance of some officers, took the three persons, Parker, Quin, and the prisoner: the boy told me he and the prisoner had sold the watch in the Minories to Mr. Coleman. I took the boy there, and Mr. Coleman brought the watch to the justice's; there the prosecutor swore to it, and to the prisoner robbing him of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-3-person77">
                  David 
                  Coleman 
               <interp inst="t17650918-3-person77" type="surname" value="Coleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-3-person77" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-3-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I bought this watch (holding a silver watch in his hand) of the prisoner at the bar, on the Saturday after the robbery: he first ask'd to see a pair of silver buckles: we agreed for a pair; then he shewed me this watch, and said he had had it twelve months: he gave me his name in writing, and I gave him two guineas for it.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is my watch, which I lost that night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I came honestly by the watch; I found it between five and six in the morning on a Saturday, and I sold it to that gentleman: I gave him a note of my name, and where I was to be found. This chap, Mackrell, that was to be evidence against me, has been an evidence here three times, and by three different names.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650918-3-verdict20" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-3-verdict20" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-3-verdict20" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing the watch
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Acquitted of the robbery. <rs id="t17650918-3-punish21" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-3-punish21" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-3-defend73 t17650918-3-punish21"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
