<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610506-20">
               <interp inst="t17610506-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-20" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610506"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-20" type="date" value="17610506"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610506-20-off107-c225" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-20-defend263 t17610506-20-off107 t17610506-20-verdict111"></join>
         
               <p>179. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610506-20-defend263" type="defendantName">
                     Andrew 
                     Orme 
                  <interp inst="t17610506-20-defend263" type="surname" value="Orme"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-defend263" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-defend263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610506-20-off107" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-off107" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-off107" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing one silver tankard, value 5 l. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17610506-20-victim265" type="victimName">
                           Joseph 
                           Inman 
                        <interp inst="t17610506-20-victim265" type="surname" value="Inman"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-20-victim265" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610506-20-victim265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-20-off107 t17610506-20-victim265"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said Joseph
            </rs>, <rs id="t17610506-20-cd108" type="crimeDate">April 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-20-off107 t17610506-20-cd108"></join>.8</p> 
               <p>Joseph Inman. I live in the Tower of London, just at the going in at the gates.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Inman. I am a <rs id="t17610506-20-viclabel109" type="occupation">victualler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-20-victim265 t17610506-20-viclabel109"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your house in Middlesex?</p>
               <p>Inman. It is. I lost a quart silver tankard, it was without a lid; I missed it about three o'clock, on the eleventh of October; my boy, named 
               <persName id="t17610506-20-person266">
                  William 
                  Twine 
               <interp inst="t17610506-20-person266" type="surname" value="Twine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person266" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , told me first when it was missing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see it again?</p>
               <p>Inman. No, never. I suspected the prisoner, he having been in the house at the time. I found him the next morning at his lodging. I said, Andrew, how are you? He staid some time, and could not speak to me. I then said, You know the errand that I am come about; he said no. I said, the tankard that you took by mistake from my house. He said he knew nothing of it. Said I, Will you go into the Tower with me? He said he would; if I wou'd go home, he would come presently (he was just getting up and dressing himself.) I said I would wait. I waited, he went with me to the Tower.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>Inman. A <rs id="t17610506-20-deflabel110" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-20-defend263 t17610506-20-deflabel110"></join>. There was a serjeant belonging to the same company took him into custody, and he was confined by the captain of the guard's order?</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own or deny it?</p>
               <p>Inman. He denied having the tankard all the time; on the Sunday night he made his escape, that was on the 12th of October, and was not taken till the 8th of April last; then he was examined before Justice Fielding but would not confess; but when he came to the place where he clerk sits, he said to me, Mr. Inman, I'll pay you so much a week for your tankard; charge what you think proper.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say what he would pay a week?</p>
               <p>Inman. He said, four or five shillings a week, till it was out. I said, what business have you to pay any money if you know you had not my tankard; I shall not do any such thing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He set some of the people to ask me to pay for it; I said, I would pay for it rather that be confined in Newgate, if I knew any thing at all of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-20-person267">
                  William 
                  Twine 
               <interp inst="t17610506-20-person267" type="surname" value="Twine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person267" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am 15 years old next August.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the nature of an oath?</p>
               <p>Twine. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you to do or say?</p>
               <p>Twine. I am to speak the truth, if not, I am to be put into the pillory, and to go to the d - l when I die.</p>
               <p>He is sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Twine. I am servant to Mr. Inman.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Twine. I do, very well, he used my master's house, and was there that day in the afternoon, that the tankard was missing. He came in and called for a tankard of beer, I went down and filled a pewter quart pot, and told him we had never a tankard out of use. He sat down in a wooden two-armed chair by a table, then there were some watermen, and some blacksmiths came in; after that he gave me a sixpence to change, he said, there were some company in the stone-kitchen (a publick house hard by) that were to come to him, he said, he would have a tankard. I went and took a silver tankard from the bar, it had a smooth handle, and never a lid to it, and filled it, and set it on the table by him; he gave me the money, and I went down stairs, and did not stay below a quarter of an hour, only a few minutes, and when I came up again, he was gone. I looked on the table, and did not see the tankard; I asked my mistress if she had taken it, and the maid. and they both said no, we have never seen it since.</p>
               <p>Rachiel Spencer. I am servant to Mr. Inman, I saw the prisoner at the bar, at our house that day, and saw the boy (the last witness) set a tankard before him, and saw him drink out of it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-20-person268">
                  William 
                  Murphy 
               <interp inst="t17610506-20-person268" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person268" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the officer that had the prisoner in custody. I heard him say, he did not steal it, but he sold it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060033"></xptr>Murphy. This was in my kitchen; I said to him, what did you sell? My arse he said: he said, at Mr. Fielding's, he would give Mr. Inman five shillings a week, if he would make it up with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention the tankard or mug, when he said he would make it up?</p>
               <p>Murphy. No, he did not; he was very much in liquor, when I took him on the eighth of April.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he drunk or sober, when he offered five shillings a week to make it up?</p>
               <p>Murphy. He was very sober.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>They asked me if I was willing to pay for the tankard, and that Mr. Inman would put up with any thing a week. I said, I would pay any thing if I was guilty; but, as I was not, I would not. They desired me as much as they could, to pay for it, but I would not. They said, if I had pawned or sold it, they would pay the money to get it again, but I said, I know no more of it than the child unborn.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-20-person269">
                  William 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17610506-20-person269" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person269" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about five years, he worked with me in the branch of making iron-chapes, for silver buckles.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he work with you?</p>
               <p>Jones. Three years, but it is two years ago since he worked with me last; I have imployed him occasionally.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Jones. He is a very honest man, he might have had it in his power to have robbed me of hundreds; and after my business fell off, I gave him liberty to make use of all my utensils.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Jones. I then lived in Foster-lane, but I live now in the Old Bailey. I would employ him now, was he discharged.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Jones. I am a working goldsmith.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-20-person270">
                  Simon 
                  Cooley 
               <interp inst="t17610506-20-person270" type="surname" value="Cooley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person270" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , I live upon Clerkenwell-green.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Cooley. I am a silver buckle-maker, I have known the prisoner five years, he has been in my shop many a time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever work for you?</p>
               <p>Cooley. No, he has had great opportunities to have robbed me within this 12 months, but I never lost any thing by him; he used to come two or three times a week to finish his work. I have had three or four hundred ounces of silver lying about, he has been there when we have been at breakfast or dinner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-20-person271">
                  Andrew 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17610506-20-person271" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person271" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Noble-street.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Price. I am a silver-smith, I have known the prisoner six years, I always took him to be a very honest worthy deserving man, he is a soldier.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-20-person272">
                  John 
                  Nicholas 
               <interp inst="t17610506-20-person272" type="surname" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person272" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about half a year, he has worked in my shop almost ever since.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Nicholas. He has the character of a very honest man, I never knew to the contrary. I have trusted him with 20 l. worth of silver in the shop, and nobody in it but me and him. He used to make chapes for silver buckles, and work in the same shop where the silver was prepared.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-20-person273">
                  James 
                  Eadey 
               <interp inst="t17610506-20-person273" type="surname" value="Eadey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person273" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a victualler, he has used my house, and paid me very honestly; I always took him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Eadey. I have known him this four years.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610506-20-verdict111" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-20-verdict111" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
