<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610506-18">
               <interp inst="t17610506-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-18" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610506"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610506-18" type="date" value="17610506"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610506-18-off94-c202" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-18-defend235 t17610506-18-off94 t17610506-18-verdict97"></join>
         
               <p>177. (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610506-18-defend235" type="defendantName">
                     Simon 
                     Pugh 
                  <interp inst="t17610506-18-defend235" type="surname" value="Pugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-defend235" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-defend235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610506-18-off94" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-off94" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-off94" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a bay gelding, value eleven pounds
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610506-18-victim237" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Robins 
                  <interp inst="t17610506-18-victim237" type="surname" value="Robins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-victim237" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-victim237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-18-off94 t17610506-18-victim237"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610506-18-cd95" type="crimeDate">July 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-18-off94 t17610506-18-cd95"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610506-18-person238">
                  William 
                  Robins 
               <interp inst="t17610506-18-person238" type="surname" value="Robins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-person238" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Bristol. On the 30th of July last, the prisoner at the bar came and hired two horses of me, one for himself, and the other for his servant, a lad about 13 years of age, to go to Bath.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Robins. I am a <rs id="t17610506-18-viclabel96" type="occupation">blacksmith and ironmonger</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610506-18-victim237 t17610506-18-viclabel96"></join> by trade, and I keep chaises and horses to let out: he hired them from the 30th of July, to the 25th of 
               <persName id="t17610506-18-person239">
                  August 
                  He 
               <interp inst="t17610506-18-person239" type="surname" value="He"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-person239" type="given" value="August"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said he was captain of a tender, and bargained for four pounds. He had them to Bath, and left one at the Angel there. It cost me a guinea to redeem him, and the other he rode to London, and sold him for half his value. I have here the receipt for the money I paid for my horse he left at the Angel. Upon<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176105060030"></xptr> hearing he was come from Bath to London. I wrote to an acquaintance here, for him to enquire after Capt. Pugh. I described the horse; in about a week or ten days after he wrote me a letter he had found the gelding, and Pugh was in prison; he did not say for what. I set out for London, and went to justice Fielding, and told him what I came about; the justice said it was of no use to grant me a warrant, for he was in jail for two or three crimes already; that he would be prosecuted, and it would be to no purpose for me to throw away money too.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen your horse since?</p>
               <p>Robins. I have, he is at Kentish-town, there is my brand-mark upon him. I saw him the eighth or ninth of September, he was in the possession of a farmer, but one 
               <persName id="t17610506-18-person240">
                  William 
                  Miller 
               <interp inst="t17610506-18-person240" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-person240" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             told me how he came by the horse. The prisoner sent me a letter from Richmond, dated July 18.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know he sent it?</p>
               <p>Robins. I have seen his hand-writing, and am pretty well assured it was his own hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen him write?</p>
               <p>Robins. I have; he gave me a note for 4 l. 10 s. 6 d. When he hired the horse I lent him half a guinea out of my own pocket. I never saw him write only that time. The direction was torn off; the contents are, He is very sorry he is so long absent, but the gelding is very well, and he is got almost at the end of his trouble, and it will be in his power to answer all in about a fortnight, and desires to be indulged that time. I went to the prisoner, he was in the Poultry-compter. He desired me not to prosecute him, and he would give me any satisfaction; and told me he had sold my horse to one Davis, an officer. I cannot say whether he told me what he sold him for. Then I went to the Grand Jury here in September sessions, and found the bill. When I came here this time I went to see him in prison; he said he would give me any satisfaction, in case I would not prosecute him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610506-18-verdict97" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610506-18-verdict97" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq.
            </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
