<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660409-57">
               <interp inst="t17660409-57" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660409-57" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660409-57" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660409"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660409-57" type="date" value="17660409"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660409-57-off333-c450" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-57-defend583 t17660409-57-off333 t17660409-57-verdict336"></join>
         
               <p>269. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-defend583" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Pepper 
                  <interp inst="t17660409-57-defend583" type="surname" value="Pepper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-defend583" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-defend583" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660409-57-off333" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-off333" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-off333" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a grey gelding, value 6 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-victim585" type="victimName">
                     Luke 
                     Sanderson 
                  <interp inst="t17660409-57-victim585" type="surname" value="Sanderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-victim585" type="given" value="Luke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-victim585" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-57-off333 t17660409-57-victim585"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660409-57-cd334" type="crimeDate">December 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-57-off333 t17660409-57-cd334"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-person586">
                  Luke 
                  Sanderson 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person586" type="surname" value="Sanderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person586" type="given" value="Luke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person586" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17660409-57-crimeloc335">Sortery in Huntingdonshire</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660409-57-crimeloc335" type="placeName" value="Sortery in Huntingdonshire"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660409-57-crimeloc335" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-57-off333 t17660409-57-crimeloc335"></join>: I lost a grey colt on the 6th of December, out of a little close about half a mile from Sortery, it was seen there the day it was lost.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe the colt.</p>
               <p>Sanderson. It was a grey gelding, with a bald face, the letter S in pitch on him in four places, a switch tail, and all white legs. Mr. Bolton's man, the Peterborough carner, brought him down from London, I think on the 6th of March.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-person587">
                  William 
                  Watkins 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person587" type="surname" value="Watkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person587" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person587" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live within four miles of Oxford, I keep a little farm and deal in horse: on the 19th or 20th of December I was in Smithfield; the prisoner shewed me a grey colt, a gelding with a bald face, a long tail, and four white legs, come three years old; he saw a black gelding of mine in the George-yard; he said he had got a pretty colt at home, he should be glad to change with me, and asked me where I lay at night; I said at the Pied-Bull at Islington; he agreed to come to me at nine in the morning: when he saw mine out he liked him very well; I agreed to go with him to Hockley in the Hole to see his, he asked me nine guineas for him; there was a man with him who said, you shall go into the house and have a pot of beer and make a bargain; in drinking, he asked two guineas and a half betwixt the horse and colt; a man along with me said, you shall give him a guinea to boot: I said I would, and no more. We were going away; he called to me and said, you shall give me half a guinea more. I said I would not: then it was agreed that I should spend a shilling. We went to Islington for the horse; he said he went down within about four miles of Oundle in Northamptonshire, and bought three or four more colts. I said, I wonder Mr. Pepper you should buy such young things as these to bring to London; he said he did not know what would suit London. After this I changed the grey colt away to one 
               <persName id="t17660409-57-person588">
                  Richard 
                  Rand 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person588" type="surname" value="Rand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person588" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person588" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             at Newport Pagnel, he lives near Stoney Stratford: after that I was taken up in Oxfordshire, by 
               <persName id="t17660409-57-person589">
                  Robert 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person589" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person589" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person589" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Nightingale, to know how I came by the colt: I said I could find the man that I bought him of; and as we were walking in Fleet-street, we met the prisoner. I said, Mr. Pepper, I find this colt is a stolen one: he said, what have you to do with me: I said it is pity I should lose all my money; said he, you have no demand on me; I said, I hope you will not let me lose the money: he said he bought the colt at Higham Ferrers fair, and that he was very sorry that he, being so very lately in trouble, should be in trouble again: he gave me a guinea and a watch. I went with Mr. King to Mr. Rand, and gave him his money back.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-person590">
                  Robert 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person590" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person590" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person590" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the colt in the custody of Mr. Rand, he delivered him to me; I brought him to London from within four miles of Stoney Stratford,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176604090028"></xptr> and delivered him to go down with the waggoner to the prosecutor. I was with Mr. Watkins when we met the prisoner; he went and took him by the collar, and said, I have a warrant against you for stealing the colt; said Pepper, what do you want with me; said Watkins, I want satisfaction. The prisoner said, go along with me and I'll give you satisfaction. We went to the prisoner's wife's father's, there he gave him a watch and a guinea. Then he said to me, I suppose you are satisfied with me for what I have done. I said, here is Sir 
               <persName id="t17660409-57-person591">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person591" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person591" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person591" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's warrant against you; said he, it is very hard you should take my money and take me too, I'll give you an hundred pounds bail. I said I should take no bail: said he, I can't say I like to go before Sir John, for I have heard he is an ill-natured man; he chose to go before Mr. Welch. I got him into a coach, and ordered the coach to drive to Sir John's; when we came there, he knew Sir John better than I did. Sir John asked Watkins where the colt was; Watkins said he is down in Buckinghamshire, within a little of Stoney Stratford, at one farmer Rand's, at Wolverton, and he knew it to be the same colt. Sir John said, I'll take care of Mr. Pepper, while you go and return again. We went down to Mr. Rand's for the colt, and Mr. Rand allowed it was the same colt he had of Mr. Watkins; Mr. Watkins gave him five guineas back, so we brought the colt to London, and delivered him at the Horseshoe inn, in order to be sent down to the prosecutor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-person592">
                  John 
                  Drake 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person592" type="surname" value="Drake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person592" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person592" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am hostler at the Horseshoe inn: Mr. Watkins delivered the grey colt to me; he had a bald face, four white legs, and a long tail; he staid there four days, then I delivered him to Mr. Bolton's man, to go to the gentleman that he belonged to.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had the colt in a chop at Higham Ferrers, I gave a guinea to boot. Please to ask Mr. Watkins whether there were any brand marks upon him.</p>
               <p>Watkins to the question. There were the appearance of the marks on him.</p>
               <p>King answered the same.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I paid 6 l. to Mr. Watkins: there was a watch valued 5 l. and a guinea, there were three of them, and that was all their demand: when we were writing the receipt, Watkins said he could not sign it, but he would make his mark.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-person593">
                  John 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person593" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person593" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person593" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a grocer in Charles-street, Grosvenor-square: I have known Mr. Pepper between three and four years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I never heard any otherwise but that he is a very honest just man; he delivered the horse. He came to my house and brought three gentlemen with him, I believe they were horse-dealers, Mr. Watkins was one of them and Mr. King another; there was a great dispute about paying for this grey colt that had been chop'd between them, their demands were 6 l. I was to pay them 6 l. and there was to be no farther demand upon Mr. Pepper; they were all seemingly contented; after they had the money the case was altered; Mr. King said it was not 20 guineas would satisfy him, he pulled out a warrant, and insisted upon Mr. Pepper's going along with him, they went away to Justice Fielding's. I always looked upon Mr. Pepper to be a very honest man; I never heard of any imputation to the contrary before this time.</p>
               <p>Q. What no sort of imputation at all?</p>
               <p>Cooper. No, none.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you never heard any ill as to his character before this?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I am sure I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. What nothing within this two months?</p>
               <p>Cooper. (No answer.)</p>
               <p>Q. Was he not tried here last sessions?</p>
               <p>Cooper. That is not two months ago: I never heard any thing before that of last sessions besides this.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you pay the money?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I paid it in a watch which was reckoned at five guineas, and a guinea, and they seemed very well contented with it. Here is the receipt, (producing it.)</p>
               <p>It is read to this purport.</p>
               <p>Feb. 17, 1766. Receiv'd of Mr. 
               <persName id="t17660409-57-person594">
                  John 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person594" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person594" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person594" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the sum of six pounds for a horse, on the account of Mr. Pepper, per + the mark of</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-person595">
                  William 
                  Watkins 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person595" type="surname" value="Watkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person595" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person595" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Are you related to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I am, he married my daughter. The matter was settled, and they said they would put Mr. Pepper to no farther trouble.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-person596">
                  Charles 
                  James 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person596" type="surname" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person596" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person596" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a pork-shop in Golden-lane; I have known the prisoner about a year, he bears a very good character as ever a man need to bear.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-person597">
                  George 
                  Whickerback 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person597" type="surname" value="Whickerback"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person597" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person597" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about nine years, I always took him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176604090029"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-person598">
                  John 
                  Hunt 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person598" type="surname" value="Hunt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person598" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person598" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 11 or 12 years, I always believed him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-person599">
                  Jonathan 
                  Crips 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person599" type="surname" value="Crips"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person599" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person599" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a cabinet and clock-case-maker, I have known him five or six years, I always took him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-57-person600">
                  Simon 
                  Pugh 
               <interp inst="t17660409-57-person600" type="surname" value="Pugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person600" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-person600" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a steel wire-drawer, I have known him eight or nine years; if I was worth a thousand pounds I would trust him with it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660409-57-verdict336" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660409-57-verdict336" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was detained to be tried at Huntingdon for stealing a gelding. See him tried for stealing a mare and gelding, No 142. in last Sessions Paper.</p>
            </div1>
