<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610225-18">
               <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610225"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="date" value="17610225"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610225-18-off90-c143" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-18-defend174 t17610225-18-off90 t17610225-18-verdict94"></join>
         
               <p>97. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-defend174" type="defendantName">
                     Willy 
                     Sutton 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18-defend174" type="surname" value="Sutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-defend174" type="given" value="Willy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-defend174" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , late of <placeName id="t17610225-18-defloc88">London</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18-defloc88" type="placeName" value="London"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18-defloc88" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-18-defend174 t17610225-18-defloc88"></join>, <rs id="t17610225-18-deflabel89" type="occupation">merchant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-18-defend174 t17610225-18-deflabel89"></join>, was indicted, for that <rs id="t17610225-18-off90" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-off90" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-off90" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               he, at the parish of <placeName id="t17610225-18-crimeloc91">St. Martin's in the Fields, in the county of Middlesex</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-crimeloc91" type="placeName" value="St. Martin's in the Fields, in the county of Middlesex"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-crimeloc91" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-18-off90 t17610225-18-crimeloc91"></join>, with force and arms, and malice aforethought, on 
                     <persName id="t17610225-18-victim175" type="victimName">
                        
                           <persName id="t17610225-18-person176" type="victimName">
                              Ann 
                              Bell 
                           <interp inst="t17610225-18-person176" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17610225-18-person176" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                           <interp inst="t17610225-18-person176" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        </persName>
                        , otherwise <rs id="t17610225-18-alias-1" type="alias">
                           <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-18-victim175 t17610225-18-alias-1"></join>Ann Sharp</rs>
                        <interp inst="t17610225-18-victim175" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610225-18-victim175" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610225-18-victim175" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-18-off90 t17610225-18-victim175"></join>
                     </persName>
                  , <rs id="t17610225-18-viclabel92" type="occupation">Spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-18-victim175 t17610225-18-viclabel92"></join>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-18-person176 t17610225-18-viclabel92"></join>, with a certain penknife, value 2 d. which he had, and held in his right hand, did strike, and stab the said Ann, on the left buttock, near the fundament; giving to the said Ann one mortal wound, of the width of three inches, and depth of one inch. And one other mortal wound, of the depth of three inches, and width of one inch; whereof she did languish from the <rs id="t17610225-18-cd93" type="crimeDate">30th of August</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610225-18-off90 t17610225-18-cd93"></join>, till the fourth of October, and then died. And that he, the said Willy, the said Ann did wilfully, and of malice aforethought, kill and murder
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted, on the statute of stabbing, for feloniously killing and slaying her, the said Ann, against an act of parliament in that case made and provided.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person177">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Honyball 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person177" type="surname" value="Honyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person177" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person177" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the deceased person, 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person178">
                  Ann 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person178" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person178" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person178" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I do; I lived with the deceased 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person179">
                  Ann 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person179" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person179" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person179" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Turnham-green.</p>
               <p>Q. At what time of the year, and what year?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. That I cannot recollect; it was last year, about the latter end of the year.</p>
               <p>Q. At what house on Turnham-green?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. At the Bohemia-head, I was a servant there.</p>
               <p>Q. When.</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. The latter end of last summer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person180">
                  Ann 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person180" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person180" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person180" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             there at that time?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She was.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen the prisoner at the bar there, visiting your mistress?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Who introduced him, or came with him?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person181">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person181" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person181" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person181" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner come often?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He was there two or three times; they were acquainted together there.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go when you went from thence.</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I went to Spring garden, as her servant, along with her, to one Mrs. Parker's.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the prisoner and she agree at Turnham green?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. They agreed very well.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you at Spring-garden, before you saw the prisoner there?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. About three weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he come there?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball, I cannot recollect that.</p>
               <p>Q. What past there?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your mistress go out with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she not asked and importuned to go with him?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was she asked by?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. By Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person182">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person182" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person182" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person182" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in company with Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person183">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person183" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person183" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I cannot tell whether he was or no.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased go out?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before she died, did she come to Spring-garden.</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. About a month.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it more or less?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. It was no more I think.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to Haddock's-bagnio?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Yes, on a Saturday morning; the porter came for me between nine and ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell what day of the month that was?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No; I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the message?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. To carry a shift and a pair of stockings, which I did. I carried a shift, and other things, to Haddock's-bagnio.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Tell in what manner, what happened to you in going there, how was you received?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I carried them to the bagnio, and left them at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done afterwards?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I went to the Rummer-tavern, after I had carried the things there, for a quartern of rum.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see your mistress at Haddock's?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I asked to see her, and they refused me.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did you ask?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250020"></xptr>E. Honyball. One of the waiters said, I could not see her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say, could not or should not?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Could not.</p>
               <p>Q. After this, what did you do then?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I went to the Rummer, for a quartern of rum. The maid belonging to the Rummer told me they heard a great noise.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. I object to that; what she told this witness is no evidence. They may call that servant if they please.</p>
               <p>Court. Certainly this is no evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you go from thence?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Then I went home.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been at home before your mistress came home?</p>
               <p>E. Hon yball. Not long; my mistress came home about eleven o'clock in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she appear to you?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She came home very saint and very ill.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was this before she went to Marybone?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Just a fortnight before she went there. She came home on the Saturday, and was taken away on the Monday fortnight afterwards.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say your mistress came home seemingly, very faint and very low.</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Yes.</p>
               <p>Counsel. This Saturday she mentions, must be the 30th of August.</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. As soon as ever I opened the door, she said, she had received her death's wound, from that villain Sutton.</p>
               <p>Q. Mention the words as well as you can recollect.</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. These were the words she said as soon as I opened the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. At Mrs. Parker's.</p>
               <p>Q. Repeat the words again, that my Lord may hear you.</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She said she received her death-wound from that villain Sutton.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition did she appear when she came home?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She appeared very low, and very faint.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing done to her, or for her, to case her?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She pull'd off her gown and stays, and lay down on the bed: nothing was done to her directly, there was soon after. The same night I went to a doctor in Pall-mall; he could not come himself but his man came, and sent a bottle of stuff to do her side and her arm, which were very much bruised.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she lie on the bed before she got up?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She lay on the bed the value of an hour, then she got up, and drank a dish of tea, and went into the kitchen. In the evening I went to this doctor, he gave me this bottle of stuff.</p>
               <p>Q. Who administered it to her?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I did; all her fingers and arms were very much bruised, they looked very black; her arms and side, and head, and all appeared very black.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any other wounds that she had?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No, I did not; she continued ill from that time, till the time that she died; that was just five weeks to a day, she died on the Saturday five weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. In what manner was she treated while she staid at those lodgings here, before she went to Marybone?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. One Mr. Bliss attended her a fortnight before she went to Marybone.</p>
               <p>Q. What course was taken with her, or what was done?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I know no particular applications besides that bottle of stuff; she was under his care.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body come to see her?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Sir. 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person184">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person184" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person184" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person184" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body else?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Miss Young did.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Any body else?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. And one Mr. West.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner at the bar come to see her in her illness?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No, he did not; before she went from Mrs. Parker's, she wrote a bit of a note, and sent it by a chairman to Mr. Sutton, and said Mr. Sutton owed her a guinea. He sent a note back by the chairman, with these words:</p>

               <p>"If you are well, I am well, pay the porter</p>
               <p>"and all is well."</p>
         
               <p>*** The Second Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17610225-18">
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610225"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="date" value="17610225"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 25th, Thursday the 26th, Friday the 27th, and Saturday the 28th of FEBRUARY.</p>
                  <p>In the first Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Third SESSION in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person185">
                     Matthew 
                     Blakiston 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18-person185" type="surname" value="Blakiston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610225-18-person185" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610225-18-person185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON. NUMBER III. PART II. for the YEAR 1761.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. SCOTT, at the Black-Swan, in Pater-noster Row.</p>
                  <p>M. DCC. LXI.</p>
                  <p>[Price FOUR-PENCE.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q WAS you present at any conversation when Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person186">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person186" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person186" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             or Miss Young visited her.</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Yes, Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person187">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person187" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person187" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came there, and gave me three guineas, and said, don't let her want for nothing. Saying, Here is three guineas, and I'll come and give her more soon. He went away, and I did not see him any more. He said he would not have her die for five thousand pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her mention to him any cause of her illness?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any conversation that past betwixt her and Miss Young?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. When she was removed to Marybone, what was the occasion of her being removed there?</p>

               <p>E. Honyball. On the account of her illness, it was for her health.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you accompany her to Marybone?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No, I did not; I was with her there.</p>
               <p>Q. At whose house was she?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She was at the house of Mr. Knight.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you yourself attend her all the time?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any ointment, or pomatum, made use of, or upon what occasion?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Yes, she used often to ask me for the box of pomatum, and used to take it into the bed. She said she had something which she did not care to tell of, and it would be her death.</p>
               <p>Q. After your mistress came home from the bagnio, on the 30th of August, do you know any thing with respect to her linnen?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. It was very bad.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by very bad?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Very bloody.</p>
               <p>Q. What linnen was it that was so?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. That that I carried, and that that she had on were the same.</p>

               <p>Q. We desire you to be a little plain on this matter: can you tell whether that proceeded from any natural cause?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. It was not, for but a week before that there was such natural cause. It did not proceed from that.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she perfectly well when she went out?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Yes, she was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it only the shift, or coat also?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Her coat and all.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you mean all her coats?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I mean through her shift, and all her coats, all but one.</p>
               <p>Q. Now we are got to Marybone, what assistance had she at Marybone?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I attended her three weeks, and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250023"></xptr> three nights; I could not hold it no longer, then I had a nurse.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the time, upon her first going there?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Before I went there.</p>
               <p>Q. Who provided the nurse?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Mr. Bliss sent the nurse.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her name?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I don't know; she attended her a fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. Who visited her there?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. One Captain 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person188">
                  Holland
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person188" type="given" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came to visit her there.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Any body else?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. One Mr. Moody, and Mr. Dibble, and Mr. Moon, and one Mr. Drake, Doctor Smith, and Mr. Chapman, were there; he is a surgeon, and Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person189">
                  Bliss
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person189" type="given" value="Bliss"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person189" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the apothecary. I cannot recollect any others.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you can recollect the day of the month, or day of the week, when Captain 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person190">
                  Holland
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person190" type="given" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person190" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             first came to visit her?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He came on the Thursday before she died.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that the first time?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He had been there once before.</p>
               <p>Q. What plan long you speak of?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He speaking of the lodgings at Marybone.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell the time he first came there?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. How long before the time of her death?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I believe about a fortnight before.</p>
               <p>Q. How often was he there?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He was there three or four times.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell us how long after you yourself came there it was, before Captain 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person191">
                  Holland
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person191" type="given" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             first came there?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. About a fortnight, or near a fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect the day of the month?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember a particular application made to the deceased, a clyster to be administered to her?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Yes, I fetched it myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Capt. Holland been there before that?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He was there on a Sunday, on the former part of the day.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any-body coming there with him?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He came there by himself in the morning, and he came in the afternoon, and brought Mr. Moon with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any conversation that passed at that time?</p>
               <p>E. Honeyball. She told me she had something to say to Captain 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person192">
                  Holland
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person192" type="given" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; but she did not care to tell him, because Mr. Moon was there; and she desired Captain 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person193">
                  Holland
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person193" type="given" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to come the next morning, and she had something to tell him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I was, and heard her; she wished he would come again the next morning: Mr. Moon was then present.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be certain whether this was Saturday, or Sunday?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. It was on a Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it the day the clyster was administered, or not?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I cannot justly say that.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was on a Sunday?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I am sure it was.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you remember any thing was done that day?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Nothing particular that day, that I can remember.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect whether it was on that day the clyster was administered, or not?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. That I cannot be certain.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there such an operation, or not, at that time?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there at any time?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. It was a day or two afterwards that the clyster was administered: I think it was a day or two after that Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when it was administered?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember, before the clyster was actually administered, any attempt to administer it?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. About the Thursday before the Sunday, I went for it myself. They could not administer it.</p>
               <p>Q. When did they attempt it?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. It was attempted to be administered before the Sunday.</p>
               <p>Q. By whom?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. By the nurse.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it not to be administered?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. The nurse ran the clyster-pipe into a wound, instead of the other part; she screamed out, and said she could not bear it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you observe upon that occasion?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I bid her let it alone till Mr. Bliss came.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250024"></xptr>Q. Did you see this wound, or do any thing to it?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I saw both the wounds at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of wounds were they?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. One was cut long, and the other was cut in deep.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they appear like?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. They appeared to me to be wounds that were cut.</p>
               <p>Q. In what part of the body?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Just above the fundament, one in the thick part.</p>
               <p>Q. First describe where the long wound was?</p>

               <p>E. Honyball. Just above the fundament, in the thick fleshy part.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the other?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. The other was in the thick part of her backside.</p>
               <p>Q. How far from the long wound you have been describing?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Not half an inch.</p>
               <p>Q. Nearer or further from the fundament, than the long wound?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. On the side of it, on her backside.</p>
               <p>Q. How far distance from the clift?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Just by the fundament or clift, just by it.</p>
               <p>Q. What wound do you call this?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. This I call the deep wound.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what depth it was?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No; I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was present besides yourself, when you first discovered these wounds?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Miss Knight and the nurse; and me, and no body else.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you at that time, or any other, see the nurse do any thing to this wound, or either of them?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Nothing at all till Mr. Chapman came on the Thursday, the same day as the clyster was attempted to be administered, after that attempt.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Mr. Chapman?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He is a surgeon.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he told or apprized of this?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He ordered the nurse to foment it, or do something to it.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to be there?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Mr. Bliss fetched him, and told him of it; and the nurse told Mr. Bliss of it, and I too. We told him of it, the same day that we told Mr. Bliss of it; Mr. Chapman brought some stuff with him to put into the wounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when he came?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I was then in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you see pass then?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He said it would do very well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him put the stuff in the wound?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I did; and put a plaister to it; it was some cotton, and some green or yellow millelot.</p>
               <p>Q. How deep did it appear by the instrument?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I cannot tell; it seemed to me to be very deep and very large.</p>
               <p>Q. Before that time had you seen any particular wound?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was said about this wound, and to whom, by your mistress, in your hearing?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She always said Mr. Sutton had cut her.</p>
               <p>Q. Before or after they were found?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. After they were found. She told Mr. Bliss that Mr. Sutton had cut her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her tell him so?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear her be this in the presence of Mr. Holland?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No.</p>
               <p>Q When you heard her say this, how did she appear to be with respect to her senses and understanding?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Perfectly in her senses. This was in the day; she was not so well of nights.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she talk sensible of it, and rational about the matter?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Very sensible.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. This was on the Thursday before she died.</p>
               <p>Q. From this time to the time of her death, who dressed her wounds?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Mr. Chapman and the nurse. Sometimes the nurse, and sometimes Mr. Chapman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her say, in respect to these wounds, after this, how she came by them?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She said, Mr. Sutton gave me these wounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see them dressed by the nurse after this Thursday that you have been talking of?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Yes. She has fomented them an hour together by Mr. Chapman's order.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250025"></xptr>Q. Did you assist in it?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any thing applied besides the fomentation?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. How did these wounds continue? Were they open or heal'd, and cured or not?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. They continued open wounds to the time of her death. At the time the nurse went to give her the clyster they were full of corruption.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them in that condition?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present at the time Mr. Holland was with her?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He was with her two days before she died. That I particularly remember.</p>
               <p>Q. What conversation past between them?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She told Mr. Holland, I was in the room at the same time, that Mr. Sutton had given her two stabs. She said he stabbed her in one place, and then stuck the knife in the other.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words she made use of?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She said she received two stabs from Mr. Sutton, and she desired Mr. Holland to see justice done her if she should die, for she should not be long in this world.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she describe the manner in which they were given?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She shew'd Mr. Holland the manner, with the length and bigness by her fingers.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she say any thing about the manner how given, or why?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She told Mr. Holland, she hoped he would see justice done her, and see her righted, for she should not be long in this world. I went out of the room and left them talking. She desired I would go out of the room.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her express the manner of giving the wounds?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she live after this?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She died within two days after.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say you was servant at the Bohemia-head, at Turnham green?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I was Mr. Johnson's servant.</p>
               <p>Q. I should be glad to know when you first became acquainted with the deceased, whether Mr. Fowler was not her acquaintance?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She was his acquaintance be fore she came there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she continue so while she was there?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use to come frequently to your house?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. He did:</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then Mr. Sutton was no other than an occasional visitor, being an acquaintance?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No otherwise.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who provided those lodgings for her at Mrs. Parker's.</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. I am sure it was herself, because she said Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person194">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person194" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person194" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was to keep her. That Miss Bell told me.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say she went to this bagnio?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did she stay there?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She staid there three days, she was away three days and three nights, and I never set eyes on her.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether she did not as her return tell you she had been drinking ratifea as if it had been small-beer? Whether she did not give you to understand that was the death wound she had got?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. As soon as ever she came in at the door, said she I have receiv'd my death's wound from that villain Sutton; and, I have been drinking ratifea as if it had been small-beer.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not she at that time a good deal in liquor?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She did not seem so.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You have been telling the gentleman here, and I wish you would recollect, for your own sake as well as others, did she continue faint and ill at her lodgings till she went to Marybone? Recollect, whether after this time she did not go to Bartholomew-fair?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No, she did not. I went there; she was ill all the time. She was very ill in bed. She was not there, nor out of doors. She said she had something she did not care to tell of, that would be her death.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did she say this to?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. She told it me a great many times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention this to any body else?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. Before she went to Marybone she did not only say it to me, and Mrs. Parker, and the maid, but to several.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you have not yourself declared, upon more occasions than one, that you thought this blood upon her linnen was natural?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. It was not natural.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you declared it was?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Counsel for the crown. What part of the linnen did you observe to be bloody?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250026"></xptr>E. Honyball. On the back-part, and on the back-parts of her petticoats.</p>
               <p>Court. Was the word, And, or Fo I have been drinking ratifea?</p>
               <p>E. Honyball. As soon as I open'd the door, she said she had received her death wound from that villain Sutton, and, that she had been drinking ratifea as if it had been small-beer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person195">
                  Thomas 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person195" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person195" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Counsel for the prisoner. We desire the other witness may go out of court, that if she gives her evidence again, she may not recollect from Mr. Holland's evidence.</p>
               <p>Holland. I desire Mr. Bliss may be out of court, and the other evidences on Mr. Sutton's side; all our witnesses are lock'd up in a room.</p>
               <p>The court ordered all the witnesses that were to the fact, out of court.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been acquainted with the deceased Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Holland. I have been acquainted with her almost four years. She lived with her father at the time I was acquainted with the family. I was not particularly acquainted till about two years ago. I have seen the girl, but not particularly.</p>

               <p>Q. Where was your acquaintance with the family?</p>
               <p>Holland. It was at Aylsham; she was introduced by her brother, now an officer in Germany, I have been at Aylsham a week at a time, but more so acquainted at the end of the year 58.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after that time did you see her again? Can you with any sort of particularity say when you left visiting the family?</p>
               <p>Holland. We came out of the country of Norfolk last June was twelve months, she was at Aylsham when I was there, we had a company of militin where I used to go to exercise the men: we left the country last June was twelve months, then the regiment marched to Portsmouth.</p>
               <p>Q. When after that time did you first see Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Holland. I did not see Miss Bell till the 27th or 28th of September, after I left Norfolk. ( Looking in a pocket-book.)</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. What book is that in your hand?</p>
               <p>Holland. It is a memorandum-book.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. Who wrote it?</p>
               <p>Holland. I did.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. When?</p>
               <p>Holland. Since the lady has been buried; I put down the memorandums the day after she died.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. Can you be certain when you put it down?</p>
               <p>Holland. I will not be positive when; it might be two or three days after her death.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. Can you be positive you put down every thing there within a month of the thing happening?</p>
               <p>Holland. I cannot tell to a month or two; I do not know but I made memorandums within seven days of every thing. I have made a memorandum of every thing within seven or fourteen days at most.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. How came it you let it be seven or fourteen days after?</p>
               <p>Holland. That I can give no account of, but it may be forgetfulness.</p>
               <p>Counsel for Crown. Are there other memorandums in that book, that are not relative to her.</p>
               <p>Holland. It is a common memorandum-book?</p>
               <p>Q. When was the first time after you left Norfolk that you saw miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Holland. I think it was the 27th of September; it was Saturday the 27th I saw her in bed at Marybone, where she died.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect the day you set it down?</p>
               <p>Holland. I really cannot recollect; it may be two or three days after, or it may be a week, I put it down: I was determined from my first promising her on her death-bed to do it: if her father would not see her have justice done her, I was determined I would.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not put down every one of those occurrences sooner than seven or fourteen days, if you did it with a view of preserving it in your memory?</p>
               <p>Holland. I have had a great deal of trouble about this affair. I have recollected them on my pillow, and thought of things, and have wrote them down, that I might not be mistaken if it came to a trial, so I put them down on my recollection?</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know that Miss Bell was ill in bed?</p>
               <p>Holland. On Friday the 26th, I was walking in the city, I called on one Mr. Drake. a merchant in Bread-street, he is of an Aylsham family, his father lived within a door or two of Miss Bell's father. He was in partnership with Linwood and Dwight, linnen-drapers, in the country, but now he is in a wholesale way, in the Norwich-stuff way. He ask'd me when I had seen Miss Bell? I told him. I had not seen her for fifteen or sixteen months.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you seen Mr. Drake before in London?</p>
               <p>Holland. I think that was the first time. [He puts the book in his pocket.]</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been in London?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250027"></xptr>Holland. I had been in London about two months, I don't recollect I had seen Mr. Drake before, since I came to London. I recollect now that I saw him once before, and the reason was this; her father came up to town in order to get the girl into the country, he put her apprentice to -</p>
               <p>Counsel. That is not material.</p>
               <p>Holland. I am only telling you that I saw Mr. Drake once before: when I said I had not seen her for 15 or 16 months, he said, Sir, I am informed Miss Bell is very ill at Marybone, that she lately lodged in Spring-gardens, and has been carried away in a chair to Marybone, and I am informed is like to die. I told Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person196">
                  Drake
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person196" type="given" value="Drake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person196" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I was sorry for it, and I would make it my business to go to Marybone the next morning, which was on a Saturday, to enquire her out, which I did; I got to Marybone about nine or ten in the morning the 27th.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose house was it she lodged at?</p>
               <p>Holland. She lodged at the house of one Mr. Knight: when I came to Marybone I came to the Rose of Normandy, and went into the house, and asked if they did not know any thing of a lady lately brought in a chair there very ill: the landlord told me he believed there was such a one lodged at such a house. I asked him if he had heard her name; he said he did not recollect it, but said he would send to know. Said I, I'll go myself, you shall not send. I went and knock'd at the door, the servant-maid, the nurse's daughter, let me in; I do not recollect her name, she is here. I asked her if one Miss Bell lodged there; the girl looked at me: said I, pray is there a young lady that is ill here? Said she, yes, there is, I'll call her servant. She ran to the stair-foot, and called her servant down, (which was 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person197">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Honyball 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person197" type="surname" value="Honyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person197" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .) I asked her if her mistress's name was not Bell: She said, Yes, Sir. - Pray how does she do? Is she well enough to see any-body? - Sir, she is very bad, but if you'll be so kind as to let me know your name, I'll tell her. I sent my name up, she came down, and desired I would walk up; the servant maid went up along with me, there was the nurse in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the maid after this?</p>
               <p>Holland. I believe she went into another room, but I called presently for her, and she came again; but the nurse remained with us the whole time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any thing pass while the maid was out of the room?</p>
               <p>Holland. I believe there did; but there was a great deal past while she was in the room, the nurse pulled back the curtain, and I saw it was the lady I expected. I said, Nancy, how do you do my dear? She looked at me, and shook her head, and did not speak, for I believe half a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body in the room when you first spoke to Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Holland. Upon my word I cannot positively say whether there was or not. I said, Nanny, do you know me? After pausing half a minute, she shook her head, and said, know you, Yes, very well; how do you do Captain 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person198">
                  Holland
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person198" type="given" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ? I cannot say the particular words; but she asked me how I did. She asked me to take a chair and set down by the bed-side. I did, I took her by the hand, and she cried; she begged I would help her up, which I did, and propped her up behind with the pillow, but it was with a great deal of pain. But when she was up, and set for a minute, she began to be easy; but in lifting her up, she complained, and said, O! my side.</p>
               <p>Q. What had she on?</p>
               <p>Holland. She had a linnen bed-gown on. I then asked her in half a minute, my dear Nanny, are you in a fine way of doing well now; do not make yourself uneasy, you will do well, and I have shall the pleasure in a week's time to take a walk with you. She shook her head, and said, no, that is impossible; had I seen you a month ago, this would not have happened.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by that - a month ago?</p>
               <p>Holland. O! says she, I am lost. I am murdered. With that I said, Nanny, do not make yourself uneasy; recollect yourself, recollect yourself, what can be the meaning of your expressing yourself in this kind? I then thought she had not been sensible; I then turned from that discourse in order to find out, whether she was in her senses or not. I said, Nanny, - the nurse and maid were by.</p>
               <p>Q. When did the maid come into the room?</p>
               <p>Holland. She came into the room at the time this discourse happened; but where abouts in the discourse, I really cannot tell, and she staid in the room till I went away. Then I asked her, if she wanted for any thing; yes, says she, I want for a great many things; I want for something to eat, Mr. Bliss has directions to take care of me from Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person199">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person199" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person199" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he will not let me eat; I have asked for a chicken to make chicken-broth; but Mr. Bliss will not let me have one. The nurse said no, Mr. Bliss used my mistress very ill, for Mr. Bliss will not<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250028"></xptr> let her have common necessaries. After the nurse had told me the ill usage of Mr. Bliss, I said, nurse, take care of your mistress, and there is a shilling for yourself, and I will go to Mr. Bliss myself; and if he does not take proper care of your mistress, I will send some body that shall. I said to Miss Bell, Nanny. my dear, you seem now to be fatigued. - She shut her eyes as she set up in the bed. I said, Nanny, I shall dine this day at my Lord Orford's, and as soon as dinner is over, I will call and see you again; I will certainly call in the afternoon, and she begged I would, and that I would help lay her down again, which I did, with equal the same pain in laying her down, as helping her up. She then complained of her side, then I left her, promising to call in the afternoon, and she begged I would. In the afternoon I went, I believe betwixt five and six o'clock, I cannot recollect the minute, but it was after dinner, I dined with Mr. Moon, and a lady in the house, and was telling Mr. Moon the story, he came along with me. I told him the distress, to me, the lady seem to be in; I said to him at dinner, here is a couple of little birds, may be she will like, and I carried them to her, and Mr. Moon along with me. I put them in my pocket, by the leave of Mr. Moon, Mr. Moon carried her a piece of pine apple, and he gave it her, and she sucked it with a great deal of pleasure.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of the servants let you in?</p>
               <p>Holland. I cannot recollect which of them let us in, but it was one of the servants, we were both carried up in the chamber, there were nobody there but the nurse, me and Mr. Moon, the maid I believe was in the other room.</p>
               <p>Q. What past in conversation?</p>
               <p>Holland. Mr. Moon sat down in a chair by the window, I went and took a chair and sat down by the bed side. She took part of the bird upon the plate, and eat part of it, and afterwards sucked the pine apple. She looked at Mr. Moon and shook her head, and said, I wish you would call to-morrow morning. and I will tell you something that shall surprize you.</p>
               <p>Q. Had any thing been said about her ill usage?</p>
               <p>Holland. No otherwise than what I said in the morning; none that I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. What past after that?</p>
               <p>Holland. Then I took my leave, and promised her I would call the next morning, which was the Sunday, which I did.</p>
               <p>Q What time did you get there?</p>
               <p>Holland. I got there about nine or ten on the Sunday morning alone.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let you in?</p>
               <p>Holland. The servant let me in, I do not know which, and I was desired to go up stairs. I met the nurse in the first room. (I went thro' one room to go into the other.) The nurse catched me by the arm or coat; and said, I want to speak with you Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any body else within hearing?</p>
               <p>Holland. There were no-body, but the nurse and I, as I recollect.</p>
               <p>Q. Was door open?</p>
               <p>Holland. It was; I went to the window, she said, La Sir, my mistress has got two frightful wounds, frightful wounds indeed, as they seemed to her to be. Sure, said she, they must be cut with some sharp instrument, by some rogue through villany, or something to that purpose.</p>
               <p>Q. How many windows are there in that room?</p>
               <p>Holland. There are two, it is a very genteel dining-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you guess how many feet square?</p>
               <p>Holland. About ten feet square.</p>
               <p>Q. Did this happen before you went to miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Holland. It did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect, whether the door that opens into Miss Bell's room, was open or not?</p>
               <p>Holland. I really do not recollect that.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the door to the stairs open?</p>
               <p>Holland. I really cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you charge your memory, as well as you can, whether any body was in the room at the time the nurse said that?</p>
               <p>Holland. I do not recollect, if any body was there, it must be the maid; but whether she was then in the room or not I cannot recollect. I then told the nurse, this must be the story that Miss Bell wants to relate to me. Nurse, said I, how came you to find those wounds out. Says she, after you went away last night, Mr. Bliss was here, and ordered her a clyster. I have no spight in the world against this gentleman, [ pointing to Mr. Sutton;] I only desire to tell the truth of the story Then she said, Sir, I put the pipe, (I cannot tell whether she mentioned the word pipe or thing) but she said, she put it into the wound, and by that means, she found the wounds out. I asked her then, Pray how long may these wounds be? Lord, says she, I ran the thing in, I do not know how far, - thus far [ shewing by his finger to his knuckle ] After this I sat down by the bed-side.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the nurse then?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250029"></xptr>Holland. She was by in the room, and 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person200">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Honyball 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person200" type="surname" value="Honyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person200" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came into the room presently afterwards; and she was in the room a good while, while Miss Bell was relating this thing to me. I asked Miss Bell how she did, she said, she hoped she was better; then she desired me, that I would help her up again; I did, and with a great deal of pain. She always complained of her side - it hurt her side.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she dressed?</p>
               <p>Holland. She was dressed in the same manner as she was before; we fell into some little discourse about her family in Norfolk. She told me she had had a letter from her father, and called for the letter, and desired I would read it, which I did. She then said, I expect my father up every day, I am surprized he is not come; but now I do not care whether he come or not, for I am sure you'll see me have justice done me. I said, Nanny, Pray what do you mean by justice done you, have you been used ill? Yes, says she. I have been used very ill. I said, Miss Bell, You may depend upon it, I'll see you have justice done you, if any body has used you ill, certainly see you have justice done you, if it is to be had; I will not say the particular words; but it was to that purpose With that I asked her, Whether she thought she was capable of relating the story? She said yes, she would tell me the whole story. Said I, Nanny, Do not be in a hurry, but tell the whole affair, they are coming to town?</p>
               <p>Q. Was she in her senses then?</p>
               <p>Holland. She was then in her senses, and the fever seemed to be quite abated, and she did not seem to be in a fever at all. I attended her twice a day, and she was as much in her senses, as I am now; there did not seem to be the least fever upon her in the world. Indeed the nurse told me, and so did the maid, that she was worse in the nights; and talked of some things in the night, that they thought her delirious. But upon my oath, she was as much in her senses the whole time I was along with her, as ever I saw any person in my life. She then began to tell me her story, from the time of her first coming to town. She said, her father came to town with her, and she was bound apprentice to a milliner, near Leicester-fields; she did not tell me the particular place; but as near as I can recollect, these were the words. She said, You know I did not like confinement, and I went along with my father a little way, to take my leave of him, and I staid all night. Now she did not relate to me how long she had been at this place, where she was apprentice; but I suppose, that could not be a great while, because her father went soon after he had settled her in her place. She told me her story down to that time, with great particularity.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she tell you, she first became acquainted with Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person201">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person201" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person201" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Mr. Sutton?</p>
               <p>Holland. She was introduced to Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person202">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person202" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person202" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , by Mr. Dibble he kept a Coffee house, near Covent garden, at that time; he is a player; she told me the whole of her being at Turnham-green.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then take her Story from the Bohemia-head.</p>
               <p>Holland. She told me she came away from the King of Bohemia's-head, at Turnham green, to take lodgings in Spring gardens, and was there some time. What time, I will not pretend to say; I think she said, three weeks before Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person203">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person203" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person203" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , or Mr. Sutton, found out her retsea. This was at Mrs. Parker's in Spring-gardens, I am telling her story as near as I can recollect the words, as she related to me. She then said, Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person204">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person204" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person204" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Mr. Sutton came one morning to her lodging, and desired her to take a walk, which she consented to; and went from her lodgings with them. That at night, they went to Haddock's-bagnio, and one Miss Young came to her there. She said, they remained at the Bagnio three nights and three days; and they obliged her to drink the value of three pints of ratisea a day.</p>

               <p>Q Did she say, obliged her?</p>
               <p>Holland. She did; that was the word upon my oath, and that Mr. Sutton at this time used her very ill, and that they quarreled; that Mr. Sutton told her then, that he would cut her backside, so that she should not be able to fit.</p>
               <p>Q. Repeat those words?</p>
               <p>Holland. She said, Mr. Sutton said to her; I have a good mind to cut your backside, so that you shall not be able to fit; and if ever I meet you again, I'll cut you so, that you shall not be able to live. As rear as I can guess, these were the words she mentioned.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she proceed with her story, after she had mentioned these words?</p>
               <p>Holland. Then she said, she had got a fall down stairs, and hurt her side; but she could not say, whether she was thrown down or not. I then asked her, whether or no she might not get these wounds by this fall. She immediately replied no; they were given me with a penknife, by that villain Sutton. She then said, this was the truth of her usage; and she hoped I would see her have justice done her. She received those<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250030"></xptr> wounds from Mr. Sutton; and she was sure the wounds would kill her, the wounds would be the cause of her death, and said this was the truth.</p>
               <p>Q. When you went into the room, did you take notice of what the nurse had told you?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, I did not, of one syllable.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she describe the manner in which the wounds were given her, and the circumstances?</p>
               <p>Holland. She made a motion on the back of her hand, when I asked her how the wounds were given: she said. With a penknife he ripped me so, and so, making a motion with her hand, as if he had been killing a hog.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did she point with her hand?</p>
               <p>Holland. On the back of her hand, pointing with one hand to the other, and made a motion in the manner that he gave her the wounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she, or did she not, describe the manner of her being overpowered by him?</p>
               <p>Holland. She mentioned a circumstance, and said he bent her fingers back till her arm was black, but did not mention any particular manner how: but absolutely said, he gave her the wounds with a penknife.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention in what part of the room, or whether on a bed, or chair?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, she did not; I did not think to ask her that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she describe the place?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, nor I don't remember that I asked her. When she concluded this discourse, her last words were desiring me to see her have justice done her. I said, Miss Bell, you may depend upon it I will see you have justice, if it is possible. I asked her who Mr. Sutton was. She said, He was a young merchant that kept company with Mr. Fowler.</p>
               <p>Q. During the time this whole story was told you, who was present?</p>
               <p>Holland. The nurse and Honyball; the nurse was backwards and forwards. Miss Knight, the young lady that lives in the house, did come up sometimes when I was there; but I don't recollect that she was present, when she related this part of the story to me. I told her I would go to Mr. Bliss, and wait on her again in the afternoon. She begged I would. I took my leave then, she began to be fatigued, and desired to be laid down. Mr. Bliss was not at home, I saw his man, I said to Mr. Bliss's man (he was in the shop) I said to him, Pray do you attend a young lady at Marybone? After he said, Mr. Bliss was not at home.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. That is not evidence.</p>
               <p>Counsel for the crown. I don't desire it.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you go next to Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Holland. I went in the afternoon to her, on this Sunday, the maid or the nurse let me in to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was present in the room?</p>
               <p>Holland. The nurse was there, and the maid I believe was there, but I will not be positive; but the nurse was always there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any conversation pass between you and her on the same circumstances?</p>
               <p>Holland. I asked her if she recollected what she had told me in the morning. She said, Yes, very well, and what I told you is a truth; my ill usage is truth, that I related to you; and Mr. Sutton, gave me those wounds with a penknife, that villain, and I hope you'll see me have justice done me.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she appear as to her fever in the afternoon?</p>
               <p>Holland. She appeared as well as to that, as in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she for understanding?</p>
               <p>Holland. She was as well in her senses as I am now.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her on the Monday?</p>
               <p>Holland. I saw her twice on the Monday, morning and afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her on the Tuesday?</p>
               <p>Holland. Twice on the Tuesday, twice on the Thursday, and the Thursday night was the last time of my seeing her?</p>
               <p>Q. Was this affair mentioned at each time of your seeing her.</p>
               <p>Holland. Every time I was there, I related one part or the other of this story to her; she always was of the same opinion, and declared over and over to me, that what she had declared was the truth, and hoped justice would overtake Mr. Sutton; or to that purpose. The last time I saw her, on the Thursday in the afternoon. I was told by the nurse, or the maid, or Miss Knight, they all seemed to be in confusion, that the surgeon had been there, and that Miss Bell's wounds were mortified.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she as to her senses them days?</p>
               <p>Holland. Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, and Thursday, she was always perfect in her senses; the same as I am now, always when I was with her; and I discoursed with her about different things, and always found her so. I asked her on the Thursday night, and said: Nanny, my dear, I will not flatter you. I am afraid you will not live; have you any thing to say to your father, or mother; I shall write, pray tell me now? She paused a little, and said: Yes ( sitting up in the bed as before; for always she desired I would lift her up) she said, yes, Captain 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person205">
                  Holland
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person205" type="given" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , pray write to night, and give my duty to my dear mother, and tell her I am sensible I shall not<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250031"></xptr> be a great while in this world; and I hope to meet her in another, where we shall be more happy than in this; and she gave a sort of a scream, and fell backwards, and I went away, and never saw her more.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you got the copy of your letters you wrote to her father?</p>
               <p>Holland. Upon my word I have not, when I told her I would write, I did not write.</p>
               <p>Q. What method did you take in order to pursue her desire, and bring this gentleman to justice?</p>
               <p>Holland. After this lady was dead (she died on the Saturday morning) I was informed that Mr. Bliss had applied to Mr. Umfreville, the coroner, for leave to bury this lady.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. This is not evidence.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. When was she buried?</p>
               <p>Holland. She was buried on the Tuesday following. I went to Mr. Fielding, and complained to him.</p>
               <p>Q. What day did you go there?</p>
               <p>Holland. I really don't recollect the day, but it was about the same time of her being buried. She died on the Saturday, and was buried on the Tuesday following. After I had told Mr. Fielding this story as near as I could recollect, he desired me to send for 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person206">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Honyball 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person206" type="surname" value="Honyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person206" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person206" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went and fetched her myself to him, and she upon her oath gave in her testimony to him. I expected he would have pursued this, and endeavoured to bring this to justice. I believe justice Fielding never took any more notice of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell him the same story as you have now?</p>
               <p>Holland. I did, as near as I could recollect. I told him she desired me to see her have justice; and I thought him the properest person I could apply to.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you apply to him for a warrant?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, I did not; then I wrote to her father - I wrote first of all to Mr. Sutton.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to any other magistrate?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, I never did, till I went to justice Wright to take a warrant out.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a coroner's inquisition sat upon this?</p>
               <p>Holland. There was.</p>
               <p>Q. How was that obtained?</p>
               <p>Holland. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you a summons to be there?</p>
               <p>Holland. I had a summons from the beadle.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you attend?</p>
               <p>Holland. I attended on the Friday - but I was not admitted. -</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. That is not evidence, and no way affects the present enquiry.</p>
               <p>Court. Whether they did their duty, or whether not, that does not seem to be matter of evidence affecting the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. I do agree, the objection is certainly well grounded, what past there does not affect the prisoner; but what I observe is this, to shew that Mr. Holland takes the earliest instances to go before Mr. Fielding. The next occurrence that offers, he presents himself to give his evidence to the coroner, and he is not admitted, that is what we want it to be mentioned for.</p>
               <p>Court. If that affected the character of Mr. Holland, in thus pursuing the matter for the sake of public justice, then the question would be whether you may not enquire into it, but now it is no evidence against the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. Would they insinuate to the jury, that Mr. Sutton had any hand in that at all?</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. I proposed my questions with a view, that if there is a doubt, it may be in favour of the prisoner; and whether the coroner did, or did not, behave properly, I gave my opinion it does not affect Mr. Sutton.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. The stile that the lady addressed herself to you in, renders it needless to ask what you are: you are a captain?</p>
               <p>Holland. Yes. I bear the king's commission; I am an officer in the Norfolk militia.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a captain?</p>
               <p>Holland. I am not a captain, but an adjutant in the Norfolk militia.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been in the army?</p>
               <p>Holland. I have been in the army 19 years.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the king's service before this?</p>
               <p>Holland. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever a captain?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, I never was.</p>
               <p>Q. I would ask you as to this memorandum-book. Did you take memorandums of the conversation, as well as times?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, Sir, you may see my book, they are memorandums of times and places.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say you took some at some distance of time, the fruit of recollection upon your pillow. Do you recollect when you took them?</p>
               <p>Holland. I do not?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any at the time?</p>
               <p>Holland. Possibly I might some. As for the memorandums, they are so small upon that subject, I'll shew them to any gentleman; frequently<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250032"></xptr> when I go to bed, I recollect what has passed, and if worthy a memorandum, I do it.</p>
               <p>Q. I would be very glad to know whether you have always; for you have been examined more than once, was you then as correct to the circumstances as you are now?</p>
               <p>Holland. As near as I can recollect upon my oath.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then you told Mr. Fielding the same story as now, did you? And he sent for 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person207">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Honyball 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person207" type="surname" value="Honyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person207" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person207" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Holland. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her examined?</p>
               <p>Holland. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. How came it, that after this story, there was no warrant granted? Did you desire a warrant?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, I did not, I did not know it was my business to desire a warrant: I wrote to the father, and thought he would have come and undertook it.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say you promised this lady to see her have justice done her.</p>
               <p>Holland. I did, I was determined to do it myself, if the father did not; but I wanted the prosecution to come from the right quarter.</p>
               <p>Counsel. The first step to be taken is to go to the justice, and get a warrant; did you ask the reason why he did not grant you one?</p>
               <p>Holland. I never asked him for a warrant.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give him your account in writing?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, but the clerk took it down; he wrote a good deal in a book. I gave him, as near as I can recollect, the story the same as I told now.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you examined upon oath?</p>
               <p>Holland. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you sign your examination?</p>
               <p>Holland. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Then did that contain the whole narrative?</p>
               <p>Holland. It did, as near as I could recollect then; I don't say it is the whole, but as near as I could recollect then.</p>
               <p>Q. Had any thing been said to you, or had you made any observation to lead you to suspect she had been delirious?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, none at all, only her making use of these expressions, of saying: She was murdered!</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain this was on the Saturday morning that she said, I am lost, I am murdered! Had I seen you a month ago, this had not happened!</p>
               <p>Holland. Yes.</p>
               <p>Counsel. When you called again on Saturday in the afternoon, you called with Mr. Moon.</p>
               <p>Holland. Yes, I did. He is steward to my Lord Orford.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you carry him, is he not a stranger?</p>
               <p>Holland. Only I had related that of seeing a young lady in distress, and he said he would go along with me.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the motive of taking him with you?</p>
               <p>Holland. My motive was, to hear whether the lady had any thing to say that Mr. Moon might be a witness to it. After I told Mr. Moon where I had been, it came into my thoughts to take him along with me, that I might not be by myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Since you did, how came you not to ask the lady in the presence of him, or any one, touching what she said in the morning?</p>
               <p>Holland. Because she looked upon him, and said, call on the morrow morning, I'll tell you something that shall surprize you; I thought the lady might find herself saint and weak. and seeing him along with me, did not chuse to relate the story to me in his presence</p>
               <p>Q. Then there was nothing said farther than that in the afternoon, was there?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, nothing more, only desired me to call on the morrow morning?</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Sutton's name mentioned in any part of the Saturday?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Nor any thing said relative to his ill-using Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Holland. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you with her on the Saturday afternoon?</p>
               <p>Holland. About ten minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you with her in the morning?</p>
               <p>Holland. Pretty near half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not she fit to hold a long conversation?</p>
               <p>Holland. She seemed not to be desirous to enter into discourse, seeing a gentleman along with me, and I suspected she might be fatigued.</p>
               <p>Q. On the Sunday morning you met with the nurse in the outward room, I would ask you whether you made your first observation to the nurse, or the nurse to you?</p>
               <p>Holland. The nurse to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you swear that?</p>
               <p>Holland. That I swear to; and it was on the account of the clyster.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250033"></xptr>Q. Was that the first information you had concerning the wounds being cut on the lady?</p>
               <p>Holland. That was the first.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say she had not the least appearance of a fever upon her in all the times you was with her?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, not to me.</p>
               <p>Counsel. She began with the account of her coming to town?</p>
               <p>Holland. She did, and related as much as she thought proper.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was you there on the Sunday morning?</p>
               <p>Holland. About nine or ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might you stay that time?</p>
               <p>Holland. I believe I might stay about three quarters of an hour. But I cannot exactly say as to the time.</p>
               <p>Counsel. No fever?</p>
               <p>Holland. To my appearance I thought she had no fever.</p>
               <p>Counsel. And quite sensible?</p>
               <p>Holland. As sensible as I am now; and was so the different times I was there. The nurse and maid told me she was worse on nights.</p>

               <p>Q. Was you told on the Sunday she was deliricus on nights?</p>
               <p>Holland. I don't know that, it may be the Monday or the Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the nurse tell you she was delirious on nights?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, she never told me so; she said she was worse on nights, and her head ran on things, one thing and another. I do not know that she mentioned the word delirious. I don't know that she understood the word.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she talk to you so, that you understood it in that light?</p>
               <p>Holland. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. When did she tell you this?</p>
               <p>Holland. I cannot recollect when. It was in the time of my going there, may be the 1st, 2d, or 3d day. I only recollect she told me she was worse on nights.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say was her reason for coming from Turnham-green?</p>
               <p>Holland. She told me it was on purpose to get rid of Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person208">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person208" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person208" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Mr. Sutton, as Mr. Baker she said paid a guinea a week for the lodgings.</p>
               <p>Counsel. She complain'd, you say, they oblig'd her to drink this vast quantity of ratifea?</p>
               <p>Holland. Yes, she did.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure of the words?</p>
               <p>Holland. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you understand by that?</p>
               <p>Holland. I understood by that, if they did, they did not behave like gentlemen, if they did force her to drink it.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by forcing her?</p>
               <p>Holland. By obliging a lady to drink against her will: I took it in that light, she was obliged to drink it against her will.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go to Mr. Bliss's?</p>
               <p>Holland. I went there on the Sunday morning, in the forenoon, immediately after I went from her.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You saw the lady once or twice every day till Thursday?</p>
               <p>Holland. I did, I was there twice on Thursday.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never see her delirious at all when you was there?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, I never did; she was not the times I was along with her, that I am clear in: all the times that ever I saw her, I found her perfectly sensible, and able to give me an answer; I had different discourse with her about past occurences.</p>
               <p>Q. I desire to know, upon your oath, whether any person was present at the time of the lady's telling you she had been ill used by Mr. Sutton?</p>
               <p>Holland. Yes, the maid, and the nurse too were present part of the time; they were backwards and forwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they present in the hearing it?</p>
               <p>Holland. They were, the maid was present in hearing her say Sutton had cut her, I am sure of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you have always been consistent in that part of your story, or whether you have said there was nobody present?</p>
               <p>Holland. I never declared so, I said the maid was present.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. Did you, or did you nor, tell the nurse what Miss Bell had said to you?</p>
               <p>Holland. I did not, the nurse nor nobody.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. After the nurse had told you of these wounds, at any time, had you then any conversation with her of what Miss Bell had told you?</p>
               <p>Holland. No, never in my life nor the maid neither.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person209">
                  Ann 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person209" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person209" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person209" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person210">
                  Ann 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person210" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person210" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person210" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Marybone.</p>
               <p>Q. Does your father live there?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. He does.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person211">
                  Ann 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person211" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person211" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person211" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person212">
                  Ann 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person212" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person212" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person212" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did, she lodged at my father's house.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250034"></xptr>Q. Do you remember the time she came there?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person213">
                  Ann 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person213" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person213" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person213" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I do, I think that was the 15th of September; it was on a Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. Who came with her?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person214">
                  Ann 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person214" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person214" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person214" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Only a maid, 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person215">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Honyball 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person215" type="surname" value="Honyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person215" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person215" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , came with her. The first nurse that came was only with her one night.</p>
               <p>Q. When did the second nurse come?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I can't positively say when; she came I believe in about twelve days.</p>
               <p>Q. What is her name?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. Her name is 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person216">
                  Frances 
                  Waldgrave 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person216" type="surname" value="Waldgrave"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person216" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person216" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know a person called Captain 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person217">
                  Holland
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person217" type="given" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. When did he come first to your house?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I think he first came the Saturday se'ennight before Miss Bell died: she died on a Saturday.</p>
               <p>Q. What Saturday do you mean that Capt. Hland came there?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. He was at our house the Saturday before she died.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he come more than once that day?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I remember he came twice that day.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did he come the first time?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. As near as I can recollect about ten in the forenoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room with him and Miss Bell the first time?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day did he come the second time?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. It may be about five or six o'clock, with another gentleman with him.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know that gentleman's name?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I do not recollect it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room with them? Do you know what past?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I was not, so that I don't know what past.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing of a clyster ordered for Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was that?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. It was the first Saturday of Capt. Holland's coming.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present when the attempt was made to administer it?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what happened upon that?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I don't know but by the maid and the nurse, they could not do it.</p>
               <p>Q. When did Capt. Holland come the next time?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. He came on the Sunday twice.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room the Sunday morning with Mr. Holland, when he was with Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. No, Sir, I was not, nor in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear in the house any discourse?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person218">
                  Anne 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person218" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person218" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person218" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did hear say on the Saturday they could not give the clyster.</p>
               <p>Q. Will you tell me whether you had any discourse with Miss Bell, or did she say any thing to you concerning wounds she had received?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. No, not till the Wednesday or Thursday before she died.</p>
               <p>Q. Be so good as recollect, and tell us what on the Wednesday or Thursday she told you?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I went in, in order to give Miss Bell a draught which was sent in, and which she refused taking any more either of the maid or of the nurse, and she told me she would tell us a secret; the maid and I were present, only us, one held the candle, and the other gave it her: she said, while drinking it, Now I'll tell you a secret. 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person219">
                  Betty 
                  Honeyball 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person219" type="surname" value="Honeyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person219" type="given" value="Betty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person219" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, Well, let's hear it: then she said, Mr. Sutton and I had a falling out, and Mr. Sutton pull'd out a knife, and said he had a good mind to cut my backside so that I should not sit. Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person220">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person220" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person220" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, Sure you will not offer to do such a thing; and that Mr. Sutton made answer, Yes, Sir; and if Madam says another word, I will cut her face in the same manner; and he bent her fingers back as tho' he would have broke them, and they immediately turned black. She was asked if Sir William ever used her so: she said No, Sir William was a gentleman, and always behav'd as such; and she believed if it had not been for Sir William, Mr. Sutton would have kill'd her; but before she said these words, she said he cut her, and shew'd it by the back of her hand, how he struck the first blow aslant, and then pull'd the knife out, and stuck it in another place up higher, shewing with her finger on the back of her hand. She said Mr. Sutton should say, he had put it out of the doctor's power to cure her, but that he could cure her with such another job, and he would do it the next time he should see her. After all, the last words were, that she had not seen Mr. Sutton<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250035"></xptr> since, till that night, and now he was but at next door; and seemed a little disturbed, a little more fatigued I thought she seemed to be;</p>
               <p>Q. Had you at any other time after this any farther discourse with this gentlewoman?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. No, nor she was never ask'd in my hearing, only she all along said, she should not live.</p>
               <p>Q. Which was the first time you saw her disturbed?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. In the night time, I observ'd her, but I was not with her.</p>
               <p>Q. What construction did you make upon the whle conversation?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I desired her to lie still and compose herself, for Mr. Sutton, nor no body, should come up to use her ill; and she lay quiet a full hour, upon it in dread of seeing Mr. Sutton.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you used to be with her often?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I have fat by her many a time. As my hand was apt to be cold, and she was in a burning sever, she would take hold of my hand in order to cool her own.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you judge her to be in the use of her reason, or not?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. She knew every thing, and would talk very sensible now and then. A trifle between whiles she would seem to be a little disturbed, but knew any of us, and would call any of us by our names.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the wounds dressed?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I never did till the night she was dying, I held the candle to the nurse. There was an ointment melted in a spoon, and I believe oil of turpentine dropp'd in the lint and afterwards laid on, after the somentation.</p>
               <p>Q. What fort of wounds were they?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. One was strait as you could lay a thread, about an inch and half long, the other was round like an issue.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q Had Mr. Sutton been at your house at all?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. No, I never saw him or heard of him to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you apprehend he was at the next door?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I don't apprehend he was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you imagine from those words?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I did imagine she was out of her mind.</p>
               <p>Q. What were her words, now I will tell you the secret?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. Her words were, now I will tell you a secret, to Honyball and me.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Honeyball said let's hear it?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she desire to hear it, as a matter quite new to her?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. This was the Wednesday or Thursday before she died.</p>
               <p>Q. Repeat what Honeyball said.</p>
               <p>A. Knight. Now then let's hear it.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Honyball ever before told you this?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I heard before that, she was either cut or torn, that they could not give her the clyster.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Honyball ever before told you this of Miss Bell, that she knew of any wounds?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. No, she did not say she knew of any wounds before the clyster came to be given, if it had not been for that it would not have been discovered. To the best of my remembrance she used to say, she had her death wound, she should die.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Honyball, before this Wednesday, tell you that her mistress had told her that Sutton had given her those wounds?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I don't know that she did.</p>
               <p>Q. When Honyball said, well, let's hear it, Did it seem to be new to her?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. It did.</p>
               <p>Q. When this young woman had been at your house some time, was not her complaint a fever?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. A very high fever.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a continued fever?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. It continued all the time she was at our house; sometimes it appeared a little better, but sometimes it would be worse.</p>
               <p>Q. At the several times when you took hold of her hand, did she appear to you to be in a violent fever?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. Scorching hot.</p>
               <p>Q. During the time when she was at your house, did she appear to have a fever?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. At one time she was a good deal better.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was she at your house?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. She was at our house three weeks, the fever seem'd to be much abated once; but it got on very high again.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the time that captain Holland came there?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I do, it was the Saturday se'ennight before she died.</p>
               <p>Q. How was her fever that day?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. It was very high, and very bad that day; that was the day the clyster was to be administered. I went into the room to the bedside<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250036"></xptr> to speak to her; she lay with her eyes shut, and took any notice of no body at all; after that she was rais'd up in her bed and spoke to me, and asked me how I did; and said she was extreamly bad.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she from Saturday after grow better or worse?</p>

               <p>A. Knight. From that Saturday, which was just a week before she died, her fever continued very bad upon her to the best of my knowledge?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her frequently?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you at any time see her when you yourself could think her free from a fever.</p>
               <p>A. Knight. No, she was better before that than after, but from that time to the time of her death, I never saw her that I could say she was free from a sever, or c old.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. Do you think her sever did never leave her?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I don't think it ever did.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. You say in the night time she would ramble and be worse?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. They did tell me so.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. Did she know you when she was raised up in the bed, and addressed herself to you, as you have mentioned? Do you apprehend she was in or out of her senses?</p>
               <p>A Knight. In her senses, I dare say, when she spoke to me, and called me by my name.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. Did you hold any conversation with her after she asked you how you did?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. No, sir, none at all, only I said, I hoped not, when she said she was very bad, I said I hoped not, and I heartily wished her better.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. Had you any other discourse with her that day?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. No.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. Had you any reason to judge that if you had pursued any conversation with her after she was raised up in the bed, she was not able to give you any reasonable answer?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I believe she could talk, if her spirits and strength would let her, but I did not endeavour to talk to her.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. Had you any other conversation with her any other days?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. No other ways than asking how she did.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. What is your opinion, as to her understanding, upon other days?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. My opinion is, on other days, she understood any thing, as she called me by my name, she would have answered if I had asked her any thing.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. Did you try her to hold a conversation?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. No.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. Do you believe her strength would let her give a history of three quarters of an hour long?</p>
               <p>A. Knight. I can't from any judgment of that. I should not have attempted to introduce any such conversation.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person221">
                  Thomas 
                  Drake 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person221" type="surname" value="Drake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person221" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person222">
                  Tho 
                  Drake 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person222" type="surname" value="Drake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person222" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am from Aylsham in Norfolk.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Drake. I am a merchant in this city.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Drake. I did in her life time, extremely well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you visit her in her illness at Marybone?</p>
               <p>Drake. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>Drake. On Thursday the second of October, at the request of her mother.</p>

               <p>Q. In what condition did you find her?</p>
               <p>Drake. In a very low condition.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she appear to you to be in her senses?</p>
               <p>Drake. She appeared to me to be perfectly in her senses.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she converse with you?</p>
               <p>Drake. She did.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell my Lord and the jury, what she said to you on that occasion?</p>
               <p>Drake. When I entered the room, I asked her how she did</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body in the room at the time?</p>
               <p>Drake. There was no body admitted in the room but me. I had a gentleman waiting for me, but not in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the conversation?</p>
               <p>Drake. I asked her how she did; she replied, O Sir, I am a dead woman. I then asked her if she knew me; she said yes, Mr. Drake, extremely well, and begged I would come to the bed-side. She then asked me, whether her father was come to town; I told her no; that I had received a letter from her mother; she begged I would be so good as to read that letter, which I did. She then called to the nurse, and desired to be helped up; upon my finding her very low, I said, make yourself easy, I hope you'll get the better of this. She replied, no, Sir, that is impossible, for I have received two<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250037"></xptr> wounds, which will be the death of me; for I am sure they will mortify. I then asked her if she knew how she came by those wounds; she replied yes, they were given her with a penknife. I then asked her, if she knew who gave her the wounds; she answered, O, yes, very well. Finding her weak, then I said, I would take my leave of her.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she tell you who gave her those wounds?</p>
               <p>Drake. No, she did not, and I did not ask her.</p>
               <p>Q. From the time you went there, to the time you went away, did she appear to be in, or out of her senses?</p>
               <p>Drake. Perfectly sensible all the while I was with her, during all the time, to the best of my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her after that?</p>
               <p>Drake. I was going on the Saturday morning, and was informed she was dead.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Capt. Holland?</p>
               <p>Drake. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he and you any conversation about Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Drake. We had; I told him I had heard she was very ill; then he said, he would go and see her.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you wrote to her mother?</p>
               <p>Drake. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your reason for it?</p>
               <p>Drake. Her mother wrote to me, and I gave an answer to that letter.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the time you saw Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Drake. This was on Thursday, about four in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Holland there at the time?</p>
               <p>Drake. He was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she appear to be in a fever?</p>
               <p>Drake. I believe she seemed rather feverish; she complained of being very thirsty, and was extremely ill; she took something to drink.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then you did not think proper to ask her the material question?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person223">
                  Drake
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person223" type="given" value="Drake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person223" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I did not apprehend her death was so near.</p>
               <p>Q. When she told you she had had two wounds which would be her death how came you not to ask her if she knew how she came by them.</p>
               <p>Drake. I had heard just before, there were two wounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Who told you?</p>
               <p>Drake. Mr. Bliss's servant told me there was a very odd affair.</p>
               <p>Mr. Moon sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Moon. I have the honour to be steward to my Lord Orford.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Capt. Holland being with you on the 27th of September?</p>
               <p>Moon. I do; I believe it was on that Saturday he dined with me in Green street, and I went with him to Marybone in the evening, to see Miss Bell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with him there above once?</p>
               <p>Moon. No; I was not. I never was with him there above once when she was alive; I went once with him there after she was dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any body in the room when you was there?</p>
               <p>Moon. There was a maid, and an old nurse.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any body else there?</p>
               <p>Moon. I do not recollect any body else.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect what was talked of?</p>
               <p>Moon. After talking sometime, she desired he would call the next day, she had something particular to say to him. This was after she had eat something.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she at that time discover any reason why she chose he should call the next day?</p>
               <p>Moon. She intimated something, that she had been used ill, but particularized no-body; she talked but very little. I imagined she was in distress, and I might be of some support to her; I took a piece of a pine in my pocket, and she eat part of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether she held a great deal of discourse or little?</p>
               <p>Moon. He did not discourse much with her, fearing it should hurt her.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you recollect at all from her discourse, whether she was in her perfect senses, or otherwise?</p>
               <p>Moon. Being but a short time with her, the latter part of it appeared to me so, she was her senses. But when when I came in at first, it appeared from some circumstances, that she was rather out of her senses, but I am not convinc'd she was so, because she talked very reasonble afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Recollect the particular discourse that led you to think she was out of her senses?</p>
               <p>Moon. When I was first in the room, she talked to her maid about caps and handkerchiefs in a bureau or box; I thought she was out of her senses at that time; but afterwards, from her talking, I thought I was mistaken I was served with a subpoena but a quarter after 12; so that I<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250038"></xptr> have but a short time to recollect what passed. She talked of some caps and handkerchiefs in a bureau or box; but it appeared to me there was no such box; afterwards I thought myself mistaken, she talked so reasonable.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go away with Capt. Holland?</p>
               <p>Moon. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you confer with him about her being out of her senses?</p>
               <p>Moon. I do not know that I did?</p>
               <p>Q. Was he with you all the time?</p>
               <p>Moon. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it was possible for any person to have been with the lady, the time you was, and not think she was out of her senses? Do you think she was perfectly cool, calm, and serene, and perfect in her senses all the while?</p>
               <p>Moon. She was excessive calm at the latter part.</p>
               <p>Q. Had she a sever upon her?</p>
               <p>Moon. I cannot say she had.</p>
               <p>Q. What were your motives for going to see her?</p>
               <p>Moon. I had no other reason, but excited by compassion?</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Holland intimate to you, to take you, that you might be a witness of what pass'd, to be an evidence?</p>
               <p>Moon. No never, not at that time I went there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person224">
                  Mary Young 
                  Sworn 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person224" type="surname" value="Sworn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person224" type="given" value="Mary Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person224" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your first acquaintance with her?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I was at Haddock's bagnio; my first acquaintance with her was there at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were in company?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person225">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person225" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person225" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Mr. Sutton.</p>
               <p>Q. When?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I do not recollect the day, I believe it was on Wednesday?</p>
               <p>Q. What month?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I do not remember the month.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the year?</p>
               <p>M. Young. The latter part of the summer.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day did you go there?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I went in the evening, and we supped there, and staid there that night, and the next day morning, till dinner-time, and went from there to the Cardigan, and dined.</p>
               <p>Q. Who do you speak of?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person226">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person226" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person226" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. Sutton, Miss Bell, and myself. We supped there, and then went back again to the bagnio that night.</p>
               <p>Counsel. This made a day and a night?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Yes: the next day we got up and breakfasted together; and a little after that Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person227">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person227" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person227" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was sent for to the Cardigan, by his brother, I believe, Mr. Jones. He had been gone but a little time, and then he sent for Mr. Sutton. He got up, and was going, and Miss Bell got up, and asked for something; I believe it was money; I heard him say he would send her some after he got to Sir William. She desired I would wait a little time. I did, and after that took a chair and went home. I heard nothing of her after that for three or four days. Then I went to her lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. How long were you there at the bagnio together, three nights, or only two?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Only two, I believe. We dined at the Cardigan-head, I think, two days. The first day Mr. Bliss came and dined with us.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lie no more at the bagnio than two nights?</p>
               <p>M. Young. No more than two nights I think,</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you return to after the second dinner at the Cardigan-head?</p>
               <p>M. Young. To the bagnio.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the first nights you lay at the bagnio on a Wednesday night?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I came in the evening to the bagnio, I believe on a Wednesday, lay there all night, and on Thursday dined at the Cardigan, and went from thence to the bagnio at night.</p>
               <p>Counsel. That makes two nights?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Yes.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Now we are come to the Friday, how did you dispose of yourself on the Friday?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I don't know; I don't know whether I dined one day, or two, at the Cardigan-head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you lie more than two nights, or only two nights at the bagnio?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I think only two nights.</p>
               <p>Q. During the time you was at the bagnio, do you know of any ill usage that Miss Bell received from any body?</p>
               <p>M. Young. In my opinion I don't think Mr. Sutton behaved well to her, but not in beating or wounding her.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell in what respect?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250039"></xptr>M. Young. In his behaviour to her, always speaking cross to her. I don't know of any thing else.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect any language made use of?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. What appeared to convey that idea to you of his not behaving well to her?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Nothing but his cool behaviour.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose companion was Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Mr. Sutton's.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person228">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person228" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person228" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's companion?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember paying Miss Bell a visit at her lodgings?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I do, it was, I believe, three or four days after I left her at the bagnio.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the first time of your seeing her again after that when you called at her lodgings?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Yes, that was the first time?</p>
               <p>Q. Be so good to tell the court and the jury how you found her?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I found her extreamly ill; she told me Mr. Sutton had used her extreamly ill, and had been the ruin of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ask her in what manner?</p>
               <p>M. Young. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you descend into any particular inquiry more than that?</p>
               <p>M. Young. No, she told me she had wrote to Mr. Sutton, and he had sent her an answer which she took very unkind. I went and told Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person229">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person229" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person229" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             how bad she was, and that she wanted money. He said he would either send her money, or something.</p>
               <p>Q. At the bagnio, whether you observed any incivility between Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person230">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person230" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person230" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and her?</p>
               <p>M. Young. No, I did not; Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person231">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person231" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person231" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             behaved in a very different manner than Mr. Sutton did.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she for understanding when you left her at her lodgings?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Then she was quite in her senses.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any weapons or blows given, or any thing of that sort?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I never saw him beat her, nor never saw any weapon.</p>
               <p>Q. During the time she was there, did she drink pretty freely?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Yes, I think she drank more than did her good; she was rather in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. In one particular time, or did she continue in it?</p>
               <p>M. Young. No, it was in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the liquor she drank?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I believe she drank ratisea.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she more than once overtaken with liquor, that she had drank in the evening?</p>
               <p>M. Young. The next day, at the conclusion of the evening; she was the same each night.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she drunk both nights?</p>
               <p>M. Young. She was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she inclinable to be passionate and violent in her temper in liquor?</p>
               <p>M. Young. No, Sir, she was frolicksome, as most drunken people are.</p>
               <p>Q. What so far as mischief may happen - throwing knives about, and the like?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I never saw nothing of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of her falling down stairs?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I don't remember any thing of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make any complaint to you at the bagnio of any injury done her?</p>
               <p>M. Young. No, she never did.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. You have said during the time you was in company with this young woman at the bagnio or Cardigan-head, you did not see any personal injury done her, or heard her complain?</p>
               <p>M. Young. No.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. But did not you leave her behind you?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I did.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. Where was Mr. Sutton when you left her?</p>
               <p>M. Young. He was gone to Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person232">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person232" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person232" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the Cardigan-head.</p>
               <p>Court. You have said already (though you did not like Mr. Sutton's behaviour to the you ng woman) that he was cool, or negligent, or something of that kind; but you never saw him hurt her, by beating or wounding her?</p>
               <p>M. Young. No.</p>
               <p>Court. Did you ever hear him menace her?</p>
               <p>M. Young. No.</p>
               <p>Court. I think you said you heard him promise to send her money, or return to her?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Yes.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. Do you recollect the time you left the bagnio?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I do not; I believe it was between one and two o'clock, but I do not recollect that particularly.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250040"></xptr>Counsel for prisoner. Did you ever hear Miss Bell say she saw Mr. Sutton after that?</p>
               <p>M. Young. I never did; I never heard her talk about it after.</p>
               <p>The Rev. 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person233">
                  Francis 
                  Boot 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person233" type="surname" value="Boot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person233" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You are a clergyman?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. I am; I attended this unhappy young woman in her last illness.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you attend her before her death?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. About a fortnight.</p>
               <p>Q. How often in that fortnight?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. Perhaps about nine or ten times.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she appear to be in respect to her senses and understanding?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. Sometimes she appeared quite sensible, but at other times not quite so. I observed her alternately, some days better, some worse; one day better, and the next day a great deal worse.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you mean in point of health, or understanding?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. Both; on the better day she appeared in her senses, I took her to be so, at other times she seemed extreamly bad, and in a tremor and confused.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she capable, in her better days, of telling a story of herself, or recollecting and knowing what she said?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. She appeared to me to be sensible some days.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think she was on some days capable of telling a story relating to herself, or not?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. I did not perceive to the contrary of her being sensible; her answers to me seemed sensible and reasonable; her behaviour discreet and devout, very much so.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she very weak of body?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. She was.</p>
               <p>Q. When might be the last time you attended her?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. I believe the day before her death, the Friday.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether she did not grow weaker in her body, and likewise in her mind?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. Alternately she did; some days better, and some days worse.</p>
               <p>Q. As you are a clergyman, and visit the sick, have not you met with people that talk reasonable, and sometimes otherwise?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. What upon the same thing?</p>
               <p>Counsel. Yes.</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. I cannot say as to that; sometimes she appeared to be fluttered and disordered; then I never pressed her, but left her.</p>

               <p>Q. How long have you talk'd to her at any one time?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. I have talked to her may be a quarter of an hour when she was well.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ever mention a syllable of this affair to you?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. No, never hinted it, I never asked her about it, I talked to her about the affair I came upon, after her soul's health, I had nothing to do with any thing relative to this; she seemed to have a good and a bad day; in her good day she could talk reasonably, I don't know that she was out of her senses, she was disordered.</p>
               <p>Counsel. I understood you that alternately she appeared to be disordered both in body and mind.</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How were her senses the day before she died?</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. She seemed very ill, very weak and sick.</p>
               <p>Counsel. We are asking after her understanding.</p>
               <p>Rev. F. Boot. I observe that goes along with the body a good deal.</p>
         
               <p>*** The Third Part of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17610225-18">
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610225"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18" type="date" value="17610225"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250041"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 25th, Thursday the 26th, Friday the 27th, and Saturday the 28th of FEBRUARY.</p>
                  <p>In the first Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Third SESSION in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person234">
                     Matthew 
                     Blakiston 
                  <interp inst="t17610225-18-person234" type="surname" value="Blakiston"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610225-18-person234" type="given" value="Matthew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610225-18-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER III. PART III. for the YEAR 1761.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by J. SCOTT, at the Black-Swan, in Pater-noster Row.</p>
                  <p>M. DCC. LXI.</p>
                  <p>Price FOUR-PENCE.</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250042"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery held for the City of London, &amp;c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person235">
                  Frances 
                  Waldgrave 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person235" type="surname" value="Waldgrave"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person235" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person235" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q DO you know Mr. Bliss?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person236">
                  Francis 
                  Waldgrave 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person236" type="surname" value="Waldgrave"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person236" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I do, since I have been in this affair, but I never knew him before.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see him?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I saw him in the gentlewoman's chamber, Miss Bell; my daughter was the servant in the house where she lodg'd, at Mr. Knight's; they complained they wanted somebody to assist.</p>
               <p>Q. Who complained?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person237">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Honyball 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person237" type="surname" value="Honyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person237" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person237" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said she could not be maid and nurse too; she grambled to the apothecary; my daughter told them her mother goes a nurse-keeping; then he said, Fetch her; and she came and fetched me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you brought as a nurse to attend Miss Bell at her lodgings?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I was: when I had been there about an hour or two the apothecary came: this was on the Tuesday, she died the Saturday se'ennight following; I was twelve days with her in her life-time, and three after her death.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you find her on the Tuesday when you came to her?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. Very bad indeed: she said, Who are you? I said, My dear, I am sent for to nurse you: do you like me?</p>
               <p>Q. What was her illness?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. She was ill of a fever, and I attended upon her as one sick of a fever from that time. The apothecary asked me how she was in her body; the maid said she was very well; I said you tell a story, for she is very costive; sometimes she was very chearful, and said she would eat; I was forced to lyringe her throat, and got out a vast quantity of stuff not fit to be mentioned; she was worse and worse till the time of her death; she was jaw-set, and could not talk much.</p>
               <p>Q. How did that affect her speech?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. She could not drink as other people, we were forced to hold her jaw down with a table-spoon to make it give way; then I would put victuals in her mouth, and she could swallow it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the apothecary order her any thing?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. He order'd a clyster to be fetch'd, but don't know whether Betty or the porter fetched it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you administer it?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I and Betty went to administer it, I turn'd up the cloaths, and said, Betty, you must assist me; when I came to turn up the cloaths, I saw, close to the very rump, it is almost a shame to speak it, but we are all women and men, (I know none of them all, I never eat not drank at none of their cost, nor never will) I saw a corrupted place between the thick<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250043"></xptr> of the buttock. I said Betty, Lord! What is this? Lord! said she, I don't know. I said, Did you ever see that? Lord! said she, here is another: that appeared corrupted like an issue, and it being a ready-furnished lodging, they would not let her have any thing.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe those sores.</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I wiped the corruption off with my handkerchief, then when that was wiped away it look'd like a clean cut to me, about this length. (Describing it by her finger about an inch and a half long.)</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this wound that you now speak of?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. This was between the clifts of the buttock.</p>
               <p>Q. In what article did that look like a cut?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. But they could not cut deep because of the bone, it was just upon the bone, or below the bone: Said Betty, Nurse, here is another on the flesh-part of it. Says I, That looks red. Bless me! says I, what is it? It look'd like a blind bile. I turned to mistress, and said, What is all this? How did you come by this? She said, I don't know nothing at all of the matter. It look'd red and angry; there was no opening of the skin at all then, but there was afterwards, and when the stuff was in there was a hole, and sore, very sore; I could not give the clyster.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe how the second appeared.</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. The skin of the blind bile appeared red, quite red, and look'd angry.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether there was any rags of skin, or any thing that looked like an impression, upon the outward skin?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I did not observe any at that time, but therewas a great deal afterwards, and it turned to a hole; and when there was a hole, there was nothing ragged round it; there was a round hole.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Miss Bell cry out first, or did you first observe the wound to be so?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. No, Sir, I was going to give her it, and laid a cloth over her, to keep her warm, and she said, You hurt me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you hurt her with?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I believe it was with the edge of my hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Capt. Holland been there that day?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. He came almost every day.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was it you went to give her the clyster?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. This was Saturday at noon.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember the first time of his coming?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I do; Betty brought him up stairs, he had boots on, but what day I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember his coming on the Sunday morning?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he learn Miss Bell had any wounds?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. That I cannot tell, I never told him any thing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when the maid brought him up stairs?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I was in the bed-chamber.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember clearly the passages that past that Saturday and Sunday?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I really think I can remember all.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember who came into the room with Capt. Holland?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I don't know; the maid that let him in might, but I think no-body but Capt. Holland came in; he came into the bed-chamber.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you clear in your memory that you did not see Capt. Holland before he came into the bedchamber?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I saw him no where but in the bed-chamber.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure you held no discourse with him in the dining-room, before he came into the bed-chamber?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. No, never in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. What reason have you for being so clear in your recollection that Capt. Holland did not hold a discourse with you in the dining-room?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. He used to come in in a civil manner, and go and fit down by the bed, and talk to her a great while: indeed on the Sunday morning he held no discourse with me, he came into the bed-chamber directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Moon coming?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room when a gentleman came with Capt. Holland on Saturday in the afternoon, when the curtains were drawn back?</p>

               <p>F. Waldgrave. He brought two birds and another gentleman along with him; I do not know who he was: he called me out of the dining-room, and said, Take care of these birds for your mistress: I said she can hardly swallow them. He said, I tell you give it<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250044"></xptr> her; and the next day he made her chew some, and it fell into his hand again.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present at the time of the discourse between Capt. Holland and Miss Bell, when he brought those birds?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I went into the dining-room, he bid me go, and out of good manners I did, when he said, Pray nurse withdraw.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you or do you not remember whether you heard any of the conversation that passed?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. No indeed, I did not.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say she was some times chearful, and at other times was not.</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. Towards night she was restless.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she when chearful?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. When I have said I hope you'll get the better of it, she has said, Don't talk nothing melancholy: she would not let me read to her in her prayer-book: I did think sometimes she would get better, at other times she was worse, and then her eyes would stare as if she was in a convulsion.</p>
               <p>Q. How long at a time would she sit up with you?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. Not a long time, because her speech was so bad.</p>
               <p>Q. When she was at her best, how long would she?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. May be two or three minutes, or a quarter of an hour, or may be more.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any particular time when she has talked with you in this chearful manner for a quarter of an hour?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you have overheard her give any account of these wounds at any time?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. No, Sir, only what I heard from other people. I asked her several times, and she said she knew nothing of the matter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you overhear her say it to any body else?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. No, indeed, Sir, I never did.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. When did that bile break?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. I don't know, it broke in the plaister I believe; the doctor came on the Sunday morning, and I shewed him it.</p>
               <p>Court. You say there was corruption on the first wound you mention?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. There was.</p>
               <p>Court. When that was wiped off, did it appear like a cut?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. It did; the other did not, that looked red and angry.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell Captain 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person238">
                  Holland
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person238" type="given" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that you thrust the clyster-pipe up into the wound a matter of two inches?</p>
               <p>F. Waldgrave. O! bless me! I never told him so! he never asked me!</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person239">
                  Thomas 
                  Bliss 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person239" type="surname" value="Bliss"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person239" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person240">
                  Thomas 
                  Bliss 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person240" type="surname" value="Bliss"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person240" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an apothecary; I attended Miss Bell at Marybone, and at Spring gardens.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you advise a clyster?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the reason it was not administered?</p>
               <p>Bliss. On the 27th of September I visited her in the morning early, and intended to call in a physician the same day. I ordered the clyster to be ready, and when Dr. Smith visited her, it was directed to be given as soon as we were gone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the reason why it was not administered?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I think my servant told me the nurse had said to him she had pockey-sores, and she was not able to give the clyster.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it you heard this?</p>
               <p>Bliss. This was at night: I suppose he returned late at night.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see Miss Bell after that?</p>
               <p>Bliss. The next day I met the doctor there about noon.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done upon this?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I first interrogated the nurse as to the reasons of not giving the clyster; she said she could not for sores at the part. I told Dr. Smith I thought it proper she should be inspected, as the nurse thought them venereal, because she at times had complained of venereal disorders; but being in a fever, we could do nothing for it; and I told the doctor he might look at it. The doctor desired the nurse to put her in a proper position for inspection. Then the doctor and I went from the next room, and he pointed with his finger to desire I would observe them. I did observe them. I opened the sore, or chasm, or wound; call it what you will, it does not make it otherwise; and, upon opening the buttocks, there was an aperture about an inch long. I observed to the doctor, immediately as it occurred to me, it looked extreamly clean, as clean as though cut with a knife. I said it looks as clean as though cut with a knife, The doctor remarked also, that it looked very clean. About an inch from that there was a little blind bile, it might be called a little tumour, not broke, with matter in it.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe the wound?</p>
               <p>Bliss. It was an inch long, and deepest in the middle; and at each extream it went to a point, and nothing. It is necessary to observe, if cut with a knife, it must be cut at twice. I have<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250045"></xptr> considered the thing since; it is a matter of conjecture in what manner it happened, the jury must determine that. It was deepest in the middle, not through the integument, it was very shallow.</p>
               <p>Counsel. If you'll look upon the top of this letter, you'll find it to be your own hand-writing. [He takes a letter in his hand.]</p>
               <p>Bliss. This is a letter I wrote to Mr. Bell, her father.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Read it.</p>
               <p>Bliss.</p>
               <p>"Accordingly she was inspected, so</p>
               <p>"that she was examined; and instead of sores at</p>
               <p>"the fundament (as the nurse pretended) we</p>
               <p>"have found the sore at the bottom of the back,</p>
               <p>"just in the clift, between the fundament and the</p>
               <p>"bone, called the Os Sacrum. The fore, or</p>
               <p>"wound, seemed about an inch and half long,</p>
               <p>"and near half an inch deep; and near to it, but</p>
               <p>"in the fleshy part of the buttock, was another</p>
               <p>"fore; it was a hole not big enough to introduce</p>
               <p>"a little finger. Upon observing the</p>
               <p>"wounds clean, and so much like a cut made</p>
               <p>"with a knife, the doctor and myself said, they</p>
               <p>"looked rather cleaner than wounds, &amp; c." - Now, Sir, you will please to observe, I tell it now as I did then, with this difference, that Mr. Chapman's deposition, before Mr. Fielding, was its being two inches long, and deeper than we described it; but those that have seen it since, will describe it as I have, for we did not properly inspect it before.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this taken?</p>
               <p>Bliss. This was taken the 10th of October.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether there was, or was not, in the second place, a little hole of the dimension you have described, that you might introduce your little finger?</p>
               <p>Bliss. It was not so big as you could introduce a large goose-quill. I think the least finger that any woman has could not be introduced into it.</p>
               <p>Counsel.</p>
               <p>"And made it so much like a cut with</p>
               <p>"a knife, you did did not think it proceeded like</p>
               <p>"a tumor." Can you inform the court whether those two places had the appearance of a cut with a knife? Had you any meaning in writing that?</p>
               <p>Bliss. The first had the appearance of a cut with a knife, the last had not, nor did I ever think of it in that manner; neither could any man alive; and if 500 people saw it, it did not look like a cut.</p>
               <p>Counsel. I apprehend if a knife was darted into the five weeks before, or thereabouts, that it might, by putrifying and closing at the ends, form itself into such a little hole?</p>
               <p>Bliss. As to the first wound, I admit it looked like a cut when I first saw it; it certainly looked so, and all the world would have said so at first fight. It was deeper in the middle than at the ends; it went gradually down, and then up again. As it was in the clift, I never thought it any other, ways than I now do; that one looked like being cut with a knife, and the other not; and I don't think any one evidence can say otherwise than what I say.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you see her on the Thursday before she died?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I did; to the best of my recollection I attended her every day, at least once, and sometimes twice.</p>
               <p>Q. I should be glad to know what your opinion was as to the state of her sense and understanding?</p>
               <p>Bliss. She was I believe even ten days before she died delirious and wavering towards night, and at noon some days tolerably sensible, and some days not sensible; so that to determine what day really sensible, is not in my power; but every night she was delirious, so as not to maintain any constant story, and I think every other day she was rather worses</p>
               <p>Counsel. Look at this letter. [He takes it in his hand.]</p>
               <p>Bliss. This is what I wrote to her father.</p>
               <p>Counsel. 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person241">
                  Read
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person241" type="given" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a part of it.</p>
               <p>Bliss. [ He reads where directed]</p>
               <p>"Your daughter</p>
               <p>"is somewhat worse, and I am sorry to let</p>
               <p>"you know she is now in the weakest stars imaginable.</p>
               <p>"She is sensible, and much wishes to</p>
               <p>"see some of her friends. A physician attends</p>
               <p>"her twice a day." -</p>
               <p>Q. What could be your meaning in this, if she was not as you mention?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I urged the father to come up, and have his letter here. I remember this was the very day that Mr. Sutton was charged; and I the more wished Mr. Bell, or some of the family would come up to town.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this letter dated?</p>
               <p>Bliss. This is dated the 2d of October.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you mean to write that she was sensible as your real opinion, or only that her father might come to town?</p>
               <p>Bliss. There were intervals that I might take the advantage of writing in that manner, in order to induce him to come to town. Her jaws were closed, and we were obliged to syringe her mouth, I believe ten days before she died.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250046"></xptr>Q. Did not you yourself ask her by what means she received these wounds?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I did more than once.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time you asked her these questions, did you think her sensible?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I did think her sensible; and when I asked her the questions, sometimes she said, she believed Mr. Sutton hurt her, or ill used her, but was not sure; that was generally her own expression and observation.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear her say, or suggest, that any one else had hurt her?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon the whole of your attendance on this young woman, let those be sores, or cut with knives; whether in the condition that they were, they did not, or might not contribute to the hastening of her death, or be the occasion of her death?</p>
               <p>Bliss. Why Sir, from the appearance of the wounds, I could not think they had been given so long as they pretended them to have been given.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, from the condition of those wounds or sores (you call them wounds) whether or no they might not, and did not, in your judgment, contribute to the woman's death?</p>
               <p>Bliss. No more than an issue in the arm would, that I verily believe; had they been seen ten days before any surgeon would have cured them, they were so insignificant; if they had been applied to ten days before.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Yet being neglected, and in the state they were when you observed them, whether in that state and condition, they did not contribute to this young woman's death.</p>
               <p>Bliss. No ways, in no manner, did they contribute to her death; he thrush was in a dangerous condition, and that, together with the high fever and the putrefaction, without having any reference to the wounds, were the cause of her death?</p>
               <p>Q. Did they gangrene?</p>
               <p>Bliss. They did.</p>
               <p>Q. If wounds gangrene, whether that circulating in the blood does not occasion a putrid fever?</p>
               <p>Bliss. No Sir, had it been a much worse putre faction, it might have been cured by surgeons at this day. I have seen mortifications ten times worse, that have been cured. With her habit of body, a mortification would have happened there, whether she had wounds or not; that I aver; she would have mortified just where she did, and when she did, and would have died at the precise time.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You think if the woman had not had these wounds, with the ill habit of body she was under, she would have died the very same time.</p>
               <p>Bliss. I speak from observation and opinion; for when the thrush comes through the body, it produces such sort of symptoms there.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. From what time did you attend her?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I attended her from the 11th of September.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray who employ'd you?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I was employ'd by Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person242">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person242" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person242" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at Mrs. Parker's.</p>
               <p>Counsel for the crown. One question more. When do you mean that Mr. Sutton was charg'd?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I do not know whether it was not talk'd of the day the clyster was to be applied; I do not know but the doctor and I might ask her, if she knew any thing of the sores the first time we saw them on the Sunday, on the first surmises of a cut; we the more inquired into it, because we had smelt a scent in the room, and wished to account for it, but it was out of my power. I cannot tell when I heard Mr. Sutton was charg'd, but I am positive on the Thursday it was fixed upon him.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. What were your directions from Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person243">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person243" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person243" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Bliss. To do every thing proper and fit for a person in her condition.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you pursue these directions?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I did to the utmost of my capacity.</p>
               <p>Q. How often did you visit her at Mrs. Parker's?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I visited her daily there.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you hear her complain at that time of having any stab from Mr. Sutton, or any body else?</p>
               <p>Bliss. Not the least ill treatment.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it your business to inquire the most minute circumstance, to distinguish the cause of the disorder?</p>
               <p>Bliss. It is, and from the first I looked upon it to be inflammatory, and not in the least any cut or ill usage. I never heard her complain of any body having used her ill.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your reason for removing her from Mrs. Parker's?</p>
               <p>Bliss. She often begged she might be removed from thence; she said, it was a place, if she remained<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250047"></xptr> in one week she must die. I mentioned this to Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person244">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person244" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person244" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and he gave me five guineas, with directions to pay Mrs. Parker for two weeks lodging; and I wrote to Mr. Bell her father, the situation of his daughter, and the condition she was in. Sir William expressed a kindness for her, I understood she had been an acquaintance of his.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know how Mr. Sutton became acquainted with her?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I have heard Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person245">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person245" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person245" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             first introduced Mr. Sutton to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear Miss Bell speak of that?</p>
               <p>Bliss. She spoke of Sir William as her particular friend.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first hear her speak of Mr. Sutton?</p>
               <p>Bliss. Never till this charge was fixed upon him.</p>
               <p>Q. How was she removed to Marybone?</p>
               <p>Bliss. She was removed to Marybone in a chair, and set up in it, on Monday the fifteenth of September; the maid went in a coach and carried all her things, and I sent a letter to Mr. Knight, desiring she might be put in that apartment, and that I would see him paid.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she removed without any injury?</p>
               <p>Bliss. She was; I attended her there every day; the wound had never been discovered, if a clyster had not been ordered by myself; and upon the attempt of that, the discovery was made.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear Miss Bell, or any-body about her, say, that in attempting to give the clyster, they had put the pipe up into the wound?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I asked the nurse how she discovered it.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you ask her?</p>
               <p>Bliss. The next day.</p>
               <p>Q. When you heard the clyster had been attempted to be given, and the nurse had not given it, did you call in the assistance of a doctor?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I did, Dr. Smith, and he went with me.</p>
               <p>Q. You say the wound, when the matter was wiped off, looked clean like a cut: do you mean it was a cut, or seemed like a cut?</p>
               <p>Bliss. It did not carry the appearance of an old wound, as a tumor would; it seemed more like a cut with a knife.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you mean to have it understood, it was a cut, or like a cut.</p>
               <p>Bliss. I do not believe a cut, I rather think it might be a little bruise, which by degrees might increase every day, by lying in the posture she did?</p>
               <p>Q. If it was a cut given so long before, as the 30th of August, whether it would not have appeared in a different manner than what you found it on the 2d of October?</p>
               <p>Bliss. Certainly it would have been a foul sore, at least in that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Could it not be a cut of so long standing as the 30th of August?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I am clear it could not.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the doctor and you agreed in your opinion?</p>
               <p>Bliss. The doctor said, it does look very clean, and we thought it of so little consequence, that we did not think of sending a surgeon to it till two or three days after. We did not think it necessary to have a surgeon to attend it.</p>
               <p>Q. How was the blind bile?</p>
               <p>Bliss. That was full of matter, the skin I think might be off then.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not that the appearance of a bile that always begins to corrupt in the middle?</p>
               <p>Bliss. Yes a little bile, circular, as biles commonly are, and it turned out into a hole, as biles always do, when it came to be dressed after the discharge of the matter.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it ever enter into your head that it was a stab?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I have thought of it a thousand times. It is impossible it should be given with a knife, by the appearance of it at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body see it besides you?</p>
               <p>Bliss. The surgeons and physicians saw it as well as me. We all concurred in that opinion, Those surgeons that were brought by Mr. Holland were of that opinion.</p>
               <p>Q. Who were they?</p>
               <p>Bliss. Mr. Wyatt and Mr. Farmer, and there is a gentleman here, nam'd Riddle, he told me it did not appear like a cut.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the bad state of the body did not occasion that gangrene?</p>
               <p>Bliss. Most certainly her bad habit of body brought on the gangrene, and not the gangrence brought on the bad habit of the body; and, as I have given offence to some here *, I hope there are hospital surgeons here that will answer.</p>
               <p>* When he aver'd she would have mortified just where she did, and when she did, and would have died at the very precise time, there was a very great hissing in court.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250048"></xptr>Counsel. Pray give it again.</p>
               <p>Bliss. I give it as my opinion as long as I live, if I die the moment after, that she would have died of a mortification if she had not had these wounds.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. You said, if there had been a bruise on that part, in time it might have form'd itself into such an appearance of a wound, as you have been giving an account of; now, sir, which of those two wounds do you mean?</p>
               <p>Bliss. I mean the large one at the bottom of the Os Sacrum. It is a mere conjecture, if she had had either a bruise or bile there, and no bigger in size, by degrees it might have been stretch'd, by lying so long upon the part, it might have opened and stretched to the dimension we saw it. It came at each end to a point and nothing.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. Would it have appeared so clean?</p>
               <p>Bliss. It would, from my manner of mentioning it, because every day might add to the extension of it.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. The nurse says she clean'd it from the corruption.</p>
               <p>Bliss. No wound can be dry; and, I suppose, that is what the nurse refers to. I did not see it in that state.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person246">
                  Henry 
                  Giffard 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person246" type="surname" value="Giffard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person246" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>

               <p>Giffard. I never saw the deceased till I went there the night with Mr. Moody and Mr. Dibble.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was she then?</p>
               <p>Giffard. She was at Marybone,</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Giffard. I believe it was the 2d or 3d of October, the night before she died.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you hear her say of her illness?</p>
               <p>Giffard. After we had been in the room some little time, she was asked by one there, to whom she ow'd the cause of her present distress. She answer'd, Sutton, Sutton. She was asked, did he wound you? - He did. I think this was the night before her death.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think she was sensible of what she said?</p>
               <p>Giffard. I think she was. I can give a reason why I think she was. When we went into the room first, I believed, by her looks, and some odd words, that she might not. She was asked by Mr. Moody and Mr. Dibble, if she knew them; she said, no: the maid advised we should ask no more questions. When she recover'd, she looked at Mr. Moody, and said, I know you, your name is Moody. She look'd on Mr. Dibble, and said, I know you, your name is Dibble. She seemed concerned at seeing me; I told her the reason of my being there; she ask'd them to drink a glass of wine, and they refused it; she ask'd me also. She seemed to be wandering, but afterwards recovered herself. I think her discourse seem'd quite clear and connected; she had the questions ask'd, some twice over, and she always answered in the same words.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she talk of at your first going into the room?</p>
               <p>Giffard. She said she was going out of town, and said, my things are getting ready, and the coach was waiting for her.</p>
               <p>Q. How many minutes betwixt that, and saying, Sutton, Sutton?</p>
               <p>Giffard. I believe there might be 20 minutes difference.</p>
               <p>Q. If she was clear and concise in her discourse, w hat need to ask the question twice? Were they ask'd in the same words?</p>
               <p>Giffard. They were not ask'd in the same words, I suppose.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think she understood them?</p>
               <p>Giffard. By her answers I conceive she did.</p>
               <p>Q. Then I would be glad to know why the question was repeated?</p>
               <p>Giffard. That I can't say, I know I asked her but very few questions.</p>
               <p>Q. Which was most sensible, the person that ask'd the question, in different words, twice, or she that answered in the same words twice?</p>
               <p>Giffard. I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the questions relative to Mr. Sutton ask'd twice over?</p>
               <p>Giffard. That I can't say, I mean questions relative to what we went about; that is, a report had been brought that Mr. Moody and Mr. Davis * had been engaged with the gentleman that was supposed to have injured her; and he was desired that he should clear himself, and I was desired to go along with him.</p>
               <p>* Otherwise Dibble.</p>
               <p> Q. What sort of injury did you understand by that, before you went?</p>
               <p>Giffard. We had heard she was injured by being cut, that was the reason we went, and we had heard Mr. Dibble was charg'd with being by at the time.</p>
               <p>Counsel for crown. We shall rest it here.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250049"></xptr>Counsel for prisoner. Whether or no the prisoner need go into his defence?</p>
               <p>Court. There was part of the evidence Miss Young gave, who was with them at the bagnio the whole time they were there, and when they dined; and, when they returned she left her at the bagnio in the morning; Mr. Sutton was absent and gone to Sir William Fowler, at the Cardigan's-head, can you prove where he was afterwards?</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. After the time she left the bagnio, he never saw her from that hour. I have likewise to prove, that she was after this time in perfect health and spirits.</p>
               <p>Court. Declarations of the party are admitted to be evidence with regard to facts, how far that consists throughout with the whole evidence they have given, is another consideration; how far the jury shall think she was sensible at the time is another part of consideration; and also that of Miss Young, that was with them and saw nothing of that kind.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. I would not have it thought I decline going into his defence, which is a very full and a very clear one; we will prove after this time Mr. Sutton did not see her, that she came to this same place on the 5th or 6th of September, called for rum, we refused to supply her with it; she went to Bartholomew-fair; we will prove that in the bed where they lay at the bagnio there were no marks of blood, or any thing at all; we will then call the physician who attended the deceased, who will satisfy the court that these fores could not at all move or contribute to her death; then we shall call other able surgeons, who will give their opinion from what the doctor and apothecary say, that they were no wounds at all.</p>

               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I stand here accused, my lord, for a murder I am not only innocent of, but for a murder that in reality never happened.</p>
               <p>Notwithstanding which, my lord, the most iniquitous intrigues have been artfully formed, and the most poisonous libels industriously spread, by Mr. Holland, to create an universal belief, that the unhappy Miss Bell had been murdered, and that I was her murderer.</p>
               <p>The ears of mankind are ever open to novelty, the very suggestion of a murder forces a persuasion of its truth.</p>
               <p>I appeal to all that are present; is there an ear that has not heard those reports? or a mind that has not been infected by their poison?</p>
               <p>Thus, my lord, I have been most undeservedly censured without doors, tried and condemned unheard.</p>
               <p>But, conscious of my innocence, I have, under these circumstances, chearfully flown to this court, a court ever distinguish'd for its candour, and its justice for the protection of innocence.</p>
               <p>My acquaintance, my lord, with the unfortunate deceased was of a late date, and of a short continuance; and as to my having given her any wound, there is not in truth the least foundation for the pretence! I never received from her any provocation; the thoughts of such an horrid action never entered into my heart.</p>
               <p>Amidst the follies of my youth, my lord, cruelty or inhumanity were never any part of my character.</p>
               <p>On the 5th day of last September, the last day I ever saw her, the deceas'd went to Mrs. Parker's, in Spring-gardens, where she was taken ill, and from thence she was remov'd to Mrs. Knight's, at Marybone, where she continued till the time of her death.</p>
               <p>On the 27th it seems that Mr. Holland went to see her, and to that visit I owe all my misfortunes.</p>
               <p>Had I really been guilty of the barbarity suggested, and given her the wounds now laid to my charge, can your lordship, or the jury, conceive it possible, that the poor girl, suffering under those wounds, should never have made the least complaint till such time as she had seen Mr. Holland?</p>
               <p>But, it may be ask'd to what motive but justice can the conduct of Mr. Holland be ascribed?</p>
               <p>Had she really made these complaints to Mr. Holland, and Mr. Holland, from his credit of them, had immediately caused me to be apprehended for a murderer, and brought me to a public trial, innocent as I am, I should have applauded his conduct. Such a disinterested conduct could have arisen from no other motive but a real for public justice.</p>
               <p>But how different to such a conduct was the conduct of Mr. Holland!</p>
               <p>He has publish'd his libels; was the publication of those libels intended for public justice? After I had mov'd the court of King's-bench for an information, he obtained a warrant against me, and went to my uncle and shew'd it to him.</p>
               <p>Does a murderer deserve such compliments? Will his waiting on my uncle be ascrib'd to his zeal to bring me to justice?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250050"></xptr>To what other motive such the conduct of Mr. Holland may be ascribed, I shall leave to the opinion of mankind to determine. I shall now call my witnesses to prove my innocence, and rely upon that, and that only, for my acquittal.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. We will now prove Mr. Sutton never saw her after he left her at Haddock's-bagnio.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person247">
                  Alexander 
                  Sexton 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person247" type="surname" value="Sexton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person247" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Sexton. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Miss Bell, Miss Young, Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person248">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person248" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person248" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person248" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Mr. Sutton, being at Haddock's-bagnio, Charing-cross?</p>
               <p>Sexton. I did live there, but do not now. I remember them being there, and going away on a Friday morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect whether the gentlemen or ladies went away first?</p>
               <p>Sexton. That I cannot be positive of.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Sutton's returning to your bagnio after Miss Young was gone?</p>
               <p>Sexton. No, I do not remember that he did; I seldom was out of the house the time they were there.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any bad behaviour in Mr. Sutton, towards Miss Bell; I find they lay there night after night?</p>
               <p>Sexton. I never saw any bad behaviour in Mr. Sutton in my life time.</p>
               <p>Q. What was your business?</p>
               <p>Sexton. I was a waiter in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there on the Thursday night, when they pretend she received the stabs?</p>
               <p>Sexton. I was, and on the Friday morning too; they all had their suppers at our house; and on Friday they breakfasted together, I carried them brandy and milk (what they call doctors) to drink together.</p>
               <p>Q. Explain what you mean by doctors?</p>
               <p>Sexton. They generally, at five or six in the morning, would ring the bell for doctors.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any crying out at the time they were there of these women?</p>
               <p>Sexton. No, I did not the least in the world.</p>
               <p>Q. After Miss Young went away that morning, did ever Mr. Sutton come to your house to lie afterwards?</p>
               <p>Sexton. He never lay in our house after, but came in once to ask for Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person249">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person249" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person249" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he never was in Miss Bell's company after, She sent for me afterwards and said, Mr. Sutton had used her ill, I said, how; she said, you know Mr. Sutton, I have kept him company so long, and he never gave me a half-penny. She said thank God I can do without him, for I had a gentleman just row, that did not keep me company above two or three hours, and he gave me a couple of guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Sexton. This was that very Friday; Mrs. Parker heard this, and said, she has my lodging to pay for.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain to the day?</p>
               <p>Sexton. This was the very day she took leave of our house.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the month was this?</p>
               <p>Sexton. This was the fifth of September, the book will testify it, we keep a ledger; we enter the time going in, and coming out. They came in at ten at night, and if they have a bottle of wine, we set down wine to the fifth.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure Mr. Sutton was never at your house after this parting?</p>
               <p>Sexton. No, he never was to lie?</p>
               <p>Q. How did Miss Bell live?</p>
               <p>Sexton. She lived a very bad indifferent life, every moment calling for a dram; I said, my dear, you'll kill yourself; she said poison, give me poison, death I want, and death I'll have.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did she belong to, or keep company with?</p>
               <p>Sexton. This was a lady never belonging to Mr. Sutton, she was Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person250">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person250" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person250" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's lady at first; she came to Mr. Sutton, by a quarrel with Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person251">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person251" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person251" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Mr. Sutton, between them at the bagnio; all things were agreed at the tavern before they came there; it was the gentlemen between themselves quarrelling.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see Miss Bell at your house afterwards?</p>
               <p>Sexton. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you it in your book?</p>
               <p>Sexton. No, I have not; if she had had what she asked for, I had had her in my book, but I denied her a dram.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Sexton. This was on Friday or Saturday either the fifth or sixth, I am positive, and Mrs. Parker was with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make any complaint of her being used ill?</p>
               <p>Sexton. No, she made none in the world; she asked for a dram, and said, she should certainly die with a dram, for drams would certainly be the death of her. Mrs. Parker and she said they were going to Bartholomew-fair, and after they<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250051"></xptr> were gone, it was some hours before I saw them again. And after the fair was over, I saw them again, they came back again. Miss Bell told me they went into Mrs. Owen's, and Mrs. Parker said, Miss Bell had cost me, I do not know how much money. I said more bitch you to let her get in your debt.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where are you waiter?</p>
               <p>Sexton I wait at no tavern nor bagnio whatever.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your employment?</p>
               <p>Sexton. I have no employment but my own.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that?</p>
               <p>Sexton. I keep a publick house in the Strand, the White-horse and Crown, on this side Exeter-change.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it a tavern?</p>
               <p>Sexton. It is not a tavern; it is an alehouse; you may call it a tavern; we sell wine, brandy, rum, and all those things.</p>
               <p>Q. If you have your book here tell me the day of the week that those four people, Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person252">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person252" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person252" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. Sutton, and those two women, came to your house?</p>
               <p>Sexton. That I cannot tell you; Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person253">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person253" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person253" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had company at our house, before ever he was in Miss Bell's company.</p>
               <p>Q. How many nights did they lie there?</p>
               <p>Sexton. I cannot tell, three or four nights, I cannot be positive which. I dare say my book will make it appear by the drams, that they lay there three nights.</p>
               <p>Q. What quantity of drams?</p>
               <p>Sexton. Not a great quantity, the gentlemen drank but a very few, the most of their drink was milk and water.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person254">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Honyball 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person254" type="surname" value="Honyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person254" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person254" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             bringing any linnen for her mistress?</p>
               <p>Sexton. No, very possible I might be up stairs at the time, there are two a-bed, and two up.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you recollect whether Miss Young went away single, leaving Miss Bell behind her?</p>
               <p>Sexton. I do not remember that; how they went away I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. How comes it that you are so very precise and positive in your recollection, that Mr. Sutton did not come again there?</p>
               <p>Sexton. I am positive he came again, and asked for Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person255">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person255" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person255" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person255" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , but Miss Bell was not there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear of no sort of injury that she received?</p>
               <p>Sexton. No, I heard of none at all I was so confident in her, if she had received any, she would have told me.</p>
               <p>Q. Why so.</p>
               <p>Sexton. For she asked me ten thousand questions about business.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. The first day of Bartholomew-fair was on Thursday the fourth day of September.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person256">
                  Daniel 
                  Haviland 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person256" type="surname" value="Haviland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person256" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person256" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Haviland. I am a waiter at Haddock's bagnio, and was there when Miss Bell and Mr. Sutton came there.</p>
               <p>Q. When did they come first?</p>
               <p>Haviland. I cannot say when they came first, but I remember on the third of September, I cannot tell the day of the week, but I have got the book in my pocket; it was in the evening, we put them down on the third coming in, but we enter them down on the fourth in the bill to be paid; Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person257">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person257" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person257" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came first, and he desired me to shew him a room, I did so. He told me Mr. Sutton, Miss Young, and Miss Bell, were coming to him; soon after the other three came over to our house; he had bespoke a room; they supped, and lay there that night. Mr. Bliss came that night, he came just as supper was on table, and Sir William desired him to walk in, he came to speak with Sir William about business, and Sir William went out and talked with him, and then he desired him to come in, there were fish and fowl for supper; and during supper, Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person258">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person258" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person258" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             got up, and said, Miss Young says, that Miss Bell looks like a whore. Miss Bell got up in some little anger, and said, Miss Young, Why do you call me names? Mr. Sutton stood behind, and Sir William was aggravating Miss Bell. That came to nothing. They lay there that night, and breakfasted there the next morning, I believe about ten or eleven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they dine there?</p>
               <p>Haviland. No, they never dined there.</p>
               <p>Q. What time might they go away?</p>
               <p>Haviland. I believe they might go away just in the afternoon?</p>
               <p>Q. Did they come again that night?</p>
               <p>Haviland. I believe they did, it appears so by the book [ holding it in his hand.] They paid two shillings for glasses and chairs, that Miss<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250052"></xptr> Bell and Mr. Sutton came home in, they broke the glasses, - they lay there that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they breakfast there on the morning on the fifth?</p>
               <p>Haviland. They did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Sutton's going away?</p>
               <p>Haviland. I do not, nor Sir William's, nor Miss Young's neither.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any noise or disturbance in the middle of the night?</p>
               <p>Haviland. I did not, Miss Bell and Mrs. Parker came over to our house, Miss Bell lodged at Mrs. Parker's house; they said they were going to Bartholomew- fair, they came and asked for a dram, which was refused them.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see her afterwards?</p>
               <p>Haviland. I never see her afterwards?</p>
               <p>Q. Did she appear to be ill?</p>
               <p>Haviland. She appeared to be very well I thought.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make no complaint at all?</p>
               <p>Haviland. None at all.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Which of them went out first?</p>
               <p>Haviland. I cannot say who went first, or who was left behind.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing of any linnen being brought by 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person259">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Honyball 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person259" type="surname" value="Honyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person259" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Haviland. I do not, that might have been brought, there are several servants in the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Mr. Sutton's being at your house after that day?</p>
               <p>Haviland. I do not remember he ever was; but I will not be positive.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of any quarrelling that there was?</p>
               <p>Haviland. There were some words between Miss Bell and Miss Young at supper, but Mr. Sutton got up, and stopped it.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person260">
                  Mary 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person260" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person260" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person260" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Is this true, that you had words at supper?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Sir, I believe it is.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person261">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person261" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person261" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             say, you called Miss Bell whore?</p>
               <p>M. Young. Yes he did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610225-18-person262">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person262" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person262" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person262" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at Haddock's Bagnio in the month of September last?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Sir William Fowler, Miss Young, Miss Bell, and Mr. Sutton being there?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your employ there?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. It is my business to make the beds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make the beds every night Miss Bell lay there?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you perceive any marks of blood on the ground, on the bed, or any where in the room?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. No, I did not, nor on nothing belonging to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Sutton ever there after the last time they supped together there?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. I don't know that he was. I believe they parted on the Friday morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make that bed after the time they were there last?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. I did; there was no appearance of blood on the bed, or ground, or any thing at all.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Miss Bell lie there that Friday night?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. I believe she did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you mean she lay there till Saturday morning?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. The book will tell you when she lay there, I am no scholar.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she stay at the bagnio the night after Mr. Sutton went away?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. I cannot say that she did.</p>
               <p>Q. What day did they go away?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Honyball coming there?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. I never saw her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear of any linnen being brought there for Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>E. Jones. I heard there was some brought, but I don't know of it.</p>

               <p>Mary Ashmead sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. I live at Haddock's bagnio.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you in the month of September last?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember Sir William Fowler, and Mr. Sutton being there, with Miss. Young and Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear any disturbance there while they were there?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. No, never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your business about the beds?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250053"></xptr>M. Ashmead. No, I never go among them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember seeing Miss Bell and Mrs. Parker together?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that before, or after the time that Sir 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person263">
                  William 
                  Fowler 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person263" type="surname" value="Fowler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person263" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. Sutton, and they went away?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. That was after they went away; it was either on the Friday in the afternoon, or Saturday. Miss Bell came in, and asked how I did, and said she was going to Bartholomew-fair, and desired to have a dram to drink. I told her I had not the keys in my pocket, and could not let her have it, and she went away without it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her afterwards?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. No, not to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she appear to be in good health?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. She appeared quite in perfect health, as well as ever I saw her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she make any complaint to you?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. She never did.</p>
               <p>Q. When she went away, after Sir William and Mr. Sutton were gone before, did she then make any complaint to you?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. No, none at all.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether it was Friday or Saturday that she went to Bartholomew-fair?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether she ever lay at the bagnio after she went to Bartholomew-fair?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. She never did; for if she did, most certainly I should have seen her.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person264">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Honyball 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person264" type="surname" value="Honyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person264" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person264" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember her coming with clean linnen to her mistress?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember her taking any away?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. No, I do not; I sent the porter over for the clean linnen, and she brought it to the bar She was not admitted, we never let women in. I took the linnen, and it was carried up to Miss Bell. I am not certain whether I, or one of the other waiters, carried it up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Honyball take away the foul linnen at the time she brought the fresh linnen?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. I am not certain of that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the foul linnen before it was carried away?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. I never saw none of her foul linnen.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether her going to Bartholomew-fair was after the time Honyball brought this linnen?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. Yes, Sir.</p>
               <p>Court. When Honyball brought the linnen, was that in the morning, or had Miss Bell gone to-bed in her foul linnen?</p>
               <p>M. Ashmead. No, it was in the morning, she wanted it to put on.</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith sworn.</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I was the physician that attended this unfortunate lady, the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. When was you first called in?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. On the 27th of September, about 11 or 12 o'clock, I went over with Mr. Bliss.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You have been a physician I think many years?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I have been a physician 30 years.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition did you find Miss Bell?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I found her under a very dreadful fever.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a fever that affected her health?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. The first time that I saw her, she was under the influence of a delirium; I could not obtain an answer from her, when I spoke to her. I don't mean to say that it lasted all the time.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was this?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. It was the Saturday.</p>
               <p>Q. What other symptoms had she about her besides that?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. She complained at first of pain on the left side of her face. I asked what was the reason of that. She said, She did not know; but I supposed there might be some cold, or some swelling. I desired to look at it. Her head was turned aside, and I examined the part carefully. I found a little swelling, and a very little, just near the ear. Then I ordered her to be fomented, that is, the jaw, which was done; and the next day she recovered a little the use of her jaw, and could speak more freely than before.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she in such a condition as to be able to hold a conversation of her life?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I should esteem it impossible, she had in her mouth a very terrible thrush, a thick coat like leather, of a pale ash-colour; she could speak hardly at all. That sort of thrush is a dry sort, not at all aiding towards a recovery. It was with great difficulty she spoke at all.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you look upon that in your judgment as a symptom of?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I was my opinion, that unless that could be carried off, she must die mortified</p>
               <p>Q. Did you use such means as you thought would carry it off?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I did, as much as if she was my own sister.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make enquiry of her as physicians always do on first visiting their patients?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250054"></xptr>Dr. Smith. I did, I enquired of every thing proper for a physician to enquire into. She was in such a condition, she could not give me an account. I was obliged to take it from the bye-standers.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you attend her on the Sunday?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I did; I had on the Saturday observed the necessity of giving her a clyster. I spoke to Mr. Bliss, as that was necessary. He made answer, he had before directed one to be brought in the evening, if the physician might think it necessary. Then on the Sunday I came between 12 and one at noon.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you find her then?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I found her in a very ill state, but relieved in her temple by the fomentation that was used the day before.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing at that time said touching that clyster that you ordered the day before? What was become of that, or what was done?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I enquired whether the clyster had been administered. They told me no, that the nurse had tried so to do, but was hindered by some sores that were found there. I then asked what the sores were. The nurse said she did not understand what they were, but she had heard the patient was venereal. Then I desired there might be a view of the body, fearing there might be some irruptions about the part of that kind, and that should render it impracticable. The lady was put in such a position that I could have an inspection of them. I was called in out of the dining-room, into the bed chamber. Mr. Bliss and I went in together. I inspected the body. I found the part that the clyster was to be applied to, in very good order: but looking with care to see what could be the occasion, I discerned an opening, which appeared to me about an inch long; it was clean, and had fresh digested matter in it. The lips of the wound (if I must call it a wound) were even; the skin seemed as even, home to the edge; so that it did not appear to me like a wound given any length of time; for if that had been the case, the lips must have been swelled a good deal, and have had an inequality, and perhaps had scabs.</p>
               <p>Q. By a length of time do you think that wound could have been given from the 5th of September?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I could not think so.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you think it could have been a wound of a fortnight standing?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I don't apprehend it to have been more than five or six days.</p>
               <p>Q. What are the circumstances that lead you to think that?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. They told me they had been attended with a very bad smell three or four days, the beginning of that week, and it had ceased about a day or two before I came. The sight of this opening made me conclude that it was an abscess, or an effort of nature, to relieve itself by a discharge of that kind. It appears to me to be so, and not of any violence used upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it contrary to your judgment that that should be a wound given so long a time?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. It is wholly contrary to my judgment.</p>
               <p>Q. You will now permit me to ask you as to the other sore?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. When I first saw that, which was the same time I saw the other, it appeared to me like a bile. I looked at it with care, there was matter in it, but the skin was not broken to let the matter out.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether that could be a wound; but you must excuse me, because the jury and I are not of the faculty?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. Taking Mr. Bliss, at that time, to be a surgeon as well as an apothecary, I ordered it to be dressed with Linimentum Artzi. Perhaps I should have done the same thing for a wound inflicted; but I had no idea in myself that this was a wound so long ago, for the reason I have already told you.</p>
               <p>Q. Give me leave to ask you whether it is not very usual in these sort of fevers of the inflammatory putrid kind, for nature to throw out some thing of this sort that you have been describing in this case?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. In the inflammatory fever, which as the consequence is putrid after, does throw out symptoms of this kind; the thrush, and eruptions.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe in your judgment that the fever was the occasion of the eruptions, or the eruptions the occasion of the fever?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. The fever was certainly the occasion of the eruptions.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then the eruptions were not the occasion of the fever?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe that those eruptions moved at all towards the death of this unfortunate young lady, the deceased?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I cannot think so.</p>
               <p>Q. Would they not rather be of service to her?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I verily think they did produce some service to her; for it was very remarkable she could the next day speak better, answer better,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176102250055"></xptr> and in short appeared a good deal easier, and had a tolerably easy good night, and spoke better in her voice.</p>
               <p>Q. I have no more to ask you, only whether you are of opinion that these wounds killed the woman?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. I can't think that they had any influence upon her death at all.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How was her speech on the Sunday?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. She could hardly speak on the Sunday. She could not open her mouth to take any thing in, without the help of a spoon to hold down her jaw.</p>
               <p>Q. How much better was she than on the Saturday?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. She was better.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not this thrush the common consequence of a gangrene?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. No, that was long before the gangrene.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose a wound had been given on the 5th of September, do you say it could not have had that countenance on the 27th of September?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. In my judgment it could not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you find all patients in the condition she was in, as to the state of her body, the same as she in them parts?</p>
               <p>Dr. Smith. No, no.</p>
               <p>Mr. Stafford Crane sworn.</p>
               <p>Mr. Crane. I never saw the body of the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard the description given of those sores? I should be glad to know your opinion, whether, according to the description given, they could in any sort contribute to this woman's death; or whether they are such things that may may be supposed possible to have been occasioned by a wound given, or whether arising from a natural cause, and what may be the consequence of them?</p>
               <p>Mr. Crane. What the doctor has advanced is exactly my opinion, that they were rather salutary, than destructive to her: I agree entirely with the doctor.</p>
               <p>Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610225-18-person265">
                  Percival 
                  Pott 
               <interp inst="t17610225-18-person265" type="surname" value="Pott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person265" type="given" value="Percival"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Mr. Pott. I being so very near Dr. Smith (altho' he spoke low) I heard every word distinctly he said. I think his account of the deceased is agreeable to what I have seen numberless times; and I am very confident the account he has given is strictly true.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. I have got not less than 20 gentlemen of the first figure and fashion to give Mr. Sutton the character of a gentleman of humanity and compassion, incapable of doing the crime laid to his charge; if the jury think it material, I will call them.</p>
               <p>Jury. We think it not material, neither need his lordship take the trouble of summing up the evidence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610225-18-verdict94" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610225-18-verdict94" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>After which Mr. Sutton addressed the court as follows:</p>
               <p>My Lord, I am very much obliged to you for your great candour, and justice.</p>
               <p>His Lordship told him, The jury were his judges, and not he.</p>
               <p>After which Mr. Sutton addressed the jury in the same words.</p>
               <p>*** The preceding Trial is printed at large, and verbatim, as delivered by the witnesses for the crown and the prisoner, without the least alteration or abridgment in any part of it. This was thought necessary to be mentioned, for the information of the public.</p>
            </div1>
