<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640912-23">
               <interp inst="t17640912-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-23" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-23" type="date" value="17640912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-23-off126-c174" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-23-defend216 t17640912-23-off126 t17640912-23-verdict129"></join>
         
               <p>502. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-defend216" type="defendantName">
                  
                     John 
                     Jourdan 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640912-23-alias-1" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-23-defend216 t17640912-23-alias-1"></join>Farrel</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-defend216" type="surname" value="Jourdan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-defend216" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-defend216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17640912-23-off126" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-off126" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-off126" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing six silver table-spoons, value 3 l. two pair of iron buckles, value 4 d. seven guineas, and 10 l. in money, numbered, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640912-23-victim219" type="victimName">
                           Jefferey 
                           Knight 
                        <interp inst="t17640912-23-victim219" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-23-victim219" type="given" value="Jefferey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-23-victim219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-23-off126 t17640912-23-victim219"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said Jefferey
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640912-23-cd127" type="crimeDate">July 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-23-off126 t17640912-23-cd127"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-23-person220">
                  Anne 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person220" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person220" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person220" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person221">
                  Jefferey 
                  Knight 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person221" type="surname" value="Knight"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person221" type="given" value="Jefferey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and live in <placeName id="t17640912-23-crimeloc128">New North-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-23-crimeloc128" type="placeName" value="New North-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-23-crimeloc128" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-23-off126 t17640912-23-crimeloc128"></join>. On the 28th of July, I locked our bureau in the fore parlour, at about half an hour after ten o'clock in the morning; before I locked it, I took a guinea out of a purse that had several guineas in it: I had put them out of my hand, and a bank note; all which I left in the purse; one was a very remarkable crooked guinea: there were in the bureau half a dozen silver table spoons, and two pair of mourning buckles, made of iron: before twelve the same day, I found the bureau was shut, but the bolt of the lock was standing out, not locked: I missed the spoons, buckles, money, and bank note; (the note is not laid in the indictment); I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person222">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person222" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person222" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the 31st, and saw the prisoner there; he was charged with stealing the things-mentioned, but denied it, and said, he knew nothing of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-23-person223">
                  Anne 
                  Broughton 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person223" type="surname" value="Broughton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person223" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person223" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live facing Mr. Knight's house: I was in my parlour, and saw the young man, the prisoner at the bar; he crossed the way, and went into Mr. Knight's entry directly, without knocking at the door; I saw him four times; he went in twice, and out twice, which lead me to observe him particularly the last time I saw him come out. I saw him put something into his right hand coat-pocket: it seemed difficult to be got in.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Broughton. This was half an hour past eleven in the morning; I never stirred from my window from the time he came out, till Mrs. Knight's coming out, and saying she had been robbed, which was near a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. How could you remark me more than any other person?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120015"></xptr>Broughton. I saw both his face and his back part too; and I knew him again, the first time I saw him at Justice Fielding's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-23-person224">
                  John 
                  Bridges 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person224" type="surname" value="Bridges"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person224" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner several times go backwards and forwards up and down that street, between eleven and twelve o'clock that day: I heard him bid another young man go up on the other side of the way; they parted, and one went up one side, and the other on the other; I met him after that, coming down the street, next door to Mr. Knight's, with a paper of something, putting it in his pocket: he went off then, and I saw no more of him; this was about a quarter before twelve o'clock. I was going to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person225">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person225" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person225" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the same day, to give a description of him, and saw him at the end of Bow-street; I said to 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person226">
                  George 
                  Noy 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person226" type="surname" value="Noy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person226" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that was with me, that was the person I was going to describe, having heard of this robbery: we pursued him to Tavistock-street.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was you to him, when you first saw him?</p>
               <p>Bridges. I was within fifty yards of him, when I first saw him; we were at Sir John's door, and I saw him passing by the pastry-cook's; I believe he came from Drury-lane: the same person I had before seen with him, was then with him; we came up pretty near him: I left Mr. Noy to follow him, and went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person227">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person227" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person227" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to give an account of him, and get assistance: by the time I returned, they had taken him, and were bringing him along; he was searched at Sir John's; there were fifteen guineas found upon him, some other things, and a few papers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-23-person228">
                  George 
                  Noy 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person228" type="surname" value="Noy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person228" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is the man that I saw go into Mr. Knight's house, about a quarter before twelve that day, as near as I can remember; he had been up and down by my door several times, before I took notice of him. I saw him step light cross the way, and go in at the door, without knocking or scraping his feet, and I never went out of sight of the door, till he came out again.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was he in the house?</p>
               <p>Noy. He was not above ten minutes in the house; there were loose papers in his hands, which he was putting into his pocket; he walked very slowly down the street; I thought he observed that I took notice of him; he crossed over, and come towards me: I thought he was coming to use some ill language towards me, I went in, and he turned back, and went down Boswell-court. I believe I heard that Mr. Knight had been robbed not a quarter of an hour afterwards: I told Mrs. Knight I saw such a man go into the house, and described him in the best manner I could; then we went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person229">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person229" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person229" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, which was about two o'clock; then I saw him, with another person, standing at the pastry-cook's shop, facing the end of Bow-street; Bridges was with me; we went and saw plainly he was the man, and followed him: then he went to Bow-street for help, and I followed the prisoner to Tavistock-street; from thence, they went into Covent-garden, and up by the church; they turned the corner, into King-street, where were two soldiers: I said, if they would stop the fellow in the blue coat, (meaning the prisoner) I would give them half a crown apiece; they immediately ran before him, and stopped him, and brought him back to me. The prisoner asked me what business I had with him? I said, you must go to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person230">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person230" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person230" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a gentleman wants to speak with you there. He said, it was an impudent thing to go to stop him; they brought him a few yards, and then he cleared himself of both the soldiers, and ran as fast as he could, and the soldiers after him: I saw no more, till I saw Mr. Knight had him by the collar, at the end of Wild-street: when before the justice, I saw him searched, and they told me there were fifteen guineas found upon him; I saw several; there were other things found upon him, which I did not take particular notice of.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-23-person231">
                  Robert 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person231" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person231" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw Mr. Noy in pursuit of the prisoner; I also pursued him in Covent-garden; he ran up James-street, and turned into Hart-street; there he was catched, and got off again, under pretence that he was pursued by Bailiffs, and the mob let him go: after that, he went through a passage, and got into Great Wild-street; I catched him there; he told me, that he was pursued by bailiffs: the mob came up to me, and begged I would let him go; I really believed that was the case, and let him go: I had not let him go above half a minute, before Mr. Knight came and said he was the man that robbed him, and desired assistance: I then assisted him, and we carried him to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person232">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person232" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person232" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's; I took part of the money out of his pockets; there were fifteen guineas, some silver, and some half-pence taken out of his right hand breeches pocket, and some silver was in his left breeches pocket. I took a clasp knife, made into a saw, out of his pocket (producing it;) there was one guinea in particular, that Mr. Knight swore to (producing a large crooked-guinea, with dents in it); this is it; Mr. Knight gave a description of it, before he saw it.</p>
               <p>Q. Does it correspond with his description?</p>
               <p>Parker. It does, exactly. (The guinea inspected by the court and jury.)</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120016"></xptr>Q. from Prisoner. Whether I had not seventeen guineas, and you pocketed two for yourself?</p>
               <p>Parker. All the money I found, was produced before the justice; I saw but fifteen guineas, some silver, and a few half-pence. I took none to myself.</p>
               <p>Mr. Knight. There were two purses in the drawer in the bureau; in one of them was a bank note, and this crooked guinea; there were between seven and nine guineas: in the other purse, there was a 36 s. piece, and to the value of twelve or thirteen guineas. It was money left in my hands, for a person's father that was in my house. I had heard of the robbery, and was going to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person233">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person233" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person233" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to give an account of what I had lost, by appointment of Mr. Noy and Mr. Bridges: going up the passage, between Wild-street and Drury-lane, I saw some people running, and asked what was the matter? they said, there was a thief. Before I could get cross the way, into Drury-lane, I called, Stop thief, knowing I had been robbed; by the time I could get into Wild-street, the prisoner was loose again, going towards the Devil's-gap; there I catched him, and told him, he had robbed me, and carried him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person234">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person234" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person234" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : before he was searched, I described a crooked guinea, with particular dents in it; it had been in that purse a considerable time, and sometime without a companion. If it was alone, I have desired my wife never to touch it; I have seen it a great many times; I saw the money taken out of the prisoner's pockets: all the money that I saw taken out, was put into Mr. Parker's hat; the very first glance I had of this crooked guinea, I knew it; I said, there is the guinea; there were fifteen guineas taken out of his pockets: the prisoner was eating something, and as there was a bank note of 20 l. lost, I thought he was eating that: I asked him if he was not eating it, and looked into his mouth; there was something white in his mouth: this was on the Saturday, and on the Monday following, I found the spoons in King-street, Seven-dials. I went to enquire whether the advertisement had taken any effect in the city, and I came to Justice Fielding's; there was the prisoner brought up again, and was then dressed in a light suit of cloaths: I had intelligence where them cloaths came from, but I cannot say by whom: I went there with the constable and a search-warrant, and found my spoons and buckles: (produced and deposed to): they were found in a one pair of stairs room.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-23-person235">
                  William 
                  Povey 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person235" type="surname" value="Povey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person235" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went with Mr. Knight, on Monday the 30th of July, to King-street, Seven-Dials, to the house of Mr. Archer, a taylor; there I found a little bairy trunk, in which I found these spoons and buckles: the people of the house told me the prisoner used to be in and out there. Here are two pick-lock keys; (Produced in court.) these were delivered to me.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. These were brought to us at the Justices, picked up by some body. I can't tell who, supposed to be flung out of his pocket when taken.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-23-person236">
                  Alice 
                  Archer 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person236" type="surname" value="Archer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person236" type="given" value="Alice"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person236" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person237">
                  Richard 
                  Archer 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person237" type="surname" value="Archer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person237" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a taylor; we live in King-street, Seven Dials; the prisoner used to come backwards and forwards to a lodger of ours, for about three weeks before he was in custody; he did not lodge at our house, as I know of; the woman's husband goes for a clerk in the city; I believe her husband and the prisoner have been acquainted.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. That woman used to wash for me; I never spoke three words to her husband.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-23-person238">
                  Martha 
                  Mark 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person238" type="surname" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person238" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person238" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I can say no more than the last witness; I particularly know the prisoner's face, seeing him go in and out at Mr. Archer's.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Mark. I am a lodger in Mr. Archer's house.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since you first saw the prisoner come there?</p>
               <p>M. Mark. I believe it was about three weeks before he was taken up; it may be a day or two longer.</p>
               <p>Q. When was the last time you saw him there?</p>
               <p>M. Mark. I saw him go up there the morning he was taken.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the Morning?</p>
               <p>M. Mark. It was after 11 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have only bee n three Weeks in London. I was recommended to that woman to wash for me, by one Glascow; she asked me to breakfast once or twice; that is all I know about her. I had proof enough before Sir 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person239">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person239" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person239" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person239" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to prove where I had this money; but Sir John and these men frighted every body, so that they, will not come near me; and I being a stranger in London, no one will come to me. My father died and left me forty guineas; I had twenty-three of them when I came to London; I bought some clothes, but since I have been in trouble, the people have run away with them; I have a young fellow, named 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person240">
                  Mark 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person240" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person240" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , that can prove how I had this money. I was born in Munster, in Ireland.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120017"></xptr>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-23-person241">
                  Mark 
                  Howard 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person241" type="surname" value="Howard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person241" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew the prisoner before I came to London.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been in London?</p>
               <p>Howard. I don't know. I met him one day; he said he had not got work; he bid me come, and he would give me a pot of beer; so I brought him with me, and he pulled out of his pocket a handful of silver and gold; I don't know how much; he told me his father was dead, and he was just come over to get work here. I knew him in Dublin in his apprenticeship: he is a shoemaker; I was an apprentice at the same time.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you seen him before he was taken up?</p>
               <p>Howard. To the best of my opinion, it was about three weeks before.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you first see him in London?</p>
               <p>Howard. It was in a house in White-cross-street, where I work.</p>
               <p>Q. to Bridges. Is this the man you saw walking up and down in New North-street?</p>
               <p>Bridges. No, it is not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Howard. When did you leave Dublin?</p>

               <p>Howard. I left it the 18th of May last; he behaved as well as any boy could do; he has a good character; his father always supplied him with money; he told me he supplied him with half a crown a week for pocket money.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he lodge in this town?</p>
               <p>Howard. He lodged in a little court that leads up into the Strand.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you ever with him at Archer's in King's street?</p>
               <p>Howard. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640912-23-verdict129" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-verdict129" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640912-23-punish130" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-punish130" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-23-defend216 t17640912-23-punish130"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There was another indictment against him, for stealing a large quantity of valuable goods, the property of 
               <persName id="t17640912-23-person242">
                  William 
                  Langdon 
               <interp inst="t17640912-23-person242" type="surname" value="Langdon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person242" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-23-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; in his dwelling house.</p>
            </div1>
