<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-58">
               <interp inst="t17661217-58" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-58" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-58" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-58" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-58-off301-c494" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-58-defend624 t17661217-58-off301 t17661217-58-verdict304"></join>
         
               <p>72. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-58-defend624" type="defendantName">
                     Francis 
                     Unwin 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-58-defend624" type="surname" value="Unwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-defend624" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-defend624" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661217-58-off301" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-off301" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-off301" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a gold watch chain, value 40 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-58-victim626" type="victimName">
                     George 
                     Lookup 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-58-victim626" type="surname" value="Lookup"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-victim626" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-victim626" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-58-off301 t17661217-58-victim626"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17661217-58-viclabel302" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-58-victim626 t17661217-58-viclabel302"></join>; <rs id="t17661217-58-cd303" type="crimeDate">Nov. 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-58-off301 t17661217-58-cd303"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-58-person627">
                  George 
                  Lookup 
               <interp inst="t17661217-58-person627" type="surname" value="Lookup"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person627" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person627" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On my Lord-Mayor's day I was at the corner of King-street, Cheapside; the procession was coming from Guildhall; finding I could not get forward, I turned back; a man pressed me, and asked me where I was going; I said I wanted to go forward: I was going to Coleman-street, and before I got there, I put my hand in my hand in my pocket, and missed my watch (a gold one;) I was a little in doubt whether I had not left it at home; when I went home, I found it was not there; I went, and gave a description of it to Sir 
               <persName id="t17661217-58-person628">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17661217-58-person628" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person628" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person628" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he published an advertisement to pawnbrokers and silversmiths; I lost it on the Monday, and this was on the Friday following, Mr. Jarvis called upon me, and said, he had a chain like mine left at his house to be sold; I looked at it, and said, it was part of my chain; (when it was lost, there was a very remarkable key and four seals to it) I took out a warrant against the man that had left it with him, which was the prisoner at the bar, and a search-warrant; he was to return to Mr. Jarvis's house for the money for the chain; Sir 
               <persName id="t17661217-58-person629">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17661217-58-person629" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person629" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person629" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             proposed, my waiting till he came there for the money; but I was for being at the searching the prisoner's house, and accordingly I sent for some of Sir John's people and a constable, and went to his house, which is beyond the turnpike at Whitechapel; one of the people came and told me, they had taken him in bed; I ordered they should not search the house till I came; I went, and we searched with great circumspection, and found nothing; the prisoner was carried to prison, and on the Monday before Sir 
               <persName id="t17661217-58-person630">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17661217-58-person630" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person630" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person630" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Nothing passed on the examination; all he said was, he found the chain among some of his wife's trinkets; the middle piece that held the whole together was very remarkable, but that is not to be found; indeed, the whole that is here produced is very remarkable, but I do not chuse to swear to it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-58-person631">
                  Thomas 
                  Jarvis 
               <interp inst="t17661217-58-person631" type="surname" value="Jarvis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person631" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person631" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a goldsmith in Whitechapel; this chain (producing it) was brought to my shop by the prisoner at the bar; he had been at my shop twice before; the first time was about six months ago; then he brought a shank of a gold seal, the stone was taken out: then he was a perfect stranger; I bought it; he brought two more about a month afterwards, them I bought. I began not to like him, and was determined not to buy any more of him. About four months after he brought<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170051"></xptr> me this chain to sell for old gold; I wondered to see such a costly chain so mangled, and to be sold as old gold; I said I should not buy it, except an assay was made of it, as there always is solder in such things; by this I was in hopes he would go away; he said he would leave it with me, and asked how long it would be before an assay could be made; I said about three or four days: he left it; I ruminated upon it some time; in the mean time a friend came in, before whom I laid these circumstances which I have here mentioned, and remembering a notice of Sir 
               <persName id="t17661217-58-person632">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17661217-58-person632" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person632" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person632" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, that there was a watch with a chain of three rows of gold lost, I went to my file where I put these things and saw it; my friend's advice was to write a letter to Sir John; I being going that way that evening, I thought proper to call myself. When I came there Sir John was not at home; his clerk recommended me to the gentleman's lodgings that had lost the watch; I went there, and the gentleman came the next morning to see the chain; he saw it, and said he did not chuse to swear to it, but he could lay an hundred pounds to one it was his chain: my servant went with the gentleman to Sir 
               <persName id="t17661217-58-person633">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17661217-58-person633" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person633" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person633" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's; I had taken a memorandum of the prisoner's name, but not the place of abode; but describing the prisoner to my friend, my servant said, one of Sir John's people said, by the description he believed it was Unwin; the result was to issue two warrants, one to search his house. The next morning Mr. Lookup came to me very early; I went with him and one of Sir John's people; when we came there, Sir John's man asked me if that was the man; (meaning the prisoner) I said, yes; then he secured him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When I came to the silversmith's house, I told him I had a chain to dispose of, and desired him to look at it; he said he thought there was some solder in it, and he could not rightly tell the value of it; said he, I can make an assay of it; you may call in three or four days, and I can let you know what it is worth, call about Tuesday or Wednesday; I told him what it weighed; he set it down in his book, and asked me what my name was; I told him; when I came before Sir John, I asked in particular whether they could swear to the chain; it was among my wife's trinkets, I had had it fourteen or fifteen months; said Mr. Lookup, it looks like mine; I said it was my property.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-58-person634">
                  John 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17661217-58-person634" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person634" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person634" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a dyer, I live behind St. Luke's church; I have known the prisoner about year and a half; he has been a seafaring man, and he trades with the East India shipping when they come in; he lives by Mile-end turnpike: I never heard any thing amiss of him; I have seen him frequently at his sister's, who keeps a public-house</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-58-person635">
                  Richard 
                  Pike 
               <interp inst="t17661217-58-person635" type="surname" value="Pike"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person635" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person635" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a Gent.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that?</p>
               <p>Pike. I am a clerk to the South Sea company now; I have known the prisoner a year and a half; I know no farther of him than that his sister keeps a public-house in our neighbourhood, and I have seen him there many a time; he always behaved in a very complaisant manner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-58-person636">
                  Thomas 
                  Dean 
               <interp inst="t17661217-58-person636" type="surname" value="Dean"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person636" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-person636" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him two or three years; I never heard any thing amiss of him.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661217-58-verdict304" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-58-verdict304" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
