<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17641212-64">
               <interp inst="t17641212-64" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-64" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-64" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17641212"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-64" type="date" value="17641212"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641212-64-off336-c412" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-64-defend540 t17641212-64-off336 t17641212-64-verdict340"></join>
         
               <p>70. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17641212-64-defend540" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Watkins 
                  <interp inst="t17641212-64-defend540" type="surname" value="Watkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-64-defend540" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-64-defend540" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17641212-64-off336" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-64-off336" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-64-off336" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that he, together with 
                     <persName id="t17641212-64-person541">
                        William 
                        Nesbit 
                     <interp inst="t17641212-64-person541" type="surname" value="Nesbit"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-64-person541" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-64-person541" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   (not taken) on the <rs id="t17641212-64-cd337" type="crimeDate">19th of October</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-64-off336 t17641212-64-cd337"></join>, about the hour of two in the night of the same day, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17641212-64-victim543" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           Warner 
                        <interp inst="t17641212-64-victim543" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-64-victim543" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-64-victim543" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-64-off336 t17641212-64-victim543"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did break and enter, and stealing one brass pottage-pot, value 6 s. one copper-tea-kettle, value 2 s. one brass water-cock, value 6 d. two pewter dishes, value 1 s. and two pewter plates, value 12 d. the property of the said Charles, in his dwelling-house
            </rs>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-64-person544">
                  Charles 
                  Warner 
               <interp inst="t17641212-64-person544" type="surname" value="Warner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-64-person544" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-64-person544" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did live in <placeName id="t17641212-64-crimeloc338">Beech-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-64-crimeloc338" type="placeName" value="Beech-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-64-crimeloc338" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-64-off336 t17641212-64-crimeloc338"></join>, when my house was robbed; I don't now. I am a <rs id="t17641212-64-viclabel339" type="occupation">brass-turner</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-64-victim543 t17641212-64-viclabel339"></join> by trade. I went to bed last, on the 18th of October, and fastened the door to the street, the back door, and made all fast, and went to bed about eleven.</p>
               <p>Q. What family have you?</p>
               <p>Warner. I have a wife, a maid-servant, and two children. On the 19th, I found my house broke open; they came over the water-tub, and then to the kitchen door, in the yard; that I fastened myself, with a padlock; I found the farther yard door open, and I found this knife (producing a case knife) It is not mine, and a large sauce-pan, on the outside of the yard door; the sauce-pan is my property (I did not lay that in the indictment): I then found my kitchen door open, and missed several things; the padlock was gone: I missed two large pewter dishes, several pewter plates, a pottage-pot, a tea-kettle, and a brass cock: I immediately suspected the prisoner; I have known him two years; he had worked with me as a journeyman; he worked with me the week before; we had had some words, and we parted: I did my best to find him out, and found him in Playhouse-yard, White-cross-street, that afternoon: he was within a few yards of Nesbit's mother's (that is an accomplice we have not taken): I followed the prisoner into 'Nesbit's mother's house; there was the prisoner's mother, who was telling him I had been after him three or four times that morning: he said, he could not think what I wanted with him (this I heard as I was at his back): I told him, if he would go along with me, I would tell him, for I had something particular to say to him, and to Nesbit too (they were both together). Nesbit said, he could not think what I wanted with him; they said they would go with me any where, where I chose: I said, to my own house: the prisoner and his mother went with me very quietly; Nesbit said he would follow, but did not. When I came home, I said, Watkins, I have great reason to believe you have robbed my house; I shall send for a constable  and take you up on suspicion, for none but you could do it: he said, if I would go into a private room, he would tell me what was done with the things; that he had neither sold nor pawned them, and that they were lodged in the second or third alley beyond the Roebuck, in Turnmill-street, Cow-cross. I charged a constable with him, and sent him to the Compter; he owned to the taking the things; he said he took the brass cock out of the water-tub, and stuffed a bit of paper in, that the water should not run out: he said the knife was Nesbit's, and that he (Nesbit) broke the padlock of the kitchen-door. I said it must be somebody that knew the door, that could do it; that part of the latch was off, and by putting his finger into a hole, he might lift it up, which people could not know but such as were in the house. I went immediately to search for my goods in that lost; there I found nothing but a flat tin candlestick, and the iron bail of the pot, with which it is lifted on and off the fire: the room below, was a lodging-room, where Nesbit lodged with a woman: while I was looking about the lost, the people below fastened the door, and went out; I came away. When we came before my Lord Mayor, on the Saturday morning, the prisoner told me he had sold the pot, tea-kettle, and brass cock, to Mr. Andrews, in Long-lane: my Lord put it off for that night, and ordered me to come again on the Monday. On the Monday morning, I got a search-warrant, and went to Nesbit's room, where I found two pewter dishes, and two plates (produced and deposed to); they were brought before my Lord Mayor, and he bound me over to prosecute. I went to Mr. Andrews, and he told me he had bought the pot, tea-kettle, and cock of the prisoner at the bar; the pot and kettle were knocked to pieces; there were no marks upon them; the brass cock I can swear to; I had bought it but a few days before, and put it in the tub: (produced and deposed to).</p>

               <p>Mr. Andrews. I live in Long-lane, and keep a founder's shop; I buy old brass and copper; the prisoner's father did keep the same sort of a shop as I do, in Barbican: he brought the pottage-pot, tea-kettle, and brass cock to me, about 10 or 11 o'clock on the Friday; the other man came with him, but I did not know him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a handle to the pot?</p>
               <p>Andrews. No, there was not: the pot and tea-kettle were knocked and bruised about, and broke in several pieces; the cock was as it is now. I asked the prisoner how he came by them? he said<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176412120045"></xptr> his mother gave him them to sell, to buy some tools; that he and another had taken a shop, in Playhouse-yard, Whitecross-street, and this man that came with him, was his partner: I gave him 8 d. a pound for the brass, 9 d. for the copper, and 6 d. for the cock: the pot weighed 6 pounds, the tea-kettle two pounds, and the cock weighed just a pound: the prisoner bought a file of me.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Which brought it in?</p>
               <p>Andrews. I can't say which did; they came both together: I was in the kitchen, and they laid it down on the counter.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I paid Nesbit's mother half a crown for tools; I had some work that was in a hurry, and was going to Mr. Andrews's house, to buy a file. I met with Nesbit, and asked him where he was going? he said, to sell this old metal at Andrews's; we went together, and sold it: coming along, he said, I have got some other things; I said, where did you get them? said he, what is that to you. When the prosecutor challenged me with the things, I gave him the best information I could, where they were, and where Nesbit might be found. I never was with him in the house, nor no way concerned with him whatsoever.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17641212-64-verdict340" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-64-verdict340" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17641212-64-punish341" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-64-punish341" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-64-defend540 t17641212-64-punish341"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
