<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680907-7">
               <interp inst="t17680907-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680907-7" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680907-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680907"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680907-7" type="date" value="17680907"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680907-7-off32-c66" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680907-7-defend79 t17680907-7-off32 t17680907-7-verdict36"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680907-7-off32-c67" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680907-7-defend81 t17680907-7-off32 t17680907-7-verdict36"></join>
         
               <p>502, 503. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-defend79" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Walldock 
                  <interp inst="t17680907-7-defend79" type="surname" value="Walldock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-defend79" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-defend79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-defend81" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Dollanson 
                  <interp inst="t17680907-7-defend81" type="surname" value="Dollanson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-defend81" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-defend81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted <rs id="t17680907-7-off32" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-off32" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-off32" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               (together with 
                     <persName id="t17680907-7-person82">
                        John 
                        Coward 
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person82" type="surname" value="Coward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680907-7-person82" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680907-7-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17680907-7-person83">
                        John 
                        Richardson 
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person83" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680907-7-person83" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680907-7-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not taken) for burglariously breaking and entering the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680907-7-victim85" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Perry 
                        <interp inst="t17680907-7-victim85" type="surname" value="Perry"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680907-7-victim85" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680907-7-victim85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680907-7-off32 t17680907-7-victim85"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , on the <rs id="t17680907-7-cd33" type="crimeDate">13th of July</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680907-7-off32 t17680907-7-cd33"></join>, about the hour of two in the night, and stealing 10 s. in silver, 10 s. in halfpence, and four china punch-bowls, value 10 s. the property of the said John, in his dwelling-house
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-person86">
                  John 
                  Perry 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person86" type="surname" value="Perry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person86" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I <rs id="t17680907-7-viclabel34" type="occupation">keep <placeName id="t17680907-7-crimeloc35">the George alehouse at Islington</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-crimeloc35" type="placeName" value="the George alehouse at Islington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-crimeloc35" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680907-7-off32 t17680907-7-crimeloc35"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680907-7-victim85 t17680907-7-viclabel34"></join>. On the 13th of July I got up about three in the morning (as I generally do,) I found my house was broke open, which was done between twelve and three; I missed my till out of the bar; I looked at the outward door and found that fast; I went to the window-shutters, they were put to, but upon putting my hand to them they flew open; I found the iron bolt lying under the window on the inside; I missed my halfpence and silver that were in the till, about 10 s. of each; I missed eleven china bowls, my books, part of a quartern loaf, and a bottle of brandy. The watchman brought me seven of my china bowls in the morning about break of day; he brought also my two till drawers empty; Dollanson was taken the second night after.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-person87">
                  Edward 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person87" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person87" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I never saw the two prisoners above twice before that night in my life. They, Coward, Richardson, and I, went to the house of Mr. Perry; one of them that is not taken forced the window-shutter open and got into the house, he brought out 7 punch-bowls and halfpence, (I never knew of the silver.) he gave them to me; I set the bowls under the bench, then he brought four more and gave them to me, then he brought some bread and a bottle of brandy, and some books and writings; then we went to the sign of the Light Horseman at the corner of Swan-alley, it was then just day-light, there we divided the halfpence, we had each 18 d. I was taken about a week or nine days after.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-person88">
                  Aaron 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person88" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person88" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I met the two prisoners and Richardson, one that is not taken, and the evidence, in Duke's-place, about nine weeks ago; Walldock had a handkerchief with four china bowls in it; Richardson came up to me and said, do you know any body that will buy some china bowls, saying he had just been on board an Indiaman at Blackwall and had bought them; I told him I did not understand them, but would help him to a man that might buy them; I took them to Houndsditch to 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person89">
                  Moses 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person89" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person89" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             my brother; they shewed him two large and two small ones; he bought them for 6 s. 6 d. the money was given into Richardson's hands; then they went away. About a day or two after I went into Red Lion-street, a man there said, I want to ask you a question; there are some people taken up about a robbery at Islington, can you give any account about any bowls that were sold; I went and got one of a woman that had bought one of my brother, he had sold two to two women, and the two small ones he had sold to a publican in Duke's-place, the sign of the Black Boy; the people were taken before Sir 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person90">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person90" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person90" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person90" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; they denied it, and said they had bought none; I can partly swear to one of the bowls, it was broke on the edge, (such a one produced,) I had it in my hand some time, and can easily know it again; I told the people at the time it was damaged.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoners before?</p>
               <p>Spencer. No, I never saw neither of them before, I knew Richardson before.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the two prisoners are the persons that were with Richardson?</p>
               <p>Spencer. I am sure they are, I was with them above twenty minutes; I was before Sir 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person91">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person91" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person91" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person91" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             when Dollanson was there first; he was then acquitted, but he was taken up again about a week after, and committed by Sir John.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-person92">
                  Isaac 
                  Elias 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person92" type="surname" value="Elias"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person92" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person92" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The two prisoners at the bar came to me where I was drinking at a public-house on Saffron-hill, the sign of the Ham; they asked me if I would buy any punch bowls; there was 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person93">
                  Anne 
                  Price 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person93" type="surname" value="Price"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person93" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person93" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and another with them. (See Price an evidence against 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person94">
                  Mary 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person94" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person94" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person94" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person95">
                  Anne 
                  Darlin 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person95" type="surname" value="Darlin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person95" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person95" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , No 316, 317, which were the two women tried with Dollanson by the names of 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person96">
                  Mary 
                  Anthony 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person96" type="surname" value="Anthony"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person96" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person96" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person97">
                  Anne 
                  Claxton 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person97" type="surname" value="Claxton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person97" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person97" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , No 128, 129, all in this Mayoralty.)</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176809070006"></xptr>Elias. This was the day after the robbery, as I heard afterwards; I said I could not look at them here, let me take them to another house; I took particular notice of the bowls, there were four of them; I carried them to the Swan in Field-lane, and examined them by myself; then I went back to them and told them I could not give the price they asked, they asked 10 s. for them, I offered them 6; I left the bowls with them, and went and told Sir 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person98">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person98" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person98" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person98" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             of the bowls; he said, why did not I stop the bowls; I said, because there were so many of them I was afraid; I heard no more of the bowls till 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person99">
                  Aaron 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person99" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person99" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             told me where one of them was sold, and I went to the house and got it, (produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. Where is 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person100">
                  Moses 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person100" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person100" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person100" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Elias. He is in Newgate.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is the woman that bought the bowl?</p>
               <p>Elias. She is not here; that woman said she bought another bowl of 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person101">
                  Moses 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person101" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person101" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and delivered it to me, (produced in court,) I can swear to both of them again; one of them has a pea-hen upon it, and like a drop of blood on the inside; the prisoners offered both these to me, (the two bowls deposed to by the prosecutor.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-person102">
                  Richard 
                  Good 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person102" type="surname" value="Good"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person102" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watchman; I was going by Mr. Perry's window the night of the robbery between twelve and one o'clock; there came a man to me and asked me to let him light his pipe by my lanthorn; he asked me if any body was up; I said they were at the Angel; said he, will you drink part of a mug of beer; there came another man up at the time he was lighting his pipe; they went to the Angel, I went with them *; they called for a pot of beer, I staid and drank once with them, and then went about my business; when I came to the Pied Bull bench I saw something under the bench, I thought it had been a cat; I went to look, and found seven china bowls there; I took and carried them to my apartment, this might be about two o'clock, and about three I went round again, and found a great white drawer, I carried that home; as soon as I came back again I met a woman going a milking, she had found another drawer, I took and carried that home; when Mr. Perry gets up, which is generally about three, I usually go in for a dram or a pennyworth of beer; I went in that morning, and found he had been robbed of the bowls and drawers.</p>

               <p>* This should be a caution to watchmen not to neglect their duty, to go to drink with strangers at that time of the night.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any knowledge of the men that took you in to drink?</p>
               <p>Good. I think he that asked me to drink, by his face and his wig was Dollanson, the other had a darkish coat on, and looked something like a smith.</p>
               <p>Walldock's defence.</p>
               <p>I desire the man in the goal may be brought out, and asked whether I sold him the bowls.</p>
               <p>Dollanson's defence.</p>
               <p>I was brought before Sir 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person103">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person103" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person103" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             five times; the last time Sir John made it his business to clear me; I get my living by going a portering, and when I have no business of that sort I work with my father.</p>
               <p>For the prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-person104">
                  Moses 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person104" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person104" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew nothing of the prisoners before I saw them in goal; I bought some bowls, but not of them, there were four or five, I gave 5 s. 6 d. for them.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a man did you buy them of?</p>
               <p>Spencer. Of a little fellow, I never had any dealings with him before.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you buy them?</p>
               <p>Spencer. In Houndsditch in my own room.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there only one man?</p>
               <p>Spencer. There were three of them together, I never saw any of them before.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you brother to 
               <persName id="t17680907-7-person105">
                  Aaron 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person105" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person105" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Spencer. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he along with you at the time?</p>
               <p>Spencer. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with the bowls?</p>
               <p>Spencer. I sold them in Duke's-place; the two small ones I sold to a woman that keeps the Black Boy alehouse, the others I sold to a young woman, I really do not know her name, her mother lives in Duke's-place.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you know the bowls again?</p>
               <p>Spencer. I cannot say whether I should or not, for I did not take notice of them.</p>
               <p>Court. Your brother says the two prisoners were the persons that sold them.</p>
               <p>Spencer. I can't take upon me to say whether they were or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you undertake to say they were not the people?</p>
               <p>Spencer. I am positive sure they were not the people.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-person106">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Cavenban 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person106" type="surname" value="Cavenban"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person106" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person106" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Walldock gets his living by working with a baker.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does the baker live, or what is his name?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176809070007"></xptr>E. Cavenban. I do not know where, or with who.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-person107">
                  Mary 
                  Robinson 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person107" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person107" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person107" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My mother knew Walldock when he was a child, I never knew any harm of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does he work?</p>
               <p>M. Robinson. I do not know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-person108">
                  Mary 
                  Anderson 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person108" type="surname" value="Anderson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person108" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Walldock a long time.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him last?</p>
               <p>M. Anderson. I don't know that I have seen him for eight months, he was somewhere in the country, I believe in Ireland; I never heard no harm of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-person109">
                  Mary 
                  Woodcock 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person109" type="surname" value="Woodcock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person109" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person109" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Dollanson worked for me, he has a very honest character; I keep Fleet-market, he has carried my things backwards and forwards, I never found any thing amiss by him, he lived at his father's in the neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680907-7-person110">
                  Thomas 
                  Dollanson 
               <interp inst="t17680907-7-person110" type="surname" value="Dollanson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person110" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am his father, I am a lapidary and glass-man; my son has been at sea, he behaved very well since he came home, he gets his bread by working for me, and sometimes by portering.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17680907-7-verdict36" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-verdict36" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680907-7-punish37" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680907-7-punish37" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680907-7-defend79 t17680907-7-punish37"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680907-7-defend81 t17680907-7-punish37"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There was another indictment against them for a burglary.</p>
            </div1>
