<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620421-20">
               <interp inst="t17620421-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-20" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620421"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-20" type="date" value="17620421"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620421-20-off104-c175" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-20-defend205 t17620421-20-off104 t17620421-20-verdict108"></join>
         
               <p>135. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-defend205" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Morgan 
                  <interp inst="t17620421-20-defend205" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-defend205" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-defend205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17620421-20-off104" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-off104" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-off104" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he on the king's highway on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17620421-20-victim207" type="victimName">
                           Zachariah 
                           Stevens 
                        <interp inst="t17620421-20-victim207" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-20-victim207" type="given" value="Zachariah"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-20-victim207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-20-off104 t17620421-20-victim207"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life; and taking from his person one half guinea and three shillings in money numbered, his property, and against his will
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17620421-20-cd105" type="crimeDate">March 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-20-off104 t17620421-20-cd105"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>Zachariah Stevens. On Friday the 2d of March last, Mr. Wogin and I set out in a post chaise from <placeName id="t17620421-20-crimeloc106">Princes-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-20-crimeloc106" type="placeName" value="Princes-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-20-crimeloc106" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-20-off104 t17620421-20-crimeloc106"></join>, in order to go to <placeName id="t17620421-20-crimeloc107">Ealing</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-20-crimeloc107" type="placeName" value="Ealing"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-20-crimeloc107" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-20-off104 t17620421-20-crimeloc107"></join> that evening. When we were about four miles upon the road about 20 minutes before seven, a man rode very swiftly by us; he crossed the head of the horses, and turning round again to Mr. Wogin's side, he presented a pistol. Mr. Wogin desired him to put the pistol aside; and said, Sir, if you must have it, here is my purse. The man took it, and said, you have more, Sir? - I have no more upon my honour. - Sir, you have more (swearing) I know you have more. I will not be imposed upon. I will have all you have. I will have more. He stopped us matter of four minutes. He said, there is nothing but silver in the purse; then he applied to me. I told him, I had but little. I gave him half a guinea. He said, gentlemen, if you do not give me all that you have, I will make you get out of the chaise. I said, I have no more, but a little silver. He said, give me that. I gave him about three shillings. Then he said to Mr. Wogin, give me your watch. Mr. Wogin slipped his watch out of his fob, and put it towards me. He told him he had no watch. Then he applied to me for my watch. I said, I had none. He said, come out of the chaise, I will search you. I said, this carrying it too far; you had better be satisfied with what you have got. Mr. Wogin got the chaise open. Then the man said, well, gentlemen, I must take your words; I wish you a good night, and rode off towards London. The next morning we<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210014"></xptr> had been telling the story with all the circumstances of it; the servants waiting at the table listened to it. Presently came a man with a bill upon Mr. Wogin for post chaises; this man was informed by the servants, that Mr. Wogin and I had been robbed the evening before; he was inquisitive what sort of a man and horse. When he was told, he said, I will be hanged if that very man and horse are not at my master's house, the three pidgeons, at Brentford. Then we were informed of it; we interrogated the man; he gave just such a description of a man and horse as we had given. We walked down to Brentford; when we came there, we were informed a man answering that description had come in there at 10 o'clock; and had ordered himself to be called at six, but had laid in bed till 10 or 11; that he had been there once or twice before; and they suspected him to be a highwayman. We went into the stable, and thought it to be the same horse. I ordered the stable door to be locked, and the horse to be secured; and the man of the house to take care of his boots. The prisoner was then in the coffee-room in his slippers. Mr. Wogin being dressed as he was the night before, and I had pulled off my great coat. I proposed to go into the coffee room without him, to see if it was the same man; but Mr. Wogin desired me not to apprehend him till we were sure. I went in, and saw him sitting in the corner, and entered into conversation with the people; they were talking about highway robberies. I could not recollect him by his face; but was certain if I heard his voice I should recollect him. He had the same hat and coat on (when he robbed us, he had his coat buttoned up to his mouth); something was said which provoked him to speak; then I had no doubt but it was the same man. Mr. Wogin came in. One of the company said, I think Tyburn has not been graced with any some time. Mr. Wogin said, I believe it will be very soon graced with an acquaintance of mine. They asked him, on what account? He said, he had been robbed. The prisoner said, was it between this and London? He said, no, it was in the other road within a mile of Acton. The prisoner looked confused. While the other people were talking about the particulars of robberies, he said nothing, but got up and went to the window, and got out at the door. Then I said, I have no doubt in the world but this is the person that robbed us; and I think it is our duty to apprehend him. I will follow him if any body will go with me, and we will take him in the garden. Then they said, you had better send for a constable. We got one. The constable said, it was better and safer to wait till he came out of the garden; and if you point him out to me, we will take him. We stood together, three or four of us; and as he came, the constable and we laid hold of him: he was conducted into a room, and appeared to have as little fear as possible a man could have upon such an occasion. He asked, what we meant? I told him, he was the person we suspected to have robbed us; and if he had any body to give an account where he was at the time of the robbery, it would be of great service to him. He sat down, pretending to write to somebody. I desired people to go and search his room; and others to search the garden. While he was writing, a person came and told me I was wanted in the garden: they brought me to the necessary-house, and pointed to a horse pistol which lay concealed [ producing one], this is it. This I believe to be the very same pistol that was presented to us. We both had described it; it was loaded with balls; I have them now in my pocket. When I came back, and produced the pistol to him, he would not proceed with his letter, or tell his name, or give any account of himself. He took out a half guinea from his pocket, in order to pay a little bill. I apprehend that half guinea he had from me; it was a new King 
               <persName id="t17620421-20-person208">
                  George 
                  II 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person208" type="surname" value="II"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person208" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. half guinea, turned up. I followed the maid, and saw it before she delivered it to her master. He was carried before Sir 
               <persName id="t17620421-20-person209">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person209" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person209" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and committed.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a pistol was it he presented to you?</p>
               <p>Stevens. It was a common size horse-pistol. It is a gentleman's pistol; here is the arms upon it; I saw it was a brass mounted pistol, very bright, but not so at the muzzle; it looked as this, appearing dull at muzzle, as if it had got some rust.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not the garden at the three pidgeons a place where a person could easily escape over the pales?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I do not think they could very easily.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he stay in the garden?</p>
               <p>Stevens. About ten minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say that was your half guinea?</p>
               <p>Stevens. If a person had been robbed of such a one, by a man of the same sort of voice, hat, cloaths, and the like, it would have raised a suspicion; and I have no doubt but that it was my half guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say this is the man that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Stevens. I have no doubt but this is the man. I wish I had; but I have none in the world; and I believe so as to the horse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person210">
                  Richard 
                  Banks 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person210" type="surname" value="Banks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person210" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person210" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to 
               <persName id="t17620421-20-person211">
                  John 
                  Campbell 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person211" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person211" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person211" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esquire, Grosvenor-square. The prisoner used to come there; and be at times in the room where pistols used to be kept; we did not miss a pistol till we heard there was one found upon a highwayman, and carried to a gunsmith to see who owned it: then upon searching we missed No. 2. This pistol here produced is the same, my master's property.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210015"></xptr>Q. How long before the second of March had the prisoner been in the room where your pistols were?</p>
               <p>Banks. I believe it was a little before Christmas, but I cannot tell the time.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. How was the pistol hid?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was in the place where they lay the paper in the necessary-house. 
               <persName id="t17620421-20-person212">
                  Thomas 
                  Noaks 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person212" type="surname" value="Noaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person212" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person212" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the post-boy found it, and stood over it till I came.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is Mr. Wogin?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He is in a very bad state of health in Pembrokeshire.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person213">
                  Henry 
                  Cotheroy 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person213" type="surname" value="Cotheroy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person213" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a stable-keeper. The prisoner had a mare of mine. I have not seen her since. It was a brown mare; he hired her I think on the 24th of February, and was to return on the Saturday following. She is about 14 hands two inches high; and is hurt a little above the hock; and has a little bit of a star on her forehead; a genteel mare.</p>
               <p>Q. to the prosecutor. Is the mare this evidence describes like her the man rode that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Stevens. She answers exactly.</p>
               <p>Q. from the prisoner. Do you remember when I went out of the yard, I told you I believed I should go to Portsmouth?</p>
               <p>Cotheroy. I believe you did.</p>
               <p>The constable. When I searched the prisoner I found some crape in his pocket, and several bills of fare from the houses he had been at, and turnpike tickets.</p>
               <p>Q. Do any of these bills shew a journey to Portsmouth?</p>
               <p>Constable. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>When they came into the room at Brentford, I was just going. Mr. Wogin was frighted, and said, he would not appear against the young man for five hundred pounds; and described the young man in a different dress than what Mr. Stevens has: he said, it was so dark he could not describe him. Mr. Stevens says the horse was very swift; as for that horse I rode, he went very lame at that time. I was then going to Kingston to a gentleman that is now in court.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person214">
                  John 
                  Allam 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person214" type="surname" value="Allam"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person214" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Three Pidgeons at Brentford. The prisoner was at my house twice; the last time he came in over night, before the gentlemen came and charged him. He got up in the morning about nine, and went into the public coffee-room.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I think it was about noon I charged him.</p>
               <p>Allam. The mare he rode on was very lame. He came on her both times.</p>
               <p>Q. Might he have made his escape out of your garden with ease had he a mind so to do?</p>
               <p>Allam. There is a little rivulet at the bottom; sometimes the water is hardly over the shoes. There is a wall on one side, and pales on the other; the latter a child of six years of age may get over.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person215">
                  John 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person215" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person215" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a farrier, and live at Highgate. I remember putting a bar-shoe on a brown mare for a chance customer, on the 27th of February. She was lame. I believe the prisoner is the person that came with her.</p>

               <p>Prisoner. I gave you eighteen pence and a glass of wine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person216">
                  William 
                  Gibbs 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person216" type="surname" value="Gibbs"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person216" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was hostler at the Three Pidgeons. The prisoner came in the night before he was apprehended. The mare he rode was very lame: he desired me to stop her foot up, which I did. She had a bar shoe on when he brought her the first time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person217">
                  Edward 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person217" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person217" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Chapter coffee-house, Pater-noster-row. I have known the prisoner about five months; he used my house during that time; he behaved well; he used to spend his evenings mostly there; and kept very good company.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person218">
                  Richard 
                  Olton 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person218" type="surname" value="Olton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person218" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about six years. I keep a rope ground just by where his mother lives. She keeps milch asses. She had a leashold estate, but I believe that is gone. He lived with her. I never knew him behave amiss in my life: he always behaved as a sober lad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person219">
                  Richard 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person219" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person219" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him five or six years. I am a cabinet maker, and live in Barbican. He was with his mother backwards and forwards, and maintained by her. He has been at my house, and might have taken things of value. I never missed any thing. I took him to be a very honest lad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person220">
                  John 
                  Kinchin 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person220" type="surname" value="Kinchin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person220" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a shoemaker. I have known him about 15 years. I never knew any thing but what he was a very honest lad. I lived upon an estate of his mother's, but it is lately gone out of her hands; it belongs to the city.</p>
               <p>Sweet Lewin. I have known him between 18 and 19 years. I knew him a little child. I never heard that he did any body any wrong in my life. He was alway industrious for his mother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person221">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person221" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person221" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person221" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the Quakers Buildings. I have known him about eight years; a very honest sober young man, and industrious for his mother. He has deined and supped at my house.</p>
               <p>Peter Hill. I have known him about four years. I live just by his mother. I never heard any thing of his character, but what was civil; he bore the character of an honest young man. His mother keeps 18 or 19 asses I believe, or thereabouts; and<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210016"></xptr> has nothing else for her support since the estate is gone out of her hands.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person222">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Harrop 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person222" type="surname" value="Harrop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person222" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person222" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about eight years; I never heard a bad character of him in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person223">
                  Catherine 
                  Harrison 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person223" type="surname" value="Harrison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person223" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person223" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 15 years; I never heard but that he was a very honest, sober young man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person224">
                  Mary Ann 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person224" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person224" type="given" value="Mary Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person224" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from a child; he has a very good character: his mother keeps asses and hogs, and sells the pigs, and gardens. He used to be very industrious in mending the pales.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person225">
                  Silas 
                  Towl 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person225" type="surname" value="Towl"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person225" type="given" value="Silas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him from between five and six years of age; he bore a good character. This is the first thing I ever heard laid to his charge.</p>
               <p>Stint Sutton, Esq; I live at Kingston. I have trusted things of considerable value in the prisoner's care; he might have taken any thing, if wickedly inclined. He has transacted business for me in paying bills. I never heard any thing amiss of him before this.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was going to this gentleman's house (at the time they stopped me) for some linen which I left there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person226">
                  William 
                  Collier 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person226" type="surname" value="Collier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person226" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about five or six years; he was at my house three quarters of a year. I never heard but that he was an honest, sober young fellow. He was industrious in keeping the garden to rights.</p>
               <p>Rev. 
               <persName id="t17620421-20-person227">
                  Thomas 
                  Curtis 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person227" type="surname" value="Curtis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person227" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about five or six years; I live at Ryegate: I never heard any thing amiss of him till this affair. When I lived in London, he used to come to my house; I never saw him the least disguised in liquor: he was very industrious. I always had a very good opinion of his honesty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person228">
                  John 
                  Seyber 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person228" type="surname" value="Seyber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person228" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about four or five years; he behaved well at my house: He has been with me breakfast, dinner, and supper, and left alone where has been plate, which he might easily have conveyed away. He bore a very good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person229">
                  John 
                  Hague 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person229" type="surname" value="Hague"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person229" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My acquaintance with the prisoner was very little; last summer I had lodgings at Newington, with my wife and niece: He lodged in the same house. We have breakfasted, dined, and supped together; and taken a walk together in the fields, and after dinner gone to Hornsey and drank tea: I never missed him one night while I was there. He was very regular; there was a communication from his room to mine, where were gold watches of my wife's and mine. He has several times gone to prayers with us: His behaviour was exceeding genteel. I looked upon him as a gentleman. I never heard any thing who he was: He told me his money was paid him by some friend at so much a month. He lived at the same rate, and paid his reckoning as we did.</p>
               <p>Q. What expence might that be weekly?</p>
               <p>Hague. I look upon it, he lived at about eighteen shillings or a guinea a week. He never dined without wine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person230">
                  Christopher 
                  Norris 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person230" type="surname" value="Norris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person230" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him four months; he lodged with me. I live behind the Chapter-house, St. Paul's Church-yard.</p>
               <p>Q. What business did he follow?</p>
               <p>Norris. He appeared as a gentleman of fortune, and behaved as such: He was recommended as such. He behaved exceeding well, and kept good company.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person231">
                  James 
                  Riddle 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person231" type="surname" value="Riddle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person231" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him three or four months. I kept company with him at different coffee-houses, and at different parts of the town: He always behaved like a gentleman. I always took him for a gentleman of fortune.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person232">
                  Frances 
                  Daniel 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person232" type="surname" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person232" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person232" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about eight or nine years; he was very industrious about his mother's asses: I always looked upon him to be a very honest man. He used to collect the rents for his mother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-20-person233">
                  John 
                  Sideway 
               <interp inst="t17620421-20-person233" type="surname" value="Sideway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person233" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 15 years; I took him to be a very honest young fellow, and I do still: I rented a garden of his mother, and have sometimes paid the rent to him, and sometimes to his mother; sometimes with a receipt, and sometimes without; and if he had a mind to ask for the money again he might.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. My mother has now eight or ten guineas a month coming in, and I have had presents from gentlemen at times. I went out of town this very time to buy milch asses for my mother.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620421-20-verdict108" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-verdict108" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17620421-20-punish109" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-20-punish109" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-20-defend205 t17620421-20-punish109"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
