<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640222-39">
               <interp inst="t17640222-39" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-39" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-39" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-39" type="date" value="17640222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640222-39-off207-c229" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-39-defend309 t17640222-39-off207 t17640222-39-verdict213"></join>
         
               <p>170. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640222-39-defend309" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Wharton 
                  <interp inst="t17640222-39-defend309" type="surname" value="Wharton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-defend309" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-defend309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17640222-39-off207" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-off207" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-off207" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640222-39-victim311" type="victimName">
                           Anne 
                           Curtise 
                        <interp inst="t17640222-39-victim311" type="surname" value="Curtise"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-39-victim311" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-39-victim311" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-39-off207 t17640222-39-victim311"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17640222-39-viclabel208" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-39-victim311 t17640222-39-viclabel208"></join>, did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and violently taking from her person two shillings in money, numbered, her property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640222-39-cd209" type="crimeDate">February 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-39-off207 t17640222-39-cd209"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-39-person312">
                  Anne 
                  Curtise 
               <interp inst="t17640222-39-person312" type="surname" value="Curtise"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person312" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person312" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Tuesday, I believe it had gone one o'clock in the day, I was coming from <placeName id="t17640222-39-crimeloc210">Newington-green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640222-39-crimeloc210" type="placeName" value="Newington-green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640222-39-crimeloc210" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-39-off207 t17640222-39-crimeloc210"></join>; between there and <placeName id="t17640222-39-crimeloc211">Islington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640222-39-crimeloc211" type="placeName" value="Islington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640222-39-crimeloc211" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-39-off207 t17640222-39-crimeloc211"></join> turnpike, on foot, in the common highway, with 
               <persName id="t17640222-39-person313">
                  Margaret 
                  Cadwell 
               <interp inst="t17640222-39-person313" type="surname" value="Cadwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person313" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person313" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the prisoner at the bar came up and bid me stand; I did not observe him till he came up to us and spoke. I said to her, the good man wants nothing of us; then he repeated the same words a second time. Then she asked him what he wanted, and he said, your money.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>A. Curtise. I live in Johnson's-court, Fleet-street. I am a Temple <rs id="t17640222-39-viclabel212" type="occupation">laundress</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-39-victim311 t17640222-39-viclabel212"></join>, and had been with 
               <persName id="t17640222-39-person314">
                  Margaret 
                  Cadwell 
               <interp inst="t17640222-39-person314" type="surname" value="Cadwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person314" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person314" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to a boarding school, to pay her daughter's quarteridge. When the prisoner said, your money. 
               <persName id="t17640222-39-person315">
                  Margaret 
                  Cadwell 
               <interp inst="t17640222-39-person315" type="surname" value="Cadwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person315" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person315" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said she had got no money. He said, don't trifle, for I'll blow your brains out. I then said I had 2 s. all that I had in the world; you shall have that, and welcome. I was attempting to pull my glove off: he said then to me, don't trifle, but make haste, or I'll blow your brains out, with an oath. Then I gave him the 2 s. and he went away, and was not far from us, when a little lad on horseback came to us (he was going towards Newington). I bid him take care how he passed that man, for he had just robbed me. He spoke to a coachman who was coming to town with a chariot; and there was a man on foot that met the prisoner, just as he went out of the road, over a hedge or gate, into a field; he robbed me in full view of the turnpike. A gentleman came on horseback; he bid the man on foot go over after the prisoner; the man went over after him, and the gentleman and his servant rode round after him, till he was taken. The prisoner walked very leisurely till he found he was pursued; then he ran.</p>

               <p>Q. Had he any pistol or instrument?</p>
               <p>A. Curtise. I saw only a stick; but he put his hand down to his pocket, on his left side, and held up his stick to the side of my head. When he was taken, he was carried to the turnpike-house; there he offered me my money again, if<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176402220023"></xptr> I would let him go about his business, and said it was the first fact he ever committed.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after you was robbed was it to the time of his being taken?</p>
               <p>A. Curtise. This was all not above a quarter of an hour after.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-39-person316">
                  Margaret 
                  Cadwell 
               <interp inst="t17640222-39-person316" type="surname" value="Cadwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person316" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person316" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar met the prosecutrix and I, between Newington-green, and Islington turnpike, near the pond in the road. About half way between the turnpike and Islington, I observed him coming along, but did not take any particular notice of him; when he came close to us, I went to give him way, to come by: he bid us stand. I said, What does the man mean? I have got nothing. Immediately I looked behind me, to see if any body was coming: then I looked the prisoner in the face; he said, your money; I said, I had not a half-penny: then he held up his stick, or cane, to our heads; and said, if we did not deliver our money immediately, he would blow our brains out. I said, What do you mean to have my money, whether I have any or no? He twice said, if we did not deliver, he would blow our brains out, fixing his eyes on her the second time. Then Mrs. Curtise said, she had 2 s. she would give him that: she took the 2 s. out of her pocket, and held up to him, and said, if that will content you, it is all I have. He snatched the money out of her hand, and bid us go along silent, and he went away towards Newington, and I walked after him at a little distance; there was a chariot coming along, and a man on foot in the foot way, by the side of the chariot; I walked up to the chariot; the prisoner took over a gate or bank, into a field; by that time I was at the chariot, there came a gentleman and his servant on horseback; they asked what was the matter? I said, that man in a brown coat, going along the field, had robbed us. He ordered the man on foot, named Hecock, to go over the field, after him, and he would ride round the road, and prevent his crossing again; the gentleman rode back, and ordered his servant to follow him; he saw other men, and bid them assist, and at last they took him. I did not see them take him, but am sure he is the man that stopped us. As soon as he was taken, the gentleman sent his footman for us; we went with him to the turnpike-house, at Kingsland; and as soon as he saw Mrs. Curtise, he offered her her two shillings again, and said, it was the first fact he ever committed. I saw the 2 s. in his hand; I can't say particularly his words, but he wanted to be set at liberty.</p>
               <p>Q. Mention his words as well as you can.</p>
               <p>M. Cadwell. He said, to be sure I have robbed you, and there was the money again, if she would be so kind as to take it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-39-person317">
                  John 
                  Hecock 
               <interp inst="t17640222-39-person317" type="surname" value="Hecock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person317" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person317" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a shagg-weaver, and live at the Green-man, at Ball's-pond, Newington. I was going from thence to Islington, just after one o'clock: about an hundred yards from Ball's-pond turnpike, I met a little boy on horseback; he shewed to me a man, and said, that man had robbed a couple of women; he was not then fifty yards from me. I was not satisfied with what the boy said; I asked where the women were: I saw them, and ran to them, and asked them; they told me the same: a gentleman and his servant came up; I told the gentleman that man had robbed the two women: the prisoner was in the field. The gentleman said, do you follow him: you may catch him before he gets out of the field, and I'll ride round, and give him a meeting. I went into the field; the prisoner crossed the first field, and came to a house they call the Rosemary-branch. I kept about 50 or 60 yards behind him; he crossed the road that leads from Rosemary-branch to Newington, and went over the bank into another field, and crossed one or two fields more, and went towards Kingsland. I was not above 10 or twelve yards behind him, when he got over the last bank. 
               <persName id="t17640222-39-person318">
                  John 
                  Waller 
               <interp inst="t17640222-39-person318" type="surname" value="Waller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person318" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person318" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was coming just to meet him; as the prisoner was on one side the bank, and I on the other, I said to Waller, Stop that man, he has robb'd a couple of gentlewomen; he seemed to shun him, and turn out of the way; Mr. Robertson was coming behind, the prisoner being betwixt us, I jumped over the ditch, and told the prisoner he had robbed two women, and I insist upon taking you. He made no resistance, but said, I'll surrender. We took him to Kingsland turnpike: I searched him, and took a small penknife, and his cane from him. (A small cane produced); this is it: when the prosecutrix came in, he offered her 2 s. again, and begged to be let go about his business: he said, it was the first thing he ever did of that sort, and would never do so any more, if she would please to forgive him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-39-person319">
                  John 
                  Waller 
               <interp inst="t17640222-39-person319" type="surname" value="Waller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person319" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person319" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was afraid the prisoner had fire arms about him, made me give way. I can only give the same account the last witness has. I saw the prisoner produce the two shillings to the prosecutrix.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-39-person320">
                  James 
                  Robertson 
               <interp inst="t17640222-39-person320" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person320" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came over the bank, and I catched hold of him; we carried him to the turnpike-house at Kingsland; and searched him, and found only a very little knife, and this small cane about him. I saw him offer the gentlewoman her 2 s. again, and begged to be let go.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176402220024"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-39-person321">
                  Uriah 
                  Honyball 
               <interp inst="t17640222-39-person321" type="surname" value="Honyball"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person321" type="given" value="Uriah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person321" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live just by Kingsland turnpike. Seeing a gentleman and his servant coming pretty fast, I said, Open the gate, here is somebody in a hurry; the gentleman said, I am after a thief, I'll pay you when I come back; there is a man on foot after him, and we have surrounded him. I went after him, and saw they had taken the prisoner. They brought him to the turnpike. When the gentlewoman came, he took out two shillings and offered them to her; she refused to take it. I thought by his talk he was not in liquor then, but appeared as if he had been over night. I said, You have been drinking, my friend; he said he had been drinking pretty hard last night.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>My father lives in Petticoat-lane, White-chapel: he is a master worsted-maker. I came out of his house very much in liquor. I walked up the road and got more by the way, and was quite out of my senses. I did not know what I did. As I came near these two gentlewomen, I thought they would not give me room to pass.</p>
               <p>Q. to Hecock. Did the prisoner appear to be fuddled?</p>
               <p>Hecock. He looked as if he had drank a good deal over night; he was stupefied, but I did not take him to be fuddled then.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-39-person322">
                  Richard 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17640222-39-person322" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person322" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-person322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I worked shop-mate with the prisoner at his father's, in Three-ton alley, Petticoat-lane, a worsted-maker. His father bears as good a character as any tradesman in London. The prisoner was very much in liquor last Tuesday, between 11 and 12 o'clock, at my master's house; he had been at his club the night before, that is kept by the wool-combers in Goswell-street, and the next morning he drank a dram or two, and a pot of beer: He went out very much in liquor: He was not at all qualified for his work. If he drinks a little too much, he is as mad as one in Bedlam. When he is sober he follows his work very hard.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640222-39-verdict213" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-verdict213" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-verdict213" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17640222-39-punish214" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-39-punish214" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-39-defend309 t17640222-39-punish214"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Recommended to mercy.</p>
            </div1>
