<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610625-36">
               <interp inst="t17610625-36" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-36" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-36" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-36" type="date" value="17610625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610625-36-off210-c258" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-36-defend320 t17610625-36-off210 t17610625-36-verdict213"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610625-36-off210-c259" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-36-defend322 t17610625-36-off210 t17610625-36-verdict213"></join>
         
               <p>215, 216 (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-36-defend320" type="defendantName">
                     George 
                     Gings 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-36-defend320" type="surname" value="Gings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-defend320" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-defend320" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-36-defend322" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Lamb 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-36-defend322" type="surname" value="Lamb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-defend322" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-defend322" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17610625-36-off210" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-off210" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-off210" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing five images, made of plaister of Paris, value 2 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-36-victim324" type="victimName">
                     Jacob 
                     Salla 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-36-victim324" type="surname" value="Salla"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-victim324" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-victim324" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-36-off210 t17610625-36-victim324"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610625-36-cd211" type="crimeDate">June 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-36-off210 t17610625-36-cd211"></join>.~</p>
               <p>The prosecutor being a foreigner, and could not speak English, an enterpreter was sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-36-person325">
                  Jacob 
                  Salla 
               <interp inst="t17610625-36-person325" type="surname" value="Salla"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person325" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person325" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going with my plaister images, and was called into a house, which was <placeName id="t17610625-36-crimeloc212">Clerkenwell-Bridewell</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-36-crimeloc212" type="placeName" value="Clerkenwell-Bridewell"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-36-crimeloc212" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-36-off210 t17610625-36-crimeloc212"></join>; as soon as I was in they took and turned the key.</p>
               <p>Q. Who turned the key on you?</p>
               <p>Salla. That was Gings. There came about ten or a dozen men about me, and took my images from me, and said, they would send me on board the boats: then I desired to go out, they would not let me out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Lamb do any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Salla. He was one that took the images from me; they broke one, and took four, which they offered me back again yesterday, and I would not receive them.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was this?</p>
               <p>Salla. This was the fifth of this instant.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Gings one that took the things?</p>
               <p>Salla. He was there, he did nothing more to me, than lock me in, and I offered him money to let me go, and he refused it.</p>
               <p>Q. How got you out?</p>
               <p>Salla. I was trembling, and in a great fright, then Gings opened the door, and let me out; when I was got into the street, I was in a great fright, and fell down, and broke some other of my images.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Lamb ever return that image which he took?</p>
               <p>Salla. No, he never did: but he offered to return me four yesterday.</p>
               <p>Q. Where are they now?</p>
               <p>Salla. They are in Clerkenwell, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. How many did you lose?</p>
               <p>Salla. I lost five.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of them?</p>
               <p>Salla. Two shillings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-36-person326">
                  John 
                  Peter 
               <interp inst="t17610625-36-person326" type="surname" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person326" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person326" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was present when the prisoner Lamb offered to return four of these images.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was that?</p>
               <p>Peter. That was in the prison.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-36-person327">
                  John 
                  Freedom 
               <interp inst="t17610625-36-person327" type="surname" value="Freedom"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person327" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person327" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor went out with a basket of images in very good health, when he returned he was convulsed, and very ill, and brought home several images broke to pieces; I endeavoured to find out where the affair happened, and he described it so as I could just understand it to be Clerkenwell-bridewell. Then I went there to Gings, he was the assistant turnkey; I understood Mr. Jones, the keeper of the prison, was in bed. I said I did not know but the man was so affrighted that he would die. After that I saw in one of the papers, that Mr. Jones was dead; I did not know who to apply to. Then I went to the men, and asked them<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250039"></xptr> if they would make the man satisfaction; they proffered me four little images.</p>
               <p>Gings. I proffered you a crown, and you would not take under ten shillings.</p>
               <p>Gings's Defence.</p>
               <p>I have two witnesses here to prove I never meddled with the man.</p>
               <p>Lamb's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was in the tap-room when this man came in, I cannot say how long he was there; I saw he had a parcel of toys in his basket, I took out two, and looked at them, and went to put them in again, and he said, No, no, me have none of dem. I offered him them again, and he would not take them. Then I sent a person to the gate with them. He would not have them. They were taken from me directly, and put up in the tap-room, and there they are still.</p>
               <p>For Gings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-36-person328">
                  Francis 
                  Jobson 
               <interp inst="t17610625-36-person328" type="surname" value="Jobson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person328" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to see a prisoner there at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. When was that?</p>
               <p>Jobson. Something above a fortnight ago, I cannot tell what day it was. This man had a basket, he came in, and Lamb went up to the basket, and took hold of the man's images, and fell to kicking the basket, and said to the man, What business have you here among prisoners? and played about them some time. He went a little way off, and soon came again, and said, Take your things away, we do not want them. The gentleman said, Now let me go out, I want nothing. This was what he said, as I understood, I think he said, he wanted to go out, he did not want the things. Then one Pearce, one of the jail-keepers, took out one of the images, and hugged it on his arms, and made game of it; and said, This is my Jesus, and took it away. The images that they had taken were delivered to Mrs. Jones. 
               <persName id="t17610625-36-person329">
                  George 
                  Gings 
               <interp inst="t17610625-36-person329" type="surname" value="Gings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person329" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person329" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took none of them, he never touched them at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him present?</p>
               <p>Jobson. He was in the yard, I cannot say where.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let the man in?</p>
               <p>Jobson. Gings did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you there the whole time the man was there?</p>
               <p>Jobson. Yes, I was, I saw him come in, and I saw him go out; he was terribly affrighted, and all he wanted was to get out.</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he apply to, to get out.</p>
               <p>Jobson. He applied to Gings to let him out, and towards the gate.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was he with his images from the gate?</p>
               <p>Jobson. The gate is, I believe, 12 or 14 yards from where they stood.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you follow him towards the gate?</p>
               <p>Jobson. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you see him first apply to Gings to let him out?</p>
               <p>Jobson. That was after Lamb had done as I have mentioned, and offered him his things again.</p>
               <p>Q. How near the gate was Gings when the man applied to him to let him out?</p>
               <p>Jobson. I cannot say, he was a good way from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Gings near the images?</p>
               <p>Jobson. I believe he was not in sight of the images, he was nearer to the gate.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of these two images afterwards?</p>
               <p>Jobson. The jail-keeper was then very bad; he died soon after, and the keeper's wife took them all into her custody.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them delivered to her?</p>
               <p>Jobson. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. By whom?</p>
               <p>Jobson. By Lamb: this was after the man would not take them again.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after?</p>
               <p>Jobson. I dare say it was within a quarter of an hour; I know Gings had never none at all, nor I believe never saw them taken.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the images since?</p>
               <p>Jobson. I saw them two or three days after that in Mrs. Jones's custody. The case was this, Pearce and Lamb made her a present of them, and she took them all; they are now in her custody, now standing over a cupboard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-36-person330">
                  Mary 
                  Barton 
               <interp inst="t17610625-36-person330" type="surname" value="Barton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person330" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-person330" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went into see a prisoner that was there; I saw the man come in with his basket of images; he did not know where he was coming to. Lamb was in the tap-room; he went out, and took two images, one of the shape of a horse, the other a man. Then he went and made an offer at his basket, but did not do any damage. After that he wanted to return them to him again, and he would not have them. He said he did not want them, but he wanted to go out. Then the head-turnkey came and took out an image. They both gave them to Mrs. Jones, before the man went away.</p>
               <p>Q. How came they to deliver them to her before the man was gone?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250040"></xptr>M. Barton. Because the man would not accept of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>M. Barton. This was in the yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the man go out?</p>
               <p>M. Barton. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let him out?</p>
               <p>M. Barton. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Who let him in?</p>
               <p>M. Barton. The prisoner Gings did.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition was the man?</p>
               <p>M. Barton. He was very much frightened, but no other way.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not go with him towards the door?</p>
               <p>M. Barton. No, I did not, I said at the upper end of the yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Gings take any part in it at all?</p>
               <p>M. Barton. I did not see that he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any of the images broken?</p>
               <p>M. Barton. No, I did not; after the man was out I saw him fall down in fits, and he broke some of them.</p>
               <p>Jobson. I think Mrs. Jones took up one, and offered him money for it; and he was so frightened he would not take any money for it; all he wanted was to be out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she return it.</p>
               <p>Jobson. No, she did not; she kept it, and all the others that were given her.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17610625-36-verdict213" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-36-verdict213" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
