<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640113-40">
               <interp inst="t17640113-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-40" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-40" type="date" value="17640113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640113-40-off211-c279" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-40-defend352 t17640113-40-off211 t17640113-40-verdict215"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176401130028"></xptr>109. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17640113-40-defend352" type="defendantName">
                  
                     James 
                     Ballentine 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640113-40-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-40-defend352 t17640113-40-alias-5"></join>Crawford</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-defend352" type="surname" value="Ballentine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-defend352" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-defend352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted, for <rs id="t17640113-40-off211" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-off211" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-off211" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that in a certain open place, near the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640113-40-victim355" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Conner 
                        <interp inst="t17640113-40-victim355" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-40-victim355" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-40-victim355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-40-off211 t17640113-40-victim355"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , with a certain pistol made an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, with intent to steal the money of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640113-40-cd212" type="crimeDate">November 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-40-off211 t17640113-40-cd212"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-40-person356">
                  John 
                  Conner 
               <interp inst="t17640113-40-person356" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-person356" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17640113-40-viclabel213" type="occupation">milk-man</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-40-victim355 t17640113-40-viclabel213"></join>. Between four and five in the morning, I was on the other side the Halfway-house in <placeName id="t17640113-40-crimeloc214">Stepney-fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-40-crimeloc214" type="placeName" value="Stepney-fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-40-crimeloc214" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-40-off211 t17640113-40-crimeloc214"></join>: two men came up to me, the prisoner was one of them; he held a pistol to my breast, but first asked me, if my name was Luise; (I had a candle and a lanthorn with me) I said, it was 
               <persName id="t17640113-40-person357">
                  John 
                  Conner 
               <interp inst="t17640113-40-person357" type="surname" value="Conner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-person357" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he then said, how much money have you? I said, but seven farthings; for I was carrying milk for another person: he gave me a kick on the arse, and bid me go about my business. I saw him on the Tuesday se'nnight after at one Williams's, at the ship in East Smithfield; I got the headborough, and took up the prisoner: he pushed through the bar to come to the door, he was stop'd; he was dressed the same as when he robbed me: to the best of my knowledge, he was the same; I know the other man, he is named 
               <persName id="t17640113-40-person358">
                  William 
                  Shields 
               <interp inst="t17640113-40-person358" type="surname" value="Shields"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-person358" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             or Williams, but never saw the prisoner before.</p>

               <p>Q. From prisoner. Whether you did not arrest him for six guineas?</p>
               <p>Conner. I did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-40-person359">
                  William 
                  Aix 
               <interp inst="t17640113-40-person359" type="surname" value="Aix"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-person359" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor came to me about seven weeks ago, on a Thursday night, and said he was robbed such a morning in Stepney-fields, and that the two men were at the sign of the Ship, and one was named Shields or Williams; we went to divers houses; when we found the prisoner, he insisted upon it, that the prisoner was the man that was in company with the man that presented the pistol to him; I carried him to Mr. Clark's: the prosecutor called me to the door to know who was to have the reward, if he was hanged; I said, d - n the reward, don't hang the man for the reward. I lodged the prisoner in the Cage, and in the morning we took him before Justice Berry: the prosecutor there swore the prisoner was in company with the man that presented the pistol, and that the other owed him some money. The prisoner was committed for farther examination: I have known the prisoner nine months; I never saw him in liquor half so much as he was that night.</p>
               <p>Q. To prosecutor. Did you ask what the reward was?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. They said I would hang him for the reward. I swore before Justice Berry the same as I now swear here. I did not say it was the other man that held the pistol.</p>
               <p>Mr. Marks. I am headborough. The first time he was before Justice Berry, he swore the prisoner was in company with the man that had the pistol: the next time, he swore the prisoner was the man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The second time I was examined before the Justice, the prosecutor desired the Justice to discharge me; he had nothing to say against me.</p>
               <p>AEneas Clark. I live near the Victualling-office. The prisoner came to me, and said he had been stopt by a person that wanted to rob him, and wanted to know of me how he should act in it, in order to make it up; he said, if he had the money it cost him, he would drop it. The woman that Mr. Ballentine lives with, said, it was a wrong thing, that the man was innocent; then the prosecutor said, if he had a guinea, he would make it up, and, if he did not agree to that, he would hang him: the woman wanted me to lend her money on her silver-buckles; I said, I would not; she got half a crown: the prosecutor said, he would take it, and then she would owe him eighteen shillings, and then he would wash his hands of innocent blood; he went to a wash-house and washed his hands in a hand-bowl; the Justice asked him, if he would swear to the man; he said he would to the best of his knowledge; the Justice said, you blockhead, what are you about? either swear it or not; he said, well then, d - n it, he is the man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-40-person360">
                  John 
                  Crawford 
               <interp inst="t17640113-40-person360" type="surname" value="Crawford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-person360" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor is my acquaintance; he came to me, and said, he was robbed last Tuesday was se'nnight; I asked, who robbed him; he said, one that was in custody; he asked me to go along with him: I went to Justice Berry; the prisoner was there; the prosecutor said to me, is there not a reward? I said, what did he rob you of? he said, he robbed me of nothing; he said, two men came to him, and one of them ask'd him, if his name was Luise; that he had only seven farthings in his pocket, and they took nothing from him: I at that time thought he was broke down, and wanted money; he did not then say which had the pistol; he came to me a second time, and said, he believed he should have no reward; he said, he would make it up for three or four guineas; I said, may be the poor people may not have a farthing; he said, there were silver-buckles and other things; I said, he must get a lawyer; he said, he could do better than a lawyer.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176401130029"></xptr> I was in company when the woman and Mr. Clark was with him; he called for a pint of gin hot; there was brandy brought by mistake; the prosecutor was consulting with Mr. Clark what to do; I told Mr. Clark, he had a mind to make it up, and not prosecute; he and Mr. Clark went out; he came back, and said, he would make it up for a guinea; she said she would agree to it, to get the man out of gaol; she gave him half a crown in part of payment; she took the buckles out of her shoes, and desired Mr. Clark would lend her some money upon them; he would not: we drank pretty freely; he said he would go back again, and get five shillings more; I had like to have got my brains beat out by a parcel of women.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you think of the honesty of the prisoner at this time?</p>
               <p>Crawford. By this discourse, I began to think him not guilty of the charge, by the prosecutor wanting to get money from the people, and he was not willing to prosecute the man. Upon the last examination, the Justice called him villain, and said he had a good mind to commit him.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. They got me drunk, and the prisoner's wife wanted to make it up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to Crawford to advise with him about this matter?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I only went to him in a civil way?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take half a crown of the woman upon this account?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I did, but I gave it her again the day following.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640113-40-verdict215" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-40-verdict215" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
