<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17641017-31">
               <interp inst="t17641017-31" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-31" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-31" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17641017"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641017-31" type="date" value="17641017"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641017-31-off166-c309" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-31-defend376 t17641017-31-off166 t17641017-31-verdict169"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641017-31-off166-c310" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-31-defend378 t17641017-31-off166 t17641017-31-verdict171"></join>
         
               <p>580, 581. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-defend376" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17641017-31-defend376" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-defend376" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-defend376" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-defend378" type="defendantName">
                     Alexander 
                     Bourk 
                  <interp inst="t17641017-31-defend378" type="surname" value="Bourk"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-defend378" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-defend378" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17641017-31-off166" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-off166" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-off166" type="offenceSubcategory" value="forgery"></interp>
               forging and counterfeiting an order for the delivery of goods, to this purport, "September 23, 1764. Sir, please "to deliver my work to the bearer, 
                     <persName id="t17641017-31-person379">
                        Lydia 
                        Bell 
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person379" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-31-person379" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-31-person379" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  ;" and publishing the same, with intent to defraud the 
                     <persName id="t17641017-31-victim380" type="victimName">
                        <rs id="t17641017-31-viclabel167" type="occupation">wardens and company of goldsmiths</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-31-victim380 t17641017-31-viclabel167"></join>
                        <interp inst="t17641017-31-victim380" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-31-off166 t17641017-31-victim380"></join>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17641017-31-cd168" type="crimeDate">September 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-31-off166 t17641017-31-cd168"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person381">
                  John 
                  French 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person381" type="surname" value="French"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person381" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person381" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17641017-31-person382">
                  Lydia 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person382" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person382" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person382" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is a silver-smith; I work for her; I made two silver tankards and two silver cups, with covers, for her, and delivered them to 
               <persName id="t17641017-31-person383">
                  John 
                  Harper 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person383" type="surname" value="Harper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person383" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person383" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , her apprentice, to carry them to Goldsmiths Hall to be marked; they never were returned: the prisoner Bourk was Mrs. Bell's apprentice; but had gone away for some time: it is usual for the person that carries it to go for it again, with a note.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176410170028"></xptr>Q. How is that note commonly worded?</p>
               <p>French.</p>
               <p>"Please to deliver to the bearer my</p>
               <p>"work," and commonly the species of work is mentioned. If work is mentioned, we look upon it the same as if it mentioned the proper species of work: the apprentice, 
               <persName id="t17641017-31-person384">
                  John 
                  Harper 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person384" type="surname" value="Harper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person384" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person384" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , generally writes the note in Mrs. Bell's name.</p>
               <p>Court. Look at this order. (The order put into his hand).</p>
               <p>French. I know her hand-writing well: this is not her hand-writing, nor like it. It is not Harper's hand-writing. It is not the hand-writing of any person that belongs to Mrs. Bell; she has no servant but me and the apprentice Harper.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since Bourk lived with her?</p>
               <p>French. He lived with her about two months before; I believe he went away about Bartholomew-tide.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it usual in the trade for apprentices to write the note?</p>
               <p>French. It is.</p>
               <p>Q. Can Bourk write?</p>
               <p>French. I don't think he can.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person385">
                  John 
                  Harper 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person385" type="surname" value="Harper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person385" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person385" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to Mrs. Bell; I carried two silver cups, and two straight bodied tankards, and two covers, to be marked at Goldsmiths Hall, on Monday the 24th of September, and delivered them to Mr. Townraw.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen your mistress write?</p>
               <p>Harper. I have, many a time.</p>
               <p>Court. Look at this order. (He takes it in his hand).</p>
               <p>Harper. This is not her hand-writing; this is dated September the 23d.</p>
               <p>Court. Here is another paper; look at that. ( He takes it in his hand).</p>
               <p>Harper. This is my paper, that I carried with the plate.</p>
               <p>Q. When is that dated?</p>
               <p>Harper. This is dated September 24th.</p>
               <p>Q. Who writes the order for plate to be delivered back again.</p>
               <p>Harper. I write them, by my mistress's order.</p>
               <p>Q. Does Mr. French write any?</p>
               <p>Harper. He has wrote none since he has been with my mistress, as I know of.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this order for the delivery of it your hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Harper. No, it is not; I went twice, in order to bring the plate back; the first time I went, they told me it would be two hours before it would be delivered; that was about four o'clock: I went again about six, then the work was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by work?</p>
               <p>Harper. I mean the plate that I left at the hall.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you phrase it?</p>
               <p>Harper. We write, Sir, please to deliver my work: and commonly mention so many tankards and mugs, spoons, or what they are.</p>
               <p>Q. How is that wrote, which you carried in the morning?</p>
               <p>Harper. It says,</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17641017-31-person386">
                  Lydia 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person386" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person386" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person386" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Fleet-lane:</p>
               <p>"two tankards, two cups, weight 83 ounces."</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who usually writes the notes, since Bourk ran away?</p>
               <p>Harper. I write them.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you lived with your mistress?</p>
               <p>Harper. I have lived with her upwards of five years.</p>
               <p>Q. Who has used to fetch and carry the plate?</p>
               <p>Harper. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you, that went to fetch the plate, write the note?</p>
               <p>Harper. I did, in her name, by her order.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever go without a note?</p>
               <p>Harper. No: they would not deliver it without a note.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you always mention the particular names of the plate?</p>
               <p>Harper. I do; but I don't always set down the weight.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person387">
                  Thomas 
                  Townraw 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person387" type="surname" value="Townraw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person387" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person387" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the senior weigher belonging to the goldsmiths company: I receive plate at the office; I am to take it into my care, and weigh it, and put it into the inward office; to be assayed and marked; after that, it comes to me again. I remember receiving two tankards and two cups of Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17641017-31-person388">
                  Lydia 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person388" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person388" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person388" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, on the 24th of September; (I can't tell who brought it to me), betwixt six and seven; 
               <persName id="t17641017-31-person389">
                  Jones
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person389" type="given" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person389" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the prisoner came and asked for Mrs. Bell's work, if it was ready; I said yes, where is your note? he gave me this note in question; I read it; the note is as common as any other note we receive in the office; and I delivered the work to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the word work a usual phrase made use of?</p>
               <p>Townraw. It is, too common.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by too common?</p>
               <p>Townraw. Because the tradesmen will not be agreeable to the office at all times.</p>

               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176410170029"></xptr>Q. What did you deliver to Jones?</p>
               <p>Townraw. I delivered two tankards and two cups; he made use of Mrs. Bell's name, he said, for her work.</p>
               <p>Q. Would you have delivered the plate to any body except they had brought a note from Mrs. Bell?</p>
               <p>Townraw. No, I would not.</p>
               <p>The note read.</p>
               <p>"September 23, 1764. Sir,</p>
               <p>"please to deliver my work to the bearer;</p>
               <p>"
               <persName id="t17641017-31-person390">
                  Lydia 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person390" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person390" type="given" value="Lydia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person390" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Fleet-lane, London.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by being agreeable to to the Office?</p>
               <p>Townraw. There is a rule, but I never knew it properly; they should mention every piece; and the weight, I look upon it, for safety.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen Jones before?</p>
               <p>Townraw. No, not to my knowledge; the trades-people change their servants so often, that I deliver the goods upon their delivering the tickets; but I had a view of his face twice, while he was there.</p>
               <p>Q. You see a great number of people in a day at your office, do you not?</p>
               <p>Townraw. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Had Mrs. Bell any other plate there, besides this.</p>
               <p>Townraw. She had some small work, such as tea-spoons; that belongs to another officer in another branch.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you understand this paper to be?</p>
               <p>Townraw. I understood it to be an order from Mrs. Bell, to deliver this plate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person391">
                  William 
                  Bell 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person391" type="surname" value="Bell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person391" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person391" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the junior weigher, in the same office with Mr. Townraw. I belong to the small work: I know Jones, by his coming to the office to ask for Mrs. Bell's small work, on the 24th of September last; I then had three dozen of tea-spoons of Mrs. Bell's in my care.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you deliver them to him?</p>
               <p>Bell. I said Mrs. Bell had not sent any money with the work when she sent it in the morning, neither should I deliver it to him, for it was not ready: he said, Mrs. Bell sent the money by the boy that brought it in the morning; it was not he that brought it. Then he applied to Mr. Townraw for the large work: I saw him give Mr. Townraw a note, and I saw Mr. Townraw deliver the plate to him: I am certain he is the person.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner Bourk?</p>
               <p>Bell. I knew him when he was with Mrs. Bell, he brought the work sometimes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person392">
                  John 
                  Bowles 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person392" type="surname" value="Bowles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person392" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person392" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know the two prisoners; (pointing to them.) I had not been acquainted with them above a week, before this happened; Bourk was an apprentice to Mrs. Bell; he said he used to fetch and carry plate belonging to her to this office: he got a note, and asked me to go with him, on the Monday the plate had been carried to Goldsmiths Hall; he told me he and Jones had been to watch it in; and there was large work and small work went in that day; I told him I would go along with him; Bourk told Jones how to write the note.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was it wrote?</p>
               <p>Bowles. It was wrote in a cart in Chick-lane, that belongs to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17641017-31-person393">
                  Dickson
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person393" type="given" value="Dickson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person393" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the Brewer.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you write?</p>
               <p>Bowles. No; I can neither write nor read: Bourk sent a girl to get a pen and ink; it was agreed upon to go about three o'clock, to get the plate; we all three went to Goldsmiths hall at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Who went in?</p>
               <p>Bowles. Jones did; and Bourk and I waited just by: he was in about ten minutes, and came again, and told us, the work was not finished, and the small work was not paid for.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the note wrote?</p>
               <p>Bowles. I did; we all three of us were in the cart; the work not being ready, we all went back to where the note was wrote; we were to go again at six: when we went again, Jones went in with the note, and we staid in a court just by; he seemed to stay a little longer than ordinary, and we went back again to the place where the note was wrote, and Jones soon came to us with the work in a green bag; the bag that the work was delivered in; there were two quart tankards, with lids to them, and two pint cups; Jones gave them to Bourk, and Bourk held them while Jones went to fetch Welch: Welch came (he knew nothing of the writing the note): he took one of the tankards with the lid.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Welch live?</p>
               <p>Bowles. He lives in Black-Boy-Alley; he is about the size of Jones; about 17 or 18 years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the note read?</p>
               <p>Bowles. No, I did not; I heard Bourk say it was to be wrote in Mrs. Bell's name.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176410170030"></xptr>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with Bourk, when he first mentioned it to Jones?</p>
               <p>Bowles. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Jones's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was on a dung-hill in Chick-lane; there was I, Bourk, and Bowles all together: first of all, Bourk asked me if I had any money? I said I had none at all; and did not know which way to get any: he said he knew which way to get some, and was sure of getting it; he said his mistress used to send plate to Goldsmiths Hall every day: Bowles and he got a note, and delivered to me, and I went to the hall, and asked for Mrs. Bell's work: I was told it was not ready; it would be ready about six o'clock: I went again about six; I asked the Gentleman for Mrs. Bell's work: it was delivered to me in a green bag; I went and delivered it to them; I did not know what was in the bag. I am an apprentice to a watch-maker.</p>
               <p>Bourk's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing about it; Jones brought me first into it.</p>
               <p>For Jones.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person394">
                  Benjamin 
                  Odel 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person394" type="surname" value="Odel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person394" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person394" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Jones between five and six years; I always looked upon him to be a morally strict good lad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person395">
                  William 
                  Odel 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person395" type="surname" value="Odel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person395" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person395" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between five and six years; to my knowledge he lived a very regular sober life; his character was always a very just lad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person396">
                  Ann 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person396" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person396" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person396" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between five and six years, he was a very sober lad, and always behaved well in his master's house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person397">
                  George 
                  Padmore 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person397" type="surname" value="Padmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person397" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person397" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him some time; I never knew him guilty of misbehaviour in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person398">
                  John 
                  Anderkin 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person398" type="surname" value="Anderkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person398" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person398" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 12 months; he is a very sober honest lad.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person399">
                  William 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person399" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person399" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person399" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between five and six years; he has been often at my house, and always behaved well, in a very sober manner; I never knew him guilty of pilfering, or any ill.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641017-31-person400">
                  William 
                  Pateman 
               <interp inst="t17641017-31-person400" type="surname" value="Pateman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person400" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-person400" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Jones is now an apprentice to me, and has been almost six years; I never had any reason to mistrust his honesty; I left him in my house with another apprentice while I went to Dover.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in London the 24th of September?</p>
               <p>Pateman. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he then?</p>
               <p>Pateman. He was away from me then; he had eloped from me.</p>
               <p>Q. How can you come to give a person the character of a sober lad that has eloped from his service?</p>
               <p>Pateman. I did intend to have mentioned that to your Lordship.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he eloped?</p>
               <p>Pateman. He went away from me in August.</p>
               <p>Jones <rs id="t17641017-31-verdict169" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-verdict169" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17641017-31-punish170" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-punish170" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-punish170" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641017-31-defend376 t17641017-31-punish170"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Bourk <rs id="t17641017-31-verdict171" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641017-31-verdict171" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Bourk was detained to be tried with others, for a conspiracy in obtaining this plate.</p>
               <p>Jones moved by counsel in arrest of Judgment, and his sentence was respited till next Sessions.</p>
            </div1>
