<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17621208-8">
               <interp inst="t17621208-8" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-8" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-8" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17621208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-8" type="date" value="17621208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17621208-8-off51-c115" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-8-defend131 t17621208-8-off51 t17621208-8-verdict55"></join>
         
               <p>8. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17621208-8-defend131" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Morris 
                  <interp inst="t17621208-8-defend131" type="surname" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-defend131" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-defend131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17621208-8-off51" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-off51" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-off51" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing nine gold laced hats, value 20 s. each, the property of diverse persons to the Jury unknown,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176212080013"></xptr> being in a certain ship called <placeName id="t17621208-8-crimeloc52">the Cecily</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-crimeloc52" type="placeName" value="the Cecily"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-crimeloc52" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-8-off51 t17621208-8-crimeloc52"></join>, on the navigable river <placeName id="t17621208-8-crimeloc53">Thames</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-crimeloc53" type="placeName" value="Thames"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-crimeloc53" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-8-off51 t17621208-8-crimeloc53"></join>
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17621208-8-cd54" type="crimeDate">Nov. 21</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-8-off51 t17621208-8-cd54"></join>. +</p>
               <p>Samul Williamson. I am second mate of the Cecily, which is going to the Havannah. On the 21st of Nov. I was taking in some goods on the forecastle, there were four hands down below to take them away as they were struck down.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did the ship lie?</p>
               <p>Williamson. She lay at Shadwell on this side the water. About five o'clock the people having done work, I called them up out of the hold, I lock'd the main hatches down, and went to secure the fore-hatches. I went down to see if all things were secure; I saw, by the light of the candle, some pieces of paper lying about; I looked farther, and saw a box broke open, which had some gold laced hats in it, and many were taken away. I came up and informed the chief mate of it; we desired all hands might be called to muster, to see if any of the people were gone on shore; we missed three of the men that had been down in the hold at that time; the prisoner and 
               <persName id="t17621208-8-person132">
                  Michael 
                  Burch 
               <interp inst="t17621208-8-person132" type="surname" value="Burch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person132" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were two of them, the other was the evidence Lawson. I had seen the prisoner come up, but did not take notice whether he had any thing with him. We went to the house of 
               <persName id="t17621208-8-person133">
                  John 
                  Carson 
               <interp inst="t17621208-8-person133" type="surname" value="Carson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person133" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and told him what had happened, and that we were informed the people were in his house; one of them made his escape. I went and got a warrant, and took the prisoner at the bar. The chief mate and Mr. Carson came down stairs and brought two hats, which they said they found put up the chimney; we found two more stuffed down into a vessel of corn up stairs, (four gold laced hats produced in Court) these are they, they were taken from on board our ship. The prisoner said, if we would let him alone, there should be nothing lost, but every thing returned; but he never would tell where the rest of the goods were. He also confessed, there were four of them concerned; and that each of them had two hats; he mentioned himself, Bunch, Lawson, and another man, I do not know his name, he got away.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-8-person134">
                  John 
                  Carson 
               <interp inst="t17621208-8-person134" type="surname" value="Carson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person134" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Morris and 
               <persName id="t17621208-8-person135">
                  Michael 
                  Burch 
               <interp inst="t17621208-8-person135" type="surname" value="Burch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person135" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were lodgers with me at that time; there were four gold laced hats found in my house, how they came there I do not know. They were both at my house the time they were found.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-8-person136">
                  Nicholas 
                  Lawson 
               <interp inst="t17621208-8-person136" type="surname" value="Lawson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person136" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at work on board the Cecily; I knew nothing at all about it. I don't know whether there were any hats on board or no; I know the prisoner and Burch were below, but I did not see them do any thing to the boxes where the hats were.</p>
               <p>Williamson. This evidence said, before the Justice, he had sworn allegiance to them, and they did not care to tell tales of one another.</p>
               <p>Court to Lawson. You are sworn to speak the truth.</p>
               <p>Lawson. There was something put into my bosom I do not know what it was, nor who put it there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not they charge you with stealing some hats?</p>
               <p>Lawson. No, please your Honour.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-8-person137">
                  Thomas 
                  Raising 
               <interp inst="t17621208-8-person137" type="surname" value="Raising"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person137" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an officer. I saw two hats found in the house of Mr Carson. Morris said, Burch shewed him two hats, and asked him, what the value of them was; and Morris said, he did not know their value.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>On Saturday the 20th of Nov. I was at work on board the Cecily, all hands were ordered to dinner between one and two, 
               <persName id="t17621208-8-person138">
                  Michael 
                  Burch 
               <interp inst="t17621208-8-person138" type="surname" value="Burch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person138" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came and asked me to go on shore and drink part of a pot of beer; he carried me into a private house. He went up stairs, and I staid below; he desired I would come up to him; he opened a large chest and took out two gold laced hats, and asked me, what they were worth; I asked him whose they were; he said, they were a friend's of his, which he had to dispose of. He put them in the chest again, and we came down together.</p>
               <p>He called Mr. Harris, who had known him from an infant, 
               <persName id="t17621208-8-person139">
                  William 
                  Williamson 
               <interp inst="t17621208-8-person139" type="surname" value="Williamson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person139" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             for twenty years, and 
               <persName id="t17621208-8-person140">
                  John 
                  Paste 
               <interp inst="t17621208-8-person140" type="surname" value="Paste"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person140" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             fourteen years, all which gave him the character of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17621208-8-verdict55" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-8-verdict55" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
