<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17671209-24">
               <interp inst="t17671209-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-24" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17671209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17671209-24" type="date" value="17671209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17671209-24-off121-c147" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-24-defend189 t17671209-24-off121 t17671209-24-verdict123"></join>
         
               <p>29. (M.)
               <persName id="t17671209-24-defend189" type="defendantName">
                  James 
                  Key 
               <interp inst="t17671209-24-defend189" type="surname" value="Key"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-defend189" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-defend189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17671209-24-off121" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-off121" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-off121" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing four guineas one half guinea, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17671209-24-victim191" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Farest 
                        <interp inst="t17671209-24-victim191" type="surname" value="Farest"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-24-victim191" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-24-victim191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-24-off121 t17671209-24-victim191"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17671209-24-person192">
                        William 
                        Gray 
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-person192" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-24-person192" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17671209-24-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
               
                  </rs>. Oct ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-24-person193">
                  Thomas 
                  Farest 
               <interp inst="t17671209-24-person193" type="surname" value="Farest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-person193" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge in the house of 
               <persName id="t17671209-24-person194">
                  William 
                  Gray 
               <interp inst="t17671209-24-person194" type="surname" value="Gray"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-person194" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , at the <placeName id="t17671209-24-crimeloc122">Old Gravel-lane, Wapping</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17671209-24-crimeloc122" type="placeName" value="Old Gravel-lane, Wapping"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17671209-24-crimeloc122" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-24-off121 t17671209-24-crimeloc122"></join>; I came on more sick from on board a ship, the 31st of October; Mr. Gray's wife showed me the room up stairs to bed; I laid myself down on the bed; the prisoner came to me, and asked me how I did; he came home in the ship that I did; he said, I had better pull my clothes off; I said, no, do not trouble me; he helped me to pull my breeches off, and I took and laid them under my pillow; then he asked me if I would have any thing to drink; I said, no; then he said, I had better go to sleep; I turned my head from him; he pretended to cover me with his left-hand, and what he did with his right hand I cannot tell; in about ten minutes time he went down from me, and said he was going to see after his landlady: there came up a ship-mate of mine, and said, Tom, how do you do; before he opened the door, I saw my breeches lying with one part on the bed, and the other hanging off, I had not been asleep; I examined my breeches, and missed four guineas and a half out of them; the captain had just paid me off, the prisoner knew that very well; I received 10 l. 14 s. we went and enquired; a coachman came and informed us he carried the prisoner to Whitechapel, where he spent some money. and from thence to the Swan and Two Necks in Lad-lane. On the Sunday morning we went there and found him; we sent for a constable, and charged him; he was asked what money he had about him; he said he had only five halfpence; then he was desired to show what he had in his other pocket; he then pulled out some silver, and more halfpence; there was a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176712090013"></xptr> Frenchman that went with me, said to him, if you know yourself to be honest, pull off your shoes; he pulled off his right foot be very willingly, there was nothing there; then the constable desired him to pull off the other; he was very dilatory about it, and did not chose to pull it off, he was a long time about unbuckling it; when it was of one guinea fell on the table, and another he had stepped into his hand; he gave no other account about them, but that he had worked hard for them; I knew the captain gave him but a guinea for working his passage, and that I know was laid out within a few shillings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17671209-24-person195">
                  John 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17671209-24-person195" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-person195" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday the 1st of November I was sent for to the Swan and Two Necks in Lad-lane; the prosecutor informed me, as he has said here, how he had lost his money; I shewed the prisoner my staff, and said, I am afraid you have robbed this man; pray where did you lie last night; said he, what is that to you, and began to grow mighty pert; then he said he was with a woman; I said, pray what money have you got, I shall search you; he said he had no money, I was welcome to search him; he had but five halfpence; I said, turn them out; then he shook cut about five or six shillings, and six pennyworth of halfpence. Mr. Gray said, you have more money than is your own there; the prisoner said, take it if you dare; I said, then put it in your pocket again, that is not what we want; the Frenchman said he thought he saw him slip something in his shoe; he was desired to pull off his shoes; he very readily put up his right foot, and pulled off the shoe; then I felt in his fob; then I desired him to pull off the other shoe; then he began to abuse Mr. Gray; he found I was resolved to have that shoe off; he shuffled about it, and wanted to get the money out; when it was off, one guinea dropped on the table, and another I took from him; I put them two in my pocket; we then took him to the Computer, and searched and found 9 s. 6 d. and some halfpence; I kept the two guineas and 5 s. to bring here, and delivered the rest back to help him in prison.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had no money but what I worked hard for; I was born in Manchester, and have been two or three voyages.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17671209-24-verdict123" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-verdict123" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-verdict123" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               Guilty of stealing, but not in the dwelling-house
            </rs>. <rs id="t17671209-24-punish124" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17671209-24-punish124" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17671209-24-defend189 t17671209-24-punish124"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
