<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640728-20">
               <interp inst="t17640728-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-20" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640728"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640728-20" type="date" value="17640728"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640728-20-off101-c132" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-20-defend179 t17640728-20-off101 t17640728-20-verdict104"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640728-20-off101-c133" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-20-defend181 t17640728-20-off101 t17640728-20-verdict104"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640728-20-off101-c134" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-20-defend183 t17640728-20-off101 t17640728-20-verdict104"></join>
         
               <p>413, 414, 415. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640728-20-defend179" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     More 
                  <interp inst="t17640728-20-defend179" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-defend179" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-defend179" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17640728-20-defend181" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Cornish 
                  <interp inst="t17640728-20-defend181" type="surname" value="Cornish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-defend181" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-defend181" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17640728-20-defend183" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Robinson 
                  <interp inst="t17640728-20-defend183" type="surname" value="Robinson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-defend183" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-defend183" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , were indicted, for <rs id="t17640728-20-off101" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-off101" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-off101" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that they, on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640728-20-victim185" type="victimName">
                           Robert 
                           Wittingdale 
                        <interp inst="t17640728-20-victim185" type="surname" value="Wittingdale"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640728-20-victim185" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640728-20-victim185" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-20-off101 t17640728-20-victim185"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and stealing from his person two yards and a half of cloth, value 3 s. one cloth waistcoat, value 20 s. and one hat, value 1 s. his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640728-20-cd102" type="crimeDate">July 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-20-off101 t17640728-20-cd102"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-20-person186">
                  Robert 
                  Wittingdale 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person186" type="surname" value="Wittingdale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person186" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person186" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 6th of this instant, I went into Rosemary-lane, near 8 in the evening; I met with More, the prisoner, and went into a public-house to drink: I do not know how we came together, for I was in liquor; we were<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176407280009"></xptr> there some time, and then went into another public-house; there we drank till pretty near twelve o'clock; then she took me down to <placeName id="t17640728-20-crimeloc103">Saltpetre-bank</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640728-20-crimeloc103" type="placeName" value="Saltpetre-bank"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640728-20-crimeloc103" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640728-20-off101 t17640728-20-crimeloc103"></join>, where we met with Robinson, and I think, Cornish, the prisoner. More called to the other woman, but what she said, I do not know: we went into a house: I did not like their company, and went out, saying, I had no money to pay for a lodging. After I came out of the house, a person behind me, which I suppose to be Cornish, laid hold on my bundle, which I had upon my right arm, two yards and a half of cloth, and a cloth waistcoat: Robinson came before me, and struck at me, and in moving my arm, to keep off the blow, the cloth and waistcoat were gone: I was looking about for help, and they were all out of my sight; and in a few minutes after, Robinson returned, snatched my hat off, and ran away: Soon after that, a man came, and seemed to be sorry for me. I went all about to see for the things, the next day in the afternoon, and to a pawnbroker's. I saw Robinson before me; I thought by the cock, he had my hat on. I asked a man what that man's name was? he said, Robinson; I gave a beckon to Robinson to come to me; I wanted to look at the hat, but he slipped away.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen either of the prisoners before?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-20-person187">
                  Robert 
                  Wittingdale 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person187" type="surname" value="Wittingdale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person187" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person187" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Never, as I know of. I cannot be so certain to the woman as the man.</p>
               <p>Q. As you was so drunk, can you be certain to the persons?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-20-person188">
                  Robert 
                  Wittingdale 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person188" type="surname" value="Wittingdale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person188" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person188" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am perfectly sure of Robinson, by his person and cloaths: at the time I was robbed, I was as sober as at this minute. I never found any of my things again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640728-20-person189">
                  Robert 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person189" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person189" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw More bring the prosecutor down to Saltpetre bank; she called Cornish: she ran away at first; then More said, come here, nobody will hurt you: then she came back to them; this was in the street, in Black-boy-alley, on Saltpetre-bank; then Robinson and the two women went together a little time.</p>
               <p>Q. You said nothing of Robinson before?</p>
               <p>Martin. At first, he and Cornish were sitting together; 
               <persName id="t17640728-20-person190">
                  Jane 
                  Cornish 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person190" type="surname" value="Cornish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person190" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person190" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came back, and snatched the bundle from under the man's right arm, and gave it to More; they were all three together; Robinson was behind the women. After that, I saw Robinson come back, and take his hat, and run away with it; the prosecutor ran after him, and fell down, with his head against a smith's shop: I was within six or seven yards of them at the time.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of night was it?</p>
               <p>Martin. About twelve o'clock, or a little after: I lodge there, at the house of O'Harra. I said afterwards that I saw the thing done; then they came and took Cornish. I saw the prosecutor walking about all night afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no watch there?</p>
               <p>Martin. Yes, there was.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not go and alarm them?</p>
               <p>Martin. I was afraid, and was sick of an ague and fever, and had no money to pay for a lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prisoners before?</p>
               <p>Martin. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Do you remember seeing this evidence that night?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor I do, by his cloaths; he was pretty near the prisoners.</p>
               <p>Q. to Martin. What are you by business?</p>
               <p>Martin. I drive a cart.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you see Cornish's face at the time?</p>
               <p>Martin. Yes, and I saw More tie the things up in her apron: I had drank with Robinson at the Black-boy; he went out before me.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you in the alley?</p>
               <p>Martin. I was there to pass time away.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you and Robinson agreed to go into that alley together?</p>
               <p>Martin. No.</p>
               <p>More's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was in Rosemary-lane; I buy and sell old stockings. I met the prosecutor, who said, he thought he knew me; he was very drunk, and gave me 8 d. for a pair of stockings, and I spent seven farthings. He called for eight or nine pints of beer for himself and me, and what people he pleased to give it to; he said, he lived as far as Aldgate, and could not go home that night; he begged of me to get him a lodging: I did my endeavour to bring him to one; he had a bundle under his arm: when we came to the house, he had no more than two-pence half-penny, and the people would not take that, so I came away and left him.</p>
               <p>She called 
               <persName id="t17640728-20-person191">
                  Charles 
                  Orr 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person191" type="surname" value="Orr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person191" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17640728-20-person192">
                  Charles 
                  Rotherey 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person192" type="surname" value="Rotherey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person192" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17640728-20-person193">
                  John 
                  Cowman 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person193" type="surname" value="Cowman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person193" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17640728-20-person194">
                  Jane 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person194" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person194" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person194" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17640728-20-person195">
                  Susannah 
                  Lawler 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person195" type="surname" value="Lawler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person195" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person195" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17640728-20-person196">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person196" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person196" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person196" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17640728-20-person197">
                  Ann 
                  Carlisle 
               <interp inst="t17640728-20-person197" type="surname" value="Carlisle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person197" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-person197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who said they never heard she was ever guilty of stealing any thing.</p>
               <p>Cornish's Defence.</p>
               <p>Mrs. More came and called me to this man, and we went into a house: he had no money to<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176407280010"></xptr> pay for his lodging but two-pence half-penny; he went out of the house about half an hour before I did; I never saw any more of him after he went out.</p>
               <p>Robinson's Defence.</p>
               <p>I work very hard for my living: I met that witness, More, (I believe it was him) on Saltpetre bank; I having no money to pay for my lodging, he called me to sit along with him; after that, I went a little farther, and met a man, who stopped me, and said he thought I had robbed him about an hour ago: I said, if you think I have robbed you, why do not you charge the watch with me? the watch was then coming by; he said, no, you are not the man.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Did you see Robinson again, about an hour after you were robbed?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No. I never saw him after I lost my hat, till the next day in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>All three <rs id="t17640728-20-verdict104" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640728-20-verdict104" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
