<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670909-4">
               <interp inst="t17670909-4" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-4" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-4" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670909"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670909-4" type="date" value="17670909"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670909-4-off29-c147" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-4-defend152 t17670909-4-off29 t17670909-4-verdict32"></join>
         
               <p>411. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17670909-4-defend152" type="defendantName">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wall 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-defend152" type="surname" value="Wall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-defend152" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-defend152" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17670909-4-deflabel28" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-4-defend152 t17670909-4-deflabel28"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17670909-4-off29" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-off29" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-off29" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that she, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17670909-4-victim154" type="victimName">
                           Charlotte 
                           Thompson 
                        <interp inst="t17670909-4-victim154" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-4-victim154" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17670909-4-victim154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-4-off29 t17670909-4-victim154"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17670909-4-viclabel30" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-4-victim154 t17670909-4-viclabel30"></join>, did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and violently taking from her person a silk handkerchief, value 2 s. the property of the said Charlotte
            </rs>, <rs id="t17670909-4-cd31" type="crimeDate">August 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670909-4-off29 t17670909-4-cd31"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-4-person155">
                  Charlotte 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person155" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person155" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at Mr. Hill's in East-Smithfield.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your employ?</p>
               <p>Thompson. I do any work I can get to do; on Sunday the 2d of August, between nine and ten at night, I had been at a public-house, the Ship, for a pennyworth of tobacco; returning I was knocked down, and my handkerchief taken from my neck; there were more accomplices, but I can speak to none but the prisoner; they came behind me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any body before you was knocked down?</p>
               <p>C. Thompson. No, I did not; I received the blow on my cheek from behind me; the prisoner came behind me, and knocked me down.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know she did it?</p>
               <p>C. Thompson. I saw her strike me, I was stunned with the blow.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her before?</p>
               <p>C. Thompson. I had seen her before several times, but had never spoke to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know where she lived?</p>
               <p>C. Thompson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her name?</p>
               <p>C. Thompson. No, I did not; when I recovered myself, I had a great mob about me; I hallooed out I was robbed, Elizabeth Wall had robbed me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say so at that time?</p>
               <p>C. Thompson. I did; I went home to bed, and she was taken the next day; I had sent to her twice in the morning, for her to send me my handkerchief, and I would forgive the abuse; but if she did not, I would swear a street robbery against her; and the answer I received was, that I might be d - d. After that, I heard she was gone for a warrant; then I thought it necessary to go for one. I went to the bench for one, and when I came home she was there, and acknowledged she had pawned it for half a crown in East-Smithfield.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176709090023"></xptr>Q. You just now said, you did not know her name, and the next breath you say you called out, Elizabeth Wall had robbed you; how do you account for that?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-4-person156">
                  C.
                   Thompson Every
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person156" type="surname" value="Thompson Every"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person156" type="given" value="C."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person156" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             body knew her; I heard her name called; they called Bet Wall has got it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her after you had recovered from the blow?</p>
               <p>C. Thompson. I did, and she went off from the mob.</p>
               <p>Q. Did nobody attempt to take her?</p>
               <p>C. Thompson. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-4-person157">
                  Mary 
                  Oats 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person157" type="surname" value="Oats"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person157" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodge at Mr. Hill's, where Thompson does, in East-Smithfield.</p>
               <p>Q. How many young women lodge there?</p>
               <p>M. Oats. There are two more, and one of them is in the hospital with a sore leg.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>M. Oats. I go out a washing and scouring, sometimes one thing, and sometimes another; I was going home that evening, and saw Bet Wall knock 
               <persName id="t17670909-4-person158">
                  Charlotte 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person158" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person158" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person158" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             down, and take her handkerchief from her neck, and said here, to somebody, I cannot tell to who; I went, and called Mr. Hill directly, and came back with him. She had recovered the blow, and went home with us; Elizabeth Wall, and a man that keeps her company, went away together. I heard her say, this b - h, I'll be her butcher.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this after you had been for Hill?</p>
               <p>M. Oats. It was; they were two or three yards from 
               <persName id="t17670909-4-person159">
                  Charlotte 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person159" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person159" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; there were a number of people about Thompson, but I do not know who they were.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell the people that was the woman that robbed her, when you saw Wall?</p>
               <p>M. Oats. I did; Mr. Hill went up to see if 
               <persName id="t17670909-4-person160">
                  Charlotte 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person160" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person160" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person160" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was robbed</p>
               <p>Robert Hill. I am a smith, and live in New Rag-fair, East-Smithfield.</p>
               <p>Q. How many women lodgers have you in your house?</p>
               <p>Hill. I have six; 
               <persName id="t17670909-4-person161">
                  Charlotte 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person161" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person161" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person161" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Oats, 
               <persName id="t17670909-4-person162">
                  Sarah 
                  Cornish 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person162" type="surname" value="Cornish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person162" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17670909-4-person163">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Wootton 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person163" type="surname" value="Wootton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person163" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person163" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and two others.</p>
               <p>Q. How do they get their bread?</p>
               <p>Hill. Some one way, some another, some by needle-work; I was called by Oats; she said, I must come quick, she did not know whether 
               <persName id="t17670909-4-person164">
                  Charlotte 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person164" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person164" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person164" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             would be murdered, Elizabeth Wall had knocked her down, and taken her handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. Where does Elizabeth Wall live?</p>
               <p>Hill. She lives about an hundred yards from my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Do all your lodgers know her?</p>
               <p>Hill. They do, I believe; she used the same public-house as they do: just as I came up, Elizabeth Wall and a woman were going away; I heard Wall say, you b - h, I will be your butcher.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you go to stop her?</p>
               <p>Hill. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was she to Thompson then?</p>
               <p>Hill. She was eight or ten yards from her; I went directly up to Thompson, and in the mean time 
               <persName id="t17670909-4-person165">
                  William 
                  Magraugh 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person165" type="surname" value="Magraugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person165" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Wall went off.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670909-4-person166">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Hull 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person166" type="surname" value="Hull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person166" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person166" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mrs. Morrison, a pawn broker, in East Smithfield; I took in this handkerchief (producing a silk handkerchief) the 10th of August, of 
               <persName id="t17670909-4-person167">
                  Bridget 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person167" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person167" type="given" value="Bridget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person167" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and about an hour afterwards, Elizabeth Wall came and asked me, if Biddy King had not left such a handkerchief there; I said she had; she said that was all she wanted, and went away. After that, I was ordered to come with it before the Justice; there Thompson said, there were some spots upon it, done by ink, which appear on it now.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>Last Sunday was a month I went out betimes in the morning with my husband; we staid out all day till about nine at night; when we came home, we went in at the ship, and had a pint of beer, we were in a box by ourselves; 
               <persName id="t17670909-4-person168">
                  Charlotte 
                  Thompson 
               <interp inst="t17670909-4-person168" type="surname" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person168" type="given" value="Charlotte"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-person168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             came in, and would shove herself in by the side of me; after we had drank our beer, we went to go home; Charlotte followed us; she went to lay hold of my husband's hand; he bid her go along; she wanted to pick him up; I pulled her away from him; she flew up to me, and tore my necklace, cap, and handkerchief to pieces; there were several people came round me; I said, how could you serve me so; she turned round, and fell to fighting; my husband pulled me away, and said, I should have all my things torn off my back; we went home, which was but four doors from the place where we were; the next morning I got up, and went into this public house; the landlady said, Bet, what a piece of work here is about the handkerchief; I told her I knew nothing about it. I went about to see if I could find Thompson; then I went to enquire for the handkerchief, and found it was at this pawnbroker's; then I went to Thompson's landlady, and told her of it; then I found she was gone for a warrant for me; Biddy King and she had been fighting together.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670909-4-verdict32" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670909-4-verdict32" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See her tried with Grief and Delaney, for the murder of Mr. Smith, No 484, in Sir William Stephenson's Mayoralty; and Biddy King and she tried, No 103 in the Mayoralty.</p>
            </div1>
