<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17601022-3">
               <interp inst="t17601022-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-3" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17601022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-3" type="date" value="17601022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17601022-3-off11-c48" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-defend54 t17601022-3-off11 t17601022-3-verdict15"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17601022-3-off16-c48" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-defend54 t17601022-3-off16 t17601022-3-verdict15"></join>
         
               <p>291. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-defend54" type="defendantName">
                     Daniel 
                     Field 
                  <interp inst="t17601022-3-defend54" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-defend54" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-defend54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17601022-3-off11" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-off11" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-off11" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing one ewe sheep, value 6 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17601022-3-victim55" type="victimName">
                  Christopher 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim55" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim55" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , against his Majesty's peace, his crown and dignity, <rs id="t17601022-3-cd12" type="crimeDate">October 5</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-off11 t17601022-3-cd12"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-off16 t17601022-3-cd12"></join> +</p>
               <p>Christopher Hill. I am a <rs id="t17601022-3-viclabel13" type="occupation">farmer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-victim55 t17601022-3-viclabel13"></join> at <placeName id="t17601022-3-crimeloc14">Finchley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17601022-3-crimeloc14" type="placeName" value="Finchley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17601022-3-crimeloc14" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-off11 t17601022-3-crimeloc14"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-off16 t17601022-3-crimeloc14"></join>; I have upwards of 200 sheep; on the 4th of Oct. I miss'd a sheep.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a sheep?</p>
               <p>Hill. Quite a small ewe sheep, of a thin horn, fresh marked on the rump with oaker; I saw the skin at William Slayter's, a butcher, at Finchley; I could know the skin from 5000.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is your servant now?</p>
               <p>Hill. It is 
               <persName id="t17601022-3-person56">
                  John 
                  Fitzwater 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person56" type="surname" value="Fitzwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person56" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you employ the prisoner once?</p>
               <p>Hill. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not sign-a paper to the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hill. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this paper; is here your name?</p>
               <p>Hill. He takes it in his hand (here is my name)</p>
               <p>Q. Had he the care of your sheep at the time you lost this sheep?</p>
               <p>Hill. No, he had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Had not the prisoner sheep of his own on the common?</p>
               <p>Hill. I believe he had.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he 20?</p>
               <p>Hill. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you come to suspect the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hill. I heard he had drove such a sheep to Brown's Wells on Finchley Common; I enquired of him where the skin was sold, and the person there told me it was to Mr. Slayter; I went and found the skin there.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Hill. This was I believe on the 9th of Oct. instant; upon finding the skin there, I desired Mr. Slayter to go with me to Mr. Cross; after he said he had the skin of Mr. Keyton, I got a warrant for Mr. Keyton, and the prisoner also, and served it on the prisoner at Brown's Wells that night, and the next morning I took him before the justice of the peace.</p>
               <p>Q. After you had serv'd him with this warrant, did you let him go at liberty, on the promise that he would come again the next morning?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176010220004"></xptr>Hill. No, I did not: I do not know what the constable might do, but I found him there the next morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you the same marks to your sheep?</p>
               <p>Hill. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not the common way to put the initial letters of your name on them, with a pitch brand?</p>
               <p>Hill. Our mark is a cross-bow.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this sheep mark'd with that mark?</p>
               <p>Hill. No; it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Then how can you be sure it was your property?</p>
               <p>Hill. It was a very remarkable one, mark'd with fresh oaker.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether people in general do not put the initial letters of their names on their sheep?</p>
               <p>Hill. They do, I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the prisoner, who has sheep of his own, does not keep his sheep without any brand mark at all, on purpose to distinguish them from others?</p>
               <p>Hill. I have seen a good many mark'd with D. F. and oaker on the hip, which I suppose to be his sheep.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never see any of his sheep without any mark?</p>
               <p>Hill. No.</p>
               <p>Q. As this skin that you found in the custody of Slayter has no mark at all, and your's are mark'd, how came you to imagine it to be your sheep?</p>
               <p>Hill. That sheep happen'd to slip out when we were marking the sheep, and we knowing it to be a very remarkable one, with the off leg behind black, and a red mark on the rump, we thought it had no need of any mark.</p>
               <p>Q. Were all this man's sheep mark'd with 
               <persName id="t17601022-3-person57">
                  D.E. 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person57" type="given" value="D.E."></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person57" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Hill. All that ever I saw were: and red oaker on the rump, not the hip.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you not discharg'd Fitzwater once?</p>
               <p>Hill. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what account?</p>
               <p>Hill. Upon a little affair; about ordering a boy to go of an errant: he said, he should not go till he had done something to the sheep.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it for something dishonest?</p>
               <p>Hill. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hill. He may be call'd a labouren.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he any farm?</p>
               <p>Hill. No, he has not.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time you employ'd him to look after your sheep, had he any authority to sell any sheep for you, or was he only to look after them?</p>
               <p>Hill. I never employ'd him to sell any sheep in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-person58">
                  John 
                  Fitzwater 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person58" type="surname" value="Fitzwater"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person58" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to the prosecutor; I remember a sheep being missing on the 4th of October instant.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find it again?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. No, never; but we found the skin; it was found at 
               <persName id="t17601022-3-person59">
                  William 
                  Slayter 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person59" type="surname" value="Slayter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person59" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person59" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen that sheep last.</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. I took particular notice of it on the 3d of October, on the common, it was a very remarkable one.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe what was remarkable.</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. It was a thin-horn'd one, a black hock behind, and a speckle face, with red oaker on the rump.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there not other sheep on the common mark'd with red oaker?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. There were.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know how the prisoner's sheep were mark'd?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. Yes; with D.F. and a little dot of oaker on the hip, about as big as a crown piece.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain as to this sheep?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. I knew it particularly well. I look'd after it two years, and I must know it, to be.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been servant to Mr. Hill?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. I have been servant to him seven years and above.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you once from him?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. I was, a little while; then the prisoner look'd after the sheep.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you serve your master in any other capacity besides that of a shepherd?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the mark your mastermarks with?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. Yes; it is a cross-bow.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this sheep mark'd so?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the examination of the prisoner before the justice of the peace?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say for himself?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. There he did not deny delivering it to Keyton the butcher, for him to sell</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176010220005"></xptr>Q. What were his words?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. He said, he carry'd it to Keyton the Butcher, for him to kill it, and make the best of it; and he told me where the skin was sold?</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen that sheep last?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. I saw it on the 3d of October, amongst my master's sheep; it was my master's property, and I am positive the skin that I saw at Slayter's was the same skin.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to put the cross-bow on it, as you have on all your master's sheep?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. I intended to put it on.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you at the marking the sheep?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. I was not; I reddled this.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time you reddled this, did you reddle any other?</p>
               <p>Fitzwater. I did; more of them the same way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-person60">
                  John 
                  Keyton 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person60" type="surname" value="Keyton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person60" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I remember the prisoner bringing a sheep on the 4th of this instant to sell. I was not at home when he brought it; he put it in the stall, and came 2 or 3 hours after, and ask'd me, if I had kill'd the sheep? I said, no. He said, I must kill it; or if I did not, it would die.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a sheep was it?</p>
               <p>Keyton. It was a very small, poor ewe.</p>
               <p>Q. How was it mark'd?</p>
               <p>Keyton. It had reddle on the rump; and some dog or other had tore the neck all to pieces; it was very thin, very poor, and very rotten. I kill'd it, and carry'd the skin to Mr. Slayter's.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Keyton. I am a butcher.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Keyton. I live at Finchley, and have for 30 years and above.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you to do with the carcase?</p>
               <p>Keyton. I was to make the best of it.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day did he bring it?</p>
               <p>Keyton. He brought it about 9 in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Keyton. I have known him betwixt three and four years.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he sheep of his own upon that common?</p>
               <p>Keyton. He has.</p>
               <p>Q. What are they?</p>
               <p>Keyton. Some ewes, and some weathers.</p>
               <p>Q. Of what size?</p>
               <p>Keyton. There is not much difference in the size of this and them.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the prisoner's are all mark'd?</p>
               <p>Keyton. That I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever sell any sheep for him before?</p>
               <p>Keyton. I bought sheep of him several times, with his own mark on them.</p>
               <p>Q. How are his sheep mark'd?</p>
               <p>Keyton. They are mark'd with D.F.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they all mark'd so, that you bought of him?</p>
               <p>Keyton. I do not say that I never bought any of him without a mark before; but I can neither read nor write.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-person61">
                  William 
                  Slayter 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person61" type="surname" value="Slayter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person61" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I bought a skin of the last evidence.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any mark on it?</p>
               <p>Slayter. There was an oaker mark on the rump, and a black mark on the hock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Hill ever see that skin?</p>
               <p>Slayter. He did, and so did Fitzwater.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Slayter. I am a butcher.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you ever buy sheep-skins of Mr. Hill?</p>
               <p>Slayter. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they mark'd?</p>
               <p>Slayter. They were mark'd with a pitch-brand mark.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they mark'd like this skin?</p>
               <p>Slayter. No; this had no pitch-mark.</p>
               <p>Q. Has the prisoner any sheep upon the common?</p>
               <p>Slayter. He has.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever buy sheep of him?</p>
               <p>Slayter. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. How were they mark'd?</p>
               <p>Slayter. They were all mark'd D.F. with green or blue paint on the horn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-person62">
                  Thomas 
                  Wager 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person62" type="surname" value="Wager"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person62" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the skin; it was the skin of a sheep that the prosecutor bought of me, about three years ago. I then sold him a sore.</p>
               <p>Q. Were did you see the skin?</p>
               <p>Wager. I saw it at Mr. Slayter's</p>
               <p>Q. Is it not generally the way, when people buy sheep, to put a new mark upon them?</p>
               <p>Wager. Yes, Sir, but not always so; I have known people keep sheep three years, without putting a mark upon them.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176010220006"></xptr>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>On saturday the 4th of October, I found one of my own sheep bit with a dog; I carried her to the butcher, for him to make what he could of her. I made no bargain with him. I know no otherwise than that it was my own, part of mine have no other mark at all upon them than oaker.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Is it not usual to sheer your sheep once a year?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. Yes, always; our usual time is the latter end of May, or the first week in June. I had this sheep in my ground at my farm in Essex, and I did not think it necessary to mark her then.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-person63">
                  John 
                  Huss 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person63" type="surname" value="Huss"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person63" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person63" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Long lane, Smithfield; I have known the prisoner above five years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Huss. He has an honest character, as far as ever I heard. I was brought up at Finchley. I know his wife had sheep before she married him, but as to the number or marks I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>

               <p>Huss. I am a pastry-cook.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-person64">
                  Thomas 
                  Vicars 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person64" type="surname" value="Vicars"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person64" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person64" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner upwards of five years.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Vickers. I live at Highgate; he keeps sheep upon the common, but what quantity I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Vicars. I never heard but that he is a very honest man, and takes good care of his family.</p>
               <p>Jos. Grove. I live at Highgate. I have known him about five years.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of his having any sheep upon the common?</p>
               <p>Grove. I know he has some, but I cannot tell what quantity.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Grove. He is a very honest man, as far as ever I heard; I have had dealings with him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Mills. I have known him above five years. I know he has sheep upon the common, but cannot tell the number; it may be 40 or 50.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his character?</p>
               <p>Mills. He is a very worthy man as any in the parish, as far as ever I heard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-person65">
                  Stephen 
                  More 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person65" type="surname" value="More"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person65" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person65" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about three years; he is an honest man, as far as ever I heard.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601022-3-verdict15" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-verdict15" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acq
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>He was a second time indicted by the same name, for <rs id="t17601022-3-off16" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-off16" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-off16" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one sheep-skin, value 8 d. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17601022-3-victim67" type="victimName">
                           Daniel 
                           Cluen 
                        <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim67" type="surname" value="Cluen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim67" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim67" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; one sheep skin, value 6 d. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17601022-3-victim69" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Odell 
                        <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim69" type="surname" value="Odell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim69" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim69" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; one sheep-skin, value 4 d. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17601022-3-victim71" type="victimName">
                           Richard 
                           Lancake 
                        <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim71" type="surname" value="Lancake"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim71" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim71" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; and one sheep-skin, value 4 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-victim73" type="victimName">
                     Martin 
                     Hokin 
                  <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim73" type="surname" value="Hokin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim73" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-victim73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17601022-3-cd17" type="crimeDate">Octob. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-off11 t17601022-3-cd17"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-off16 t17601022-3-cd17"></join>. *</p>
               <p>James Steel. The prisoner was <rs id="t17601022-3-deflabel18" type="occupation">common-keeper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-defend54 t17601022-3-deflabel18"></join> at <placeName id="t17601022-3-crimeloc19">Finchley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17601022-3-crimeloc19" type="placeName" value="Finchley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17601022-3-crimeloc19" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-off11 t17601022-3-crimeloc19"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-3-off16 t17601022-3-crimeloc19"></join>; he used to bring sheep-skins sometimes to my work-shop, and hang them up over a beam.</p>
               <p>Q. What shop is yours?</p>
               <p>Steel. Mine is a turner's shop.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that of common-keeper?</p>
               <p>Steel. He us'd to tag and dress the sheep, and drive strays off the common.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who the skins belong to?</p>
               <p>Steel. No, I do not indeed.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your's an open shop?</p>
               <p>Steel. It is a very open one; people might see the skins the same as any gentleman may be seen in this court.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-person74">
                  Martin 
                  Yaulding 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person74" type="surname" value="Yaulding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person74" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner sold me those skins that he had hung up at Mr. Steel's; he told me he was common-keeper, and had a right to them.</p>
               <p>Q. How many skins were there of them?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. I cannot tell the number of them, there might be 18.</p>
               <p>Q. Are any of them here?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. Yes, four of them are; he told me the fallen skins were his perquisites.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by fallen skins?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. I mean sheep that die of the rot.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make any secret of it?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. He did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body see you buy them?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. There were half a dozen people by at the time. ( four sheep-skins produced in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. Is it usual for shepherds to sell fallen skins?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. I always thought it was the custom.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you distinguish whether the skins were skins of fallen sheep?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. Three of these are such, the other I think is not; that belongs to Mr. Hokin, a farmer at Paddington.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176010220007"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-person75">
                  Daniel 
                  Cluen 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person75" type="surname" value="Cluen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person75" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was chose in common driver, to keep strays off the common, he being about on the common. The people allow'd him a little trifle; I allow'd him 18 d a week for looking after my sheep.</p>
               <p>Q. If any sheep die, is he intitled to their skins as a perquisite?</p>
               <p>Cluen. It never was known in the world as a perquisite in our parish. I have forewarn'd him touching mine many a time.</p>
               <p>Q. Look upon this skin?</p>
               <p>Cluen. (He takes one in his hand) This is my property; here is my mark very plain.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the value of it?</p>
               <p>Cluen. I put it in the indictment at 8 d. it is worth more money.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it a fallen skin?</p>
               <p>Cluen. I thought it was not a fallen skin, but the felmonger says he thinks it is.</p>
               <p>Q. to Yaulding. What did you give for this skin?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. This skin I think I gave 8 d. or 9 d. for it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to forewarn him not to sell your skins?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. I have lost more sheep this year than usual; and if I saw a sheep lie dead, I soon found the skin was taken off. I don't know but I have lost 20 or 30 this year, and he always said he did not take them.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know how they died?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-person76">
                  John 
                  Platt 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person76" type="surname" value="Platt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person76" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Odell. The prisoner is chose in sheep-keeper and common-driver.</p>
               <p>Q. When the sheep dies, who does the skin belong to?</p>
               <p>Platt. To the man whose mark is upon the sheep.</p>
               <p>Q. Does the common-driver claim them as his property?</p>
               <p>Platt. I never heard of such a custom. (he takes a skin in his hand.) This is my master 
               <persName id="t17601022-3-person77">
                  John 
                  Odell 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person77" type="surname" value="Odell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person77" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's property. I can sware this is a skin belonging to one of his sheep.</p>
               <p>Q. Has the prisoner any right to the skins of such as die on the common.</p>
               <p>Platt. If he takes them off, he has a right to bring them home to their owners, they are not his skins.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your master's mark?</p>
               <p>Platt. His mark is J.O.</p>
               <p>Q. to Yaulding. Did you buy this skin?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. I did, of the prisoner Field.</p>
               <p>Q. Is there any body in your parish whose name begins with J.O. besides your master?</p>
               <p>Platt. No, there is not.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you lived long in that parish?</p>
               <p>Platt. I never lived out of it above a year.</p>
               <p>Q. By what do you know, that the skins are not the perquisite of the common driver?</p>
               <p>Platt. Because no body ever allow'd it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-3-person78">
                  Thomas 
                  Wallis 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person78" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person78" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . (he takes up another skin) this is the property of my master Mr. 
               <persName id="t17601022-3-person79">
                  Richard 
                  Laneake 
               <interp inst="t17601022-3-person79" type="surname" value="Laneake"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person79" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-person79" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. to Yaulding. Who did you buy this skin of?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. I bought it of the prisoner Field.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it a fallen skin?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. It is.</p>
               <p>Q. to Wallis. How do you know this skin to be the property of Mr. Laneake?</p>
               <p>Wallis. Because I put the mark on it myself.</p>
               <p>Q. to Yaulding. What did you give the prisoner for this skin?</p>
               <p>Yaulding. I gave him about 6 d. a piece for them all together.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I took that little skin last mentioned, the sheep was dead: the prosecutor's own man said, he would not meddle with it; the other I found on the Common, I did not know whose they were.</p>
               <p>The witness on the former trial were again examined to his character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601022-3-verdict20" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-3-verdict20" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
