<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17641212-19">
               <interp inst="t17641212-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-19" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17641212"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-19" type="date" value="17641212"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641212-19-off92-c119" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-19-defend157 t17641212-19-off92 t17641212-19-verdict97"></join>
         
               <p>20. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17641212-19-defend157" type="defendantName">
                     Moses 
                     Birch 
                  <interp inst="t17641212-19-defend157" type="surname" value="Birch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-defend157" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-defend157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17641212-19-off92" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-off92" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-off92" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch, value 30 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17641212-19-victim159" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Howell 
                        <interp inst="t17641212-19-victim159" type="surname" value="Howell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-19-victim159" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-19-victim159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-19-off92 t17641212-19-victim159"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17641212-19-cd93" type="crimeDate">November 14</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-19-off92 t17641212-19-cd93"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-19-person160">
                  James 
                  Howell 
               <interp inst="t17641212-19-person160" type="surname" value="Howell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-person160" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17641212-19-viclabel94" type="occupation">gentleman's servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-19-victim159 t17641212-19-viclabel94"></join>, at Ratcliff-cross. I was going into the city, on the 14th of November, and the prisoner went with me for company: I have known him four years: (he is a <rs id="t17641212-19-deflabel95" type="occupation">waterman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-19-defend157 t17641212-19-deflabel95"></join>): we went to the house of 
               <persName id="t17641212-19-person161">
                  Nicholas 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17641212-19-person161" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-person161" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a private house, in <placeName id="t17641212-19-crimeloc96">Cable-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-19-crimeloc96" type="placeName" value="Cable-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-19-crimeloc96" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-19-off92 t17641212-19-crimeloc96"></join>; my watch was in my fob when I went in, which was between ten and eleven at night: they got some beer for us; there were a servant maid, a woman lodger, and the man of the house, all strangers to me; they were on one side the fire, and we on the other. In about half an hour, I missed my watch, and taxed the prisoner with it, because he sat close by that side of me. He blasted my eyes, and said, he had not got it, and swore I never wore a watch. I told Butler I had been robbed in his house, and expected he would look into it: I went for an officer, and when I came back the door was shut, and I could not get in. I knocked at a door, but am not sure it was the right door. The next morning, I got a warrant, and took the prisoner up at his own house; before the justice, he said he had not got it; then he told the justice I had lost it in Butler's house, up stairs with a woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go up stairs with a woman?</p>
               <p>Howell. I don't remember that I did; I was in liquor. The justice said, he must find that house and the woman; we went there with a constable: going back, he told me if I would make it up, he would let me have my watch, and pay the expence I had been at. I told him I was very agreeable to that, if the justice was. His wife was present: he desired leave to speak with her. He sent her home, and she carried the watch to my master's house: then I had word sent me it was there, and I was desired to come home. After that, the watch was carried before the justice, and he committed the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-19-person162">
                  Anne 
                  Low 
               <interp inst="t17641212-19-person162" type="surname" value="Low"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-person162" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a lodger in Butler's house; the prisoner and prosecutor came in between ten and eleven o'clock; the prosecutor was very much in liquor, and had like to have fell down, as he was going to sit down. My landlord said to him, you seem to be very much in liquor; if you'll go to bed, you shall have the key of your door, and if you have money, or any thing, deliver it to me, and I'll return it in the morning. He said he had no money, but he would deliver his watch: he put his hand to his fob, and missed his watch; this was after he had been in the house about three quarters of an hour: Mr. Butler and I were sitting on one side of the fire, and the prisoner and prosecutor on the other. When he said I am robbed, Mr. Butler said, God forbid: the prisoner said he never knew him to wear a watch in his life. He went out to call the watch, and the prisoner staid all night. About a quarter of an hour after he was gone, I saw a silver watch in the prisoner's hand, but whose it was, I know not; he took it out, to see what o'clock it was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-19-person163">
                  Nicholas 
                  Butler 
               <interp inst="t17641212-19-person163" type="surname" value="Butler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-person163" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Cable-street. The prosecutor and prisoner came to my house between ten and eleven o'clock that night. He confirmed the testimony of the last witness.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-19-person164">
                  William 
                  Siseham 
               <interp inst="t17641212-19-person164" type="surname" value="Siseham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-person164" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. I had a warrant to take the prisoner up: I told him, he had better give the man his watch again, than go before the justice; he denied having it, or ever seeing it. I carried him before Justice Berry; he said the same there. He said they were at a house in the Back-lane, and Mr. Howell was lying on a bed with a woman: the justice said, if the prisoner could not find that woman, he must be committed. I went with him to the house of Butler; the people told me the same as they have here. When we<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176412120010"></xptr> were coming back, near the justice's house, the prisoner said, let us go in at the sign of the Bell: Mr. Howell was very willing to make it up, but I said I could not discharge the prisoner without going to the justice. I asked the justice if it might be done? he said no, bring him before me. The prisoner had sent his wife for the watch, and that was carried to Mr. Crump, the prosecutor's master. (The watch produced and deposed to by prosecutor.)</p>
               <p>Butler. This is like the watch I saw in the prisoner's hand.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I live within four or five doors of Mr. Howell: he was drinking at the Antigallican-arms, and asked me to go with him: I said, where? he said, never mind where, I'll pay for you: he carried me into the Back-lane, and went into a house that I don't know again, and came out again; then into another; he called only for a pint of beer: when he came out there, I would have had him to go home: then we went to the Three Tuns, where he began to heave money about on the table: I said, let me take care of your watch; he being very drunk, put it down on the table, and bid me take care of it till next morning: I took it up after that, and instead of going home, he went to the house of Butler; there he wanted something to drink: he being so very drunk, I thought it best to get out of his company; I gave six-pence to go to bed: the reason I denied it, was, to see whether he knew what was become of it: if I had any roguishness in my heart, I might have sold or pawned it, but I never thought of keeping it; if I did, I wish I may die in the place where I stand.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17641212-19-verdict97" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-19-verdict97" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
