<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680518-49">
               <interp inst="t17680518-49" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-49" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-49" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680518"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680518-49" type="date" value="17680518"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680518-49-off268-c421" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-49-defend537 t17680518-49-off268 t17680518-49-verdict272"></join>
         
               <p>403. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-defend537" type="defendantName">
                     Peter 
                     Perrin 
                  <interp inst="t17680518-49-defend537" type="surname" value="Perrin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-defend537" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-defend537" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, <rs id="t17680518-49-off268" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-off268" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-off268" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               together with 
                     <persName id="t17680518-49-person538">
                        Thomas 
                        Bowles 
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person538" type="surname" value="Bowles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680518-49-person538" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680518-49-person538" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17680518-49-person539">
                        Andrew 
                        Rogan 
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person539" type="surname" value="Rogan"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680518-49-person539" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680518-49-person539" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not taken, for breaking the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680518-49-victim541" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           Bailey 
                        <interp inst="t17680518-49-victim541" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680518-49-victim541" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680518-49-victim541" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-49-off268 t17680518-49-victim541"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                   on the <rs id="t17680518-49-cd269" type="crimeDate">17th of April</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-49-off268 t17680518-49-cd269"></join>, about two in the night, and stealing 100 pieces of ribbon, each piece containing 36 yards, value 70 l. thirteen guineas, and 17 s. in money numbered, the property of the said William
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person542">
                  William 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person542" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person542" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person542" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17680518-49-viclabel270" type="occupation">ribbon-weaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-49-victim541 t17680518-49-viclabel270"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17680518-49-crimeloc271">Oakley-street, Bethnal-green</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680518-49-crimeloc271" type="placeName" value="Oakley-street, Bethnal-green"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680518-49-crimeloc271" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680518-49-off268 t17680518-49-crimeloc271"></join>. On the 17th of April about two in the morning, I heard a noise of six or seven people in my passage within the street-door, crying, blast your eyes and limbs, open the door, get your pistols ready; I heard one of them say, Cox says the door is on this side; they soon broke the door open and came in to my bedside; two of them said, if he speaks a word blow his brains out directly; I saw the glimpse of a light, as if they had a dark lanthorn; I rose up on my backside; they cried, cut him down; they struck me several times with I believe the flat side of a cutlace over my arm; I then lay down, and they put a pillow over my face, so I saw no more of them. I heard them plundering the room, and open my book to look for bank notes; they staid about half an hour, I could distinguish there were four in the room, besides several in the passage; they seemed to change their voices, and speak in an odd manner; I got up after they were gone, and went up into a two pair of stairs room, where the evidence 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person543">
                  John 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person543" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person543" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person543" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lodged, for a light; I went into my room, and found the door broke to pieces, two drawers of ribbons, 70 l. worth gone, four 10 l. bank notes, one of 20 l. thirteen guineas in gold, and seventeen shillings in silver, and five shillings in halfpence gone; I received a letter from Coventry last Friday, that there were some ribbons stopped there; I went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person544">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person544" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person544" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person544" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , he advised me to go down; I did, and found about forty guineas worth of my ribbons there in a box, in the hands of one 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person545">
                  John 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person545" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person545" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person545" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; they took away my pocket-book, with my wife's marriage certificate, and an old indenture of mine in it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person546">
                  Mary 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person546" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person546" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person546" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor; the night our house was broke, I was in bed with my husband; they began calling out, blast your eyes and limbs; I put my petticoats on, and said to my husband, for God's sake get up, and take care of your notes; they said, get the pistols ready, we will soon have entrance; they broke the door and came in, and knocked me down with a pistol, and made my head bleed very much; there were four of them came in, how many there were in the entry I know not; there was a light in the passage, I saw the prisoner very plain as I lay in bed, he was in the passage; I suppose the light was the lamp which they had fetched from over the way, and they had broke the glass.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever seen the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>M. Bailey. No, but I am sure it was him; I looked very much at him, to be sure of knowing him again; as soon as he came into Sir John Fielding's office, I knew him again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person547">
                  John 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person547" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person547" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person547" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a ribbon-weaver, and lodge in the prosecutor's house and work for him; I was at the White Hart in Vine-court, Spitalfields, drinking with the prisoner and Rogan and Bowles, the night this thing happened; they were to cut my master's looms because he worked under price; the prisoner said he would come that night and rob my master; he told me if I would not tell any body, I should have part of the money; I was to leave the street-door open; I went home about half an hour after eleven, and only pushed the door to and went to bed, I was fuddled; my master came up afterwards and struck a light; my master told me he heard them mention my name in the passage; I was taken up, and told what had passed of it in the morning.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>Every word they have said is false as God is true; I have not been within half a mile of Bethnal-green these three months; I was at the house Cox mentions that night, I set out to go home, and met one 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person548">
                  James 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person548" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person548" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person548" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in Sun-street at near 12 at night; I asked him to let me lie with him and he let me.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person549">
                  James 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person549" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person549" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person549" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a weaver, and lodge at the bottom of Sun-street in Lamb-alley, at the house of 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person550">
                  Samuel 
                  Barber 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person550" type="surname" value="Barber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person550" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person550" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I spent the best part of that Saturday evening in Long-alley, at the Admiral Vernon; coming home I met the prisoner at the bottom of Sun-street about twelve o'clock; he asked me if he might go and lie along with me, being locked out; I said, if he would pull off his shoes to go up stairs he might; he did, and he got up in the morning I believe between six and seven; he is a weaver; I never heard any body give him a bad character.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176805180041"></xptr>Q. Are the prisoner and you acquainted?</p>
               <p>Cox. I have no particular acquaintance with him, only I have sometimes drank with him at public-houses.</p>
               <p>Q. Does he follow the business of a weaver?</p>
               <p>Cox. He does, I once bought a loom of him, he then lived in Crown-court.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know where he lodged at this time?</p>
               <p>Cox. I cannot say I did, he told me he lived as far off as Smithfield.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he drunk or sober at that time?</p>
               <p>Cox. He was a little in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Cox. I was perfectly sober, I had been spending the evening at two public-house, the Admiral Vernon and the White Swan.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you where he had been, and what about?</p>
               <p>Cox. He told me he had been drinking with some young freemen in Vine-court, talking about going to Coventry.</p>


               <p>Q. Can you be certain to the time you met with him?</p>
               <p>Cox. I am positive it was between half an hour after eleven and half an hour after twelve.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person551">
                  Joseph 
                  Essex 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person551" type="surname" value="Essex"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person551" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person551" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a weaver, I lodge in a one pair of stairs room, in the same house that Cox does; I remember his coming in that night, there was one with him, I thought it had been a woman; one of them went across the room with shoes off.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see either of them?</p>
               <p>Essex. No, I did not, I saw the prisoner the next morning when he went down stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did they go up stairs?</p>
               <p>Essex. It was about a quarter after twelve; I said, who is there; Mr. Cox said, a friend.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did the prisoner go down stairs?</p>
               <p>Essex. It was very near six in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he dressed?</p>
               <p>Essex. He was dressed in his regimentals, the same as now; I got up on purpose to see, because I thought Cox had brought a woman there; Cox and I work for one master.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Essex. I have known him three years, we did both work for one master.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you speak to him that morning?</p>
               <p>Essex. Yes, I said, ah! Peter!</p>
               <p>Q. What said he?</p>
               <p>Essex. Nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Are the prisoner Cox and you in the same branch of weaving as the prosecutor is.</p>
               <p>Essex. No, he is in the ribbon way, we are in the lace.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person552">
                  Michael 
                  Bilson 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person552" type="surname" value="Bilson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person552" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person552" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a master ribbon-weaver; I met the prosecutor on the Monday morning, after he had been robbed in Shoreditch; I asked him about it; he said he had been robbed of near 200 l. in notes, money, and goods.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say he knew who had done it?</p>
               <p>Bilson. No, he did not; I said I heard it was about five in the morning; he said, no, it was about two, and it was dark, and they had paper masks on; I met his wife last Saturday morning, I asked her if any more were taken up besides 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person553">
                  Peter 
                  Perrin 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person553" type="surname" value="Perrin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person553" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person553" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; she said, no; she said there were two advertised; I asked her whether she knew them; she said she could swear to the prisoner; and the other two; I said, if it was dark, how could you swear; she said she could swear to what 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person554">
                  John 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person554" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person554" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person554" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said. I knew the prisoner when he was an apprentice, he always bore a very good character as a workman and as a soldier; I look upon the prosecutor to be a very bad man.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character, is he to be credited upon his oath, or not?</p>
               <p>Bilson. From the character he bears, he is not to be believed upon oath.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Bilson. I live in Old Nicholas-street.</p>
               <p>Q. How many journeymen do you employ?</p>
               <p>Bilson. I employ eighteen.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person555">
                  Sarah 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person555" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person555" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person555" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a weaver, the prosecutor bears a very indifferent character; I believe his wife will encourage any thing of thieving; I have been acquainted with them both.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>S. Wood. I lodge in Old-street-square.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person556">
                  William 
                  Huggins 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person556" type="surname" value="Huggins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person556" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person556" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a serjeant in the first regiment of guards, the prisoner belongs to the same.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he belonged to it.</p>
               <p>Huggins. Seven years and odd months, I never knew any thing amiss of him, to always obeyed; every order in the military way, I never heard a person speak a word of ill of him in my life; I cannot say I ever saw him drunk in my life.</p>
               <p>Serjeant Smith. I belong to the same company, I have known the prisoner almost seven years, he has behaved well as a soldier, I never heard his honesty brought in question before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person557">
                  Richard 
                  Pain 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person557" type="surname" value="Pain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person557" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person557" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a journeyman bricklayer, and live in Baldwin's-square; I have known him ever since (I can remember any thing) we were<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176805180042"></xptr> children together, he is a very honest worthy young man as ever was known.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person558">
                  Thomas 
                  Pickering 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person558" type="surname" value="Pickering"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person558" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person558" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a master weaver, and live in Acorn-alley, No. 9; I have known the prisoner between three and four years; I always looked upon him to be a very honest man, I could trust him with all I am worth.</p>
               <p>Bailey. This evidence I believe has been at Coventry where my ribbons were lodged.</p>
               <p>Pickering. I went down last Wednesday night was a week, and came up again on Sunday night, I never knew there were any ribbons lodged there; I did not stay in Coventry a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you told there were some of his ribbons lodged there?</p>
               <p>Pickering. I was, but I saw none of them, I made no enquiry after them; I went down to see my mother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person559">
                  Richard 
                  Holland 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person559" type="surname" value="Holland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person559" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person559" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a victualler; I have known the prisoner thirteen or fourteen years, he is an honest industrious man; the day after this affair happened, the prosecutor got an order to enquire after me and to examine my house; he came with several officers, they went away very well satisfied, and said they found nothing leading towards a discovery.</p>
               <p>Bailey. 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person560">
                  James 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person560" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person560" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person560" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             signified when we were at the 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person561">
                  Brown 
                  Bear 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person561" type="surname" value="Bear"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person561" type="given" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person561" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             by Sir 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person562">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person562" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person562" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person562" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, being in a passion with me, that I had two names, that one I was called by in my marriage certificate, and another in my indenture, (I once was a soldier and deserted by reason whereof I changed my name;) I bid the people take notice of these words of Cox's; on this account, I was sure nobody had seen the certificate and indenture for some time past, from whence I imagine he had seen them which were in my pocket-book when it was stolen out of my house; this 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person563">
                  Sarah 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person563" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person563" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person563" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             who is come to swear falsely, her husband was taken last Sunday in the afternoon at Coventry, on suspicion of being concerned in this fact.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person564">
                  James 
                  Cox 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person564" type="surname" value="Cox"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person564" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person564" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . How came you to know of this marriage settlement?</p>
               <p>Cox. I heard 
               <persName id="t17680518-49-person565">
                  Andrew 
                  Rogan 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person565" type="surname" value="Rogan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person565" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person565" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             speak of it on the Saturday before this thing was done, at the sign of the Admiral Vernon.</p>
               <p>Q. How came that to be talked on?</p>
               <p>Cox. They were talking about his giving bad prices; he said he went by the name of Jackson in the marriage certificate, and in the indenture also.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he say he came to know that?</p>
               <p>Cox. He said some little girl shewed them to him.</p>
               <p>Bailey. Please to call Haliburton; no little girl ever lived in my house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680518-49-person566">
                  William 
                  Haliburton 
               <interp inst="t17680518-49-person566" type="surname" value="Haliburton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person566" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-person566" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to apprehend the prisoner; his brother asked what we wanted with him, and if he had done any harm; the prosecutor said his brother had robbed him; said one of these serjeants, Smith, I was afraid he had done something, he was yesterday cleaner them, I have seen him a great while, he had on a particular red waistcoat which I never saw him in before, and I think there was something said about breeches.</p>
               <p>Smith. What he says is very true, I did say I saw him the day before appear cleaner them I had seen him for some time; he appeared in a red waistcoat, which I had never seen before.</p>
               <p>Holland. I am the prisoner's brother-in-law; he had the breeches of me, they were a pair of nankeen breeches, he was to give me half a crown for them.</p>
               <p>Haliburton. His brother asked the prisoner where he had the waistcoat; the prisoner said he bought it in Rag-fair.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680518-49-verdict272" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680518-49-verdict272" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
