<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600709-21">
               <interp inst="t17600709-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600709-21" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600709-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600709"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600709-21" type="date" value="17600709"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600709-21-off112-c177" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-21-defend214 t17600709-21-off112 t17600709-21-verdict115"></join>
         
               <p>230. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-defend214" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Roberts 
                  <interp inst="t17600709-21-defend214" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-defend214" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-defend214" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17600709-21-off112" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-off112" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-off112" type="offenceSubcategory" value="murder"></interp>
               the wilful murder of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17600709-21-victim216" type="victimName">
                           Wm 
                           Robertson 
                        <interp inst="t17600709-21-victim216" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600709-21-victim216" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600709-21-victim216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-21-off112 t17600709-21-victim216"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>.</p>
               <p>He stood also charg'd on the coroner's inquisition for manslaughter, <rs id="t17600709-21-cd113" type="crimeDate">May 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-21-off112 t17600709-21-cd113"></join>.*</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person217">
                  John 
                  Dav 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person217" type="surname" value="Dav"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person217" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person217" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a chairman, I Windsor on the 7th of May last.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I am a chairman.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go to Windsor?</p>
               <p>Davidson. My partner 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person218">
                  Wm 
                  Robertson 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person218" type="surname" value="Robertson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person218" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the deceased, and I went there for work at the installation; we were coming from Windsor on the 7 th of May, about 8 o'clock in the evening, and about a hundred yards on the other side the 10 mile stone on <placeName id="t17600709-21-crimeloc114">Hounslow heath</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600709-21-crimeloc114" type="placeName" value="Hounslow heath"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600709-21-crimeloc114" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-21-off112 t17600709-21-crimeloc114"></join>, we overtook a waggon, they had been with leather to Eaton they were returning empty, we ask'd them to give us a lift.</p>
               <p>Q. How may were there of you?</p>
               <p>Davidson. There were 4 of us; there were 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person219">
                  David 
                  Tooth 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person219" type="surname" value="Tooth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person219" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person219" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person220">
                  John 
                  Lomas 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person220" type="surname" value="Lomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person220" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the Deceased and I.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened, did you see the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I wish I had never seen him; when we had got into the waggon, coming along, we were merry, there was an old woman in the waggon with us; the prisoner overtook us on the other side the way, with a chaise marine, the chaise marine went by us, and as high as I can guess the prisoner was on the left hand side on horseback; he said nothing to us, nor we to him, but he turn'd back again and whipp'd our horses; the waggoner ask'd him what that was for? he turn'd back again a 2 d time, and whipp'd the other 2 horses.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether at the time he turn'd back and whipp'd your horses, the chaise marine was nearer to Hounslow than your waggon was?</p>
               <p>Davidson. Then the chaise marine was pretty near the end of the town, for they ran a full trot.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance from you?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I can't account within a few yards; we were near the 10 mile stone, and they near the end of the town; the 10 mile stone stands about a 100 yards from the end of the town, I cannot be exact.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon his coming back, and striking the other 2 horses, what happened then?</p>
               <p>Davidson. Then they ask'd him what that was for; then he whipp'd us with his horsewhip in the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe in particular that he whipp'd the deceased?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He did not strike at any body in particular, but whipp'd who he could.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090018"></xptr>Q. Who did he whip?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He whipp'd me several times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any blow to light upon the deceased?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, I did not, the deceased had a little willow stick in his hand, he shook it at the prisoner, and said he deserv'd to be beat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you keep your eye upon the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he receive any blow?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he within that distance to receive a blow?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, the deceased could not reach him if he would have struck him.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then, if I understand you right, the prisoner could reach the deceased with his whip, but the deceased could not reach the prisoner with his stick.</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, the deceased could not reach him, his stick was about 3 feet long, the prisoner had a whip with a lash.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I desire to send for my whip (a messenger goes for it)</p>
               <p>Davidson. The prisoner immediately said, if you don't like that take this, and pull'd out his hanger?</p>
               <p>Q. What is become of the willow stick?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I don't know, we were glad to make away to save our lives; we let alone the stick, the prisoner made a stroke at the deceased at the tail of the waggon with his hanger, and the deceased had a cut over his right eye, but whether he receiv'd it at that blow I can't take upon me to say.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that a fresh cut?</p>
               <p>Davidson. It was a fresh cut, and the blood ran down his cheek.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there not a wound there before?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you with him all that day before?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I was; the deceased either tumbled or jump'd out of the waggon then, I can't say which.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sitting or standing?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He stood up an end then, he had been sitting before at the tail of the waggon, by the means of either falling or jumping he was down on his backside in the road; and as he was rising up, the prisoner at the bar came with his hanger and made a stroke at him; the deceased seeing it coming over his head, he held up his right hand to save the blow, to defend his head; I heard the blow, and heard the bone crack, I was by the side of him at the same time he received it, the blow was given with great force indeed.</p>

               <p>Q. Where did the blow fall?</p>
               <p>Davidson. It fell cross his wrist (he show'd the place on his own hand, about 8 or 9 inches from his knuckles)</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you apprehend, if he had not held up his hand in that position the blow would have fell on his head?</p>
               <p>Davidson. It must, it could not be avoided.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done after this?</p>
               <p>Davidson. The deceased clapp'd his left hand under his right hand, and said, Lord have mercy upon me, he has chopp'd my hand off.</p>
               <p>Q. After this, did you endeavour to give this man any assistance?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He dropp'd down. I was stooping to take him up, the prisoner came and made a cut at me, and cut my coat cross my back with his hanger (he show'd a chairman's blue coat, with a small mark on it) I stoop'd down, and he could not reach me; the deceas'd bled excessively, we brought him to Hounslow.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you bring him?</p>
               <p>Davidson. We led and guided him along, he was able to walk, we had not above a hundred yards to go; there were 2 surgeons, one that liv'd in the town, and another that belong'd to the regiment that lay there; they stopp'd the bleeding; then we took a post chaise for him, and I came with him to London.</p>
               <p>Q. How was he all the way he came?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He was very sick, he complain'd he was very sick. I brought him to Hyde Park corner, he could not bare going over the stones; then I got a chair, and brought him home to his own apartment, at a butcher's shop at the upper end of Old Bond Street.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him after this?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I did, he once thought himself better, but he grew worse at last, and died the 18th of May, about 20 minutes past 12 at mid-day, I was with him when he died.</p>
               <p>Q. After this blow was given, did the prisoner declare any thing what he would do in case any body offer'd to take him?</p>
               <p>Davidson. At the Rose at Hunslow he dismounted his horse, and there is a little room on the right hand, he got into that, and with his hanger drawn in his right hand, lying over his left hand, he stood in the doorway, and said, if<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090019"></xptr> any body came there to disturb him, he would cut their ears off, and make bakers of them: we took him, and carry'd him before a justice of the peace.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do after the wound was given?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He made all the way he cou'd to the town of Hounslow, he rode as fast as he could, he was pursued with the cry stop thief; the woman at the 5 bells said, what is the matter; I said, he has chopp'd a man's hand off.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he taken?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He was taken at Mr. Fuller's, at the Rose at Hounslow.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the justice with him?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say there?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He said, pray Sir do you know who I am. No really, said the justice, I don't know who you are. Said he, I am groom of the chamber to the right honourable secretary Pitt.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any driver to this waggon?</p>
               <p>Davidson. The drivers were in the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. How were the horses going?</p>
               <p>Davidson. They were going quietly along.</p>
               <p>Q. Were the horses led by any body?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, there were nobody but what were in the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. How many drivers were there?</p>
               <p>Davidson. There were 2.</p>
               <p>Counsel. And both in the Waggon?</p>
               <p>Davidson. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was they at the tail of the waggon, or fore part?</p>
               <p>Davidson. They were at the fore part, speaking to their horses.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time Mr. Roberts came by, was there or was there not any body conducting the waggon?</p>
               <p>Davidson. There was not, they were in the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the waggon in the middle, or on one side the road?</p>
               <p>Davidson. On one side the road.</p>
               <p>Q. When the chaise past you, was the waggon in the middle or on one side?</p>
               <p>Davidson. It was on the left hand side the road, leaving room for the chaise, and 2 chaises more to pass.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the chaise marine when the prisoner spoke to you?</p>
               <p>Davidson. That was gone by us before he spoke any thing to us.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the waggoner drive up, in order to overtake the chaise, or not?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, not to my knowledge; no not at that time before the wound was given.</p>
               <p>Q. When the chaise had overtaken the waggon, did the waggon overtake the chaise again?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, sir, not at all.</p>
               <p>Counsel. I would be very glad to know how this was introduced; whether by any provocation or not, that the prisoner was riding on the left hand side the chaise, and past you, and nothing was said, but the prisoner, without any thing having been said, turn'd back, and whipp'd your horses. Can you assign any reason at all for it, why he should turn back and whip your horses, if the chaise had clearly past you?</p>
               <p>Davidson. There was no reason at all why he should turn back and whip our horses, nothing had been said, and the prisoner had past us.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Nothing had been said from the waggoner to him?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, not a word.</p>
               <p>Counsel. I am answered. You say, after the chaise past you, and were got a hundred yards before you, there were some words past, what words were they?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I can't tell.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Angry words?</p>
               <p>Davidson. They were not very pleasant words.</p>
               <p>Q. In what nature were these words?</p>
               <p>Davidson. It seem'd as if it was in passion.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the deceased then?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He was then laid down.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there angry words on both sides?</p>
               <p>Davidson. My partner, the deceased, or some body else, said to him that he deserved licking for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Before he whipp'd you in the waggon, were there angry words past?</p>
               <p>Davidson. Yes, after he had whipp'd the horses a second time.</p>
               <p>Q. What were these words, were they hard names.</p>
               <p>Davidson. I don't know what you call hard names.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the whip had a thong to it?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I am sure it had.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I can't tell the length of it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was the willow stick?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090020"></xptr>Davidson. That was about 3 feet long.</p>
               <p>Q. How thick?</p>
               <p>Davidson. About as thick as my finger.</p>
               <p>Q. Had any one in the waggon a stick besides?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, nobody.</p>
               <p>Q. This man being your partner, how was his left hand?</p>
               <p>Davidson. His left hand was a little lamish by a hurt he had; he had not the use of his fingers so well as a great many people, but he could close them well enough to get his bread.</p>
               <p>Q. Could he grasp a stick?</p>
               <p>Davidson. Really I cannot tell whether he could or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see him grasp any thing in that hand?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe his wound over his eye bleed before he came out of the waggon?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I did not see that wound till I came to take him up.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then you did not see that wound in the waggon?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, whether he received it before or after he came out of the waggon I cannot say. I did not observe the blood run down his cheek till I came to take him up when he was out of the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the deceased was on his legs in the waggon?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He was lying in the waggon at first, but he was on his legs when he came out; but whether he jump'd or tumbled out I can't say.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he been on his legs?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I can't say how long.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then he might have been on his legs 5 or 6 minutes.</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, no.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he on his legs at the time of shaking his stick at the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I can't say whether he was or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was one of the waggoners in a white coat?</p>
               <p>Davidson. Upon my life I can't tell what cloaths he had on.</p>
               <p>Court. You are upon your oath?</p>
               <p>Davidson. Upon my oath I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. What cloaths had the deceased on?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He had a chairman's green coat on.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You just now described to the court, by showing in what manner he held his hand at the time he receiv'd the blow, do that once more?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He holds his right hand from the elbow very near, he holds his right hand up, just so, it was not a pitch'd guard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner strike at the head by the manner of the blow?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I really believe it was designed for the head, or any where were he could hit.</p>
               <p>Q. What leads you to say, if the deceased had not held up his hand, the blow would have fallen on his head?</p>
               <p>Davidson. Because it fell so high his head.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe then where the wound was?</p>
               <p>Davidson. It was over here, putting his finger towards the inside of his wrist.</p>
               <p>Q. How then, as he held his hand, could the wound be there?</p>
               <p>Davidson Because he was on horse back.</p>
               <p>Q. How could he receive the blow on the inside the hand?</p>
               <p>Davidson. The blow came over the head.</p>
               <p>Q. On what side was the prisoner's horse at the time of the blow?</p>
               <p>Davidson. The prisoner's horse was on the deceased's right hand, he was on horse back, my partner was on the prisoner's right hand side.</p>
               <p>Q. Now again say how that was; if he held his hand in the way you describe, how could a man prevent the blow from falling on the head by holding his hand so?</p>
               <p>Davidson. The wound was there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he hold his hand in such sort, that if it had not been held up the blow would have fell upon his head?</p>
               <p>Davidson. Yes; I told you so before, it was held to guard the head.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any dirt, stones or pebbles thrown?</p>
               <p>Davidson. Yes, sir, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. How came they to be thrown?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I do not know which of them throw'd them, it was gravel, they were upon the ground then, it was thrown by those belonging to the waggon, I can't give an account of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any stones or gravel thrown?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Can't you say by who?</p>
               <p>Davidson. It was by the people belonging to the waggon, and our company, they had not time to look for any pick stones, for he was for riding over them, they picked up the gravel in the road.</p>
         
               <p>Note, The Remainder of these Proceedings will be published in a few Days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17600709-21">
                  <interp inst="t17600709-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600709-21" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600709-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600709"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600709-21" type="date" value="17600709"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090021"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commissioners of the Peace, Oyer, and Terminer, and Gaol Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON, And also the Gaol Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 9th, Thursday the 10th, and Friday the 11th, of JULY,</p>
                  <p>In the Thirty-third Year of His MAJESTY'S Reign. NUMBER VI. PART II. for the YEAR 1760. Being the Sixth SESSIONS in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person221">
                     Thomas 
                     CHITTY 
                  <interp inst="t17600709-21-person221" type="surname" value="CHITTY"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600709-21-person221" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600709-21-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Printed, and sold by G. KEARSLY (Successor to the late Mr. Robinson) at the Golden-Lion, in Ludgate-Street, 1760.</p>
                  <p>[Price Four-pence.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090022"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commissions of the Peace, and Oyer and Terminer, for the City of LONDON, and at the General 
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person222">
                     Sessions
                  <interp inst="t17600709-21-person222" type="given" value="Sessions"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600709-21-person222" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                of Gaol Delivery for Newgate holden for the City of LONDON, and County of MIDDLESEX, at Justice-Hall in the Old-Bailey, &amp; c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>Q. WAS this before or after the wound given?</p>
               <p>Davidson. This was after the wound given.</p>
               <p>Q. Had neither of you stones till after the wound?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, nor stick neither, but that willow stick; I saw none thrown till after the wound.</p>
               <p>Q. Must you have seen it if any had been thrown?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I must, but I saw none thrown before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the deceased, your partner, continue holding the stick in his hand after he got out of the waggon?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, he was not long upon the ground before he receiv'd that cut.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you, or do you not remember seeing him with the stick in his hand after he was out of the waggon?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I don't remember that I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body hit the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No, there were nobody at all did.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Nor no stones thrown till after the wound?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you pursue the prisoner on foot?</p>
               <p>Davidson. We were all on foot, we had no horses to ride.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he stop at Hounslow?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it by force?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I don't know whether it was or not; he was pursued into the town, and we alarmed the town.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after you got into the town that you saw him?</p>
               <p>Davidson. I saw him in the little room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was his horse?</p>
               <p>Davidson. His horse was in the stable.</p>
               <p>Q. Who paid for the chaise?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he or did he not behave with humanity towards the deceased, and express his sorrow for what had happened?</p>
               <p>Davidson. No sir, I did not see any such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. How came the deceased to be carried home?</p>
               <p>Davidson. He said he desired to go to his own being, as he had a wife to nurse him, and I carried him there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person223">
                  David 
                  Tooth 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person223" type="surname" value="Tooth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person223" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was one of the company; at the time I had been at Windsor, and was coming back, we had been to the installation, to carry any gentleman that wanted a chair; we were coming along about 200 yards beyond the 10 miles stone on Hounslow Heath, on the 7th of May, about 8 in the evening, we overtook this Waggon, and ask'd the waggoner to let us ride towards London; he gave us leave, and said with all his heart; we all got up in the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. How many were there of you?</p>
               <p>Tooth. There were 4 chairmen of us, 2 waggoners, and a woman, 7 in all; we had not been in the waggon a quarter of an hour before we were overtaken by the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Which side of the road was the waggon on at that time?</p>
               <p>Tooth. The waggon was on the left side of the road, there was room for 3 or 4 carriages to go along on the other side the way without any interruption at all; the prisoner rode by the waggon, and struck the foremost horse with his whip; he left the waggon on the left hand; he was on the right of the chaise and the left of the waggon; after he had struck the fore horse he rode on, and rode a little way; the waggoner call'd him 3 or 4 names, and said, what busin ess had you to do so,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090023"></xptr> he might swear, but that I cannot say; he returned back immediately and cut the horses 3 or 4 times, till the horses went out of the road; we were all afraid at that time, that the horses would turn the waggon over in the ditch.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words?</p>
               <p>Tooth. They were, as near as I can guess, what business have you to meddle with the horses.</p>
               <p>Q. Who spoke them?</p>
               <p>Tooth. The waggoner spoke them; he rode up and flourished his whip, he struck at us in the waggon, but whether he hit any body I don't know; and directly said, if this will not do you shall have something here that will do for you; then he clap'd his hand to his side and drew his hanger; I am not certain whether he drew his hanger before the deceased got out of the waggon; neither am I certain whether he jump'd out or fell out; he was sitting in the tail of the waggon directly when he got out with a little willow stick in his hand about 3 foot long, I saw it in his hand when he got out of the waggon; he went up to the prisoner, and as he had struck at every body, there was a sort of a scuffle between them.</p>
               <p>Q. Explain what you mean by that scuffle?</p>
               <p>Tooth. They seem'd to be striking at one another, one with the hanger the other with the stick.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the stick in motion?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I saw the stick come, but whether he struck the prisoner I don't know.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that before he drew his hanger, or afterwards?</p>
               <p>Tooth. His hanger was drawn then.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether or not the prisoner had struck the deceased with his hanger before you observed the deceased to complain?</p>
               <p>Tooth. Within a few minutes I heard him cry out my hand is off; there were 2 or 3 blows past between them before I heard the cry, O, he has cut my hand off.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say, that either of them blows light upon either of them?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I did not see a blow light upon either.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say, that the deceased had struck the prisoner before he receiv'd the blow given by the hanger?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the hanger drawn or not drawn when you saw the stick lifted up?</p>
               <p>Tooth. Before the stick was lifted up I saw the hanger drawn.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he made any blow at the deceased before such time he lifted up the stick?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I do not know that he had, he had waved his hanger before that.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you imagine that was for?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I imagine in order to save himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Why?</p>
               <p>Tooth. Because the man got out of the waggon, and went up to him; the deceased had a stick in his hand, and might strike at him; but I did not see it hit him; after the wound was given we got out of the waggon directly, except the woman, I don't know whether she got out or no; when I got out of the waggon I saw the deceas'd's hand, the wrist was quite full of blood, it bled vastly; we pursued him, and call'd stop thief, and run all the way to Hounslow as fast as we could, and he stood at the Rose and Crown gate; the waggoner that belong'd to the waggon saw him first; he said, that is the man, I'll take my oath of it. Directly I made answer, as soon as I saw him, come all away, for fear of mischief, I know him, he lives with Mr. Secretary 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person224">
                  Pitt
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person224" type="given" value="Pitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; then directly he made an offer to run after me, with his hanger, because I knew him; I run away from him, and glad enough I was, or else he would have given me a slash; we went and got a couple of constables, and took him before a magistrate.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time Mr. Roberts whipp'd the horses at first, was the chaise marine gone by?</p>

               <p>Tooth. The chaise was gone by.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the waggoners speak to their horses, to encourage their horses to go on?</p>
               <p>Tooth. Not a word as I heard.</p>
               <p>Q. When the deceased got out of the waggon, what distance was it from the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Tooth. 4 or 5 yards.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he go up to Roberts, or Roberts come to him?</p>
               <p>Tooth. He went up to Roberts, I suppose he was angry.</p>
               <p>Q. Who went out of the waggon with him?</p>
               <p>Tooth. His partner followed him directly.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was his partner?</p>
               <p>Tooth. That is Davidson.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour was the waggoner's coat?</p>
               <p>Tooth. He had a light colour'd coat on.</p>
               <p>Q. Had any body a stick in their hands besides the deceased?</p>
               <p>Tooth. No, nobody.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see his stick move up and down?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I did.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090024"></xptr>Q. Did you see him strike?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I imagine he must strike, I saw it in motion.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you recollect how often you saw it in motion?</p>
               <p>Tooth. May be 2 or 3 motions, I can't say, that was all the defence he had against the hanger.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he immediately go up to Mr. Roberts, as soon as he got out of the waggon.</p>
               <p>Tooth. He did.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Tooth. He was then sitting on horseback, they soon got together, they were not far apart.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any stones thrown?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I did not see it, the waggoner throw'd stones, that was all the defence he had, or he would have been cut in two.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after the deceased got out of the waggon that the waggoner got out?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I am not certain, whether it was before the wound was given, I think he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any gravel thrown at the prisoner before the wound was given?</p>
               <p>Tooth. No, nothing in the world.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when the wound was given?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I was in the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. What was done after the wound given?</p>
               <p>Tooth. The prisoner rode away directly after that.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he dirty at all?</p>
               <p>Tooth. His face was very dirty, and his cloaths spotted with dirt, by people throwing at him to save themselves.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you when he rode away?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I did not get out of the waggon till after he rode away.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after he rode away?</p>
               <p>Tooth. It might not be half a minute after, he rode away as fast as he could, and we call'd stop thief.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you see him afterwards?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I saw him at the Rose and Crown in Hounslow, standing in the gateway.</p>
               <p>Q. What open to the public road where carriaes come in?</p>
               <p>Tooth. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any horsemen pursue him?</p>
               <p>Tooth. No, there were no horsemen; there was a man offered a guinea for a horse to pursue him to London.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was he?</p>
               <p>Tooth. His name is Lomas.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner then in custody, or not?</p>
               <p>Tooth. He was not in the custody of any body, till we got the constables to take him, none of us dare go near him.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then from what appear'd to you, he might have rode straight to London, and escap'd?</p>
               <p>Tooth. Yes, he might. We all went before justice Bulstrode at Hounslow; the justice enquired, and sent for a surgeon, the surgeon of the regiment, and surgeon of the town, they both dress'd the wound; he said, please your worship let me go to London to-night, I have a great deal of business upon me. The justice said I cannot, if it was Mr. Pitt himself; he order'd us to sit up with the prisoner all night long, and search him. When he was in the gateway he said to a chairman, I wish I had had a pistol, I would have shot you. What for, said I; for his insolence, said he; what, said I, because people have not so much wit as you, you call them insolent.</p>
               <p>Q. What was that chairman's name?</p>
               <p>Tooth. It is 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person225">
                  John 
                  Lomas 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person225" type="surname" value="Lomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person225" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the deceased been on his legs in the waggon before he got out of it?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I was sitting by the woman playing the rogue, and did not take notice; I did not see him on his legs at all, I was looking more after the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the deceased a stick in his hand in the waggon?</p>
               <p>Tooth. He had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him shake it while in the waggon?</p>
               <p>Tooth. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take notice of the whip the prisoner had in his hand?</p>
               <p>Tooth. To the best of my remembrance it was a short lash'd whip, I believe it was, I am not certain, I did not apprehend it had a thong to it; you will find it a streight whip when it comes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it longer than the stick?</p>
               <p>Tooth. I did not measure them, I don't know.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say, when you came to Hounslow none of you dare to take him.</p>
               <p>Tooth. Because he had a hanger drawn in his hand within the door, that was the reason we took the constables.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the hanger drawn when they came?</p>
               <p>Tooth. Yes, and he opposed at first, and afterwards said, let me have the constable I'll surrender, and he surrender'd himself directly; we did not dare to go within 10 yards of him hardly; he said to one of the constables, come here I'll cut your ears off, and make a baker of you; but afterwards he did surrender.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090025"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person226">
                  John 
                  Lomas 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person226" type="surname" value="Lomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person226" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with the rest of them on Hounslow heath on the 7th of May.</p>
               <p>Court. Tell your story what you saw.</p>
               <p>Lomas. There was Davidson, Tooth, I and the deceased coming from Windsor; there was a waggon coming to town, we ask'd the waggoners to give us a cast, which they agreed to; we all 4 got up in the waggon, and was overtaken by the prisoner on horseback, and a cover'd cart; we were on the left hand side the road, he rode up, and whipp'd the sore horse out of the road into the ditch; the waggoner ask'd him what he did that for? he turn'd back and whipp'd the horses a 2d time, and drove us out of the road a 2d time, they had some words with one another.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of words?</p>
               <p>Lomas. I can't tell what words, they were angry words, there might be an oath or two, to know the reason of his using us so, and calling names; then he rode up to the side of the waggon, to horsewhip us, and I got a blow on my chin.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the waggon covered?</p>
               <p>Lomas. No, it was an open waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he strike at you, or promiscuously, as you were all together, or any one in particular?</p>
               <p>Lomas. No one in particular, any one he could come at.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceas'd in the waggon at that time?</p>
               <p>Lomas. He was, he had a little stick in his hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him use it?</p>
               <p>Lomas. I saw the stick up, but whether he hit I cannot say.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that when he was in the waggon?</p>
               <p>Lomas. It was.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do with it when it was up?</p>
               <p>Lomas. I saw it up waving, I could not perceive whether it hit Mr. Roberts or not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you imagine he might be striking at him?</p>
               <p>Lomas. I imagine he might.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that before or after his whipping at you?</p>
               <p>Lomas. It was after his striking with the whip; whether the deceased tumbled out, or jump'd out of the waggon I know not; but he and his partner and one of the waggoners were out of the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. What happen'd then?</p>
               <p>Lomas. I saw no blow given by the cutlass, but heard the deceased cry out, O, my arm is cut.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe the stick in the deceased's hand when he was out of the waggon?</p>
               <p>Lomas. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you first observe after they 3 were out of the waggon?</p>
               <p>Lomas. The first thing was, I heard the deceas'd cry out, his arm was cut.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see nothing done till then?</p>
               <p>Lomas. No, I was not out of the waggon at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see no blow given on either side till you heard him cry out?</p>
               <p>Lomas. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say?</p>
               <p>Lomas. His arm was cut.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first see the hanger drawn?</p>
               <p>Lomas. I did not see it drawn till the prisoner was riding away.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance of time do you conceive from the time of the deceas'd going out of the waggon, till you heard him say his arm was cut?</p>
               <p>Lomas. O, very soon after that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing concerning his hanger before?</p>
               <p>Lomas. No, nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner, when you heard the deceased say his arm was cut.</p>
               <p>Lomas. He was then riding by the waggon, and I jump'd out and pursued with one of the waggoners.</p>
               <p>Q. How far did you pursue?</p>
               <p>Lomas. Into Hounslow town, we made the best of our way to know who he was, and he cut several times at the young man and me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do?</p>
               <p>Lomas. We call'd stop thief, the young man stoop'd down, and throw'd up gravel at him; he made several cuts at us, we overtook him at the end of Hounslow town, and we were withinside the rails; he said to the waggoner and me, come up, and I'll do for you, he had his hanger then drawn in his hand; he rode away from us there, and we lost sight of him, we ran down the town, and could see nothing of him, but turned back again, and they had got the deceased into the inn. I went into the inn and he was bleeding; I ran out at the gateway, and said, I'll give any body a guinea for a horse to pursue, to know who he is; the waggoner and I went down the town, the prisoner was standing at the Rose and Crown, with his hanger drawn on his arm at the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Lomas. The waggoner said, I'll be upon my oath that is the man. Tooth look'd at him, and said, I know him, his name is Roberts, he lives with secretary Pitt, in St. James's square; he cut at Tooth; he ran away, and desired me to come away, for fear of being cut.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090026"></xptr>Q. Did he attempt to cut any body?</p>
               <p>Lomas /. I saw him make a blow at Tooth with his hanger; he was taken at last by the 2 constables and me, the others were by at the time. He had been in a little room, and had laid his hanger on the table, and was gone out, and the constable came and knock'd at the door; the prisoner went in, and took the hanger up, and told us, no body should come into the room but the constable; he surrender'd himself, I went into the room afterwards, and he told me, if he had had his pistol he would have shot me; I ask'd him for what reason? he told me, for my insolence; I heard him tell one of the constables, he would cut off his ears, and make a baker of him.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether at the time you have been speaking of being pursued, and making several cuts, the prisoner had any notice of the accident or mischief that he had done to the man?</p>
               <p>Lomas. I do not know whether he knew he had given such a prodigious wound.</p>
               <p>Q. Were those cuts made at you, in order to avoid your taking of him, from the apprehension of the consequences of the injury he had done, or to avoid any assault from you?</p>
               <p>Lomas. That I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether the deceased was or was not on his legs in the waggon at the time he flourished and waved his stick at the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Lomas. I can't tell whether he was on his legs or no, he was the only one that had a stick in the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time the deceased, and his companion and waggoner getting out, had you your eye upon the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Lomas. I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you notice what kind of a whip it was?</p>
               <p>Lomas. I think I can tell it, it was a hand whip, not with a thong to it, I did not perceive a thong, to the best of my knowledge I saw it in the parlour where he was.</p>
               <p>Q. Should you not have seen it, if he had had a hanger in his hand at the time they 3 were getting out of the waggon?</p>
               <p>Lomas. I did not see the hanger in his hand, and what I did not see, I cannot say, it was partly dark, it was about 8 in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q. Might the prisoner have escaped if he would?</p>
               <p>Lomas. He might easily have escaped.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a stick was it the deceased had?</p>
               <p>Lomas. It was a willow twig, about as thick as my finger; Davidson saw the deceased cut it as we came along.</p>
               <p>Q. to Davidson. Whether the whip the prisoner had, had a long thong or a lash, that is as it were straight at the end of it?</p>
               <p>Davidson. To the best of my judgment it was a thong, but I cannot be particular in it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person227">
                  Mary 
                  Carter 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person227" type="surname" value="Carter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person227" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the waggon at the time this mischief happened, I was a passenger.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts in the waggon was you?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. I was sitting by the waggoner close to the head of the waggon; the prisoner and the chaise went on by the fore horse; he turn'd and hit the fore horse on the head; then the waggoner that had the whip in his hand said to 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person228">
                  Wm 
                  Shotter 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person228" type="surname" value="Shotter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person228" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , the other waggoner, mind that; 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person229">
                  Wm 
                  Shotter 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person229" type="surname" value="Shotter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person229" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, what is that for?</p>
               <p>Q. Who did he speak to?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. To the prisoner; then the prisoner said nothing at all, but turn'd again, and repeated the blows more than once or twice, he struck the fore horse again, and turn'd the fore horse shear round, and hit the middle horse also; then the waggoner, and others that were in the waggon, said, what do you do that for; there were words arose between them.</p>
               <p>Q. What words?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. Angry words; then the prisoner rode up to the side of the waggon, and held the lash of his whip in his hand; it was a longish whip, he held it double, he held the lash and handle in his hand, and hit 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person230">
                  John 
                  Lomas 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person230" type="surname" value="Lomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person230" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he was mark'd somewhere in the face; after he had struck several blows with his whip, he said, if you don't like this, you shall have that, and drew his hanger immediately.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the deceased at the time he drew his hanger?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. I think he was at the hinder part of the waggon, I was at the fore part; I cannot say whether he was in or not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the next thing you observed when he said, if you don't like this you shall have that?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. The chairman got out of the waggon, the deceased.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him get out?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. I did not, they said he was down.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you observe after that declaration?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. I saw the hanger up, and I saw it go down, and I heard the blow; I heard the words, he has cut my partners hand off.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090027"></xptr>Q. Did you hear the deceased say any thing?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Who do you mean by partner?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. Davidson spoke he meant the deceased?</p>
               <p>Q. When the prisoner came up with his horsewhip to the side of the waggon, did he strike at any particular person?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. No one in particular.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the deceased in the waggon at that time?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. He was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any blows given to the prisoner before the hanger was drawn?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. Nobody attempted it, nor the waggoner never so much as shook his whip at him, he always gave good words, and desired him to be easy, there were no blows at all struck but what the prisoner struck.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there no ill words?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. There were words past, they were not very good ones.</p>
               <p>Q. What will you call them?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. There were angry words, I can't say any thing in particular, there were nothing said in anger till after he struck the horses a second time; they only ask'd him what he did so for.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the word blackguard?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. I don't know any body that call'd blackguard.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear swearing?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. I don't know that there was swearing; I had a child with me, a little boy.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased move his stick in the waggon?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What distance was the horse that Mr. Roberts was on from the waggon when the deceased got out?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. I cannot tell, I take it to be at the hinder part of the waggon when he jump'd out.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether the deceased went to the prisoner, or the prisoner to him?</p>
               <p>M. Carter. They were soon met, I cannot tell which moved towards the other.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person231">
                  John 
                  Bayles 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person231" type="surname" value="Bayles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person231" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was one of the Waggoners; on the 7th of May last I was coming along with my waggon, about a hundred yards from the 10 mile stone, on the near side the road, there came this gentleman on horseback (I'll tell the truth, one man is as much to me as another) there was a tilted cart with him, with two horses in it, the cart went by us; after it was by us, the gentleman took his whip in his left hand, and struck our horse over the head as he past the horse.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts in the waggon was you?</p>
               <p>Bayles. I was in the fore part of the waggon; I said, what does the man mean by striking the horse; so did my fellow servant; he turn'd his horse round, and came and struck the fore horse again 2 or 3 times, and likewise the body horse; upon which words arose in the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of words?</p>
               <p>Bayles. Spiteful words, as other people will say, if their horses are beat in the road; this was among the chairmen, I never spoke a word; the prisoner road back to the side of the waggon, and flourished his whip over the side of the waggon, whether he struck any body I can't say, I saw nobody struck.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you mean by flourishing his whip, did he strike at them?</p>
               <p>Bayles. I can't say he did, but he flourished his whip over amongst them; the deceased said, for your impudence, if I was out of the waggon, I should not begrudge to lay you on with my stick; he had a little white stick in his hand. Said the prisoner, what don't you like it, if you don't like that, you shall have this, and drew his hanger.</p>
               <p>Q. What happened after this?</p>
               <p>Bayles. The first thing that I heard; for I did not know that the man was out of the waggon, I heard the deceased call out, lord have mercy upon me, I have lost my hand, or he has cut my hand; I did not see a blow struck. I saw the sword drawn when the prisoner mentioned them words, if you don't like that you shall have this. My partner and one of the chairmen jump'd out of the waggon; I found the deceased was out of the waggon then; my fellow servant said to the chairman get down; the gentleman on horseback made towards my fellow servant, his horse did.</p>

               <p>Q. Do you suppose the horse went of his own accord?</p>
               <p>Bayles. I suppose he did not without being guided.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the hanger then drawn?</p>
               <p>Bayles. It was; my partner had nothing to defend himself with (it was wet, slappy weather) he stoop'd, and gathered up some dirt, there might be stones in it, but not very bigg, he hit both him and his horse; the horse being a spirited horse would not come nigh him; he immediately turn'd into a gallop, and they ran after him; I was in the waggon all the time; they ran after him, calling<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090028"></xptr> stop thief; they all left me and the woman in the waggon; and I got out, and drove the horses I saw the prisoner afterwards in Hounslow as I came by.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether when the prisoner first drew his hanger, was the deceased in or out of the waggon.</p>
               <p>Bayles. I cannot say justly; for I did not know that he was out of the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon after the deceased said I should not grudge laying you on with this stick, that you heard him call out of his hand?</p>
               <p>Bayles. It was some small triffle of time, a very small time.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Was it a minute or 2?</p>
               <p>Bayles. I cannot say to a minute, I will not wrong my conscience.</p>
               <p>Counsel. I think you say he struck the fore horse, just as he past him?</p>
               <p>Bayles. As he past him, and the second time he came back and struck him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the chaise then?</p>
               <p>Bayles. That was gone by, and he was riding by as he struck him first.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the chaise past your horses when he first struck the fore horse?</p>
               <p>Bayles. I believe their horses might be gone by our horses; I think he was at the tail of their chaise, they were going on very fast.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was your waggon to their chaise?</p>
               <p>Bayles. I dare say there was room enough for any carriage to go between them and us.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person232">
                  William 
                  Shotter 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person232" type="surname" value="Shotter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person232" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Fellow servant to the last witness; on the 7th of May, about 8 o'clock in the evening, I was assisting in driving this waggon; we had been to Eaton with a load of leather; on this side Cranford bridge we overtook 4 chairmen, they ask'd us to ride as far as Hounslow; we told them they might get up, they got up; when we got within 200 yards on the other side the 10 mile stone, the gentleman on horseback, and a tilted cart, came and overtook us; they came along very fast, going along by us the gentleman took his whip in his left hand, and with the butt end of it hit the fore horse on his head, and our horses went out of the road.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was he to the chaise marine then?</p>
               <p>Shotter. He was by the side of it, that is what I call'd a tilted cart.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the chaise gone past your waggon?</p>
               <p>Shotter. It was past the body of the waggon, but not past the horses.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was it to the waggon?</p>
               <p>Shotter. There was room enough between us for another carriage; I said what is your fancy for hitting the horse?</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts in the waggon was you?</p>
               <p>Shotter. I was in the middle of the waggon, my partner set first, and I next him; the prisoner immediately turn'd round, and I believe he was 2 horses length before us; he turned back and hit the horse again once or twice; then he repeated his blow on the next horse, call'd the body horse; then he came to the body of the waggon, I heard his whip come against something, but I did not see the whip, it was like lashing; then the deceased shook his stick at him that he had in his hand; said he, if I could get at you I would not grudge to lay you on with this; said the prisoner, D - n you, don't you like it, if you don't you shall have this; speaking to the man that shook his stick.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing in the prisoner's hand at the time he mentioned that expression?</p>
               <p>Shotter. He immediately clap'd his hand on his hanger, and drew it; there was something happened that I did not mention when before the coroner, which I have since recollected (that was this) as soon as he drew his hanger, he said, you are chairman, I know what you are, and where you ply. Then the chairmen wanted to get out of the waggon; I laid hold on his arm to prevent him getting out, fearing Mr. Roberts should do him a mischief, for he waved his sword about very much.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you appehend he wanted to get out of the waggon for?</p>
               <p>Shotter. I could not be a judge.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he his stick in his hand then?</p>
               <p>Shotter. I think he had, but I cannot be positive; when I let him go, I cannot be positive, whether it was by a jolt of the waggon, or whether by a fright, I look'd towards the fore horse, and turning my head back again he was out of the waggon; I saw him on the ground on his back in the dirt, I went to jump out of the waggon, thinking he was hurt; and the chairman, who was first examined, jumped out at the same time; before I could recover myself, I found Mr. Roberts and the deceased in a sort of a scuffle together.</p>
               <p>Q. Describe as exactly as you can this scuffle.</p>
               <p>Shotter. I saw the sword waver up and down 2 or 3 times.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the stick in the deceased's hand then?</p>
               <p>Shotter. I do not remember that I did; this was before the blow given.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090029"></xptr>Q. What was the deceased doing at the time that the prisoner was flourishing his sword?</p>
               <p>Shotter. They were very nigh together, in that instant I heard him cry out, O, my hand, my hand, I have lost my hand, or something to that effect; then the prisoner rode towards me wavering his sword, I had nothing to defend myself with, but I gathered up dirt, and as he came to cut at me, I flung it up in his and his horse's face in this manner ( describing, by stooping with his belly near the ground, and with his hand casting up the dirt backwards (as he kept his backside to him) into the horse's face;) I believe it went both in his and his horse's face, but kept the horse off; then he rode off, and I and 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person233">
                  John 
                  Lomas 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person233" type="surname" value="Lomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person233" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person233" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             follow'd him, calling stop thief.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take particular notice of the prisoner's whip?</p>
               <p>Shotter. I can't say whether it was a long or a short whip; we overtook him at Hounslow, at justice Bulstrode's rails; he rode up to the rails, and struck at us, but especially at me, and said to me, D - n you come out, and I'll do for you; I told him to put up his sword and I would.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he put his sword up?</p>
               <p>Shotter. No, he did not; then he rode on pretty fast, and we ran a little way down the town after him; we lost sight of him, and came back to see how the deceased was; we went in at the Red Lion, there was a surgeon dressing the deceased; the deceased said he was almost spent with the loss of blood, there was a great deal of blood on the floor; I went out again; then Lomas said, he would give a guinea for a horse to pursue. I said to him, let you and I run forward to Brentford, it is my opinion we may overtake him, as somebody said he did not go very fast; said he, with all my heart; we ran along, and at the Rose and Crown door there the prisoner stood; whether he had his hanger drawn then I cannot say, I was the first man that came up to him, he stood up against one of the posts in the gateway; said I, that is the man, I'll sware to him; said he, come on, if you want me, what do you want with me, and drew his hanger, if it was not drawn before. Said I, put up your sword, for you have done mischief enough with it already, you have cut one man's hand off already. Said he, and God d - n you, I'll cut your's off, and made at me directly; I got into the road, and flung up dirt at him as before; then I made to our company; then there came up David Tooth, he look'd at him, and said, my lad come away, I know him, his name is Roberts, he lives with Mr. Secretary 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person234">
                  Pitt
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person234" type="given" value="Pitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person234" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; our waggon came up by that time; then the prisoner ran up with his sword drawn to my partner, and desired to know whose team it was; my partner ask'd me to come along home; I said, I was afraid to go home; then we went home with the waggon and the woman.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. At the time you had hold on the deceased's arm, that he insisted upon getting out of the waggon, what did he say to you?</p>
               <p>Shotter. I don't remember he said any words, but be seem'd to struggle to get out of the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Mr. Roberts near the deceased when he was all along upon the ground?</p>
               <p>Shotter. No, I think he only got on his legs when the scuffle began; I think it was on the same spot.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the stick?</p>
               <p>Shotter. I don't know, it was not left in the waggon, I never saw him with it after he was out; the thing was done in a minute's time.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a loaded or an empty waggon?</p>
               <p>Shotter. It was an empty waggon, with 3 horses.</p>
               <p>Q. When you saw Mr. Roberts in the town, was he in the custody of any body?</p>
               <p>Shotter. No, he was not.</p>
               <p>Q. When he said they were chairmen, and he knew were they ply'd, had he received any injury from them do you think?</p>
               <p>Shotter. There were only bad words, which there were on both sides, and I think the prisoner gave as bad as he received.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person235">
                  William 
                  Fregley 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person235" type="surname" value="Fregley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person235" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person235" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon and apothecary, and live at Hounslow; I was sent for to attend the deceased at the Red Lion; I remember it was the day after the installation; when I came there, there was a person scraping of lint, I look'd upon to be a surgeon, I thought then I had nothing to do; I found the man standing in the gateway; I said, why are you here; he said, I can't stand no where else, I have fowl'd my breeches; the wound seem'd to me to be cut quite through the bone; the bleeding was stop'd by the other person, I had nothing to do but to secure it will they got him to the hospital.</p>
               <p>Q. From the experience you have, do you or do you not apprehend it might be the death of the person?</p>
               <p>Frogley. Yes, it might; I never saw him since that.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090030"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person236">
                  John 
                  Riddle 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person236" type="surname" value="Riddle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person236" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person236" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the deceased on the morning of the 8th of May, after he came to town, at his own house, he had lost a great deal of blood, and was in a great deal of pain; I was under the apprehension that he would bleed to death; I let him alone for some days to prevent a farther effusion; the wound was cross the wrist, the bone and artery were both divided; I attended him constantly till the time of his death, which was on the 18th of the same month; at last he was taken all of a sudden, with a violent fever, and that carried him off.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you look upon to be the occasion of his death?</p>
               <p>Riddle. I look upon it, his death was the consequence of the wound.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. From the situation of the wound, whether it was possible, that a blow should be given while the deceased was holding up his hand in a defensive way?</p>
               <p>Riddle. I apprehend the deceased must have been in an offensive situation, to have received the wound in that place as it appear'd; had the hand been held up, and the cut struck downwards, the cut would have went towards the shoulder; but it appears to me, the hand was not up, for the cut went a slant towards the fingers.</p>
               <p>Mr. Tompkins. I was desired by Mr. Roberts the prisoner to attend the deceased, which I did, along with Mr. Riddle, the whole time; he went on in a favourable manner some time, but at last a violent fever came on, and notwithstanding all the efforts made use of, the fever carry'd him off.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you think was the cause of his death?</p>
               <p>Tompkins. The fever was occasioned by the wound, I have no doubt of that, and he died of that fever.</p>
               <p>Mr. Pickford. I am an apothecary.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you conceive to be the cause of the deceased's death?</p>
               <p>Pickford. I believe the cause of his death was a fever, proceeding by the wound.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>My Lord, it is my misfortune to appear at this bar, but it is great comfort to me, that I feel myself innocent of the crime I am charg'd with; no one is more heartily concern'd for the accident which befell the deceased than I am; but he, poor man, and his companions, were the occasion of its all that know me can testify, that I never was addicted to quarrelling, a revengeful temper is no part of my character; and as to any malice towards the unhappy deceased, I never saw him before in my life; the truth my Lord is, that the provocations I received were what no man besides could have borne with. I wish, my Lord, I could; not for my own sake only, but for the sake of the poor deceased. Notwithstanding, my Lord, what is sworn by some of the witnesses, I assure your Lordship, that I never drew my hanger till I had been assaulted, and pelted at; nor us'd it, till the deceased himself had even attempted to catch hold of my bridle; the blows I received from the deceased upon my shoulder was so great and painful, that the effects of it were visible for 14 days after, and the several other blows which I afterwards received from his companions, inflam'd me, and made me insensible of what I did; sorry I am, my Lord, for it's consequences, but I depend upon the justice of this honourable court for my acquittal.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person237">
                  Edward 
                  Cooper 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person237" type="surname" value="Cooper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person237" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person237" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Secretary 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person238">
                  Pitt
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person238" type="given" value="Pitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person238" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the prisoner is groom of the chamber, not in livery.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your imploy?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I work at the farming business; I drove the chaise marine on the 7th of May; he was along with me, he was guide; there were a great many valuable things in the chaise, jewels and things of great value; we were on Hounslow Heath, coming up to this waggon, very near the town; there were several chairman in the waggon, they were going along the same tract that I was; I got out to pass them on the right hand; I was sitting on the seat to drive, and Mrs. Matthews along with me; I was driving fu ll trot; they were walking very slow; just as I got over right them they whipp'd and cut their horses, and I thought they had a mind to drive against me; their horses came along full trot, rather faster than I; with that Mr. Roberts rode in between, and with his whip he wore their horses that I got past them; he just bore them that they did not come against me, after I was got by, then they drove up a 2d time, but rather faster then they did the first, then Mr. Roberts rode along against their horses again, and held his whip, and wore them away to the left again.</p>
               <p>Q. What words were made use of the 1st time?</p>
               <p>Cooper. There were no words made use of the 1st time; after they came the 2d time, they seem'd<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090031"></xptr> not to get away, then he gave them a cut with his whip, and turned then on the other side of the road, this was the first stroke he made.</p>
               <p>Q. How near were they then to the waggon?</p>
               <p>Cooper. They were sideway rather before me, they were getting ground of me, I believe the body of the waggon was about equal with my chaise marine, or rather behind, but that I cannot say, their horses kept on, and got some distance before me, but they were on the other side of the way; with that I heard several words from the chairmen, that is, the found of them, what they were I could not understand, upon the account of the waggon making such a noise, and also my chaise marine. Mr. Roberts had a short hand whip, with a short lash; one of the chairmen had a white stick, he shook his stick very much towards Mr. Roberts.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the waggon before you or behind at that time?</p>
               <p>Cooper. When I got clear of him, it was before me at first, and it was before me when he shook his stick; I saw him make 2 or 3 attempts to get out of the waggon; I kept on my old pace as at first, and got by, and saw no more, I sat under a cover, so that I could not well see them when behind me. I stopt at Hounslow, Mr. Roberts overtook me as I was going along, I believe before I came to the inn where I rested my horses, the same inn where he was taken up at; I did not know then what accident had happened; soon after came the people with the waggon, then I heard how it was, I lay there that night.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was not the road broad enough for you to have past without any interruption at all?</p>
               <p>Cooper. Yes</p>
               <p>Q. How came that into your fancy, to think the waggoner whipp'd their horses intending to cross the way upon you?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I heard them whip and speak, as if seemingly they bore up to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see them whip?</p>
               <p>Cooper. No; I sware to the found, it was the lash of a whip, I did not know who it was, but I perceived the horses bore up to me.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the men say?</p>
               <p>Cooper. They said bite and gee to their horses; and I saw Mr. Roberts come to put them out of my way.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the waggoners at that time?</p>
               <p>Cooper. They were in the waggon when I first saw them, and I never saw them out of the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they overtake you a second time?</p>
               <p>Cooper. They got rather before me, their sore horse was rather before mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you keep on?</p>
               <p>Cooper. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. How big was the stick as the man shook at Mr. Roberts?</p>
               <p>Cooper. It appeared to me to be bigger than my finger.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts was Mr. Roberts when he shook his stick?</p>
               <p>Cooper. He was about half a dozen yards behind the waggon then.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person239">
                  Mary 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person239" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person239" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person239" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Bath, I had been at the installation; I was on the seat with the last witness on the chaise marine; at this time on Hounslow Heath we saw a waggon before us, there were people in it, we were going a trot; when we came nearer them, they went a good deal faster, and we past by them; after that the waggon came a very fast pace on one side us, and indeavoured to cross the road, to get into the track before the chaise, there horses went quite cross; upon which Mr. Roberts came up between the carriages, and with his whip indeavoured to keep the waggon horses off; upon that I heard the men in the waggon make use of very loud words, and swearing, and I believe threatened the prisoner, and the chairmen seem'd to me to be rising up; our carriage still kept on, and left them behind, so that I know nothing as to the blows; when we were got home, Mr. Roberts complain'd very much of his arm; he show'd me a mark on his left shoulder, it was very red, and look'd to me to be swell'd; that morning he said he could not use his arm, and desired me to buckle his stock.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he complained of it before?</p>
               <p>M. Matthews. I never heard him complain of it before.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you imagine it was necessary for him to do what he did to the waggon horses?</p>
               <p>M. Matthews. I do, or else they would have driven against us, and turn the chaise over, or hurt us, our chaise could not bare no more to the right, and they pressing still upon us.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you by when the things were put in the chaise marine?</p>
               <p>M. Matthews. I was; there were strong boxes in them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person240">
                  Evan 
                  Moses 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person240" type="surname" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person240" type="given" value="Evan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person240" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a soldier; I was sent for<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090032"></xptr> from Germany to attend this trial. I was quarter'd at Hounslow at the time, and was passing by on foot when this happened; I first saw the chaise marine about 20 yards before the waggon; I believe I was 30 or 40 yards distance, they were coming towards Hounslow, and I going the other way, the waggon overtook the cart in a short time, when they came along side, they took and drove their horses cross the road.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they speak to the horses?</p>
               <p>Moses. They said to their horses come bether; and I perceiv'd them to whip them; the waggon horses cross'd the other horses, as the cart was on the right hand side the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. How near was the cart to the road side?</p>
               <p>Moses. I can't say that; I believe it was as close as it could be; then Mr. Roberts put his whip again to the horses to keep them from coming upon the cart; he was between the horses in the cart and the horses in the waggon; then the waggon got by the cart, they were going faster than the cart horses; I saw a chairman in the waggon shaking his stick at Mr. Roberts as he past by; Mr. Roberts kept pace with the cart on the left side of the cart. The next thing I observed, was the waggon went a little flower, and the cart overtook them; then they came along side, I saw the chairman making a stroke at Mr. Roberts: I can't tell whether it hit him or not; he made an offer 2 or 3 times after that, but Mr. Roberts gave way to him, and kept a little farther from him; the next thing I observ'd was the chairman came out of the waggon.</p>
               <p>Q. Before you come to that, did you see Mr. Roberts go towards the horses once or twice?</p>
               <p>Moses. I did not observe it but once, that was the first time the waggon past them; but I did not then observe him to strike the horses; the chairman that came out of the waggon had a stick in his hand; Mr. Roberts was then rather behind the waggon; the chairman jump'd out after him, the man in a white coat; then he got rather before Mr. Roberts, and got up gravel, and throw'd it against the horse's head; the horse turn'd about, at that time the chairman was behind the horse; the horse turn'd about and fac'd the chairman; at this time all the chairmen were on the ground, throwing things at the horse, all were about the prisoner throwing at him, and the man with the stick laying upon him, and very often gave him and the horse several blows. Mr. Roberts strove to get his horse from among them to get after the chaise, but could not, for which way soever he went to go they met him, and throw'd gravel in his horse's face, I saw the chairman strike him several times with his stick.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the hanger drawn?</p>
               <p>Moses. I did not; I thought it was a stick.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the man that is dead call out, he has cut my arm?</p>
               <p>Moses. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q Did you see the chairman fall down?</p>
               <p>Moses. No, and if he had I should have seen it; neither did I know that he was cut till I came to Hounslow, which was in about a quarter of an hour; then there were a great mob there; and I was told a chairman was cut; there was a chairman wanted to get one of our men's hangers out of his hand; and said, give it me, and I'll go into the room and cut the rogue's head off: and another said to another chairman, if you had done as much as I did, we wou'd have had him off his horse, and his brains about the road before then.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the waggoner at the time you heard him calling to his horses?</p>
               <p>Moses. He was in the fore part of the waggon, it was a man in a white coat that whipp'd the horses along.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the deceased when he made these offers at the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Moses. He was in the waggon, standing towards the middle of it, it was with a good large stick.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the deceased get out of the waggon?</p>
               <p>Moses. I did; and it was not above 4 or 5 minutes after that he fell to striking the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner with his hanger make a cut at any body in the waggon?</p>
               <p>Moses. No, I did not; I saw him lay about him, but with what I know not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person241">
                  Daniel 
                  Bready 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person241" type="surname" value="Bready"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person241" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person241" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Isleworth, and sell fish and fruit about in the neighbourhood. On the 7th of May last, about 8 o'clock, I saw a man in a blue coat, a chairman, jump out of this waggon, and made a run at a man on horseback, and struck at him twice with a stick or cane, I am not a judge which; I was within about 50 or 60 yards when he began, and I went along nearer and nearer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the blows reach the man on horseback?</p>
               <p>Bready. He could not miss hitting him, without he defended himself. I saw also a man in a white coat stoop down, gathering gravel and dirt,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090033"></xptr> and throwing it at the man on horseback at the time the chairman was striking him with the stick.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the man that is dead cry out?</p>
               <p>Bready. No, I did not; I was not near enough.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him fall?</p>
               <p>Bready. No. I did not; I heard a man say stop the man, for he has cut a man's arm off.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after the dirt was thrown?</p>
               <p>Bready. They were throwing dirt at the same time; I saw the man with the stick strike several times after the dirt was throwing, I am sure of that.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see a soldier on the road at the time?</p>
               <p>Bready. No, I saw no soldier only in the town of Hounslow.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the chairman fall at jumping out of the waggon?</p>
               <p>Bready. I saw his foot slip at jumping out, but he recover'd himself, and made a blow at the man on horseback.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts was that man on horseback when the chairman ran up to him?</p>
               <p>Bready. He was about the 2d horse in the waggon at that time.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the man on horseback any instrument in his hand?</p>
               <p>Bready. I can't tell. I did not see any thing in his hand, his back was towards me, and I did not observe, I had a tub of salmon on my head, and for that reason I kept out of the mob; the time that the chairman ran at him he was a naked man; I believe he gave his horse a spur and rode away; he was oblig'd to ride away, there were 5 or 6 of them.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was all this about after the man got out of the waggon?</p>
               <p>Bready. Not a great while.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not see a hanger?</p>
               <p>Bready. I saw a hanger in his hand when he set off.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it drawn?</p>
               <p>Bready. It was, but I did not see him strike at any body.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you going?</p>
               <p>Bready. I was going from Hounslow to a gentleman's house.</p>
               <p>C. for prisoner. This witness says he saw no soldier. This same soldier was examined by the prosecutors themselves the next morning before a justice of peace, and the deposition was return'd.</p>
               <p>The deposition produced.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person242">
                  Evan 
                  Moses 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person242" type="surname" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person242" type="given" value="Evan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person242" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Was that the truth that you mentioned before the justice of the peace when this deposition was taken?</p>
               <p>Moses. It was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person243">
                  Wm 
                  Marsden 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person243" type="surname" value="Marsden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person243" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person243" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mr. Fielding's; I remember that soldier being examin'd before justice Fielding; the examination was return'd; here this is it. There was an information made before the justice against the waggoners, for riding in their waggon, and not having a driver; the waggoners were convicted upon the evidence of Mr. Roberts, and this soldier.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this examination only relative to that of the riding in the waggon to drive?</p>
               <p>Marsden. The information was to take the truth of every thing; every thing he had to say was taken; we did not know but the man might die that had been cut (which he did afterwards) so it was taken to the whole of all he had to say.</p>
               <p>It is read to this purport.</p>
               <p>That on wednesday last, about 8 in the evening, he was taking a walk, upon Hounslow Heath; he observed a tilted cart and waggon driving towards London; that he saw the person then present (Mr. Roberts) accompanying the said cart on horseback; that he observed, the said waggon to be drove improperly against the said tilted cart; and that Mr. Roberts endeavour'd to drive the said horses on one side the road in order that the said tilted cart might have a free passage; that there were in the said waggon several chairmen, who, after he had so endeavour'd to drive the said waggon on one side the road, shook their sticks at the said Mr. Roberts; and that he saw nothing more pass.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person244">
                  Stafford 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person244" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person244" type="given" value="Stafford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person244" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am one of his majesty's messengers; I was at Mr. Secretary 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person245">
                  Pitt
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person245" type="given" value="Pitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person245" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's on the 8th of May, between 10 and 10; Mr. Roberts came in from Hounslow; I went to take hold of him by the hand, he said, for God's sake Spencer don't touch my hand, I am in such violent pain, by a hurt that I received on my shoulder, that I cannot bare touching; he said, he had been abused by some chairmen at Hounslow.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known him?</p>
               <p>Spencer. I have known him above 3 years, and most days I have seen him; I never knew a better temper'd man, every body that comes to the house have civil, genteel treatment from him; I believe he must have had some very bad treatment, to do an ill-natur'd thing to any man.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176007090034"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person246">
                  John 
                  Monty 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person246" type="surname" value="Monty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person246" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person246" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a messenger; I have known him upwards of 3 years; I saw him on the 13th of May; then I saw a bruise on the upper part of his arm, it appeared very black and much bruised; as to his character, I never-heard a man have a better in my life; he is look'd upon to be as good-natured, inoffensive a man, as any in the world; I have had occasion to be, in his company many times, I never saw him inclin'd to quarrel in my life.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wilbear. I am steward to Mr. Secretary 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person247">
                  Pitt
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person247" type="given" value="Pitt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person247" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and live in the family; I have known Mr. Roberts 5 years and 7 months; he has liv'd with my lady Esther and Mr. Pitt 13 or 14 years; he is a good natured, humane man, far from out-rages or cruelty, willing to make up breaches. On the 15th of May he was showing his arm to some of the servants, I saw it; there was a stroke 3 quarters of an inch wide, it was between 4 and 5 inches in length, like the stroke of a stick, of a dirty blackish yellow cast; it look'd like a bruise worn out, it look'd like the mark of a bruise given about a week before.</p>
               <p>The whip brought into Court; a common hand whip, with a straight lash, about 6 inches from the end of the whip, depos'd too by Cooper to be the same that Roberts had on the 7th of May.</p>
               <p>Dr. Hunter. I have known Mr. Roberts about 3 or 4 years; his behaviour in the family was really civil, I have the best authority for saying it, a man extremely civil and obliging. I saw the body of the deceased open on the coroner's inquest.</p>
               <p>Q. Could that wound be received when the man was acting on the defensive?</p>
               <p>Hunter. I imagine it is impossible; it was just as much cut on the outside as the inside, and cut slanting towards the fingers; it could not be cut as his hand was up, for if so, it would have been slanting towards his body, it must be while his hand was down, or holding the horse's bridle.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing a man was raising his hand, and a blow was to come on that sort, would it not depend much on the direction of the weapon, and the force of the blow, to beat down the arm, and carry it before it.</p>
               <p>Dr. Hunter. When a man is striking at another, he has his face towards him, it must cut him in the direction towards his body, and not towards his fingers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person248">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Sparry 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person248" type="surname" value="Sparry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person248" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person248" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Mr. Pitt's family, 18 years or better, with my Lady Esther, and with Mr. Roberts between 14 and 15 years of that time: when he came into the family first he was my Lady Esther's footman; but, upon his being a diligent servant, he was remov'd to be groom of the chamber; he was always ready to do every good office that was in his power, a civil good-natur'd man, I never knew him quarrelsome, or any instances of cruelty by him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Renoe. I am butler to Mr. Pitt, Mr. Roberts complained of a violent blow he had received at his coming back at that time; I saw the bruise 2 or 3 days after, it appeared blue, black, green and yellow; it was from his shoulder half way down to his elbow; it appeared to be a violent bruise. I have liv'd with him in the family almost 4 years; he is a very humane, good-natur'd man, very serviseable to any one that wants his assistance, far from that of a cruel or passionate man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600709-21-person249">
                  Francis 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person249" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person249" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person249" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Who had known him from a child. 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person250">
                  Edward 
                  Baxton 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person250" type="surname" value="Baxton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person250" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person250" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             28 years. 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person251">
                  Moses 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person251" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person251" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person251" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             from a child. 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person252">
                  John 
                  Matthews 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person252" type="surname" value="Matthews"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person252" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person252" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             6 or 7 years. Jos. Stevens 40 years. 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person253">
                  William 
                  Harris 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person253" type="surname" value="Harris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person253" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person253" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             12 years. 
               <persName id="t17600709-21-person254">
                  Edward 
                  Bishop 
               <interp inst="t17600709-21-person254" type="surname" value="Bishop"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person254" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-person254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             20 years. 2 Mr. Paterson's, one 3 years, the other 5 or 6. Mr. Campion 5 years, and 7 or 8 months. 2 Mr. Howell's, one 6 or 7, the other 12 or 13 years. Mr. Linnel 14 or 15 years. Mr. King 6 or 7 years. Mr. Squib 14 years. Mr. Crisp about 5 years. Mr. Richardson between 6 or 7 years. Mr. Johnson between 6 and 7 years. Mr. Neild between 13 and 14 years. Mr. Sheldon about 14 years. 2 Mr. Jones's, one 13 or 14 years, the other about 9. Mr. Bangham about 8 years. Mr. Price between 15 and 20 years. Mr. Hawkins between 14 and 15 years. Mr. Dawson 15 years. Mr. Wallis about 5 years. Mr. Featherstone almost 2 years. Mr. Summer 7 years. Mr. Holmer 7 years. Mr. Jacket almost 6 years. Mr. Ross 5 or 6 years; and Mr. Creswell, who all depos'd him to be a good natured, peaceable, inoffensive man, not inclinable to passion, quarrelling, or cruelty, but ready to make up breaches where in his power.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoner. We have, I believe, 100 witnesses more to character if needful to call them.</p>
               <p>Court. No man's character was ever better established.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600709-21-verdict115" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-verdict115" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-verdict115" type="verdictSubcategory" value="manslaughter"></interp>
               Guilty of manslaughter
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600709-21-punish116" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-punish116" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600709-21-punish116" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="branding"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600709-21-defend214 t17600709-21-punish116"></join>
               
                     <note>[Branding. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
