<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17651016-26">
               <interp inst="t17651016-26" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-26" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-26" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17651016"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17651016-26" type="date" value="17651016"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17651016-26-off146-c227" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-26-defend277 t17651016-26-off146 t17651016-26-verdict150"></join>
         
               <p>542. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17651016-26-defend277" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Ponsonby 
                  <interp inst="t17651016-26-defend277" type="surname" value="Ponsonby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-defend277" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-defend277" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17651016-26-deflabel145" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-26-defend277 t17651016-26-deflabel145"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17651016-26-off146" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-off146" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-off146" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing four guineas, one half guinea, one quarter guinea, and one moidore
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17651016-26-victim279" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Majour 
                  <interp inst="t17651016-26-victim279" type="surname" value="Majour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-victim279" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-victim279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-26-off146 t17651016-26-victim279"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17651016-26-cd147" type="crimeDate">October 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-26-off146 t17651016-26-cd147"></join>.++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651016-26-person280">
                  John 
                  Majour 
               <interp inst="t17651016-26-person280" type="surname" value="Majour"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-person280" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Newport, in the Isle of Wight. On Tuesday last, in the afternoon, about three or four o'clock, I went in at the <placeName id="t17651016-26-crimeloc148">Three Lemons, in Lemon-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17651016-26-crimeloc148" type="placeName" value="Three Lemons, in Lemon-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17651016-26-crimeloc148" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-26-off146 t17651016-26-crimeloc148"></join>: I never was in the house before or since. I enquired after a person; I was inform'd she was not at home, but gone down to Gravesend; but if I chose a young lady to drink a glass of wine with, there was one in the house, and they introduced the prisoner. I pulled out a green purse, in which were four guineas, one half guinea, one quarter guinea, a moidore, and some silver; I don't know how much. The prisoner snatch'd my purse with the money in it, out of my hand, and ran out of the room: I followed her immediately, but was prevented going out into the street after her: the waiter met me in the passage; he shut the door against me directly, and fell upon me, and beat me. Upon my calling out at the door I was robbed, there was a porter, who went and got a constable; the prisoner was taken, and carried to the watch-house; and in the watch-house the waiter swore with terrible oaths, he never would be easy till he had satisfaction of me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176510160025"></xptr>Q. Have you seen your money since?</p>
               <p>Majour. No, I never have. She was brought back again, but where she had been, I know not.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was she gone, before she was taken?</p>
               <p>Majour. She might be gone an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the prisoner is the person that took your money?</p>
               <p>Majour. I am sure she is the very person.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give her any money?</p>
               <p>Majour. No, I never gave her a farthing in my life; neither was I near her to kiss her lips, any farther than when she came to take a glass of wine from me. When she was before the justice, she declared she was with me, and drank several glasses of wine, but did not take any money: there was nobody else in the house but a soldier, another man, and the waiter. The soldier came to me at the latter end of the time, and forced me out of the house.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been drinking before you came there?</p>
               <p>Majour. I had been drinking two or three pints of wine at the Fox, in Goodman's-fields.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been at any other house that day?</p>
               <p>Majour. I had been at another house about ten o'clock in the morning, and drank two pints of half-and-half.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you drink alone at the Fox?</p>
               <p>Majour. There were several people drank with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any company go in with you?</p>
               <p>Majour. No, I went in alone.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure what money you had in your purse?</p>
               <p>Majour. I had six guineas and a moidore in the morning. I had five guineas and a moidore, when I went in at the Fox.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was your money taken from you?</p>
               <p>Majour. That was about half an hour before dark; it was just coming dark.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you call for at the Three Lemons?</p>
               <p>Majour. I call'd for half a pint of wine.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober when you went in?</p>
               <p>Majour. I was as sober as I am now. I had changed a guinea at the Fox, out of the five; they gave me half a guinea and quarter of a guinea in change.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there no other person in your company at the Three Lemons, but the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Majour. There was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner come voluntarily to you again?</p>
               <p>Majour. No, she was brought in by the waiter. After I charged the house, on account of the woman, then they produced her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not charge another person besides the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Majour. No, I did not. I had no discourse with any body besides her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the house the whole time, till the prisoner was brought to you again?</p>
               <p>Majour. I was.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never saw a purse, nor a farthing of the gentleman's money.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>The witnesses were examined apart.</p>
               <p>Grizzle Hussey. I never saw the prisoner till about ten o'clock last Tuesday evening, at the Three Lemons in Goodman's-fields; I called to see the gentlewoman of the house, that lay-in lately; the prosecutor brought in two women with him; one is named Smith, I made her a gown; they came in about seven o'clock; Mrs. Dutfield was giving suck to her young child; the prosecutor catch'd hold of her arm, and said, You b - h of hell-flames, if you don't deliver me four guineas and a moidore, that was taken from me, I will destroy you, and blow up the house. I sent for a person to come and get the mob away: Mr. Beal came, and the gentleman did not mention a word of the prisoner; he said his pocket had been picked.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he drunk, or sober?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176510160026"></xptr>Hussey. He was very much in liquor. The waiter said the gentleman had been at the Hoop and Bunch of Grapes, the house of one Shelly; not a house of good same.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray what sort of a house is this Three Lemons?</p>
               <p>Hussey. It is a tavern. I believe.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it a house of good or ill same?</p>
               <p>Hussey. I never heard any ill same of the house: the people are lately come into it.</p>
               <p>Court. If you have any pretensions to any character yourself, you will do well to know what sort of a house you come to speak to: Is that a house of of good same where they will produce women to drink with strangers?</p>
               <p>No answer.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you doing there?</p>
               <p>Hussey. I was drinking tea in the parlour forward, with the gentlewoman of the house, and her mother.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after you was in the house, was it that the prosecutor came in?</p>
               <p>Hussey. He came in about half an hour after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him at the door before you came in?</p>
               <p>Hussey. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Which door did you go in at?</p>
               <p>Hussey. I went in at the fore door.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Hussey. I am a mantua-maker, and live at the Crown and Slipper, in Lemon-street.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Dutfield. The prosecutor came into my house, about three or four in the afternoon, last Tuesday; he said there first and last, till he took the people up, which was near nine at night: he was out three times; the first time, I believe, he was gone near an hour: he came back alone, and went out again; that I take to be about five or six: then he was gone about an hour. The next time, he was gone about two hours: then he came in, and did not go out any more. Mrs. Hussey and my mother were drinking tea in the fore parlour: he made a great uproar in the house; he took me by the hand, and d - d, and said, the man had robbed him. I said, have you no money in your pocket? consider where you was last. I said to the waiter, open the door, and let the man go; don't make an uproar about eighteen pence: the gentleman said, You b - h of hell-flames, if you don't give me my moidore, four guineas, and green purse, I'll be death of you. I said, I am not used to these flusterations; why do you behave so? I am sensible nobody here could see your money: he walked out of one room into another, and told us the house where he changed a guinea; he was very much in liquor. When he came in the second time, he brought in a young woman with him; I never saw her in my life before, to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he bring any body else with him?</p>
               <p>Dutfield. I saw nobody else; the house was in great confusion; I believe the prisoner was in a room with him, and drank a glass of wine with him, but she was not long in the room; they were together backwards in the passage, five or ten minutes before she went out. She comes in sometimes, when her mistress sends her for a job in the mantua-making way.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17651016-26-person281">
                  Jonathan 
                  Budge 
               <interp inst="t17651016-26-person281" type="surname" value="Budge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-person281" type="given" value="Jonathan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waiter at the Three Lemons; Mr. Majour came in about three or four o'clock in the afternoon, last Tuesday, and ordered half a pint of Lisbon; my mistress rang the bell, and I went in to wait on him: I saw he was in liquor: said he, I want to enquire for one 
               <persName id="t17651016-26-person282">
                  Mary 
                  Saxby 
               <interp inst="t17651016-26-person282" type="surname" value="Saxby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-person282" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I said she was there, but was then gone to Gravesend said he, is there never a lady to oblige me with her company, to take a glass of wine? this lady being in the house, he said to her, what do you chuse to drink? she said, she chose a pint of port; I carried it in. When the bell rung again, I said, do you call me? he arose up, and was going out of the room; I said, you have not paid your reckoning; you lie, said he: if you don't let me go, I'll call murder and thieves. My mistress desired me to let him go: he said he had lost a green purse, a moidore, four guineas, half a guinea. a quarter guinea, and four shillings in silver; he said he had given me a guinea, and I had not given him his change. I asked the lady if she saw any money pass between him and me? she said no. After that he went out, and was gone some time. My mistress said, never mind it; it is better to lose the reckoning, than have an uproar: he came in at candle-lighting, with two women; my mistress had her little child at her breast, with Mrs. Hussey in the fore room. The gentleman laid his hand on her, and accused her, and struck me: after that I got him out, he struck his hand through a pane of glass in the door. When he was out, I said the woman was one of a very good character, I'll send for her; I went, and she came freely with me.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. As I hope to be saved, the prisoner is the person that took my money; I was not out of the house, till the constable came and took her away. It was the waiter beating me, made me break the glass, by driving me against it, and made me cut my hand.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176510160027"></xptr>Prosecutor. I have been <rs id="t17651016-26-viclabel149" type="occupation">master of a man of war</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17651016-26-victim279 t17651016-26-viclabel149"></join> all this war, and can bring numbers of gentlemen to my character. To be sure I was fool enough to go into that house.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17651016-26-verdict150" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17651016-26-verdict150" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
