<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660409-2">
               <interp inst="t17660409-2" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660409-2" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660409-2" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660409"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660409-2" type="date" value="17660409"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660409-2-off5-c35" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-2-defend38 t17660409-2-off5 t17660409-2-verdict11"></join>
         
               <p>203. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660409-2-defend38" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Stevens 
                  <interp inst="t17660409-2-defend38" type="surname" value="Stevens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-defend38" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-defend38" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660409-2-off5" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-off5" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-off5" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing 4 linen shirts, value 2 s. 3 pair of silk stockings, value 3 s. 3 pair of thread stockings, one yard of gold lace, 3 linen handkerchiefs, and 10 guineas, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660409-2-victim40" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Creswell 
                        <interp inst="t17660409-2-victim40" type="surname" value="Creswell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660409-2-victim40" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660409-2-victim40" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; 3 pair of cotton stockings, a silk handkerchief, a linen ditto, a breast buckle, a hand-whip, 4 pieces of silver coin, value 6 d. and 11 guineas, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660409-2-victim42" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Webb 
                        <interp inst="t17660409-2-victim42" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660409-2-victim42" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660409-2-victim42" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  ; one leather portmanteau and a pair of pistols, the property of the Right Hon. the 
                     <persName id="t17660409-2-victim43" type="victimName">
                        <rs id="t17660409-2-viclabel6" type="occupation">Earl</rs>
                        <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-2-victim43 t17660409-2-viclabel6"></join> of Dartmouth<interp inst="t17660409-2-victim43" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said Earl
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660409-2-cd7" type="crimeDate">March 7</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-2-off5 t17660409-2-cd7"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-2-person44">
                  Thomas 
                  Creswell 
               <interp inst="t17660409-2-person44" type="surname" value="Creswell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person44" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person44" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17660409-2-viclabel8" type="occupation">
                     <rs id="t17660409-2-deflabel9" type="occupation">footman</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-2-defend38 t17660409-2-deflabel9"></join>
                  </rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-2-victim40 t17660409-2-viclabel8"></join> to the Earl of Dartmouth, the prisoner was also one of his Lordship's footmen; the things mentioned in the indictment and prisoner were missing on the morning of the 7th of March, and also one of our horses and a pair of pistols. My things were taken from out of the servants-hall, my box was broke open in which they were. We went directly to Sir 
               <persName id="t17660409-2-person45">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660409-2-person45" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person45" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person45" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and gave an account of the things, and described the prisoner. Sir John sent people out, and the prisoner was taken at Harwich, and brought up and examined before Sir John. I was present, and heard him confess that he had taken the things mentioned; the things found upon him were brought up with him and produced there. (The portmanteau; pistols, shirts, stockings, and handkerchiefs produced in court. This portmanteau and pistols are the property of the Earl of Dartmouth. He takes up the shirts, handkerchiefs and stockings, and deposed to them as his property, which were missing at the time mentioned.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-2-person46">
                  Thomas 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17660409-2-person46" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person46" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person46" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am under <rs id="t17660409-2-viclabel10" type="occupation">butler</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-2-victim42 t17660409-2-viclabel10"></join> to the Earl of Dartmouth: I lost 11 guineas, 3 pair of cotton stockings, 2 handkerchiefs, a breast buckle, a hand-whip, and 4 pieces of silver coin, one of them a Queen Elizabeth's shilling, and 40 shillings in silver, from out of my box in the servants-hall, which I found broke open, at the time Mr. Creswell's things were missing. I was present at Sir 
               <persName id="t17660409-2-person47">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660409-2-person47" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person47" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person47" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's when the prisoner was examined, there were 2 handkerchiefs and the hand-whip produced there my property. I heard the prisoner there confess he had taken the things.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-2-person48">
                  William 
                  Sprigins 
               <interp inst="t17660409-2-person48" type="surname" value="Sprigins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person48" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person48" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waiter at the Artichoke at Blackwall: I was going to fetch a horse from beyond Rumford; I overtook the prisoner between the 10 and 11 mile stones betwixt 10 and 11 o'clock. I did not take an account of the day of the month, it was on a Friday about a month ago; he was bargaining with a man that had a cart to carry his portmanteau, and after he had delivered it he overtook me, he was on horseback; he asked me if I had seen the Harwich fly, saying he should be glad to get there to night, for he had got his uncle's horse that kept the, Vine inn in Vine-street, Piccadilly, and if he could get in the fly he would send the horse back. We went on to the White-hart at Rumford, there we were told the fly went by at 7 in the morning; we went to another inn, and he asked for a machine; it wanted then 5 minutes of 11 o'clock, he could get no carriage. We agreed to ride on; he said if I would go with him to Brentwood he would take a post-chaise, and he would satisfy me if I would bring the horse to his uncle. We went there to the White-hart; he ordered a post-chaise, and called for a bottle of port and something to eat, and a barber to dress his hair; after he had paid for the chaise he turned out some pieces of silver coin, and said they were of no service to him, and said I was welcome to them. (Four pieces produced, one of them a Queen Elizabeth's shilling, and deposed to by Webb as his property.) He got into the chaise, and ordered to be drove to Chelmsford, and gave me half a guinea to bring the horse to Piccadilly. When I came there to the Vine, the landlord asked me where the man was that I brought him from; I said I believed he was at Harwich. He told me that man had robbed the Earl of Dartmouth, and that it was the Earl's horse. I then went with him and the horse to the Earl's house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-2-person49">
                  John 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17660409-2-person49" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person49" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person49" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Upon this information I was sent by Sir 
               <persName id="t17660409-2-person50">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660409-2-person50" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person50" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person50" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to Harwich after the prisoner; an express had been sent down, which got there before me, and I found him in custody. I asked the prisoner where his fellow servants things were: he said Mr. Bennet the constable had them. There I found them; I understood they had been produced before the Mayor; I brought him and the things to town, and he was examined before Sir 
               <persName id="t17660409-2-person51">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660409-2-person51" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person51" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-person51" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; there the things were opened, and Mr. Creswell and Webb swore to their<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176604090004"></xptr> things. He said as to the money he had spent them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I leave it to the mercy of the court; I have nothing to say for myself; I have no friend in the world</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660409-2-verdict11" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-verdict11" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-verdict11" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty, 39 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17660409-2-punish12" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660409-2-punish12" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-2-defend38 t17660409-2-punish12"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
