<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620421-10">
               <interp inst="t17620421-10" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-10" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-10" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620421"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-10" type="date" value="17620421"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620421-10-off47-c101" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-10-defend116 t17620421-10-off47 t17620421-10-verdict49"></join>
         
               <p>125. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-defend116" type="defendantName">
                  Uzriel 
                  Baruch 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-defend116" type="surname" value="Baruch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-defend116" type="given" value="Uzriel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-defend116" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , of <placeName id="t17620421-10-defloc45">Shoemaker-row</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-10-defloc45" type="placeName" value="Shoemaker-row"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620421-10-defloc45" type="type" value="defendantHome"></interp>
                  <join result="persNamePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-10-defend116 t17620421-10-defloc45"></join>, <rs id="t17620421-10-deflabel46" type="occupation">butcher</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-10-defend116 t17620421-10-deflabel46"></join>, was indicted, for <rs id="t17620421-10-off47" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-off47" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-off47" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               that he, together with 
                     <persName id="t17620421-10-person117">
                        Rockom 
                        Polock 
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person117" type="surname" value="Polock"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-10-person117" type="given" value="Rockom"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-10-person117" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17620421-10-person118">
                        Abraham 
                        Lopaz 
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person118" type="surname" value="Lopaz"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-10-person118" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-10-person118" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not taken, on the <rs id="t17620421-10-cd48" type="crimeDate">27th of March</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-10-off47 t17620421-10-cd48"></join>, about the hour of two in the morning, the dwelling-house of 
                     <persName id="t17620421-10-victim119" type="victimName">
                        Lyon 
                        Marks 
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-victim119" type="surname" value="Marks"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-10-victim119" type="given" value="Lyon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17620421-10-victim119" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-10-off47 t17620421-10-victim119"></join>
                     </persName>
                    did break and enter, and stealing one black petticoat lined with Persian silk, value 4 l. 4 s. one red sattin waistcoat laced with silver-lace, value 21 s. one damask gown, value 40 s. one waistcoat, value 10 s. 6 d. one cloth coat, value 22 s. one other cloth coat, value 15 s. one brown woollen waistcoat, value 10 s. one paper snuff-box, value 2 s. 6 d. four iron keys and a ring, value 1 s. and divers other things, the property of the said Lyon in his dwelling house
            </rs>. ++</p>
               <p>Lyon Marks. I lost those goods and more than are in the indictment. I went to bed on Saturday night, a little after eleven o'clock, the 27th of March. I had nobody more in my house but my wife and my son. When I was in my bed sleeping, the watchman came, halloo! halloo! what's the matter here; why are all these cloathes thrown about? This was exactly at four o'clock. I got up. Some were in the street, some in the kitchen My door was open, and my shelves almost stripped. My son got up. We found a great many things again.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you fasten your door when you went to bed?</p>
               <p>Marks. I did. In the morning Mrs. Alexander sent for me; she asked me if some things she had were not my goods; a pair of stocking breeches and a laced hat? I said they were; and she gave them to me; her maid had seen them at Mr. Lopaz's house; he is not to be found. I went to Mr. Abraham's, and asked his advice; then I heard there were a great many of my goods at Monsanto's house. I took up Spencer the evidence. He confessed all; then I went and searched the prisoner's house, but found nothing there.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person120">
                  Mark 
                  Marks 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person120" type="surname" value="Marks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person120" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person120" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am son to the prosecutor; the prisoner is a master butcher in the neighbourhood over against us; all the coats and waistcoats were taken out of the shop, and they had just begun to take the breeches. The pin of the window is lost; to this minute we cannot tell how they got in; the lock was not broke. When the prisoner was taken up, he said he would make every thing right. I said, how could you go to do such a thing to a neighbour? He said, it cannot be helped.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person121">
                  Aaron 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person121" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person121" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person121" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I can give the best account how the house was broke open. Last-Saturday was three weeks I was coming by 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person122">
                  Abraham 
                  Lopaz 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person122" type="surname" value="Lopaz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person122" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person122" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house, about eight at night. -</p>
               <p>[At the desire of the jury all the evidences on both sides were put out of court, and called in by one at a time.]</p>
               <p>Spencer. We met the prisoner at the bar; he spoke to us. He asked me, if I had a mind to earn any money to night? I said, in what? He said, come at eleven o'clock by my shop, and then I'll tell you. We went to the Rose and Crown alehouse in Whitechappel; there was Rockom Polock. As soon as it was eleven we all three went to the prisoner's house. The prisoner was at his door. We asked him, what we had to do? He desired me to stay in his shop or at his door. He took a candle, and went with the other two to the prosecutor's door, and turned the pin of the window about, and the key dropped out; then he took the shutter down and opened the sash of the window, and put the lock of the door back and opened it. They went in and brought bundles and bundles of goods, and threw them into his own shop all scattered on the floor; then he went to his bed and brought a pair of sheets and two blankets, and bundled all up in them; then we went all of us with them to 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person123">
                  Moses 
                  Baruch 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person123" type="surname" value="Baruch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person123" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person123" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's: He was going to be married to his daughter.</p>

               <p>Q. How far does 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person124">
                  Moses 
                  Baruch 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person124" type="surname" value="Baruch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person124" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person124" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             live from his shop?</p>
               <p>Spencer. About four minutes walk. Moses told him he would not let them be there till after day light; if they did not take them away before, he would turn them all out in the street. They were left up one pair of stairs. When we went out of that house, the prisoner said, I am in a worse hobble<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210009"></xptr> than before, but if you will go along with me to 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person125">
                  Philip 
                  Abraham 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person125" type="surname" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person125" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person125" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, perhaps he will buy them or keep them for me. We went there; the prisoner called to him at the window, and said he had got something for him which he believed would do for him. The other asked him, who he was? He said, he was the butcher name Baruch. Rockom Polock had one bundle with him. They were carried up stairs. Abrahams said, he could perfectly guess where they came from, and he would have nothing to do with them. Said the prisoner, I will lend you money to buy them; he would have no concern with them. Then we took them away. Then coming along Houndsditch he pitched them on the steps, till we went back for the other three Bundles; then we went to Duke's-place, and called to 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person126">
                  Moses 
                  Caravallo 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person126" type="surname" value="Caravallo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person126" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner told him he wanted the key of his room that was in Goodman's-fields; Caravallo gave him no answer When he could not get the key, the prisoner said we may as well drop them, for we cannot go lugging them about the streets. I said it was the best way to go and open the prosecutor's door, and go throw them in again. We carried three bundles back into the house, but in the hurry some of them were left by the door in the street, the watchman being coming his beat. The prisoner took the sheets and blankets away; we also left a pair of Breeches and a hat upon Lopaz's stairs. It was now about four o'clock, I said to the prisoner. Lopaz and Polock took two coats, two waistcoats, a velvet cloth, and one of the prisoner's sheets with them. [Here is that sheet in court.] I went to call 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person127">
                  Gabriel 
                  Monsanto 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person127" type="surname" value="Monsanto"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person127" type="given" value="Gabriel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he opened the door, and we threw them in; then I went to work. The prisoner sent for me from work about nine o'clock; he said, Spencer, what must I do in this affair? I said, I did not know no more than he did. Then I went to Mr. Marks, and told him the whole affair. After this I gave the same account to the prosecutor. We were examined before my lord-mayor; the prisoner denied it. I told my lord I had a sheet of his. My lord asked him if he lay with one sheet or two? He said with one because he had the Rhumatism, and he sweated pretty much; after that, he was asked if he had any servant? He said a boy. The boy was sent for; he was asked where he lay? He said in the same room and bed with his Master. He was asked if he laid with one sheet or two? He said two. The two sheets were produced before my lord mayor, and he had no doubt but they were fellows.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person128">
                  Gabriel 
                  Monsanto 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person128" type="surname" value="Monsanto"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person128" type="given" value="Gabriel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know no more of it than that two coats, two waistcoats, and a velvet cloth were thrown into my house by 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person129">
                  Aaron 
                  Spencer 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person129" type="surname" value="Spencer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person129" type="given" value="Aaron"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person130">
                  Abraham 
                  Lopaz 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person130" type="surname" value="Lopaz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person130" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Spencer worked at the passover-cakes along with me; he called me to come to work. I opened the door, and they flung them in. I said are they honestly come by? Spencer said let them alone; I'll warrant you, you shall come to no harm: then I said to Spencer, I am very drowsy, go and make my dough for me; he did. Then I looked over the things, and put them on my bed and went to work; as soon as I went to work, at ten o'clock, Spencer said to me, I am ruined and am afraid to confess. I said, do not be afraid to confess. for I shall say nothing at all; then he told me those things in the room belonged to Marks, and he had been robbed. I ran to Mr. Marks, and met him and the constable together, and desired him to come to my house, for some of his things were in my room. I could not find my key. I took the constable's staff and broke the window, and went in and brought out the things, and Marks, owned them immediately.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person131">
                  Coleman 
                  Solomon 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person131" type="surname" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person131" type="given" value="Coleman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. Mr. Marks and Mr. Abrahams came on the Sunday morning to my house, and told me his house was broke open and robbed, and that he had a suspicion of 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person132">
                  Abraham 
                  Lopaz 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person132" type="surname" value="Lopaz"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person132" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and Spencer. Lopaz is a shoe blacker. I sent for him immediately; he said he knew nothing at all of it. We went to several houses: as we were going to 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person133">
                  Gabriel 
                  Monsanto 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person133" type="surname" value="Monsanto"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person133" type="given" value="Gabriel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's house we met him, and told him we were going to his house; and said we had intelligence that some goods were lodged there; let us know and no harm can come to you. He seemed a little concerned. He said, you must take me along with you, for I shall certainly be murdered by the gang, they are very bad people, that is Spencer and Lopaz. We sent to his house; the door was locked: we got into the yard backwards; he opened the casement and got in, and let us in. The prosecutor owned the things.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing after he was taken?</p>
               <p>Solomon. I never heard a bad character of him in my life, and I dare say now he is innocent. Spencer at first said, Lopaz and Polock were concerned in breaking open the house, and that the prisoner received them of them, and lent them a knife to break the house; after that, he said the prisoner at the bar was concerned in breaking the house; and I heard the prosecutor's son say there would be 40 l. reward, and a ticket on their conviction.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person134">
                  Mark 
                  Marks 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person134" type="surname" value="Marks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person134" type="given" value="Mark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . This constable threatened to get me committed, if I would not make it up. I said I would go to the rigour of the law.</p>
               <p>Spencer. Please to call 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person135">
                  Abraham 
                  Baruch 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person135" type="surname" value="Baruch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person135" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he can explain this matter.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person136">
                  Abraham 
                  Baruch 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person136" type="surname" value="Baruch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person136" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . When Spencer was taken, the first word he said was, that the prisoner was the man that did it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person137">
                  Abraham 
                  Abrahams 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person137" type="surname" value="Abrahams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person137" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person137" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The morning after this thing happened Mr. Marks came to my house, and told me his house had been robbed of a considerable quantity of cloaths, and that he had reason to suspect Spencer and Lopaz to be two of the people that did it; he said at Lopaz's steps were found some of the things, and the watchman thought Spencer was one of the men that run away. I sent for Lopaz,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210010"></xptr> he denied knowing any thing about it; we were going to search several houses, and met Monsanto: we told him we mistrusted some things being in his house; he owned he had some things put in by Spencer and Lopaz, and desired they would take him in custody, being afraid of being killed by the gang. The watchman had given an account of seeing three men run away. Spencer said Lopass and Polock were with him in it; and that the prisoner lent him a knife to break the house, and that they carried the goods to the prisoner's house.</p>
               <p>Spencer. This evidence is brother-in-law to 
               <persName id="t17620421-10-person138">
                  Moses 
                  Baruch 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person138" type="surname" value="Baruch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person138" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person138" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I told this man, Baruch was with me.</p>
               <p>Abrahams. When Spencer found the other two were absented, and we could not take them, then he said the prisoner was with them at the breaking of the house, and held the candle; then I said how came you not to say this at first?</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of this man Spencer; I never kept company with him, or drank with him; I know him no other way than by living in the neighbourhood; I disdain such company. I have witnesses here that I have paid hundreds of pounds to; I am very innocent of the affair.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person139">
                  Joseph 
                  Orwood 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person139" type="surname" value="Orwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person139" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner has dealt with me about three quarters of a year; he is a very sober honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person140">
                  Thomas 
                  Martin 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person140" type="surname" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person140" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person140" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ten years; he is a very honest sober young fellow: I think he deserves that character. I have paid his father through his hands many hundreds of pounds.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person141">
                  William 
                  Till 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person141" type="surname" value="Till"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person141" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person141" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him pretty near two years; he is a very honest, sober, hard-working young fellow: he has dealt with me for pounds and pounds, more than 10 or 14 l. a week.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person142">
                  Joseph 
                  Marks 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person142" type="surname" value="Marks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person142" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 10 or 12 years; I never heard any thing of him, but that of a very honest man. I have dealt with him.</p>
               <p>Robert Hall. I have known him four years; I have dealt with him for pounds; he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person143">
                  John 
                  Wrench 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person143" type="surname" value="Wrench"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person143" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him four years. I have had dealings with him; he is a very honest man for what I know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person144">
                  Abraham 
                  Riatie 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person144" type="surname" value="Riatie"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person144" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him ever since he was a child; he is a very industrious, sober young man. I believe he has been butcher to me 16 years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person145">
                  James 
                  Rickaby 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person145" type="surname" value="Rickaby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person145" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him above two years; I believe him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person146">
                  Moses 
                  Fonseca 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person146" type="surname" value="Fonseca"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person146" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 15 years; he is a very honest, hard-working man; he lives near me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person147">
                  Solomon 
                  Cordosa 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person147" type="surname" value="Cordosa"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person147" type="given" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was his master to teach him Hebrew; he never was out of my sight two days in his life, in comparison; he always bore a very good character. He has been set up for himself about two years.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person148">
                  Isaac 
                  Devall 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person148" type="surname" value="Devall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person148" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 10 or 12 years; his character is as good as any man's can be in the world. He lodged about eight or nine months with me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-10-person149">
                  Moses 
                  Ebeau 
               <interp inst="t17620421-10-person149" type="surname" value="Ebeau"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person149" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 8 or 9 years; he is a very sober honest young man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620421-10-verdict49" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-10-verdict49" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
