<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650522-9">
               <interp inst="t17650522-9" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-9" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-9" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-9" type="date" value="17650522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-9-off51-c84" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-9-defend99 t17650522-9-off51 t17650522-9-verdict55"></join>
         
               <p>300. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-defend99" type="defendantName">
                     Dennis
                      M'Guire
                  <interp inst="t17650522-9-defend99" type="surname" value="M'Guire"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-defend99" type="given" value="Dennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-defend99" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17650522-9-off51" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-off51" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-off51" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch, value 3 l. one silver chain, and a silver seal, value 8 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-victim101" type="victimName">
                     James 
                     Sherridon 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-9-victim101" type="surname" value="Sherridon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-victim101" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-victim101" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-9-off51 t17650522-9-victim101"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-person102">
                  James 
                  Sherridon 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person102" type="surname" value="Sherridon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person102" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person102" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On last <rs id="t17650522-9-cd52" type="crimeDate">Easter Monday</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-9-off51 t17650522-9-cd52"></join>, between eleven and twelve in the morning, I was at the end of Poppin's-alley: I am a <rs id="t17650522-9-viclabel53" type="occupation">milkman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-9-victim101 t17650522-9-viclabel53"></join>: I was with my customers; I met the prisoner; he asked me to drink share of a pint of purl; he brought me in at the Red-lion; I was a little in liquor; he took me out of that to the <placeName id="t17650522-9-crimeloc54">Plough alehouse</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-9-crimeloc54" type="placeName" value="Plough alehouse"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-9-crimeloc54" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-9-off51 t17650522-9-crimeloc54"></join>; there he borrowed half a guinea of me: we came out there, and then he hauled the chain of my watch and got my watch, and a shilling and three-pence half-penny out of my other pocket; I said, do not take my watch, for I am capable to carry it home myself. There was a workman, a stranger to me; he said, M'Guire, do not take the man's watch: the prisoner went up Fleet-street, and I went the other way, home. My wife and I went to the prisoner's house in the evening; and I demanded my watch of him; the prisoner said, if I have your watch, I did not rob you of it: a man said, you'll be so good as to return it; no, he said he would not: I went to Mr. Alderman Blackistone in two days after, as I could not get it; he said he would stand a trial with me, saying, you said you would hang me. I took him before Mr. Blackistone; he was at that time acquitted for want of an evidence: he made it out there it was nothing but a drunken sit; he denied having the watch; after that he laughed at me. In two or three days after I took the prisoner up; I took him before the alderman at Guildhall; there he was committed.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you and the prisoner very intimate?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. I never was in company with him but twice; and one time he used me very ill.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. I live in Red-Lion-court, Fleet-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there not a number of people passing by when he took the watch?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. Yes, there was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never deliver the watch to him?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you consent he should take it to take care of it?</p>

               <p>Sherridon. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you call any body to your assistance?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220008"></xptr>Q. How much money have you demanded for this watch?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. Since he has been in confinement he has sent his friends and offered me some money; they have asked me if I would take any money.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17650522-9-person103">
                  Richard 
                  Leonard 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person103" type="surname" value="Leonard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person103" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person103" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. What money did you mention would satisfy you?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. I told them my watch and lent money came to 8 l. 5 s. that was for expence and costs to look for him in the city and country; I had had two or three people along with me; I did not think it proper to meet with him alone.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say you would take that money?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. No; I did not: I said, I would leave it to the law; as I could not answer it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17650522-9-person104">
                  Charles 
                  Simpson 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person104" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person104" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person104" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never tell any body you was so drunk that you did not know what was become of the watch?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. No, I did not to any one; that is all a heap of stuff.</p>
               <p>Q. With proviso he had delivered it to you the next day, would you have prosecuted him?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you look upon it he stole the watch?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. He forced it away without my inclination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever find your watch again?</p>
               <p>Sherridon. No; I never did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-person105">
                  John 
                  Dailey 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person105" type="surname" value="Dailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person105" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person105" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a pavior's labourer, and live in Poppin's alley: I was going through the alley between 11 and 12 that day; I saw M'Guire take hold of the chain of the prosecutor's watch, and pull the watch out; he put it from his right hand into his left, and put it into his left hand pocket. I said, M'Guire, what are you about? why do you take the man's watch? said he, I'll take care of it for him: he then put his hand to the prosecutor's breeches pocket; hearing nothing in it, he took hold of his waistcoat, and in the pocket found some half-pence, and put them into his pocket; then he counted fifteen-pence half-penny, and said, fearing the man should go into any company he returned him them. Now, Dailey, said he, I'll give you a pot of beer to see this man home; said I, see him home yourself; you have got his watch. I went over to the Borough to my work, and staid there four nights: when I came home, as my wife and I were at supper, she told me that M'Guire and the other milkman had had a trial at Guildhall that day: I said, did he return the man his watch; no, said she; so I went and told Sherridon that I saw him take it from him.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known M'Guire?</p>
               <p>Dailey. I have known him about thirteen or fourteen months: he lives in Plumbtree-court, Shoe-lane.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you one that went as a guard with Sherridon to see for the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Dailey. I went with him three days.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you for your trouble?</p>
               <p>Dailey. I never had a farthing; I borrowed six-pence of him, that is all I got.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. What sort of a watch was yours?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was a silver watch, with a silver chain and silver seal.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing at all of the thing they charge me with: Mr. Sherridon and I happened to be together; we had three pots of beer in Poppin's-alley; then we removed to the Plough, in Black Horse alley; he forced me to stay with him: I told him I must go to my cow-keeper for my monthly bill, and I wanted money to pay it; he lent me half a guinea; we shook hands, and he went one way and I another: I went and paid my cow-keeper; and about two o'clock he and his wife came to the Red Lion, in Poppin's-alley; she demanded his watch and 7 s. 6 d. in money; she said, she catched him asleep with his breeches about his heels, and that he had been asleep in the street about an hour; that he could neither stand nor go: after that he came and demanded his watch of me, and 13 s. 6 d; I thought at first he was joking with me; I said, you know what is between us, I owe you half a guinea, and no more: about three or four days after he served me with a summons; I went and answered to it before Mr. Alderman Blackistone; I was there acquitted: after that this Dailey happened to be in the way; then I was served with another summons: Dailey owes me a trifle of money for milk; I had asked him for it; he swore he would be up with me; but I never thought he would be the man that would go to swear my life away: Mr. Sherridon never owned that I had his watch, till after Dailey came and swore I had it: since that Sherridon swears point blank that I had it: I never saw Dailey at the time they speak of, to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220009"></xptr>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-person106">
                  John 
                  Collins 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person106" type="surname" value="Collins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person106" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person106" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Red Lion in Poppin's-alley: the prisoner and prosecutor were at my house on Easter Monday; the prosecutor was quite drunk; M'Guire was pretty sober: about two hours after they were gone, Sherridon's wife came, and said her husband had left his watch and 7 s. 6 d. with me; I said, good woman I do not think your husband is worth a watch: he came in the afternoon; he asked me if I saw any thing of his watch; I said to him, I did not think he was worth one: his wife abused him at my house, and said he had been out all night: she struck him; this was while they were drinking three tankards of beer together in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Sherridon say that the prisoner had taken his watch in Poppin's-alley?</p>
               <p>Collins. No: he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Dailey?</p>
               <p>Collins. I do not know Dailey.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never see him?</p>
               <p>Collins. I have seen him go backwards and forwards; he lives near me; but I do not know what character he bears.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-person107">
                  Charles 
                  Simpson 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person107" type="surname" value="Simpson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person107" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person107" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard Sherridon say, a night or two after he lost his watch, he had lost it, but did not know how, where, or when.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Simpson. This was in Mr. Collin's house; he was telling it to a woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say any thing about M'Guire?</p>
               <p>Simpson. He did not mention a word about him.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Simpson. I live in Fleet-Street.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Simpson. I am a mathematical instrument maker; servant to Mr. Wyn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-person108">
                  Thomas 
                  Moran 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person108" type="surname" value="Moran"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person108" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person108" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a milkman, and live by the Temple-gate, White-friars: I have known Sherridon about 18 years, I never knew any thing to stain his character till this time.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he not to be credited upon oath?</p>
               <p>Moran. I can't justly say whether he is or not: last Tuesday was a week he and I were at Islington; we went in at the Angel, and had a pot of beer: before we drank it he said he had lost his watch; he said it had a shagreen case: and nobody being in company but he and I, said I, Sherridon, do you want to bring me into the same line with M'Guire; he insisted I should take off my cloaths and be searched: after I was searched, I insisted upon his being searched, and the watch was found within the knee of his breeches.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Moran. He was drunk.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-person109">
                  William 
                  Leeson 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person109" type="surname" value="Leeson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person109" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know Sherridon; I drink a pot of beer now and then with him: I was telling him it was pity to put the poor man to trouble and expence; he said, he was sure M'Guire had his watch; I said, I would give him a trifle on my own account, if he would make it up with him; he said, he was willing to make it up with him for so much money: but M'Guire did not know of my proposal; I did it out of perfect charity.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he say he lost his watch?</p>

               <p>Leeson. He said he lost it out of a drunken frolick: I have known M'Guire thirteen or fourteen years; he and I have milked both in one yard for twelve months; I never saw anything by him but what was just and honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-person110">
                  Richard 
                  Lenard 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person110" type="surname" value="Lenard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person110" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person110" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known M'Guire ever since he was a boy, in Ireland and England; he is a very honest, careful, industrious man; he bears a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-person111">
                  Joshua 
                  Sharp 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person111" type="surname" value="Sharp"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person111" type="given" value="Joshua"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known M'Guire about six years; his general character is very good.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-person112">
                  Peter 
                  Murphy 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person112" type="surname" value="Murphy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person112" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a milk-man: I have known M'Guire two or three years; he is an honest man. Sherridon told me he really believed he lost his watch through a drunken fit, and that he was doubtful whether M'Guire had took it or not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-person113">
                  Christopher 
                  Duff 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person113" type="surname" value="Duff"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person113" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person113" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in White-cross-street, and am a servant to Mr. Calvert, a brewer: I have known the prisoner ever since he was born; I never knew any thing of him but what was honest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-9-person114">
                  Francis 
                  Derham 
               <interp inst="t17650522-9-person114" type="surname" value="Derham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person114" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him twelve months and better. I never knew any thing by him but what was honest.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650522-9-verdict55" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-9-verdict55" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
