<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640222-49">
               <interp inst="t17640222-49" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-49" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-49" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-49" type="date" value="17640222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640222-49-off276-c343" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend446 t17640222-49-off276 t17640222-49-verdict279"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640222-49-off276-c344" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend447 t17640222-49-off276 t17640222-49-verdict279"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640222-49-off276-c345" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend450 t17640222-49-off276 t17640222-49-verdict279"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640222-49-off276-c346" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend451 t17640222-49-off276 t17640222-49-verdict279"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640222-49-off276-c347" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend453 t17640222-49-off276 t17640222-49-verdict279"></join>
         
               <p>182, 183, 184, 185. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-defend446" type="defendantName">
                  Isaac 
                  Usher 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend446" type="surname" value="Usher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend446" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend446" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             , (a second time) 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-defend447" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Philip 
                     Abrahams 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640222-49-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend447 t17640222-49-alias-5"></join>Scampy</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend447" type="surname" value="Abrahams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend447" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               
                  <persName id="t17640222-49-defend450" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Munday 
                  <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend450" type="surname" value="Munday"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend450" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend450" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-defend451" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Joseph 
                     Taylor 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640222-49-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend451 t17640222-49-alias-6"></join>Turner</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend451" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend451" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend451" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-defend453" type="defendantName">
                  
                     John 
                     Carpenter 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640222-49-alias-7" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend453 t17640222-49-alias-7"></join>Huckle</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend453" type="surname" value="Carpenter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend453" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-defend453" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , were indicted for <rs id="t17640222-49-off276" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-off276" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-off276" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing (together with 
                     <persName id="t17640222-49-person455">
                        William 
                        Hays 
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person455" type="surname" value="Hays"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-49-person455" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-49-person455" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , 
                     <persName id="t17640222-49-person456">
                        James 
                        Lawler 
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person456" type="surname" value="Lawler"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-49-person456" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-49-person456" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and Edward Roach, not taken) a gold watch, value 5 l. and a cornelian seal, set in gold, value 20 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17640222-49-victim458" type="victimName">
                     Andrew 
                     Trembley 
                  <interp inst="t17640222-49-victim458" type="surname" value="Trembley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-victim458" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-victim458" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-off276 t17640222-49-victim458"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17640222-49-cd277" type="crimeDate">January 19</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-off276 t17640222-49-cd277"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-49-person459">
                  Andrew 
                  Trembley 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person459" type="surname" value="Trembley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person459" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person459" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 19th of January I was in <placeName id="t17640222-49-crimeloc278">Cranebourn-alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640222-49-crimeloc278" type="placeName" value="Cranebourn-alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640222-49-crimeloc278" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-off276 t17640222-49-crimeloc278"></join>, about 6 in the evening, there came eight or ten men, and pushed me into the middle of the street: I fell down; they surrounded me; my watch, a gold one, was gone in a minute: I believe Munday was one of them, but I will not swear to him: When I was at Justice Fielding's I fixed my eye upon him; and said, I believed he was one of them.</p>
               <p>Q. How many were there at Sir 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person460">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person460" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person460" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person460" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's?</p>
               <p>Trembley. I believe there were about eight of them, but I did not count them.</p>

               <p>Q. Had you taken any notice of these men before you was pushed down?</p>
               <p>Trembley. I did not particularly; but it immediately struck me, when at Sir 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person461">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person461" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person461" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person461" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, that that man was the nearest to me before I was pushed down; but, in my hurry, I had not time to observe him: It was a tall man like him. The whole was not above a minute.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever get your watch again.</p>
               <p>Trembley, No, I never did: It was a gold watch, with a green shagreen case, a steel chain, and white cornelian seal, on which my arms were engraved, set in gold.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-49-person462">
                  Francis 
                  Parsons 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person462" type="surname" value="Parsons"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person462" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person462" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Thursday, the 19th of January, when the king and queen were going to Covent-garden playhouse, there were 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person463">
                  Isaac 
                  Usher 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person463" type="surname" value="Usher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person463" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person463" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Watson, Philips, Abrahams, and myself. We went from one Lumley's in Golden-lane, up Fleet street, towards Temple-bar. Usher, I, and Abrahams, had a shilling's-worth of punch at a public-house, between two and three o'clock: I don't know the sign; it is by Chancery-lane end. From thence we went directly to Covent-garden playhouse: This was between three and four o'clock. There we saw Mr. Marsden, and some of Mr. Fielding's people, coming cross Covent-garden. I saw Carpenter; he asked me if I had seen any thing of Munday or Taylor; I said, no: Said he, What do you do here? I wonder you are not among the people: Says I, I have a couple of watches in my pocket. I left him there. Then we went to Kit Andrews's, in Charles-street: We had not been there long, before in came Munday, Taylor, Hays, Carpenter, one Irish Jemmy, and 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person464">
                  Edward 
                  Roach 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person464" type="surname" value="Roach"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person464" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person464" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . We had not been there long, before one came in, and said, there was Mr. Fuller in the tap-room; with that, we all ten of us came away directly: We were afraid of him; he belongs to Mr. Fielding's people. We went all together down the Strand, towards St. Clement's church. One of them said, let's turn back to Cranebourn-alley, then we shall see the king and queen go to Leicester-fields; and, if we go there, we shall be pretty sure there will be none of Sir John's people there, and we shall be pretty safe. We all went back, and into Cranebourn-alley.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176402220039"></xptr> Just as a gentleman was coming, almost at the end towards Leicester-fields, Munday said, Here it is. We all got round the gentleman: He fell down, and Munday picked his pocket of a gold watch. I don't know who that gentleman was, I did not see his face. I was close to Munday's hand; he delivered the watch to me, and I walked away directly, and looked at it, and found it had a shagreen case to it. I gave it to Watson, and we all ten of us went down to a house in Tavistock-street: I don't know the sign. We staid there, and had seven or eight pots of beer; then we agreed to go to the Black Prince, in Shandois-street; there we went up-stairs, and had some a-la-mode beef. Watson pulled out the watch; and, as he was looking at it, somebody came up with the a-la-mode beef; upon which, he put it in his pocket again. We agreed to stay there till the play was over, and then go back again to Covent-garden.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the seal?</p>
               <p>Parsons. I did not observe that: It was a gold watch, with a box and case in one; with an enamelled dial-plate, and yellow hands.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. My watch, that I lost, was as he describes.</p>
               <p>Parsons. We spent a quarter of a guinea, and, I think, six-pence besides: I saw it paid. I believe we had about ten or twelve plates of a-la-mode beef there; we eat them as fast as they were brought up. I don't know which paid: It was proposed, that when the watch was agreed about, it then should be settled. I know we had two quarterns of gin. We came away, just before ten, to Covent-garden, and there we again saw Mr. Marsden; so came away, leaving only Edward Roach, and Irish Jemmey, by the end of Charles-street. The other eight of us went to the house of a woman, whose name is English, near Drury-lane playhouse, where we had not been long, before Mr. Fielding's people came in, and took us all but Watson. Hays got away as we were going to Justice Fielding's. I saw 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person465">
                  Isaac 
                  Usher 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person465" type="surname" value="Usher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person465" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person465" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             drop something by his heel; what it was, I do not know. We had them among us to buy what we got, that is, Watson and others. We were all upon a fair footing; the money was to be divided equally among us; that is, all that are in company; except they have a mind not to tell them of it; sometimes they do not tell of all they get. We are not always true to one another.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-49-person466">
                  Moses 
                  Barnard 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person466" type="surname" value="Barnard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person466" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person466" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I did not take any particular notice of the day of the month, but, about a month ago, I happened to be at the Cock alehouse, by Temple-bar; I had three pennyworth of rum and water. I did not stay ten minutes. As soon as I came out, I met Usher, Abrahams, and Parsons the evidence. I asked Usher to drink a glass of punch; he said, he would, and went in with me, and Abrahams and Parsons followed us. I believe I have known Usher ten years: I had a good opinion of him; I never heard any harm of him in my life. He is a Jew, and so am I.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Parsons?</p>
               <p>Barnard. I have known him some time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-49-person467">
                  Ann Barber 
                  Suken 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person467" type="surname" value="Suken"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person467" type="given" value="Ann Barber"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person467" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant at the Black Prince in Chandois-street. I remember the night the Prince and Princess of Brunswick went to the play. I don't know any of the prisoners, but remember eight or nine people being up-stairs at our house that night, eating a-la-mode beef, and paying a quarter of a guinea in gold, and a shilling. They had two quarterns of gin.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they served with each man a separate mess, or in common.</p>
               <p>Suken. In common. There were ten plates of a-la-mode beef.</p>
               <p>Q. What day of the week was it?</p>
               <p>Suken. It was on Thursday night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-49-person468">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person468" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person468" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person468" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. On Thursday, the 19th of January last, the day his Majesty, and the Prince and Princess of Brunswick, went to the play, I was at the apprehending seven men, at a house in Russel-street, two doors below the blue posts; the five prisoners, the evidence, and another that got away, named Hays. They were all in company, and I think they had a bottle of wine before them on the table. We carried them to the Blakeney's head, and put them in a room all together. There were six of us, and seven of them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-49-person469">
                  Michael 
                  Mackabey 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person469" type="surname" value="Mackabey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person469" type="given" value="Michael"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person469" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Russel-street when some people were apprehended there on a Thursday night. I was desired to go and put up the window shutters at the house where they were taken out. The woman of the house, whose name is English, went out and left me to take care of her house, and not stir till she came in. She did not return that night. I fell asleep upon a chair. About 7 or 8 in the morning I took down the shutters, and saw a handkerchief under a chair, with a watch appearing out of it. I went to the Angel, in Charles-street, and enquired for her. She came home, and took up the handkerchief. There were two silver watches, and two covered, like leather; (they were yellow ones); and another in a woman's glove. I do not know what became of them.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176402220040"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-49-person470">
                  Thomas 
                  Stainpart 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person470" type="surname" value="Stainpart"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person470" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person470" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with Smith and others at the apprehending the prisoners and evidence, in Russel-street: There was another of them, but he got away from me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-49-person471">
                  Richard 
                  Fuller 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person471" type="surname" value="Fuller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person471" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person471" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I know all the prisoners, and Parsons also. About 5 o'clock, the night the Prince and Princess of Brunswick went to the play, I saw Parsons, Usher, and I believe every one of the prisoners, at Andrews's, in Charles-street.</p>
               <p>Usher's Defence.</p>

               <p>I was not at any of them places. I belong to a club in Panton-street; I was there. I went to the play with Abrahams. After that, he said, I have got a little money to receive, come along with me. We went to that house, and were not there above two or three minutes, before Mr. Fieldings men came and laid hold of us, and carried us all away to the Blakeney's head; there they stripped and searched us: They took a watch, a pair of silver buckles, and two notes from me: They have been advertised several times: They are my own.</p>
               <p>Smith. These things not being owned, I was ordered to deliver them back to the prisoner, which I did.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person472">
                  Thomas 
                  Baldwin 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person472" type="surname" value="Baldwin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person472" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person472" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him nine years; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person473">
                  Abraham 
                  Cordosa 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person473" type="surname" value="Cordosa"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person473" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person473" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , twelve or fourteen; Febea Philips, fifteen; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person474">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Barns 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person474" type="surname" value="Barns"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person474" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person474" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , fifteen; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person475">
                  Samuel 
                  Solomon 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person475" type="surname" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person475" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person475" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , seventeen; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person476">
                  Isaac 
                  Pensarve 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person476" type="surname" value="Pensarve"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person476" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person476" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , six or seven; and 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person477">
                  Mary 
                  Eadey 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person477" type="surname" value="Eadey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person477" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person477" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , four months; who said, they never heard any ill of him.</p>
               <p>Abrahams's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went to the play along with Usher, and took him along with me to this house, as I had some money due to me. I had sold the woman a gown and petticoat. We had not been in the house above three or four minutes, before I saw Munday come in along with a girl. Some gentlemen knocked at the door, and in came Mr. Fielding's men, and took us away.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person478">
                  Abraham 
                  Cordosa 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person478" type="surname" value="Cordosa"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person478" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person478" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him a good many years; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person479">
                  Samuel 
                  Solomon 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person479" type="surname" value="Solomon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person479" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person479" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him eight or nine; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person480">
                  William 
                  Shepherd 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person480" type="surname" value="Shepherd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person480" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person480" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , two or three; and 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person481">
                  William 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person481" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person481" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person481" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 14 months; who gave him an exceeding good character.</p>
               <p>Munday's Defence.</p>
               <p>I know nothing of Parsons. I was at the play at 5 o'clock, and staid there till it was over; coming out, a young woman asked me to give her a glass of wine; I said, I did not care if I did: She took me up-stairs, and treated me with a pint of wine: When we came down, I treated her with another in the parlour; and had not been there above three or four minutes, before these people came and knocked at the door, and came in and took us away. I never saw Parsons in my life before that night.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person482">
                  Daniel 
                  Thomas 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person482" type="surname" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person482" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person482" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him four months; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person483">
                  John 
                  Vandame 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person483" type="surname" value="Vandame"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person483" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person483" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , two months; and 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person484">
                  Jeremiah 
                  Amnet 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person484" type="surname" value="Amnet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person484" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person484" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , between three and four months; who said they knew no ill of him.</p>
               <p>Taylor's Defence.</p>
               <p>I went to Drury-lane playhouse to see the Prince and Princess of Brunswick; after which I went to English's, where I had not been above six or seven minutes, before Fielding's people came, and took me away with the rest.</p>
               <p>He called - Aldridge, who had known him two years; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person485">
                  Henry 
                  Francis 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person485" type="surname" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person485" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person485" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , about the same time; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person486">
                  James 
                  Burdet 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person486" type="surname" value="Burdet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person486" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person486" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , about three; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person487">
                  Isaac 
                  Drain 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person487" type="surname" value="Drain"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person487" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person487" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , about two; and 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person488">
                  Thomas 
                  Cutler 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person488" type="surname" value="Cutler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person488" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person488" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , between eight and nine months; who gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>Carpenter's Defence.</p>

               <p>I was coming out of Drury-lane playhouse: by the Rose tavern, a young woman met me, and asked me to treat her with a glass of wine: We went over to English's, and into a back parlour, and had one pint of wine. Mr. Fielding's men came in as we were coming away.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person489">
                  Henry 
                  Rogers 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person489" type="surname" value="Rogers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person489" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him between six and seven years; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person490">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Yearley 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person490" type="surname" value="Yearley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person490" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person490" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , betwixt five and six; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person491">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Floyd 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person491" type="surname" value="Floyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person491" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person491" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , eight; 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person492">
                  Sarah 
                  Hammond 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person492" type="surname" value="Hammond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person492" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person492" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , from a little boy; and - Tompson, about seven months; who gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>All five <rs id="t17640222-49-verdict279" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-verdict279" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640222-49-punish280" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-punish280" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend446 t17640222-49-punish280"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend447 t17640222-49-punish280"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend450 t17640222-49-punish280"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend451 t17640222-49-punish280"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-49-defend453 t17640222-49-punish280"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>See Abrahams tried before, No. 59, in Mr. Alderman Bethell's mayoralty; No. 182, in Mr. Alderman Cokayne's; and No. 190, in Mr. Alderman Jansen's; where 
               <persName id="t17640222-49-person493">
                  Isaac 
                  Usher 
               <interp inst="t17640222-49-person493" type="surname" value="Usher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person493" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-49-person493" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , by the name of Asher, appears to his character.</p>
               <p>See Munday tried, No. 203, in Mr. Alderman Bethell's mayoralty, and cast for transportation.</p>
            </div1>
