<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661022-37">
               <interp inst="t17661022-37" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-37" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-37" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661022-37" type="date" value="17661022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661022-37-off187-c291" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-37-defend370 t17661022-37-off187 t17661022-37-verdict190"></join>
         
               <p>513. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661022-37-defend370" type="defendantName">
                     Christopher 
                     Boydell 
                  <interp inst="t17661022-37-defend370" type="surname" value="Boydell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-defend370" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-defend370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661022-37-off187" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-off187" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-off187" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a bay mare, value 40 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17661022-37-victim372" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Ashley 
                  <interp inst="t17661022-37-victim372" type="surname" value="Ashley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-victim372" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-victim372" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-37-off187 t17661022-37-victim372"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17661022-37-cd188" type="crimeDate">October 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-37-off187 t17661022-37-cd188"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-37-person373">
                  John 
                  Ashley 
               <interp inst="t17661022-37-person373" type="surname" value="Ashley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-person373" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-person373" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17661022-37-crimeloc189">Parson's-green, in the parish of Fulham</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17661022-37-crimeloc189" type="placeName" value="Parson's-green, in the parish of Fulham"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661022-37-crimeloc189" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661022-37-off187 t17661022-37-crimeloc189"></join>; we catched the prisoner upon a bay mare of mine, last Friday morning, about half an hour after twelve, in the road, about one hundred yards from the place where I put her.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. What, tried for horse stealing, for stealing a mare, how is that?</p>
               <p>Court. Prisoner behave decently; consider you are trying for your life.</p>
               <p>Ashley. About half an hour after nine that night, I went to fodder up my cattle, the prisoner was in the yard; he came running to me with a fork, as if he intended to run it through me, and asked me what I wanted there; I said, I would let him know, and desired him to let me have the fork to serve up my cattle; he delivered it to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Ashley. He is quite a stranger to me. The mare was in this yard; the yard is about one hundred yards from my house; after this he began to beg for mercy, for fear I should hurt him; I said, I had no ill against him; then he begged leave to lie down there; I gave him leave. I went home to bed; the landlord at a public house near me, was alarmed by his bitch; he seeing the prisoner on my mare in the road, called out at the window to me; two young men that are here, and my wife and I, ran out and took him on the mare.</p>
               <p>Q. How did the prisoner behave upon that?</p>
               <p>Ashley. He behaved foolish, as I thought.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he in liquor?</p>
               <p>Ashley. No, he was rather foolish.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you think he was in his senses?</p>
               <p>Ashley. Sometimes we thought he was, and sometimes not; we could not tell what to make of him; we took him before Sir 
               <persName id="t17661022-37-person374">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17661022-37-person374" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-person374" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-person374" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; Sir John asked him what he was; he answered, What am I, why a man. The Justice said, that was not what he asked him; he said what countryman are you; he said he was a man of Kent: the Justice asked him where he lay; he said, where some hogs and cows, and where the mare was; he asked him what he was going to do with the mare; he said, d - n the mare, she was not worth two pence. (Indeed she was just come off a journey from Leighton-Buzzard in Bedfordshire, and was very tired.)</p>
               <p>Q. Had the prisoner a bridle or saddle?</p>
               <p>Ashley. He had, and a halter too; I had left them in a shed in the yard.</p>
               <p>- Dickenson. I was one that went to the prisoner when he was upon the mare; I asked him where he was going; he said, about four miles into the country to his farm; he had a pitchfork in his hand; I said, what are you going to do with that; he said he was going a haymaking; I said, where did you get this mare; he said out of a wood; I said, who does she belong to; he said, to his master; I asked him who was his master; he said, himself; the constable ordered me to search him; I found his pockets loaded with brickbats, and pieces of tiles, and glass, and the like.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he going away with the mare?</p>
               <p>Dickinson. The prosecutor's wife went up to him first; when I came to him he was on the mare, standing still on the road.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176610220027"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17661022-37-person375">
                  James 
                  Priseman 
               <interp inst="t17661022-37-person375" type="surname" value="Priseman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-person375" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-person375" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went out and saw the prisoner on the mare in the road, and Dickenson led the mare to the public-house; I was charged to aid and assist to get him to the Round-house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>They make a very long story of it, in telling a pack of lies; now they have told their story, it is time to tell mine: I was tired upon the road, and had no money, and destitute of lodging, I came by the house - there was no house: I saw a hay-stack or two; I went into the yard, and saw two horses, and two cows; thinks I, I must lie down somewhere; I saw a post-chaise coming by; I thought there was something more than ordinary; I thought something was coming over the wall; I took hold of a fork, and put up some straw; and got in among the hogs; I did not quite like that; then I got upon one of the horses, and rode backwards and forwards; I thought if any body came to hurt me, I would run the fork in them; some body called out at a window; there came five or six of them, and got hold of the bridle, and stopped me; I told them I was a centinel; I thought I would ride as well as sleep, but d - n the mare, she would not go when I wanted her to go; I wish I had never seen her; she was not worth a farthing; I could not see any body to ask leave; I have been a soldier; I lost my right-hand where general Wolfe was killed; I am an out-pensioner at Chelsea, and have been going on these seven years.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I have heard he has been a watchman somewhere in St. James's, and that he behaved much in the same manner there.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661022-37-verdict190" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661022-37-verdict190" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
