<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680706-61">
               <interp inst="t17680706-61" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-61" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-61" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-61" type="date" value="17680706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680706-61-off327-c531" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-61-defend670 t17680706-61-off327 t17680706-61-verdict333"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680706-61-off327-c532" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-61-defend672 t17680706-61-off327 t17680706-61-verdict336"></join>
         
               <p>491, 492. (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680706-61-defend670" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Hawkins 
                  <interp inst="t17680706-61-defend670" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-defend670" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-defend670" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17680706-61-defend672" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Wild 
                  <interp inst="t17680706-61-defend672" type="surname" value="Wild"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-defend672" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-defend672" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted, for that <rs id="t17680706-61-off327" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-off327" type="offenceCategory" value="breakingPeace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-off327" type="offenceSubcategory" value="riot"></interp>
               they, together with divers other persons to the number of an hundred or more, being malefactors and disturbers of the peace, on the <rs id="t17680706-61-cd328" type="crimeDate">9th of May</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-61-off327 t17680706-61-cd328"></join> with force and arms <placeName id="t17680706-61-crimeloc329">near the Mansion-house</placeName>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-crimeloc329" type="placeName" value="near the Mansion-house"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-crimeloc329" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                     <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-61-off327 t17680706-61-crimeloc329"></join> of the Right Hon. 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680706-61-victim674" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Harley 
                        <interp inst="t17680706-61-victim674" type="surname" value="Harley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-61-victim674" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-61-victim674" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17680706-61-viclabel330" type="occupation">Lord Mayor of the city of London</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-61-victim674 t17680706-61-viclabel330"></join>, unlawfully, riotously, and tumultuously did gather together, in order to disturb the peace of our Lord the King; that he the said Hawkins did threaten to knock down the said Lord Mayor acting in the execution of his office, and in and upon one 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680706-61-victim676" type="victimName">
                           Philip 
                           Pyle 
                        <interp inst="t17680706-61-victim676" type="surname" value="Pyle"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-61-victim676" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-61-victim676" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , being one of the <rs id="t17680706-61-viclabel331" type="occupation">servants</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-61-victim676 t17680706-61-viclabel331"></join> of the Lord Mayor, assisting, and by his commands, and in his presence, him the said Pyle with a certain slambeau and a large stick over his head and divers other parts of his body, did beat and strike, so that his life was greatly despaired of, &amp;c. &amp;c.
            </rs> ++</p>
               <p>Mr. Way. About eight o'clock in the evening of the 9th of May, going from Swithin's-alley to Batson's coffee-house, I saw a croud of people carrying a gibbet, on which hung a boot and petticoat, going down towards the Mansion-house; I stopped to observe whether they made any stand at the Mansion-house, I observed they halted there; there were great hissing and hallooing; I went to the Mansion-house, and had not been there above a minute or two before I saw my Lord Mayor come out of the gates of the Mansion-house, making his way towards the people that supported this gibbet; I believed when I saw them in Cornhill, there did not seem to be more than fifty or sixty; seeing my Lord go out by himself I made my way up to him; before I got to him, I saw the prisoner laying about him with a stick, which I afterwards observed had some nails in it; he had struck one or two people, which afterwards I found to be my Lord Mayor's servants; they had hold of him, endeavouring to bring him into the Mansion-house at the little gate by Charlotte-row; while the scuffle was between him and my Lord's servants, I heard several people cry, knock him down, knock him down; the prisoner had disengaged himself from them, and was making towards the corner of the Poultry by the linen-draper's; I stepped very briskly cross the kennel and laid hold of him by the collar; I drew him back; and with the assistance of the other servants he was lodged in the Mansion-house; the mob was by that time increased to I believe 150, making a noise, hollooing and hiffing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-61-person677">
                  Philip 
                  Pyle 
               <interp inst="t17680706-61-person677" type="surname" value="Pyle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-person677" type="given" value="Philip"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-person677" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to my Lord Mayor; I was attending my Lord Mayor on the 9th of May about eight o'clock in the evening, my Lord and Lady were going out in a coach; some persons brought in notice that there was a large mob coming down Cornhill; I was standing in Charlottle-row with a flambeau in my hand, I went to see who they were; my Lord Mayor in the mean time came down the steps, as the gibbet was brought to the Mansion-house; there might be 150 of the mob, the street was all full from Cornhill to the Poultry, they were hissing and crying Wilkes and liberty; I observed one in particular had a blue cockade in his hat, the same as Mr. Wilkes gave at the election; my Lord Mayor said, bring back that thing, throwing out his hand; I believe there might be a dozen or fourteen had hold of it, carrying it along; it was a pretty formidable thing when it was together; they turned their heads many of them, but made<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176807060064"></xptr> no halt; I followed the gibbet as far as the pastry-cook's; I got hold of it and gave it such a shake, they were obliged to quit it; I turned with it in my hand, and was pulling it back towards the Mansion-house; there was one man came to me, I believe not the prisoner, and catched the slambeau out of my hand (it had not been lighted) and laid it about my head, and broke my head in several places; I let drop the gibbet which I had in my left-hand, in order to defend myself against the mob; I twisted the flambeau out of the man's hand, and I believe I did return it, I believe I did not strike above once; I believe there were two or three about me striking of me; I thought I must make a retreat, fearing they should get me down, which if they had, they certainly would have murdered me; I made my way into Charlotte-row, I thought some of my fellow-servants might see me, and I might be relieved; just as I was turned the corner they fell upon me again; I received several violent blows on my head, I did not see from whom I received them; my coat was torn; I turned and saw the prisoner on my right-hand, the stick flew out of his hand, and my fellow-servant picked it up; he defended himself with his hands as well as he could, but I pulled him I dare say twenty yards through the mob; the mob had hold of him and me likewise; when I got within ten yards of the Mansion-house the mob rescued him from me; I catched at him again, but missed him, and I believe I was not three yards from him when Mr. Way took hold of him, then we brought him into the Mansion-house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thing throwed?</p>
               <p>Pyle. No, I did not; then after that the windows were broke; that was an hour and a half or two hours after this.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the croud disperse upon these people being apprehended?</p>
               <p>Pyle. No, so far from that, they said they would have them out again; there was a single pane in one window, and another in another broke, when the prisoner was in the Mansion-house; he said he was coming by and had not touched any body, and that he did not think of any riot at all.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-61-person678">
                  Thomas 
                  Woodward 
               <interp inst="t17680706-61-person678" type="surname" value="Woodward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-person678" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-person678" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to my Lord Mayor. On Monday the 9th of May about eight in the evening, my fellow servant and I were standing at the Mansion-house back door in Charlotte-row, waiting for my Lord and Lady who were going out; the people were coming down with a gibbet, with a boot and two petticoats; my fellow-servant said, here is something coming, we will go to the corner and see what it is; my Lord came out from the steps and called out, what is that, bring it back; they had halted, but were moving on; my Lord said something to my fellow servant; he went to the gibbet and pulled it down; I saw the people take his flambeau out of his hand, and give him one or two blows with it, I could not see who struck him; afterwards the prisoner Hawkins took a piece of wood from the gibbet and struck my fellow-servant, (produced in court a large piece of timber about four feet long with nails in it;) he struck him with it more than once, twice, or three times; I received one blow upon my head and shoulder with it; I received a blow or two from some other person, but do not know who: as we were conveying the prisoner Hawkins to the back door, the people came on so fast, if I had not had this stick the prisoner would have been rescued from Mr. Way and my fellow-servant; I struck at one or two, one I knocked down, I believe in the kennel; when we got the prisoners in, I was left in a room with them; all that I know of Wild, I did not see him before he entered the door, I can give no account of him; I asked him how he could do so; Hawkins said he was sorry for it, but said he did not know he had struck any body.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any of you see where my Lord Mayor was in the time of the scuffle?</p>
               <p>Woodward. I saw him on the steps, and afterwards I saw him out in the mob near the pastry-cook's; I think he had a scarlet coat on and green silk waistcoat.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-61-person679">
                  Edward 
                  Stinton 
               <interp inst="t17680706-61-person679" type="surname" value="Stinton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-person679" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-person679" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am also a servant to my Lord Mayor; my Lord Mayor stood upon the steps of the Mansion-house; he came down and desired the mob to disperse, and not breed any riot; he said he wondered what he had done that he could not rest in his house; he came out at the front gate, and came round upon the broad stones, the gibbet and boot were taken down then; I with the rest ran into the mob to see that nobody used my Lord ill; I saw a stick throwed at him, it came within two or three yards of him; I heard the prisoner Wild say, there he is, pointing to my Lord Mayor, knock him down, knock him down.</p>
               <p>Q. What was my Lord doing?</p>
               <p>Stinton. He had desired them to disperse.</p>
               <p>Q. How far might Wild be from my Lord Mayor?</p>
               <p>Stinton. About half a dozen yards or more from him.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176807060065"></xptr>Q. Was there a number of people round Wild at the time?</p>
               <p>Stinton. There were a great many; I laid hold of him, and I think I said, d - m you, what do you mean by knock him down; he said, I did not know who to knock down.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know Wild again?</p>
               <p>Stinton. Yes, very well; I took him in myself, and my Lord was at the door at the same time.</p>
               <p>Pyle. When Hawkins was examined at Guildhall, he acknowledged he took the stick from the gibbet, though before he had denied having any stick at all.</p>
               <p>Hawkins's defence.</p>
               <p>Best part of what is charged against me is very wrong; I am <rs id="t17680706-61-deflabel332" type="occupation">a lighterman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-61-defend670 t17680706-61-deflabel332"></join>, and came from the water-side; about five o'clock I left the Custom-house and came to Bear-key, I live in Old street; coming home I saw a great mob going along Cornhill; I followed the mob, I saw my Lord's servant lay hold of the gibbet on a man's shoulder, and haul it down; I saw several people strike him with a flambeau; the mob hauled me in among them; the gallows was lying under foot, he had got hold of one part of it, hauling it away; he laid hold of me by the collar twice; I took hold of a piece of wood, but this is not the piece, it was a broomstick, and I throwed it out among the mob, who it hit I cannot tell; he got hold of me as I was making off from among the mob; then Mr. Way collared me, and brought me into the Mansion-house, there the footman ran his fist in my face three times, and said, I wish I had no more to do than to lick you and half a dozen such.</p>
               <p>Wild's defence.</p>
               <p>I saw a man in a white coat in the croud; I asked what he had done, I was told he was a pick-pocket; I heard others say, knock him down, and I believe I said so; they laid hold of my collar and asked me who I would have knocked down; I said, nobody, friend; he said he heard me say, knock him down; I said, I said no such word; he said he did insist upon my going into the Mansion-house; I made no resistance, but went; I am very wrongfully accused, I was not there three minutes; there was no gibbet, no boot, no nothing when I came there.</p>
               <p>Hawkins <rs id="t17680706-61-verdict333" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-verdict333" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680706-61-punish334" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-punish334" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-punish334" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-61-defend670 t17680706-61-punish334"></join>
               Imp.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680706-61-punish335" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-punish335" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-punish335" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-61-defend670 t17680706-61-punish335"></join>
               
                     <note>[Fine. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>Wild <rs id="t17680706-61-verdict336" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-61-verdict336" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
