<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660219-18">
               <interp inst="t17660219-18" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-18" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-18" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660219"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660219-18" type="date" value="17660219"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660219-18-off82-c150" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-18-defend189 t17660219-18-off82 t17660219-18-verdict86"></join>
         
               <p>130. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-18-defend189" type="defendantName">
                     David 
                     Miller 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-18-defend189" type="surname" value="Miller"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-defend189" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-defend189" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660219-18-off82" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-off82" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-off82" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing three pair of pistols, value 14 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660219-18-victim191" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Henshaw 
                  <interp inst="t17660219-18-victim191" type="surname" value="Henshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-victim191" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-victim191" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-18-off82 t17660219-18-victim191"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660219-18-cd83" type="crimeDate">Jan. 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-18-off82 t17660219-18-cd83"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-18-person192">
                  William 
                  Henshaw 
               <interp inst="t17660219-18-person192" type="surname" value="Henshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person192" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person192" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17660219-18-crimeloc84">Norfolk-street in the Strand</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-18-crimeloc84" type="placeName" value="Norfolk-street in the Strand"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660219-18-crimeloc84" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-18-off82 t17660219-18-crimeloc84"></join>, and am a <rs id="t17660219-18-viclabel85" type="occupation">gun-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660219-18-victim191 t17660219-18-viclabel85"></join>. On the 1st of January last, about 8 o'clock in the morning, I missed three pair of pistols.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-18-person193">
                  Alexander 
                  Atkins 
               <interp inst="t17660219-18-person193" type="surname" value="Atkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person193" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person193" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Henshaw. I was shutting up the windows, about 8 o'clock, and discovered a hole in the window. I went within side, there I missed three pair of pistols from off the hooks, near the hole.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-18-person194">
                  Patrick 
                  Rock 
               <interp inst="t17660219-18-person194" type="surname" value="Rock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person194" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person194" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the corner of Hatton-garden, Holborn. I keep a silversmith's shop, and sell pistols. On the 22d of January, the prisoner came and asked me if I would buy a pair of pistols, and shewed me a pair: he asked me 30 shillings for them; they were unfinished; I bid him 15; he agreed to take that (produced in court, and deposed to by prosecutor). I paid him for them. Said he, I have some other things of value and consequence to sell. After he was gone, I suspected him, and was determined to stop him when he came again. On the 23d he brought me another pair, silver mounted, (produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutor). He asked six guineas for these. I was behind the counter, and kept talking to him in order to keep him till somebody came by to assist me. He suspected I was going to apprehend him; he catched that I had out of my hand, and ran away. I called, stop thief, and pursued: he threw the pistols out of his hand in a handkerchief into the high way. A gentleman here took them up. I took him, with assistance, opposite the bishop of Ely's gate, in Holborn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-18-person195">
                  Richard 
                  Cadwell 
               <interp inst="t17660219-18-person195" type="surname" value="Cadwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person195" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person195" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 23d of January, I heard Mr. Rock cry, stop thief. The prisoner ran by me with a handkerchief in his hand, which he threw into the high way, and in running about 12 yards farther, we secured him: the pistols were taken up, which he threw away in the handkerchief. He said, they were his own property.</p>
               <p>Lambeth Case. I was going up Holborn the 23d of January, between 8 and 9 o'clock. I was on one side the way, and the prisoner on the other; running, he threw the handkerchief and pistols away so artfully, that I did not see the pistols till the handkerchief was taken up. I took them up. The prisoner demanded them as his property. He was taken before Justice Girdler, and committed.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I had been in the city: coming home there were people fighting, and a mob, near St. Clement's church-yard. I felt something with my foot, a person near me stumbled over it; he turned back, and I picked it up. There were two pair of pistols. He claimed a right to them. I said, do they belong to you? I did not show him them. This was between 6 and 7 in the evening. I went on about my business. I said, he should drink if he pleased. We went to a public house, and had a pot of beer; after that I had another pint; he wanted half what I had found, but I would not give him any thing. I went home, and after that I went to sell them to that gentleman. I carried a pair first that were unfinished; a workman told me they were worth 4 guineas, but it would cost 2 or 3 more to finish them. I sold them for 15 s. and bought two silver tea spoons. I said, I had another pair at home of consequence. Said he, if you'll bring them, I'll buy them. I brought them about 9 o'clock. We did not agree. When I was got about 2 or 3 yards from the door, he called, stop thief. I stumbled, and they sell out of my hand. The gentleman came and said I was a thief. I said, they were my pistols and handkerchief. They took me before the Justice.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660219-18-person196">
                  James 
                  Elmore 
               <interp inst="t17660219-18-person196" type="surname" value="Elmore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person196" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person196" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a night-man. I never knew the prisoner till I met him in the Strand about a month or five weeks ago. About 6 or 7 in the evening I had my rod in my hand, by St. Clement's church-yard. I saw a mob of people. I got up near the houses: there I felt something.<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176602190012"></xptr> The prisoner stooped and picked it up. I said, friend, what have you got there? He said, what is that to you; he still kept going on towards Catherine-street. I was going to Hanover-street, Long acre. I saw him look several times at it, but he did not open it. He asked me if I had lost any thing, I said, no. I asked him two or three times what he had got there. I saw it was something tied in a handkerchief. We stopped at the White Bear, at the corner of Hanover street; there he would treat me with a pot of beer; then he opened the handkerchief, and shewed me four pistols, then he called for another pint, and threw down six-pence, and ran away, and I never saw him since, only once in Newgate; he sent me a letter to come to him there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell him where you lived?</p>
               <p>Elmore. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to know how to direct to you?</p>
               <p>Elmore. I can't tell that, and this day a woman brought me a subpoena. I went to a lawyer in Clifford's-inn to know whether I must come here, and he told me I must. I received two letters from him, one from New Prison, that I have lost, the other from Newgate (producing it.) I went to him accordingly. I did not go to New Prison, the letter being signed David Miller, and I did not know any person of that name.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were your letters directed to?</p>
               <p>Elmore. To the White Bear. I use that house, and always leave my rod there. I received the letters there, directed to Mr. James, night-man, at the White Bear, Castle-street.</p>
               <p>Q. How came he to know your business?</p>
               <p>Elmore. I can't tell that.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did the prisoner mention any thing of this before the Justice?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He said he found them close up against a door in the Strand. I never heard him mention any mob or fighting, or any thing of this man.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17660219-18-person197">
                  Mary 
                  Hains 
               <interp inst="t17660219-18-person197" type="surname" value="Hains"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person197" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person197" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17660219-18-person198">
                  Jacob 
                  Janeway 
               <interp inst="t17660219-18-person198" type="surname" value="Janeway"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person198" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-person198" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who had known him about two years, who said, they never knew any ill of him.</p>
               <p>The letter read to this purport:</p>
               <p>"SIR,</p>
               <p>"I should be obliged to you if you will let me</p>
               <p>"see you to-morro w morning. I sent one letter</p>
               <p>"to you before, when I was in New Prison; as</p>
               <p>"I did not see you then, I beg, for God's sake,</p>
               <p>"you will come to me, and ask for one David</p>
               <p>"Miller.</p>
               <p>"Newgate, Dated Feb. 14."</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660219-18-verdict86" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660219-18-verdict86" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>;</p>
            </div1>
