<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640113-28">
               <interp inst="t17640113-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-28" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-28" type="date" value="17640113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640113-28-off148-c211" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-28-defend262 t17640113-28-off148 t17640113-28-verdict152"></join>
         
               <p>97. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640113-28-defend262" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Osborn 
                  <interp inst="t17640113-28-defend262" type="surname" value="Osborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-defend262" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-defend262" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17640113-28-deflabel147" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-28-defend262 t17640113-28-deflabel147"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17640113-28-off148" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-off148" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-off148" type="offenceSubcategory" value="robbery"></interp>
               that she, in the dwelling house of 
                     <persName id="t17640113-28-person263">
                        Stephen 
                        Scott 
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person263" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-28-person263" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-28-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , near the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640113-28-victim265" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Bailey 
                        <interp inst="t17640113-28-victim265" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-28-victim265" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-28-victim265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-28-off148 t17640113-28-victim265"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person one shilling, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640113-28-cd149" type="crimeDate">December 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-28-off148 t17640113-28-cd149"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-28-person266">
                  John 
                  Bailey 
               <interp inst="t17640113-28-person266" type="surname" value="Bailey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person266" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I and my fellow-<rs id="t17640113-28-viclabel150" type="occupation">apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-28-victim265 t17640113-28-viclabel150"></join> were going to the play, on the 10th of December; we stopt about a door or two from Little Queen's-street, about half an hour past seven at night. My companion went up an Alley, and I stood at a corner: the prisoner was there; she said, I should go home along with her, which I refused doing; she pulled me round the corner of Queen's-street, and called to another woman (that is here a witness) to assist her: that woman did not very readily comply with her; the prisoner did swear a great many oaths at her, and asked her, why she did not assist? after that, one took hold of one arm, and the other the other, and dragged me into <placeName id="t17640113-28-crimeloc151">Cross-lane</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-28-crimeloc151" type="placeName" value="Cross-lane"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-28-crimeloc151" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-28-off148 t17640113-28-crimeloc151"></join>; when they got me to the door, I said to the prisoner, what shall I give you to let me go about my business? she said, any thing; I gave her two-pence for a pint of purl; after that<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176401130019"></xptr> she said to the other woman, go up stairs, and light a candle; the other ran up and lighted a candle. Then the prisoner said, take hold of his arm; then one took me by one arm, and the other by the other, and dragg'd me up stairs, into a one pair of stairs room. Then the prisoner said, you shall give us 6 d. I said, for what? she said then you shall lie with us both. After that was over, I said, I will give you 6 d. if you will let me go? she said, she would, if I would give it her. After I had given her 6 d. she said I must give her 6 d. more for her sister: I gave her another 6 d. Then she said, now, d - n your blood, I'll have another shilling; I said, you shall not. She said, then I'll murder you: I said, no, you shall not. She took a knife, and held it to my belly, and swore she would murder me, in case I did not give her another shilling. When I saw the knife, I hesitated a little; she said, d - n you, why don't you give it me? then I put my hand into my left side pocket, and gave her a shilling: then she said, d - n you, you have got some sly pocket, or other, let me see it; then she turned my apron aside, and put her hand into my pocket. I began to call out; then a person came down from a one pair of stairs higher, and bid her let me go: then I said, one 6 d. was my master's, and I dare not go home without it; she swore she would not give it me: then the other woman that had received a 6 d. of the prisoner, gave that to me again. I was then on the middle of the stairs; then I went to my fellow-'prentice at the play-house, and told him what had happened: I was advised to go to Justice Fielding. I went, and told his clerk of it; he desired me to come again on the Monday evening, and described the two women, and they were taken up very near the same place where I first saw them.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know either of the women before?</p>
               <p>Bailey. I never saw either of them before, to my knowledge.</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>Bailey. I shall be 20 years of age next June.</p>
               <p>Q. How many times might you have been at the play last year?</p>
               <p>Bailey. I was there but once last year, and but once or twice this year.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any attempt to get free from them?</p>
               <p>Bailey. I can't say I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not, when you was in the street?</p>
               <p>Bailey. I began to be frighted, seeing nobody but whores and thieves: I was afraid she would call out murder, and I should fall into bad bread.</p>
               <p>Court. So then you rather chose to wait till the other woman came down, to help you up stairs.</p>
               <p>Bailey. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What did they get from you in the whole?</p>
               <p>Bailey. Two shillings and two pence, but I got one sixpence back again.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it your master's money?</p>
               <p>Bailey. No; but I wanted it to go to the playhouse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-28-person267">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17640113-28-person267" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person267" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person267" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was never in company with the prisoner at the bar before that night; going thro' Holborn, I met with her: she asked me if I would go and drink a draught of purl.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. It was this day 5 weeks.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. I lodge in Cross-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you lodged there?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. I lodged there a month.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has she lodged in that lane?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. I don't know. As we were coming out from drinking the purl, she said, will you go home with me? She met this young man; I was on the other side, turning into Queen-street, about five yards before her: we went cross the street, through Queen-street, and to Cross-street; she asked the young man to go with her; she said, he was her acquaintance: she said, her husband was at home, and he would hand me down the candle to one pair of stairs; we went into a court, to a house next door to the Boot. As I walked before them, she asked me to take hold of his hand; he refus'd it. I said, why should you ask the young man to go, when he does not chuse it; she call'd me fool. I refused to lug him along: I walked before them, and at the door he gave her 2 d. for a pint of purl: she told me to go up stairs, I did: there was a drummer, he gave me a candle upon the stairs: I held it in my hand, and lighted them up stairs as I stood upon the stairs. When they were up stairs, she asked me to come in; then she asked me if I would be concerned with him. I told her I would not: she picked him up. They offered me some beer; I saw him give her 6 d. she asked him for another; he gave her another: she gave me one of them; then she intruded upon him to give her a shilling more: I turned my face to the fire, and he cry'd out murder. I turned round, and saw a knife in her hand: I asked her if she was not ashamed to show a knife to any body. She bid me mind my own business. She did not intend to hurt him, but to fright him, to see if he would<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176401130020"></xptr> give her more money. He said his master sent him on an errand, and gave him 6 d. and if he went home without his errand, his master would use him ill.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him give her any thing after you saw the knife?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. No, I did not. I desired her to give him the 6 d. but she would not; then I gave him the 6 d. I had; he was then gone down stairs, and stood at the street door. There were several people came down, and asked her if she was not ashamed of herself, by reason the young man call'd out, and cry'd, concerning his master's 6 d. I would not go in her company any more. On the Monday, I went and bought me a pair of pumps, and met the prisoner, and another woman with her. I told the other woman what a fright I was in: we were all three taken up about the middle of Queen-street.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of the drummer after that?</p>
               <p>M. Jones. I do not know. He came to the gaol, and threatned to destroy me.</p>
               <p>Q. to Bailey. Who is your master?</p>
               <p>Bailey. 
               <persName id="t17640113-28-person268">
                  Samuel 
                  Taylor 
               <interp inst="t17640113-28-person268" type="surname" value="Taylor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person268" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he is a jeweller.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he here?</p>
               <p>Bailey. No, he is not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-28-person269">
                  Thomas 
                  Oaks 
               <interp inst="t17640113-28-person269" type="surname" value="Oaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person269" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable. On Monday evening, the 12th of last month, Mr. Marsden, and this lad, Bailey, came to my shop: Marsden said, this lad has been robbed by some of my neighbours. I asked the lad if he should know them? he said, he should. I desired him to go into a public-house, a little way down Drury-Lane, and see if any of the parties were there: he did, and said there was none of them. We went down Great Queen-street, then into Little Queen-street; going along, I saw some women standing; I went to them, and said, young man, look at these women; he bid me take hold of the prisoner at the bar: I took her by the wrist; he said, this is the woman, I will swear, that held the knife to me and robbed me; the evidence was going along towards Holborn. I said to her, where are you going? she said she was going home. I called to the young man, to come and look at her: he had a sight of her face, by the light of a lamp, in Little Queen-street; said he, this is the woman that was with her. Mr. Fielding's clerk asked the young man to show the place where he was ill treated; he said he could; we went to Cross-lane: when we came to the place, it was dark; he went and got a half-penny candle, and lighted it, and went directly up to the very room of the prisoner at the bar, and said, this is the room where I was threatened and robbed: we took the two women to Sir 
               <persName id="t17640113-28-person270">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17640113-28-person270" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person270" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; he committed one to one place, and the other to another: the drummer was sitting by the fore-side, when we went into the room.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>The young woman, 
               <persName id="t17640113-28-person271">
                  Mary 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17640113-28-person271" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person271" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person271" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was at the door; she was a stranger to me; I never 
               <persName id="t17640113-28-person272">
                  drew
               <interp inst="t17640113-28-person272" type="given" value="drew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-person272" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             a knife on any body in my life; that was an old rusty knife, with which I fastened the door. I held it in my hand, but never threatned to stab him; I never put it near his belly, nor any thing like it; I never was so bloody-minded.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640113-28-verdict152" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-verdict152" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-verdict152" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640113-28-punish153" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-28-punish153" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-28-defend262 t17640113-28-punish153"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. Recommended to mercy.</p>
            </div1>
