<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600521-28">
               <interp inst="t17600521-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-28" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600521"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-28" type="date" value="17600521"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600521-28-off141-c248" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-28-defend304 t17600521-28-off141 t17600521-28-verdict144"></join>
         
               <p>205. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600521-28-defend304" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Field 
                  <interp inst="t17600521-28-defend304" type="surname" value="Field"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-defend304" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-defend304" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17600521-28-off141" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-off141" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-off141" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 38 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17600521-28-victim306" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Eustace 
                  <interp inst="t17600521-28-victim306" type="surname" value="Eustace"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-victim306" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-victim306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-28-off141 t17600521-28-victim306"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17600521-28-cd142" type="crimeDate">March 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-28-off141 t17600521-28-cd142"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>John Eustace. About Christmas, as I was going to bed, I dropp'd my watch and broke the glass; I gave it to my wife to put by; about the 14th of Dec. the prisoner came to work with me, he is a <rs id="t17600521-28-deflabel143" type="occupation">journeyman carpenter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-28-defend304 t17600521-28-deflabel143"></join>; he and my apprentice work'd at several places together, at which places there were things missing, such as handkerchiefs, shoes, lead, and other things; I at last discharg'd him, for what he had done in taking things at Capt. Hunt's at Mile-end; about a fortnight after he was gone, I ask'd my wife for the watch; we then miss'd that; I went and took up the prisoner, and charg'd him with taking it; he said, master hold your tongue and I'll tell you how I got it; he said, you know I was doing a bit of wainscotting, and I dropp'd my hammer, and stooping for that, I saw a watch hanging up the chimney as I look'd up, when stooping I took it away; I took him to Aldgate watch-house, there he own'd he took it before the constable; the next morning we went to take him before my Lord Mayor, a gentleman going by, ask'd what was the matter, and looking on the prisoner, said, he had brought him a watch to sell; he is here, and will give a farther account.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-28-person307">
                  Moses 
                  Barnet 
               <interp inst="t17600521-28-person307" type="surname" value="Barnet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-person307" type="given" value="Moses"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-person307" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . About 6 weeks ago, one night about 9 o'clock, a young man knock'd at my door, and ask'd for me; he ask'd me if I was a constable, I said yes; he said there is a young man offers a watch to sell for 27 s. to a Jew, which is worth 4 l. and he believ'd it was not honestly come by; I went with him to the 3 pigeons alehouse in Hounsditch, he shew'd me the person, which was the prisoner at the bar; I took the watch, and said to the prisoner, is this the watch you offer to sell; he said it is, what right have you to examine me; then I said I would keep the watch, and take you to the compter, except you give me a satisfactory account; he said, if I would go with him to his lodgings he'd make it appear to be his own property. He said he lodg'd with Mrs. Smith that keeps a school, one that I kne w very well; I went with him, I ask'd her if she knew that man; she said yes, he was a lodger of her's, and had been for about six months; I shew'd her the watch, and said, do you know this watch; she said yes; she thought it to be the prisoner's property; then I said take your watch again, and gave it to him, and I went away. After<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176005210036"></xptr> that I went back again, and desired to look at it again; Mrs. Smith had it, I look'd at it; I saw the name Gardner on it; I was foolish enough to deliver it again: about 3 weeks after this I seeing a mob of people, ask'd what was the matter, was told a man had stole a watch; I said I would look at him, it was the prisoner; I said friend, do you not remember me; he said yes, you are the man that stopp'd me with a watch, now he says he has lost it, I was with him before my Lord Mayor, there he said he took it from the prosecutor's chimney-piece, and was sorry for what he had done.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Eustace. When my husband had let his watch fall and broke the glass, he gave it me to take care of it, I put it into a drawer and cover'd it over, after which we miss'd it, the drawer was lock'd; afterwards I had seen it several times there; and one time I remember I found the lock shot up and the key out, and the drawer a little out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-28-person308">
                  John 
                  Bingham 
               <interp inst="t17600521-28-person308" type="surname" value="Bingham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-person308" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-person308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an apprentice to the prosecutor, I went with my master when he took the prisoner at his lodgings; I heard him own he took the watch, both then, and before my Lord Mayor.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I work'd in the next room to where this watch was, by all account in putting up some wainscot, either my hammer or chissel fell down, I stoop'd for it, I look'd up the chimney and saw this watch, if it was my master's watch; I jump'd up a little faster then ordinary, and took and put it in my pocket.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600521-28-verdict144" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-verdict144" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600521-28-punish145" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-28-punish145" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-28-defend304 t17600521-28-punish145"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
