<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-61">
               <interp inst="t17661217-61" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-61" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-61" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-61" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-61-off315-c517" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-61-defend653 t17661217-61-off315 t17661217-61-verdict318"></join>
         
               <p>75. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-61-defend653" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Curtis 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-61-defend653" type="surname" value="Curtis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-defend653" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-defend653" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, together with 
               <persName id="t17661217-61-person654">
                  Jacob 
                  Buckey 
               <interp inst="t17661217-61-person654" type="surname" value="Buckey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person654" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person654" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not taken, for <rs id="t17661217-61-off315" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-off315" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-off315" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one hempen sack, value 18 d. and three bushels of oats, value 3 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-61-victim656" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Sherwood 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-61-victim656" type="surname" value="Sherwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-victim656" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-victim656" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-61-off315 t17661217-61-victim656"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17661217-61-cd316" type="crimeDate">Feb. 6</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-61-off315 t17661217-61-cd316"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-61-person657">
                  William 
                  Elliot 
               <interp inst="t17661217-61-person657" type="surname" value="Elliot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person657" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person657" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a waterman; I was looking out for a fare about nine or ten months ago, about twelve at night; the prisoner and Buckey went into my boat; I went into her to stop them; they took my boat by force, and threatened to throw me overboard if I attempted to stop them; then they rowed over, and up the shore on the other side the water, between Horsleydown and Pickleberring; they went into a long-boat, and took me away with the boat, and threatened to drown me if I resisted; they lifted up the tarpaulin, and took out a sack, and put it in my boat, and brought it on shore at St. Catharine's; as they were carrying it up from the boat, some how or other it spilt; there came an officer, and said there had been some roguery, by seeing oats lying about; they were almost all shot out; I do not know what they did with the oats that were not scattered; we were all suffered to go away that night.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Elliot. He is a <rs id="t17661217-61-deflabel317" type="occupation">waterman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-61-defend653 t17661217-61-deflabel317"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to tell of this affair now which was done so long ago, and not speak of it then?</p>
               <p>Elliot. I was afraid to tell of it before.</p>
               <p>Thomas Green. I am a watchman at St. Catharine's; about half an hour after twelve that night, I saw some oats on St. Catharine's-stairs, and also an empty sack was found there; Buckey brought them on shore; they were going to empty them into another sack on the stairs, and some were scattered about; there were such a gang of them I was afraid of my life; I go in danger of my life now, and dare not do my duty.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-61-person658">
                  John 
                  Vaughan 
               <interp inst="t17661217-61-person658" type="surname" value="Vaughan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person658" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person658" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . At that time I was headborough; on the 5th of February at night, I went down to the watch-house, and asked if all was right; Green told me something was not right; I went down to the stair-head, and saw some oats lying; I took and filled my handkerchief, the prisoner was there, he took up some; I thought a robbery had been committed; I desired a watchman to light me about; looking under the waterman's bench, I found a sack, with Mr. Sherwood's name on it; the next morning Mr. Sherwood's man came and owned it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-61-person659">
                  William 
                  Sherwood 
               <interp inst="t17661217-61-person659" type="surname" value="Sherwood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person659" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person659" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I am a corn-factor; the sack which was found was my property; I lost a sack of oats that night, it was stolen from out of one of my crafts; the few that was scattered there, which was about half a bushel, they appeared to be the same as mine.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I and 
               <persName id="t17661217-61-person660">
                  Jacob 
                  Buckey 
               <interp inst="t17661217-61-person660" type="surname" value="Buckey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person660" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person660" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had been down below, coming up, we met with the King George, a Holland trader; we towed the vessel up to Lime-house, after that we took the passengers out; they said they wanted to go to the Thirteen Cantoons, we thought at Iron-gate; when we came to St. Catharine's-stairs, there was this 
               <persName id="t17661217-61-person661">
                  William 
                  Elliot 
               <interp inst="t17661217-61-person661" type="surname" value="Elliot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person661" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person661" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I saw a sack in his boat, he was going to lend a man a hand up with the sack, he wanted me to lend him a hand; I would not, having other business to do; Elliot swore at me, and called<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170053"></xptr> me all the dogs he could think of; I went away, and when I came to the Thirteen Cantoons, they were not the right; it should have been the Thirteen Cantoons, at the Seven Dials; being tired I could not get there; we had two pots of beer, and were coming down to the waterside; the headborough was coming out of the Two Brewers, and followed us down; when he came to the stair-head, there lay the oats, but in the night nobody knew what it was; I came down, and said it was oats; the headborough filled his handkerchief, and I filled mine; we carried them both into the watch-house; Elliot was standing at the same time by the fire-side, in the watch-house; I said there must have been thieves; the officer said bring a light out, look about, and see if you can find any thing else; they found a sack with Mr. Sherwood's name on it.</p>
               <p>He called 
               <persName id="t17661217-61-person662">
                  Francis 
                  Steadman 
               <interp inst="t17661217-61-person662" type="surname" value="Steadman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person662" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person662" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17661217-61-person663">
                  John 
                  Lee 
               <interp inst="t17661217-61-person663" type="surname" value="Lee"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person663" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-person663" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who gave him a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661217-61-verdict318" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-61-verdict318" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
