<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660514-22">
               <interp inst="t17660514-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-22" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-22" type="date" value="17660514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660514-22-off130-c173" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-22-defend220 t17660514-22-off130 t17660514-22-verdict135"></join>
         
               <p>306. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-defend220" type="defendantName">
                     Charles 
                     Presley 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-22-defend220" type="surname" value="Presley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-defend220" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-defend220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660514-22-off130" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-off130" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-off130" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing eleven callico shirts, value 3 l. seven pair of silk stockings, value 30 s. four cotton nightcaps, value 1 s. one linen towel, value 6 d. five muslin stocks, value 5 s. one silk handkerchief, value 12 d. 3 cotton handkerchiefs, value 12 d. one stone stock-buckle set in silver, one stone garnet ring set in gold, two pair of knit worsted breeches, one cloth coat, one cloth waistcoat trimmed with gold lace, five yards of flannel, two pair of shoes, one pair of metal shoe-buckles, gilt, and other wearing apparel
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-victim222" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Carr 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-22-victim222" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-victim222" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-victim222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-22-off130 t17660514-22-victim222"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660514-22-cd131" type="crimeDate">May 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-22-off130 t17660514-22-cd131"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-person223">
                  John 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17660514-22-person223" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person223" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17660514-22-viclabel132" type="occupation">Lieutenant in his Majesty's navy</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-22-victim222 t17660514-22-viclabel132"></join>; I came to the <placeName id="t17660514-22-crimeloc133">Golden Cross, Charing-cross</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-22-crimeloc133" type="placeName" value="Golden Cross, Charing-cross"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-22-crimeloc133" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-22-off130 t17660514-22-crimeloc133"></join>, last Sunday night, between seven and eight o'clock, in a post-chaise; I desired Mr. Sloman to get me a coach; I had a leather portmanteau, with these things mentioned in the indictment in it; I saw the portmanteau safely landed in the entry at the inn; when Mr. Sloman called a coach, he told me he put the portmanteau into it; and when I went to see for the coach it was gone; the things were found again, there was nothing taken away; the prisoner was before Justice Girdler on Wednesday morning; he said he knew nothing of the matter; it appears he was the master of the coach.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-person224">
                  William 
                  Sloman 
               <interp inst="t17660514-22-person224" type="surname" value="Sloman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person224" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person224" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Golden Cross, Charing cross; on Sunday evening last it was very wet, and coaches were very scarce. Mr. Carr ordered me to call a coach; I saw the prisoner near my door; I asked him if he would go; he said he would. I took Mr. Carr's portmanteau and put it in his coach.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner see you put it in?</p>
               <p>Sloman. I will not take upon me to say that; I returned and acquainted Mr. Carr I had got a coach for him, and went for the rest of the things to put them into the coach, and when we returned, the coach and portmanteau was gone; by knowing the coachman's name, I went to the coach-office, and got an account where he lived; I went to his house and spoke to his wife; she said she knew nothing of the matter; the next morning I went to Justice Fielding and got a warrant, and went to the prisoner's house again on the Tuesday morning, there I found him; he said he knew nothing of a portmanteau; I might take what method I pleased, I took him before Justice Girdler, who committed him. In our return from the Justice's, I told him he had better produce the portmanteau; he said he had a man that cleaned his coach and looked after his horses sometimes, of whom he had a very bad opinion; and he had great reason to think, from his absconding, he had got the portmanteau: that he could not tell his name, only that he went by the name of Gallows Jack; he sent a man to look for him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-person225">
                  George 
                  Erskine 
               <interp inst="t17660514-22-person225" type="surname" value="Erskine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person225" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the Tuesday night this gentleman brought me a warrant to apprehend the prisoner at the bar; I took him before Justice Girdler; he said he knew nothing about the portmanteau, it was never put into his coach: but he had a servant who had absconded ever since the Monday, which he had reason to suspect had taken it away, he not coming to his work as usual. A man came to us; I said to him, If you have any regard for this man, go and seek after him; he said he would, and come and let me know if he heard any intelligence of him; in the morning he came, and told me he had heard nothing of him. On the Wednesday morning the prisoner's wife came to me between six and seven o'clock, and told me the portmanteau was thrown into their coach-yard; I went, and there I found it. There was a padlock upon the place where the coach went in; I believe it never had been<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176605140018"></xptr> opened till I opened it; it has been in my custody ever since, (produced in court, and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was at Charing-cross between six and seven that night; Mr. Sloman came and ply'd me; I said I would, but he did not deserve serving, because he never employed me when the weather was fair, and this was a very wet evening; I went to get myself a glass of rum, a few doors beyond the Golden-Cross; in the mean time, a gentleman dressed in black, and a lady, were got into my coach; they ordered me to go to Ludgate-hill; there I set them down; I got a fare into Cheapside, and from thence came into Holbourn, and from thence returned home, and put my coach up: the next morning I went out as usual; when I came home at about ten at night, Mr. Sloman had been to my wife after a portmanteau; I told her I had not seen any such thing, and if there was any such thing missing my servant that was absconded was the likeliest person to have it. Mr. Sloman came again on Tuesday in the afternoon, and charged this thing upon me; I denied it: he took me before Justice Girdler; as we were coming back, I told him, if there was any thing lost, the servant that was gone from my service had got it; upon that, I employed a neighbour to see after him; soon after, I had intelligence the portmanteau was brought to light. I did not see it put into the coach, and I never saw it before I was at Justice Girdler's; the two people that came into my coach came out of Mr. Sloman's house.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-person226">
                  Edward 
                  Cozens 
               <interp inst="t17660514-22-person226" type="surname" value="Cozens"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person226" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Sloman desired me to get a coach; I called the prisoner; he went to get a dram, and Mr. Sloman put the portmanteau into the coach; two people came out of Mr. Sloman's house and got into the coach; the prisoner came and got upon the box; they desired him to drive them to the Fleet-market. Mr. Sloman came out afterwards, and asked where the coach was; I told him, the people that came out of his house got into it, and ordered him to drive to Fleet-market.</p>
               <p>Q. to Sloman. Do you recollect what this evidence has related?</p>
               <p>Sloman. I asked him where the coach was; he told me it was drove on with people in it; I am pretty clear in it, he did not say they came out of my house, though he said it afterwards.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-person227">
                  Thomas 
                  Bamford 
               <interp inst="t17660514-22-person227" type="surname" value="Bamford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person227" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner sometimes employs one man and sometimes another; he did not employ one in particular long; I know a man that was employed, has not been in his service since.</p>
               <p>Q. What was his name?</p>
               <p>Bamford. I really do not know his name; he is called by the name of Gallows Jack. I am a <rs id="t17660514-22-deflabel134" type="occupation">coachman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-22-defend220 t17660514-22-deflabel134"></join>, and live in the same yard where the prisoner does.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen that Gallows Jack last?</p>
               <p>Bamford. I think I saw him the day before the portmanteau was said to be lost; I have known the prisoner between two and three years; I never heard any ill of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-person228">
                  James 
                  Ballanger 
               <interp inst="t17660514-22-person228" type="surname" value="Ballanger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person228" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person228" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a carpenter, and live at Hatton-wall; I have known him about four years; he has been tenant to me that time; I never heard any thing bad of him before this. I never saw him in liquor in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-person229">
                  Thomas 
                  Rusby 
               <interp inst="t17660514-22-person229" type="surname" value="Rusby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person229" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person229" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a corn-chandler; I have known him upwards of three years: I live at Hatton-wall. I never heard any thing to the discredit of the man in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-person230">
                  Peter 
                  Vigers 
               <interp inst="t17660514-22-person230" type="surname" value="Vigers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person230" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Hat and Tun, a public-house at Hatton-wall; I have known him between five and six years; he bears a very good character for whatever I heard. I never saw him in liquor in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-person231">
                  Thomas 
                  Farley 
               <interp inst="t17660514-22-person231" type="surname" value="Farley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person231" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person231" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the Royal Oak at Hatton-wall; I have known him five or six years; I never heard or saw any thing amiss of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-22-person232">
                  Joseph 
                  Harper 
               <interp inst="t17660514-22-person232" type="surname" value="Harper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person232" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Hatton-garden; I have known him a year and a half, he is a very honest industrious man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660514-22-verdict135" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-22-verdict135" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
