<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680706-42">
               <interp inst="t17680706-42" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-42" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-42" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680706"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680706-42" type="date" value="17680706"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680706-42-off230-c261" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-42-defend346 t17680706-42-off230 t17680706-42-verdict233"></join>
         
               <p>457. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680706-42-defend346" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Johnson 
                  <interp inst="t17680706-42-defend346" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-42-defend346" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-42-defend346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17680706-42-off230" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-42-off230" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-42-off230" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape on the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680706-42-victim348" type="victimName">
                           Elizabeth 
                           Watson 
                        <interp inst="t17680706-42-victim348" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-42-victim348" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680706-42-victim348" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-42-off230 t17680706-42-victim348"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17680706-42-viclabel231" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-42-victim348 t17680706-42-viclabel231"></join>, <rs id="t17680706-42-cd232" type="crimeDate">July 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680706-42-off230 t17680706-42-cd232"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-42-person349">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17680706-42-person349" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-42-person349" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-42-person349" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was twelve years of age the 20th of last month; I live with my father and mother in Windsor-street, Spitalfields; the prisoner is my father's brother-in-law, he married my mother's sister, and lives in Catherine-wheel-alley, Whitechapel.</p>
               <p>Q. Is your aunt alive?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. She is; I went up to his house and asked for a bit of bread, he gave me a bit; then he shut the door and pushed me down on the bed, nobody was there but he and I; I asked him why he shut the door; he said nothing; I asked him to let me go, because I had been playing by the way going to school, and it was then past one o'clock; after he got up I did, and went home; I did not go to him for some time after; when I went again he served me the same as before.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he serve you?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. He put his hand up my coats.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is the first time ago?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. That is three quarters of a year ago.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. Because I told the quarters.</p>
               <p>Q. How?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. With chalk in my own room on a piece of board.</p>
               <p>Q. How many quarters are there in a year?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. Nine.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know to set the second chalk up?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. I asked my mamma when the quarter was, and she told me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he do any thing on the bed to you?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. Yes, he made me wet on my private parts and on my shift; he said if ever I divulged it, or told it to any body, how he would serve me; the next time I sat in a chair.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. He put his impudence into my hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your aunt?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. She was gone out with old clothes; the last time was three weeks ago from this time.</p>
               <p>Q. What month was it?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has there been a difference between your mother and him?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. My mother has not spoke to him since yesterday was a week.</p>
               <p>Q. Is this all he has done to you?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. Yes, this is all.</p>
               <p>Q. How came your mother to know any thing about it?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. That was because I could not walk nor sit in a chair.</p>
               <p>Q. When did your mother find it out?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. She found it out yesterday was a week; he has given me a disorder, my mother and the doctor say so.</p>
               <p>Q. Has he done any thing to your body?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. He has.</p>
               <p>Q. With what?</p>
               <p>E. Watson. With his finger the first time, and a great many times after; that was the time he made my linen so wet, I was afraid to tell my mother.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680706-42-person350">
                  Margaret 
                  Watson 
               <interp inst="t17680706-42-person350" type="surname" value="Watson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-42-person350" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680706-42-person350" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am mother to the child; she told me this yesterday was a fortnight; she sat very uneasy on a chair; I said, what is the matter you are so uneasy; she said, I am very bad, I wish you would let me go to bed; she put her finger to her private part, and brought something very odd from her; I asked her who had been meddling with her; she said nobody had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you look at her?</p>
               <p>M. Watson. No, I did not indeed; my sister came and was kind enough to send for a quartern of gin; when my husband came home I said, I am afraid something is the matter with your daughter, and told him what I suspected; my brother the prisoner came in, he was three halfpence and I the same, and we had a quartern of gin between us four; I said to the girl, now if you do not tell me who has been meddling with you, I'll cut you to pieces; her uncle took the whip and looked severe at her; she said, mother, I will tell you the truth, it is my uncle; I clapped my hands together and made bold to call her b - h; I said what uncle; she said that uncle, there he stands; I let fly with great vengeance, and asked him how he could be guilty to lie with that child; he went up<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176807060020"></xptr> to her and said, you wicked hussey, what do you mean by that, do you mean to take my life; she said, you may say what you will, for you are the man; he made great wishes that he was innocent.</p>
               <p>Q. was the prisoner ever searched to see what condition he was in?</p>
               <p>M. Watson. No, he never was.</p>
               <p>Q. How does he live with his wife?</p>
               <p>M. Watson. As well as other people, they jar sometimes as the best of people do; I never heard no harm of him, he is a working man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I went in at her mother's, there was another woman drinking a dram; they said, brother, will you drink, my wife was there, (the father and mother have both had the misfortune to have the soul disease between them;) said the mother, what do you think, my daughter has got so and so; then said she, we are all alike; there lay the horsewhip on the floor; said I, if she has got that distemper I would take the horse-whip and whip all the skin from her bones; the girl sat a little while and said, uncle, if I must tell you, you gave it me; she lay along with her father and mother every night; had it been as she said so long ago, must they not have found it out; there is a boy of about eighteen years of age lives in a room above them, and whenever the mother stirs out they are together; the mother has catched him on the stairs with her, and licked him for it; I have told her mother several times the girl would be ruined.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680706-42-verdict233" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680706-42-verdict233" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
