<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610625-13">
               <interp inst="t17610625-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-13" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-13" type="date" value="17610625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610625-13-off70-c88" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-13-defend108 t17610625-13-off70 t17610625-13-verdict74"></join>
         
               <p>190. (M) 
               <persName id="t17610625-13-defend108" type="defendantName">
                  Cecily, <rs id="t17610625-13-deflabel69" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-13-defend108 t17610625-13-deflabel69"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17610625-13-person109">
                        Richard 
                        Adams 
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-person109" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610625-13-person109" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610625-13-person109" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-defend108" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-defend108" type="given" value="Cecily"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-defend108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610625-13-off70" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-off70" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-off70" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing three guineas, and two nine shillings pieces of Portugal gold
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-13-victim111" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Tudor 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-13-victim111" type="surname" value="Tudor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-victim111" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-victim111" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-13-off70 t17610625-13-victim111"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610625-13-cd71" type="crimeDate">May 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-13-off70 t17610625-13-cd71"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-13-person112">
                  William 
                  Tudor 
               <interp inst="t17610625-13-person112" type="surname" value="Tudor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-person112" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-person112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lost a queen Ann's guinea, and two others, and two nine shilling pieces, they were taken out of a little tin box, within a deal box, from out of a lower room.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Tudor. I live in <placeName id="t17610625-13-crimeloc72">East-smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-13-crimeloc72" type="placeName" value="East-smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610625-13-crimeloc72" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-13-off70 t17610625-13-crimeloc72"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>

               <p>Tudor. I am a <rs id="t17610625-13-viclabel73" type="occupation">coal-heaver</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-13-victim111 t17610625-13-viclabel73"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner live in your house?</p>
               <p>Tudor. She came the Sunday before to lodge in the house; she lodg'd six nights in the house, but not in that room. She came in over night that the money was lost, and sham'd drunk, and wanted to lie in that room, and pulled all her cloaths off, but my wife drove her up stairs.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-13-person113">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Hopkins 
               <interp inst="t17610625-13-person113" type="surname" value="Hopkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-person113" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-person113" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prosecutor is my father-in-law. About five o'clock that morning the money was lost, the prisoner came into the room where I lie, I was in bed, she look'd at me; the first thing she took, was a cardinal, and laid it over her left arm; the next thing, was a pair of black breeches, the next a shirt, the next a pair of stockings, the next a shift, and put them over her arm. Then she came and look'd over me again, then she went to the deal box that was close by my bed-side (this was on the Saturday morning) and I had had the money in my hand but the Friday before, it was in that deal box, put into a little tin box; she lifted the lid of the box up with her left hand, and drawed two of the nails.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to speak to her?</p>
               <p>E. Hopkins. I did not know what mischief she might do me, as my mother nor no-body else could hear me if I had called out. I saw the box in her right-hand, and heard the money jingle in the box. Then she went up where my mother lay, I followed her up. I said to my mother, where is the box that the money was in; she said, it is in that box by your bed-side. I told her, the prisoner had got the money. She throwed the cloaths down upon the table and flew away. My mother followed her, and down'd on her knees to the prisoner, and said, for God's sake, give me my money. The prisoner said, (what do you talk on) was all she said. Then my mother lock'd the door upon her. Then she said, d - n you, do you make a prison of your house; and said, she would break every pane of glass in the house, and tear my mother to pieces. Then my mother went for a constable, and a young woman that lay with the prisoner took care of her till the constable came. She was carried to justice Berry, I was at her examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What did she say?</p>
               <p>E. Hopkins. She said, she knew nothing of it, and was very unmannerly, and said, she long'd to go to Newgate, and that they were a long while writing her mittimus.</p>
               <p>Virtue Tudor. I am wife to the prosecutor. I was robbed of 4 l. 1 s. in gold, it was in a little tin box, put into a deal box; it was taken out of a lower room, my daughter lay there. She came up and asked me where was the key of the box; I said, it was in my pocket. Then she asked where the box was that had the money in it. I said, in the deal box. Then she said, the prisoner had taken the money out. The prisoner throwed the things from off her arm, and ran down two pair of stairs. I ran after her in my shift. I locked the door, and asked her for it. She turned about, and said, what do you talk of? I sent for my husband. She said, she would break the windows, and tear all the things to pieces. Then I called a constable; after that my husband came home.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never was out of their custody, till they carried me to New-prison. I had a shirt to wash for a seaman, that young woman washed it, and I ironed it; and I desired Mr. Tudor to call me up to go by times to Cherry-garden stairs, to deliver it. She came up and called me, I did not get up directly. When I came into the room where his wife lay, said she, I imagine you were a little in liquor, when you affronted me last night: I said, then I humbly ask pardon. Said she, I forgive you. I said, will you please to drink any thing? She said, I cannot say I chuse it. She said, you have no money; said I, will you lend me some. She said, I cannot say I have any. I goes back again, and took up a cardinal, a pair of breeches, and other things, and brought them, and laid them down on a chair by the bed-side. The young woman came in with a black petticoat on; said she, mother give me the key of the box, - what box, - Why, the box that the money is<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250011"></xptr> in, and the India handkerchief, that the outlandish-man gave me. She gave her the key; then she went away, and came to us in about a quarter of an hour, and said, mother, I want to speak to you, and whispered to her. Then she said, where is the money that was in that box? Said the mother, is not the money there? - no. Then the mother jumped out of bed, and took hold of me by the arm, and said, I insist upon you having the money. Said I, you are welcome to search me, you know I had none last night. She kept me, till she sent the girl and another person to Wapping-wall, for the father-in-law. He came in about three quarters of an hour after; and said, you had better deliver the money, and made a great many words; I had a great many things in my lap. Said I, I will not offer to stand in defiance against you in your own apartment. Then a constable was fetched, he took charge of me; they told him the affair. I was carried to justice Scott, we were in an alehouse three quarters of hour, before he was to be spoke with, they brought the box before him locked. Justice Scott desired him to go to justice Berry, we went and waited there about a quarter of an hour, then the young woman and mother were sworn, and I was committed to New-prison. I was searched, I pulled all off but my under petticoat, I had nothing about me, I never saw nothing of the money. Please to call the constable.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-13-person114">
                  John 
                  Harding 
               <interp inst="t17610625-13-person114" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-person114" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable, I searched the prisoner in the justice's yard, and found nothing at all upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it that you searched her?</p>
               <p>Harding. This was about ten o'clock.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He lives opposite the prosecutor, he was brought to me in the morning before he open'd shop, and was with me all the time almost.</p>
               <p>Harding. I had opened the shop before I came, and as the justice was not up, I left the prisoner in charge of the prosecutor's wife, and desired to be sent for, when it was a proper time, and when they were ready to go. When we came to justice Scott, he ordered me to carry her to 
               <persName id="t17610625-13-person115">
                  Walter 
                  Berry 
               <interp inst="t17610625-13-person115" type="surname" value="Berry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-person115" type="given" value="Walter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-person115" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610625-13-verdict74" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-13-verdict74" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
