<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650116-23">
               <interp inst="t17650116-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650116-23" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650116-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650116-23" type="date" value="17650116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650116-23-off125-c152" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-23-defend199 t17650116-23-off125 t17650116-23-verdict129"></join>
         
               <p>115. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650116-23-defend199" type="defendantName">
                     Joseph 
                     Wiggins 
                  <interp inst="t17650116-23-defend199" type="surname" value="Wiggins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-23-defend199" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-23-defend199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17650116-23-off125" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650116-23-off125" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-23-off125" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he, on the 12th of December, about the hour of one in the night, the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650116-23-victim201" type="victimName">
                           Bridget 
                           Jackson 
                        <interp inst="t17650116-23-victim201" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650116-23-victim201" type="given" value="Bridget"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650116-23-victim201" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-23-off125 t17650116-23-victim201"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17650116-23-viclabel126" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-23-victim201 t17650116-23-viclabel126"></join>, did break and enter, and stealing a brass kettle, value 2 s. a copper kettle, value 1 s. and a brass skellet, value 1 s.
            </rs> the property of the said Bridget, <rs id="t17650116-23-cd127" type="crimeDate">December 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-23-off125 t17650116-23-cd127"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-23-person202">
                  Bridget 
                  Jackson 
               <interp inst="t17650116-23-person202" type="surname" value="Jackson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-23-person202" type="given" value="Bridget"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-23-person202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . My house was broke open on the 12th of December, at night: there were two iron bars forced off the window, on the back part of my house; (producing the iron bars). The shutter to the window fastened with a button on the inside; the window was in the scullery: all the things mentioned in the indictment, except the brass kettle, were in that room; that was on a room joining to it: they were missing. After this was published abroad, Mr. West came and told me, he met the prisoner with a kettle, about the size of mine, on his head.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-23-person203">
                  Thomas 
                  West 
               <interp inst="t17650116-23-person203" type="surname" value="West"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-23-person203" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-23-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On a Friday, five weeks ago, tomorrow, I met the prisoner between the hours of twelve and one in the day, (this was two days after the house was broke open) in Norton-falgate, he had a brass kettle, covered over with a flag basket; I saw only the rim of it; it was the size and shape of her kettle; I had lived with the prosecutrix fifteen years, and she had told me of the robbery the day before; I know her kettle very well. I asked the prisoner if he had got his mistress's kettle, saying she had lost her kettle: said he, I live with a coppersmith, in Bishopsgate-street: he asked me when I should be at the Coach and Horses? he said he should be there in half an hour; and that he often carried kettles and things, 200 weight. He came to the Coach and Horses to me; we had some beer: he said, he could not get a coachman's place, on account of his character; so he got to be a porter, and had 15 l. a year, at this copper-smith's.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the justice, when he was examined?</p>
               <p>West. I was. There he was asked whether he lived with a copper-smith? his answer was, he lived here and there, and every where; sometimes in one place, and sometimes in another. On his second examination, the day before Christmas-day, I was there: then he said, he did not keep an almanack in his head. He was asked how he came by that kettle that I saw him with? then he said he bought it on the main road: he was asked what he did with it? he said, he sold it to a Jew.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutrix. Have you found any of your things again?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix, No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. He was <rs id="t17650116-23-deflabel128" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-23-defend199 t17650116-23-deflabel128"></join> to me about three years ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he use to lie in the house?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. No, he was by the week; but he used to come into the house.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650116-23-verdict129" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650116-23-verdict129" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
