<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660409-61">
               <interp inst="t17660409-61" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660409-61" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660409-61" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660409"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660409-61" type="date" value="17660409"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660409-61-off357-c502" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-61-defend643 t17660409-61-off357 t17660409-61-verdict360"></join>
         
               <p>273. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660409-61-defend643" type="defendantName">
                     Robert 
                     Slack 
                  <interp inst="t17660409-61-defend643" type="surname" value="Slack"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-defend643" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-defend643" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660409-61-off357" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-off357" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-off357" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing a bay mare, value 6 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660409-61-victim645" type="victimName">
                     Joseph 
                     Wilmot 
                  <interp inst="t17660409-61-victim645" type="surname" value="Wilmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-victim645" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-victim645" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-61-off357 t17660409-61-victim645"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660409-61-cd358" type="crimeDate">December 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-61-off357 t17660409-61-cd358"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-61-person646">
                  Joseph 
                  Wilmot 
               <interp inst="t17660409-61-person646" type="surname" value="Wilmot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person646" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person646" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mile-end; I lost a bay mare out of a field <placeName id="t17660409-61-crimeloc359">opposite Bancroft's alms-houses, in the parish of Stepney</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660409-61-crimeloc359" type="placeName" value="opposite Bancroft's alms-houses, in the parish of Stepney"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660409-61-crimeloc359" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-61-off357 t17660409-61-crimeloc359"></join>: there was an account in the news-papers, that Mr. Alderman Hewitt had committed 2 men who rode 2 bay mares; I wrote to a gentleman to describe them; and, by the description, I found one to be mine: I went down to Coventry, and found her in the possession of 
               <persName id="t17660409-61-person647">
                  Edward 
                  Tune 
               <interp inst="t17660409-61-person647" type="surname" value="Tune"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person647" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person647" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and swore to her as my property before the Alderman, and she was delivered to me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660409-61-person648">
                  Edward 
                  Tune 
               <interp inst="t17660409-61-person648" type="surname" value="Tune"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person648" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person648" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Coventry. On the 24th of December Mr. Alderman Hewitt sent for me, and told me a man at 
               <persName id="t17660409-61-person649">
                  William 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17660409-61-person649" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person649" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person649" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's was suspected to have a stolen mare; I went there, and seized the prisoner at the bar; the mare was at the shop-door. 
               <persName id="t17660409-61-person650">
                  William 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17660409-61-person650" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person650" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person650" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             keeps a public-house, and is a blacksmith. The prisoner was offering her to sale; Mr. Wilmot came to me, I showed him that mare; he claimed her as his property, and she was delivered to him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Alderman Hewitt. King came to me, and said there was a person offering a mare to sell, which he thought was worth 20 l. for 5 guineas, and he thought he did not come honestly by her. I desired the man might be brought before me. He was brought; it was the prisoner; I examined him how he came by the mare. He said he bought her in Smithfield. I ordered him to be searched: they found upon him a loaded pistol and a pocket-book, containing some notes; upon which I committed him that night upon suspicion, for farther examination. The next morning an account was brought me of Mr. Digby's being stopped; and the person that stopped him being described, gave me some reason to think this was the man. I sent for a constable, in order that he should be brought again for examination. The goaler himself came to me, and said the prisoner desired to be brought to me again, that he had something to say. He was brought; I examined him; he asked me some questions, to know, if he should make any discovery of his accomplices, whether he could have favour showed him. I told him, with respect to that, I could say nothing to it; if he had any thing to say, I was ready to take an account of it: but what use could be made of it I could not tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he sober?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hewitt. He was perfectly sober; he told me his brother was at Cuttle-mill.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give him any hopes at all of being made an evidence?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hewitt. At that time I did not. He was brought before me again: then I went upon a fresh examination; he then charged one Stedman as being concerned with him in cutting off the teats of cows. I sent this information to Sir 
               <persName id="t17660409-61-person651">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17660409-61-person651" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person651" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-person651" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , which he made against Stedman and others; and I had word again that they were taken and examined, but were certainly innocent.</p>
               <p>Q. Would he have made that confession if he had no expectation of favour?</p>
               <p>Mr. Hewitt. To that I cannot answer.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I used to buy and sell horses. On Friday the 20th of December, my brother and I bought these 2 mares of a country-like man; he said he came from Brentwood; we gave him 6 l. for one,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176604090034"></xptr> and 3 l. for the other: I have bought many horses in Smithfield-market. After I bought him, I went home to my father's house, and laid the receipts by, and could not tell Mr. Alderman Hewitt what I had done with them; I have had them brought to me; they are here: I never was in my father's house after the day we bought the mares.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660409-61-verdict360" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-verdict360" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660409-61-punish361" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660409-61-punish361" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660409-61-defend643 t17660409-61-punish361"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There was another indictment against the 2 brothers, for stealing a promissory note, value 14 l. 10 s. the property of their father.</p>
            </div1>
