<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680224-74">
               <interp inst="t17680224-74" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-74" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-74" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680224-74" type="date" value="17680224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680224-74-off461-c652" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-74-defend818 t17680224-74-off461 t17680224-74-verdict464"></join>
         
               <p>248. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680224-74-defend818" type="defendantName">
                     Peter 
                     Heliott 
                  <interp inst="t17680224-74-defend818" type="surname" value="Heliott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-defend818" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-defend818" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17680224-74-off461" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-off461" type="offenceCategory" value="miscellaneous"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-off461" type="offenceSubcategory" value="conspiracy"></interp>
               conspiring, together with 
                     <persName id="t17680224-74-person819">
                        Simeon 
                        Wall 
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-person819" type="surname" value="Wall"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-74-person819" type="given" value="Simeon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680224-74-person819" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , to sink a vessel, called the Felicity, on the high seas, with intention to defraud the insurers of several sums of money, to the amount of 1660 l
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680224-74-cd462" type="crimeDate">July 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-74-off461 t17680224-74-cd462"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>The prisoner being a foreigner, an interpreter was sworn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-74-person820">
                  John 
                  Haguerone 
               <interp inst="t17680224-74-person820" type="surname" value="Haguerone"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-person820" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-person820" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was on board the vessel Felicity at Honfleur in France, on the 3d of June, in order to conduct the ship to Barfleur; when I came in the road of Harve the hatches were covered with tarpawlin, there was a small quantity of corn strewed about the deck; Mr. Simeon Wall came on board, upon her setting sail for England; upon her arriving at Dover I went on shore, and brought the pilot on board; while I was at the helm the <rs id="t17680224-74-deflabel463" type="occupation">captain</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-74-defend818 t17680224-74-deflabel463"></join> ordered me down into the cabin, there he told me he was an undone man, that he could not appear in France or England, that his principals were bankrupts, and that Wall had brought him into the scrape; after this conversation, he told me I must help him to make a hole to sink the ship; I represented to him that was a very wicked act, and it would bring me into a bad scrape, it would make me lose all my clothes and effects, and risque my life: the captain (that is the prisoner) said, I should have all my clothes paid for, and he would give me an<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176802240057"></xptr> hundred pounds, and a note for the payment of it; I rejected the whole of that proposal; after that he told me he had begun, I advised him to repair the damage he had done.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he repair it?</p>
               <p>Haguerone. I do not know whether he did or not, the ship made no water before, and after that he began to make the hole she did not make water; there was one Champion on board. I told him what had passed; we both agreed to watch the captain.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether there was a cargo on board?</p>
               <p>Haguerone. The captain always told me there was. On that morning there was no complaint of the ship making water, till after the captain told me he had begun to make the hole; we were obliged to go to the pump; the ship made less water in the night; I imagine he had in part stopped the hole, least she should sink in the night; we were obliged to leave the vessel at about half an hour after eleven in the forenoon on the Thursday, in order to go on board an English vessel within about a cable length; when we apprehended danger, the captain was laid down on his bed, but not asleep; I went and told him he had begun his work; he said he had done nothing; he was one of the first that went out of the ship to go on board the English vessel, Champion was the last man that staid on board our ship; the ship disappeared in about three hours and a half after, whether she sunk or drove out of our sight I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the ship you was on board at anchor or under sail?</p>
               <p>Haguerone. She lay at anchor.</p>
               <p>Q. What water was in your ship when you all left her?</p>
               <p>Haguerone. The water was up to our middles in the bread-room, I believe the hole must have been made in the bread-room, and I believe he made it while we were under sail; we suppose it was made in the night, for we watched him in the day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-74-person821">
                  John 
                  Champion 
               <interp inst="t17680224-74-person821" type="surname" value="Champion"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-person821" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-person821" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Honfleur, I was pilot or second captain; the prisoner told me it was intended to load this ship with wheat and indico for London; I offered to supervise the taking in the cargo, as it is the business of the second captain; the captain said it was not necessary, that he only went for from, but the ship would be loaded; when we came on board we found all the batches fastened up, as if the cargo had been taken in; I went on board the 3d of July, on the 9th the ship was off Margate; the captain took me down into the cabin, and put me out a glass of brandy; he said he had no heart to drink, for he was an undone man; he showed me the bill of lading, and mentioned some casks of indico and some linen, and said he had signed a bill for goods not on board; I asked him where he had signed these bills; he said it was done, and he wished the ship was sunk; I said I shall never consent to it; he threw himself down on his bed, and seemed much distressed; we were obliged soon to quit the ship.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680224-74-person822">
                  Andrew 
                  Bezian 
               <interp inst="t17680224-74-person822" type="surname" value="Bezian"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-person822" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-person822" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I made insurances of goods on board this vessel, 800 sacks of wheat, 8 casks of indico, 4 bales of linen; after I had made insurances, Wall came to me, and said, we landed in Dover in a hard gale; after that I saw a person, who said the prisoner said the ship was lost off Margate; after this Wall came and desired me to get the money ready for the insurance; after that a report prevailed upon 'Change that the ship was found, and brought into Margate; I saw the prisoner and Wall together that afternoon, but soon heard they were gone to France, and there was a protest drawn up concerning the bill of lading; these two witness refused to sign it; I was then perfectly satisfied something was very bad; I gave notice to the under-writers to meet, Wall and the captain came together to get the insurance received; (the police produced, and proved by Mr. 
               <persName id="t17680224-74-person823">
                  Abraham 
                  Ogier 
               <interp inst="t17680224-74-person823" type="surname" value="Ogier"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-person823" type="given" value="Abraham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-person823" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a notary public, and a letter produced and read, giving an account of the cargo, and the demand of the money.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680224-74-verdict464" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-verdict464" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680224-74-punish465" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-punish465" type="punishmentCategory" value="noPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680224-74-punish465" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="sentenceRespited"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680224-74-defend818 t17680224-74-punish465"></join>
               
                     <note>[No punishment. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
