<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610625-35">
               <interp inst="t17610625-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-35" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610625"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610625-35" type="date" value="17610625"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610625-35-off206-c255" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-35-defend316 t17610625-35-off206 t17610625-35-verdict209"></join>
         
               <p>214 (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17610625-35-defend316" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Gathney 
                  <interp inst="t17610625-35-defend316" type="surname" value="Gathney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-35-defend316" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-35-defend316" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17610625-35-deflabel205" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-35-defend316 t17610625-35-deflabel205"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17610625-35-off206" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-35-off206" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-35-off206" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one piece of foreign silver, called a dollar, value 4 s. 6 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17610625-35-victim317" type="victimName">
                  Isabella 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17610625-35-victim317" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-35-victim317" type="given" value="Isabella"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-35-victim317" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-35-off206 t17610625-35-victim317"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17610625-35-viclabel207" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-35-victim317 t17610625-35-viclabel207"></join>, <rs id="t17610625-35-cd208" type="crimeDate">June 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610625-35-off206 t17610625-35-cd208"></join>. ++ .</p>
               <p>Isabella Morgan. I had a dollar that my husband brought home from Spain, and gave to me five years ago; I gave it into the landlady's hand to be looked at, she gave it me back again; then I let the boy at the ale-house where we were, take it to look at, he put it into a jay's cage, the joy took it in his mouth, and the boy and he played with it, till it dropped through, then the prisoner took it; she was the last in whose hands I saw it, she was in company with us in the same box. When I asked her for it she said, Do you want to rob me? and she would not comply with us to give it me again: it was lost between the prisoner and the bird.</p>

               <p>Q. Are you sure she had it last?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176106250038"></xptr>Is. Morgan. I never saw it after she had it; and when the constable was coming, she ran away, and locked herself up in her own apartment.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she ever own that she had it?</p>
               <p>Is. Morgan. No, she denied it; I never found it again.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the value of it?</p>
               <p>Is. Morgan. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it worth half a crown.</p>
               <p>Is. Morgan. It was about the bigness of a crown-piece. I cannot tell whether it was silver or not. I was told it was worth about four shillings and six pence.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body tell you it was not silver?</p>
               <p>Is. Morgan. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body tell you it was silver.</p>
               <p>Is. Morgan. Yes, a gentleman did, that I left it in pledge with.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610625-35-person318">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Cantlin 
               <interp inst="t17610625-35-person318" type="surname" value="Cantlin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-35-person318" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610625-35-person318" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep a publick-house. The prisoner and prosecutrix came in, the prisoner call'd for a pint of beer, and the prosecutrix for a pennyworth.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they come in together?</p>
               <p>E. Cantlin. No, they did not, but they knew one another. There were nobody but them in the house, but myself and my boy. The prosecutrix had got a piece of money, she asked me if I would change it, I told her I could not, for I did not know what piece it was; I could not tell whether it was brass or silver. My boy and the prisoner looked at it, then they put it into the cage to the jay, it had it in its bill five or six minutes, at last the money was dropped through into the bottom of the cage, the prisoner took it out, and I never saw any more of it from that time to this; I saw her put it down her bosom.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>A friend of mine came to see me, I got a drop of liquor, and went into that woman's house, and sat down, and they accused me with a thing I knew nothing of. I was searched that very night, by the constable, and other people, and after that I searched myself. I never saw it.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610625-35-verdict209" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610625-35-verdict209" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
