<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-16">
               <interp inst="t17610916-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-16" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-16" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-16-off83-c105" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-16-defend127 t17610916-16-off83 t17610916-16-verdict86"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-16-off83-c107" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-16-defend130 t17610916-16-off83 t17610916-16-verdict86"></join>
         
               <p>235. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17610916-16-defend127" type="defendantName">
                  Nicholas, <rs id="t17610916-16-deflabel82" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-16-defend127 t17610916-16-deflabel82"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17610916-16-person128">
                        William 
                        Adams 
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person128" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-16-person128" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-16-person128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17610916-16-alias-2" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-16-defend127 t17610916-16-alias-2"></join>Lawrance</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17610916-16-alias-3" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-16-defend127 t17610916-16-alias-3"></join>Law</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-defend127" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-defend127" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-defend127" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-defend130" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Woodley 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-16-defend130" type="surname" value="Woodley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-defend130" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-defend130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610916-16-off83" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-off83" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-off83" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               were indicted, together with 
                     <persName id="t17610916-16-person131">
                        John 
                        Lawrance 
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person131" type="surname" value="Lawrance"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-16-person131" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17610916-16-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , not taken, for stealing five silver table spoons, value 7 s. three gold rings, value 1 l. 1 s. one silver pepperbox, value 10 s. one metal watch with a shagreen case, value 40 s. one gold seal, value 3 s. one green silk tabby gown and apron, volue 40 s. one straw coloured Irish stuff sack, value 10 s. one black silk gown, value 4 s. one white linnen gown and apron, value 10 s. four white under petticotas, value 10 s. one quilted black callimanco petticoat, value 7 s. one pink coloured petticoat, value 1 s. one scarlet feather muff, value 1 s. one black shade, value 18 d. four linnen aprons, value 4 s. two yards of lace, value 12 s. one pair of silk shoes, value 2 s. three window curtains, with lines and rings, value 2 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-victim133" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Eliott 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-16-victim133" type="surname" value="Eliott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-victim133" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-victim133" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-16-off83 t17610916-16-victim133"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610916-16-cd84" type="crimeDate">June 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-16-off83 t17610916-16-cd84"></join>.~</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person134">
                  John 
                  Eliott 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person134" type="surname" value="Eliott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person134" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person134" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodged about 15 months with the prisoner 
               <persName id="t17610916-16-person135">
                  Nicholas 
                  Adams 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person135" type="surname" value="Adams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person135" type="given" value="Nicholas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person135" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , in George and Plough yard. She removed into <placeName id="t17610916-16-crimeloc85">Baker's street, Westminster</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-16-crimeloc85" type="placeName" value="Baker's street, Westminster"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-16-crimeloc85" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-16-off83 t17610916-16-crimeloc85"></join>, and I went with her there. I never left her till the week my things were taken away. Then I missed the things mentioned in the indictment, [mentioning them by name.] When I went away, and took a lodging over the way, I left those things in a chest, and locked it up. Upon hearing it was taken away, I went and demanded the chest, and said I was ready to pay the balance that was between us. She said she would not take the money, I might keep my money, and she would keep my thing, and she told me my chest was removed to Mr. Woodley's. I went there, and he said he had the chest for 6 l. and if I would pay the money I might have the things again. After I had demanded it they swore the peace against me, and bound me over. Then I was advised to go and find a bill against them; the prisoners were then in prison. Then I obtained a search warrant, and then was informed the chest was carried back again to Mrs. Adams's house. I went there, and found the chest broke open, and the goods taken out.</p>
               <p>Counsel for prisoners. We admit having the goods.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at this paper (it is a promissory note) is the name 
               <persName id="t17610916-16-person136">
                  John 
                  Eliott 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person136" type="surname" value="Eliott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person136" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person136" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             your hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Eliott. [He takes it in his hand.] I did not write the name.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Nor no part of the note?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No, nor no part of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see it before?</p>
               <p>Eliott. It was produced to me at justice Cox's.</p>
               <p>Q. Here is another, look at that. Did you write the name or any part of the note?</p>
               <p>Eliott. I did not; I never wrote this nor any part of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of the writing these notes?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No, I never knew any thing of them.</p>
               <p>Q. Were either of them wrote by your direction?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No, they were not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you positive of that?</p>
               <p>Eliott. I am.</p>
               <p>Q. How long since you first went to lodge with her?</p>
               <p>Eliot. I think it was in the beginning of July.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your wife living then?</p>
               <p>Eliott. She was, but was very ill, and was from the first of my marrying of her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you borrow any money of Mrs. Adams?</p>
               <p>Eliott. I borrowed 6 l. 3 s. of her, about the 14th or 15th of Nov. last, I am not certain to the day of the month.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give her a note for it?</p>
               <p>Eliott. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. For what purpose did you borrow that?</p>
               <p>Eliott. My wife being ill a great while, I borrowed it to take several things out of pawn. I paid her all that money since, but about 9 s. and have receipts for it.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160012"></xptr>Q. What became of that note you gave her?</p>
               <p>Eliott. She told me it was lost, was the reason I had receipts of her. I offered to pay her the 9 s. several times, and she will not take it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your watch in pawn?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No, it never was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you once borrow 2 l. 8 s. of her?</p>
               <p>Eliott. The whole I borrowed was 6 l. 3 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever borrow any of her since?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No, never.</p>
               <p>Q When you was before the justice, were these notes produced to you?</p>
               <p>Eliott. Yes, these two notes before Mr. Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he do upon that?</p>
               <p>Eliott. Mr. Fielding said, if they make such a demand, I must find a bill of trover against them; they swore the peace against me when I made a proper demand, before Mr. Alexander and his clerk, of my things, and they would give me no account of them; and they swore the peace against me before justice Cox, and I was bound over to appear at Westminster, and at the same time I imployed Mr. Ridgway, he shewed me the way to find the bill against them at Hicks's-hall; he is my proper attorney, but now he chuses to turn on the other side.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17610916-16-person137">
                  Sarah 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person137" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person137" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person137" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Eliott. I do very well; she was at Mrs. Adams's.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you did acknowledge to Mrs. Hawkins, that you owed Mrs. Adams 9 s. 6 d. exclusive of the money contained in the notes?</p>
               <p>Eliott. I told Mrs. Adams, I had not money about me to pay the ballance; but she knew I had a guinea paid me every three months by a gentleman in Oxford-Road, and I would leave the note as a security: no, she said, I might receive my own money, and she would keep the things.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you acknowledged in Mrs. Hawkins's hearing, that you owed Mrs. Adam's 9 s. 6 d. exclusive of the other note?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know Mr. Darby?</p>
               <p>Eliott. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever acknowledge that to him?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you pay the money you borrowed of Mrs. Adams?</p>
               <p>Eliott. I paid it at several times, and the receipts are in the chest.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether you did not perswade Mrs. Adams to make you a bill of sale of her goods?</p>
               <p>Eliott. Sir, she has two husbands now living; she told me so. She said she should be ruined by her first husband, who was coming home, and he did come home: that was the reason of her carrying this chest away. She was afraid she should be prosecuted, and desired I would accept of a bill of sale on the account of a child she has by the second husband, when the other came home; it was in favour of her own child.</p>

               <p>Q. Did you give any consideration for it?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you any thing out of pocket by it?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether when you saw Mr. Darby you did or did not give him directions to seecure your chest?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No, Sir, I made all over to the child; I was not a farthing gainer.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever acknowledge to Mr. Darby you owed Mrs. Adams 8 or 9 pounds?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say she had notes of hand of your writing, but she could not prove your hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Eliott. No Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the occasion of leaving your trunk in the house?</p>
               <p>Eliott. I was about moving my lodging.</p>
               <p>Q. Who had the key of it?</p>
               <p>Eliott. I had.</p>
               <p>Q. What room did you leave it in?</p>
               <p>Eliott. I left it in the room where I had lodged; but it was so full of bugs, that I could not lie in it; it was one of the back rooms.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it in the same room where you found it broke open?</p>
               <p>Eliott. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. How many lodgers were there in the house?</p>
               <p>Eliott. There were several; they are all here.</p>
               <p>Q. In which room did you lodge?</p>
               <p>Eliott. In the back room, up two pair of stairs; but after it was troubled with bugs, I lodged in the room opposite to it; I rented two rooms. I went away a week before my time was out; I told her I should quit the lodging at the time; but I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mrs. Adams deny having the things?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160013"></xptr>Eliott. She would give no account at all of them.</p>
               <p>Q. You say she said she would keep the things; what was she to keep them for?</p>
               <p>Eliott. That I do not know.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person138">
                  Mary 
                  Banks 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person138" type="surname" value="Banks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person138" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person138" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I lodged at Mrs. Adams's in June last, I knew Mr. Eliott there, he was a lodger there when I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember his going away and leaving a chest there?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. Yes, in my room, up two pair of stairs, in a back-room.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what was in that chest?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. No, I do not; I know it was full of something, and it was locked; I saw Mr. Eliott lock it that very morning when he went away.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know of its being removed?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. To the best of my knowledge it was the 18th of June, it was on a Thursday I know; I was going of an errand, and coming in again, I believe between nine and ten at night, I met Mr. Woodley and 
               <persName id="t17610916-16-person139">
                  John 
                  Laurence 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person139" type="surname" value="Laurence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person139" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person139" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , with the chest, but I do not know where they carried it; they carried it out of the street-door. I knew it was the same chest, because when I came into my room I missed it; it was a remarkable one; he had left it in my custody; Woodley used to be about our house frequently.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know it to be this man's chest?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. I know it by seeing him take things out, and put things in; and I have heard Mrs. Adams say it was his chest; it was a long red chest.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you a lodger to Mrs. Adams in a ready furnished lodging?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose was the furniture?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. The furniture was Mrs. Adams's; this gentleman lodged in the room just before I came there; and when he left the room, I came into it that day.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you continue to lodge there after this chest was removed?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. Only that very day; I think I went away the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was Mrs. Adams when the chest was carrying away?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. I did not see her, I was very much confused.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see Mrs Adams and Woodley together?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. No, not after that.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear of any money Mr. Eliott owed Mrs. Adams?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever understand from him, or any body else, that the chest was left there as a security for money?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. No, I never heard of such a thing; they were very familiar in eating and drinking together.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you apprehend, from the appearance of the thing, their carrying the chest in that manner, they intended to steal every thing in it? Can you give an account how it came to be taken away?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. I do not know, there were some words arose between them; that is, Mrs. Adams and Eliott, and this was that very same week; I think the day or two before the chest was carried away.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the result of that quarrel?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. I heard mentioned, that her husband was coming home; Mr. Eliott persuaded her to take him home, saying, he was the fittest person to live with her. She said, Dear Mr. Eliott, I cannot do it, nor will I. He said, it must be so, and it should be so. I heard her say, she wished she had taken the chest out. I thought it was all as one betwixt them.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the second husband's name?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. His name is Laurence, it was he that was with Woodley, with the chest, carrying it away.</p>
               <p>Q. You say she wished she had taken the chest away, why did she wish that?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. For fear Mr. Eliott should bring a constable, and take it away. They were upon very good terms 'till this husband came home; and after that I heard Mrs. Adams say to him, You black-guard; and he said, Very well, Madam, I shall soon fetch the things.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you seen Laurence there before the things were taken away?</p>
               <p>M. Banks. I believe I saw him there a fortnight before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person140">
                  Sarah 
                  Ewers 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person140" type="surname" value="Ewers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person140" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person140" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was a lodger in this house in June last.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of Mr. Eliott's leaving his lodgings, and leaving his chest there?</p>
               <p>S. Ewers. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. What room did you lodge in?</p>
               <p>S. Ewers. I lodged in the one pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160014"></xptr>Q. What room did Mr. Eliott lodge in?</p>
               <p>S. Ewers. I believe he lodged in the two pair of stairs floor; just as this affair happened I quitted my lodgings.</p>
               <p>Q. You speak of this affair, I suppose you know something of the out-lines of it?</p>
               <p>S. Ewers. No, I know nothing of the affair; Eliott and Mrs. Adams lived on very good terms; he was a very sober man, and Mrs. Adams gave him that character. They eat and drank together; and sometimes, when I was ill, they would both come into my room together to see me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you overhear any conversation between them relating to this chest?</p>
               <p>S. Ewers. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor about a bill of sale?</p>
               <p>S. Ewers. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Nor no apprehensions of her first husband's coming home?</p>
               <p>S. Ewers. No, I did not know that she had any husband but one.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay after Mr. Eliott?</p>
               <p>S. Ewers. I believe no more than a week; Mrs. Adams was in custody before I went away; and I quitted my lodgings, not bearing to be in a house that bore so bad a character.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of the chest being removed, or brought back again?</p>
               <p>S. Ewers. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know 
               <persName id="t17610916-16-person141">
                  Mary 
                  Banks 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person141" type="surname" value="Banks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person141" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person141" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ;</p>
               <p>S. Ewers. I do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you declare to her, Good-lack, they have been carrying away Mr. Eliott's chest.</p>
               <p>S. Ewers. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person142">
                  George 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person142" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person142" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person142" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Cabbage-lane, Westminster, I nailed up the window shutter on the outside of the window belonging to Mrs. Adams's house; I took no notice of what was in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you nail up the window-shutter for?</p>
               <p>King. For the safety of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any windows broke?</p>
               <p>King. No, there were none broke, it was backwards, and might easily be approached, being a ground-floor back-parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you nail up the door?</p>
               <p>King. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see Mrs. Adams and Mr. Eliott together.</p>
               <p>King. I was once there when they were together; Mr. Eliott came in, and demanded the chest.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>King. It was in June last, I cannot tell the day of the month; when he came in, he addressed himself to 
               <persName id="t17610916-16-person143">
                  John 
                  Laurence 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person143" type="surname" value="Laurence"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person143" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person143" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; there was a woman came in before him. I did not know her.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the chest delivered to him?</p>
               <p>King. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person144">
                  Peter 
                  Perry 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person144" type="surname" value="Perry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person144" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Eliott desired me to go to Mr. Woodley, he said he had got a chest, and I was to ask him for it. I went and knocked at the door, and Mr. Woodley came himself. I told him my message. He said Eliott should not have the chest, 'till such time as he had paid Mrs. Adams, or him, the sum of 6 l. or six guineas, or to that purpose; he should have it if he paid the money</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the chest?</p>
               <p>Perry. I saw it behind a coach this morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person145">
                  John 
                  Darby 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person145" type="surname" value="Darby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person145" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Grange-court, Gray's-inn-lane; about the 17th of June last I went to Mrs. Adams's, by the desire of Mr. Eliott and Mr. Nicholson, who is the master of the daughter-in-law of Mrs. Adams. Mr. Eliott had informed Mr. Nicholson, that Mr. Law, Mrs. Adams's former husband, had made a will, and left all to this daughter, 
               <persName id="t17610916-16-person146">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Law 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person146" type="surname" value="Law"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person146" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person146" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; but that Mrs. Adams being in possession, would not assist the daughter, although she was appointed executrix. I went to Mrs. Adams, and saw the will; she produced it. I found it quite the reverse to what Mr. Eliott had told me. I found he had left every thing to his wife. I then told Mr. Eliott it was in vain for me to apply for any thing for the benefit of the daughter; but Mr. Eliott then being indebted to Mrs. Adams about 8 l. 9 s. or 10 s. and he confessed to me that he had got a bill of sale, from Mrs. Adams, of her houshold goods; upon which, he said, he would assign this bill of sale over to Mr. Nicholson, the girl's master, if he thought I could get him a discharge from this debt that he owes this woman. I told him I would do my endeavour to do it. I waited then on Mrs. Adams, and told her that Mr. Eliott had assigned the bill of sale over to Mr. Nicholson, for the use of the daughter-in-law. Then Mrs. Adams was very much concerned, and said, she never had any consideration for this bill of sale, and that it was done by the desire of Mr. Eliott; and the reason he assigned to her was, to prevent her husband's selling the goods, in case he came home. Then she agreed to give me a note for five guineas, for the use of the girl. This I think was on the 18th of June; and I received the money in about ten days after. Mr. Eliott called upon me the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160015"></xptr> next day, and asked me about this chest; and said, he owed the woman this money, and wanted to get his chest away before she had the bill of sale returned.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he said any thing to you about the things in the chest?</p>
               <p>Darby. He said the things in the chest were there by way of security for the money he owed her. I asked her if she would discharge the debt. She said, she never would; and when he called on me the next day, I told him I would have no future concern in it; I would have nothing to do with him, nor his chest neither. I have known Mr. Nicholson many years; I believe he is here.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you advise Mr. Eliott how to get at the chest?</p>
               <p>Darby. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Eliott say to you he had given any security to her for the money?</p>
               <p>Darby. He said he had given two notes for it, and that they could not prove his hand-writing, and he would not own it.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain of this?</p>
               <p>Darby. I am, and also that he gave me a commission to go there, and make use of this bill of sale, on purpose that he might have his debt forgiven.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. With what view did he bring this bill of sale to you?</p>
               <p>Darby. With a view of getting his chest.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he tell you he would deny his handwriting?</p>
               <p>Darby. Upon my oath he did, and rely upon their not being able to prove it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he mention the goods left in the chest were left as a security for the money he owed Mrs. Adams.</p>
               <p>Darby. He did.</p>
               <p>Adams's Defence.</p>
               <p>This man, Eliott, and his wife, came to lodge with me; his wife was dying; he told me he had such and such things in pawn; he begged I would lend him some money to take them out of pawn, otherwise they would be lost. I lent him six guineas; he went and brought home the things, and gave them into my possession. After his wife died he brought me that note, which is here produced, for the money, and the box was still to be in my custody. After that he very artfully got me to make a bill of sale to him, which I very foolishly did. He desired me to put it into his chest, in case my husband should come home; saying, he could answer breaking open my drawers, but could not his chest. I did as he said. He had a watch in pawn, and he said he did not value that so much as the seal, because that had his name on it. He desired I would lend him two pounds eight shillings to bring it out of pawn. I let him have it. He gave me a note for that sum, and the watch was put in my possession 'till the money could be paid. After that, when he found he could not get the things away without the money being paid, then he went and made over this bill of sale to this gentleman. When Mr. Darby came to me, and told me what Eliott had done, I told him I should insist on every halfpenny of the money. Eliott knows what I have said is truth before God and man. When he could not get the things, he took me before justice Fielding, when I gave an account he had been at this court, and tried, ||</p>
               <p>|| See Numb. 237. in Sir 
               <persName id="t17610916-16-person147">
                  Thomas 
                  Chitty 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person147" type="surname" value="Chitty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person147" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's mayoralty,</p>
               <p>(Eliott. I was acquitted in court.)</p>
               <p>the justice discharged the warrant. Then he came into my house, and said justice Fielding gave him an order to take away the chest, and bred a riot in the street. The next day I got a warrant from justice Cox against him, and he was bound over.</p>
               <p>Woodley's Defence.</p>
               <p>I lent Mrs Adams a hand to remove the chest out of a back-room, up two pairs of stairs, into a back-room on the ground-floor.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Adams. I desired Mr. Woodley to help me down with the chest. The chest was never out at my door. I removed it into that room, fearing Mr. Eliott should come and take it away by force, without paying the money. He brought a soldier, and took it away soon after. Before justice Fielding, and justice Cox, these notes were produced, and he denied giving them to me.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person148">
                  Sarah 
                  Hawkins 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person148" type="surname" value="Hawkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person148" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person148" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had some conversation with Mr. Eliott, relating to Mrs. Adams.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. I live in the Abbey-cloisters. I am servant to Dr. Osborne; Eliott brought me to Mrs. Adams's, and wanted her to make the affair up; she asked him to give up the bill of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160016"></xptr> sale. Mr Eliott said, if I do you will sell my things to a disadvantage.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. This was about two months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it before Mrs. Adams was taken up?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. It was about a week before that, to the best of my knowledge; she said in answer to that, I will orn to do such a thing, you may lodge in where you will</p>
               <p>Q. Was it mentioned how much he owed her?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. No; I do not remember that.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any talk of a debt due from Eliott to Mrs. Adams?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any discourse, that the goods were left as a security with Mrs. Adams.</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any talk about the notes of hand being given?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. No; I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you at any time seen Eliott, since that?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. Yes; once.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. In a few days after, he brought me to Mrs. Adams's house, and said, he would make it up; there were some china, and a pair of stays, that he had made a present to her of; Mrs. Adams said, Mr. Eliott, I have never made any note to you for your washing; so, if you are willing, one shall go against the other; he said, yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you understand from Eliott's talk, that he owed Mrs. Adams some money?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. I did, the sum I cannot say; but I have heard Mrs. Adams and Mr. Elliott talk about seven or eight pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never hear her talk to him, about lending him money to redeem cloaths?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. Yes, I have; then I lodged in the house, and frequently heard them talk of it; that was in that house in Westminster.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear Mr. Eliott speak of it as a debt, due to Mrs. Adams?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. I have; as a debt of seven or eight pounds.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never hear him talk of a note or notes, given her for that money?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How was Mrs. Adams's money to be secured to her, that Eliott owed to her?</p>

               <p>S. Hawkins. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never hear talk, that part of the money had been paid?</p>
               <p>S. Hawkins. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person149">
                  Mary 
                  Bulwash 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person149" type="surname" value="Bulwash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person149" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person149" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I once saw Eliott write, [she produced a paper] this is his hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these two notes, [she takes them in her hand. ]</p>
               <p>M. Bulwash. These are very different from mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person150">
                  John 
                  Peyton 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person150" type="surname" value="Peyton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person150" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Eliott lived servant with me, three or four years; he left me about two years ago; I have seen him write.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at these two notes [he takes them in his hand. ]</p>
               <p>Peyton. He writes very different; sometimes large, and sometimes small; the name upon one of them, seems to be like his handwriting, but I can't swear to it; the other, to the best of my knowledge, I verily believe to be his hand-writing.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. By what do you believe it to be his hand-writing?</p>
               <p>Peyton. I believe it, from what I have seen him write.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person151">
                  John 
                  Fryer 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person151" type="surname" value="Fryer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person151" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a serjeant; I have known Eliott about a year; he is a soldier in the company I belong to; the man behaves well as a soldier, that is all I know of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person152">
                  Thomas 
                  Busford 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person152" type="surname" value="Busford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person152" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am acquainted with Woodley, and have known him seven or eight years; he is a carpenter and joiner, in Chapel-street; he is a housekeeper; I live in the same parish; I look upon him to be a very honest, worthy man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person153">
                  Samuel 
                  Carr 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person153" type="surname" value="Carr"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person153" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a neighbour to Mr. Woodley, and have known him between nine and ten years; he is a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person154">
                  Thomas 
                  Cock 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person154" type="surname" value="Cock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person154" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person154" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in the same parish, and have known Mr. Woodley seven or eight years; he has an exceeding good character in every respect, he is universally respected by all his neighbours, there are a great part of the neighbourhood here to give him a character</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160017"></xptr>Fortman of the Jury. We are all satisfied as to his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-16-person155">
                  Daniel 
                  Comings 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person155" type="surname" value="Comings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person155" type="given" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person155" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known Mrs. Adams fourteen years; she is a very honest, sober woman; she lived twice with me a servant, in Delabay-street; I always found her honest.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Magellery. I have known Mrs. Adams between two and three years; she always bore a very honest character; I never heard any ill of her.</p>
               <p>Mr. Nicholson. I live at Knightsbridge; 
               <persName id="t17610916-16-person156">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Law 
               <interp inst="t17610916-16-person156" type="surname" value="Law"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person156" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-person156" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             lived servant with me, she is daughter-in-law to Mrs. Adams; the girl living with me, Mr. Eliott came to me with this bill of sale, and said, it was the girl's right; so I went to Mr. Darby, as he was a country man of mine, and sent him to Mrs. Adams, to make inquiry of her, concerning the will of the father, but found Eliott had given a wrong account.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17610916-16-verdict86" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-16-verdict86" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The jury declared, it was their opinion, that Eliott had been guilty of perjury; upon which he was committed to Newgate, in order to be tried for the same.</p>
            </div1>
