<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660903-48">
               <interp inst="t17660903-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-48" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-48" type="date" value="17660903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660903-48-off257-c344" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-48-defend440 t17660903-48-off257 t17660903-48-verdict261"></join>
         
               <p>446. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-48-defend440" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Kingston 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-48-defend440" type="surname" value="Kingston"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-defend440" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-defend440" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660903-48-off257" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-off257" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-off257" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing seven pennyweights of silver, being part of a buckle rim, value 18 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-48-victim442" type="victimName">
                     Simon 
                     Hughes 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-48-victim442" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-victim442" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-victim442" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-48-off257 t17660903-48-victim442"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660903-48-cd258" type="crimeDate">July 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-48-off257 t17660903-48-cd258"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-48-person443">
                  Simon 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17660903-48-person443" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person443" type="given" value="Simon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person443" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17660903-48-viclabel259" type="occupation">silver smith</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-48-victim442 t17660903-48-viclabel259"></join>, and live in Butcher-hall-lane. On the 9th of July I sold six pair of silver salts to Mr. Stevenson, and the nature of our trade is to give old silver in exchange for new, in payment; it weighed 25 ounces; I carried it up stairs, and locked it up; the next morning I brought it down into the shop in order to work it up, and Mr. Stevenson sent for me; I went; he asked me if I had lost any; he shewed<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030039"></xptr> me this half rim of a buckle, and asked me if I knew it; I said I did, and could be upon my oath it was my property; we got a warrant, and went and took the prisoner's brother and the prisoner's wife up; we asked them how they came by it; they said they found it in Ludgate-street; then we came to my shop, and took the prisoner up, and asked him if he knew any thing of that piece of a buckle; he said he did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Hughes. He was my <rs id="t17660903-48-deflabel260" type="occupation">journeyman</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-48-defend440 t17660903-48-deflabel260"></join>, and had been for about ten months; the constable told him he had better confess, that it would be the better for him; then he confessed he took it from off my counter; upon that he was committed; this was the next morning after I received the 25 ounces, and I am certain this piece of buckle was among it; it was the only piece of buckle there was in the parcel; (produced and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-48-person444">
                  Benjamin 
                  Stevenson 
               <interp inst="t17660903-48-person444" type="surname" value="Stevenson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person444" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person444" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a goldsmith, and live in Fleet-street; I paid Mr. Hughes in old silver; I knew this piece of buckle rim, I was in possession of it before I parted with the old silver; I have the other part of it new in my shop, but I cannot recollect I paid this piece in part with the rest; the prisoner's wife came and offered this piece to me to sell on the 10th of July; she said her brother found it at Islington the Sunday before; I remembered it as soon as she brought it in; I stopped her, and went with her to her brother; she told me he lived in Water-lane; he was not then to be found; after that, I rec ollected I had paid some old silver to Mr. Hughes; I sent for him, and asked him whether he weighed his silver when he got home; he said he did, and it answered to the weight; I shewed him the piece of buckle, he said he particularly remembered it, and upon enquiring if any of his people had any relations in Water-lane, he said, one of his men was married and lived there; we first took up the prisoner's wife and brother, and afterwards him; at first he denied it, and at last he said he did take it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I found that piece of buckle, when I went home to breakfast by my master's door; I gave it my wife, and bid her go and sell it to Mr. Stevenson.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-48-person445">
                  John 
                  Foy 
               <interp inst="t17660903-48-person445" type="surname" value="Foy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person445" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person445" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a baker, and live in Shoe-lane; I have known him about 7 years; I never heard any thing of him but that of an honest man till this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-48-person446">
                  William 
                  Seers 
               <interp inst="t17660903-48-person446" type="surname" value="Seers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person446" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person446" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Crown-court, Fleet-street, and am a publican; the prisoner lodged with me two years and a half before I was in this business, then I left my house to him; I never saw no harm of him; I always heard a good character of him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-48-person447">
                  John 
                  Sarney 
               <interp inst="t17660903-48-person447" type="surname" value="Sarney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person447" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person447" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a goldsmith in Gutter-lane; I have known him about two years; I worked journey work where he did; I never heard but that he was a very honest man.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-48-person448">
                  Mary 
                  Chitham 
               <interp inst="t17660903-48-person448" type="surname" value="Chitham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person448" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person448" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Water-lane, Fleet-street; I always took the prisoner to be a very honest man till this time; I have had transactions with him; he acted honestly by me; I took a shop of him, and gave him a note of hand; there was a mistake in our account, I paid him too much, he honestly returned the money.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-48-person449">
                  William 
                  Boddington 
               <interp inst="t17660903-48-person449" type="surname" value="Boddington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person449" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-person449" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a baker; I have known him about four years; I never heard but that he was a very honest young man till this affair.</p>
               <p>Sandal Rushforth. I live in Goldsmith's-hall, Foster-lane; he always had a very honest character for whatever I heard.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did the prisoner know the salts were for Mr. Stevenson.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I do not believe he did.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I have worked night and day to serve my master, and worked hard to get them salts done for Mr. Stevenson.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He was very diligent; he has a wife and three small children, and his wife not three months to go.</p>
               <p>Q. What can he get a week?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He can get a guinea a week.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660903-48-verdict261" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-48-verdict261" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
