<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-17">
               <interp inst="t17610916-17" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-17" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-17" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-17" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-17-off88-c133" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-17-defend157 t17610916-17-off88 t17610916-17-verdict90"></join>
         
               <p>236. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17610916-17-defend157" type="defendantName">
                  M
                   - N - 
               <interp inst="t17610916-17-defend157" type="surname" value="- N -"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-defend157" type="given" value="M"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-defend157" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , <rs id="t17610916-17-deflabel87" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-17-defend157 t17610916-17-deflabel87"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17610916-17-off88" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-off88" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-off88" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one gold repeating watch, with three gold seals, and one gold locket, value 19 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-17-victim159" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-17-victim159" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-victim159" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-victim159" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-17-victim161" type="victimName">
                     Ambrose 
                     Godfrey 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-17-victim161" type="surname" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-victim161" type="given" value="Ambrose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-victim161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             
                  <rs id="t17610916-17-cd89" type="crimeDate">June 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-17-off88 t17610916-17-cd89"></join>.~</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-17-person162">
                  William 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17610916-17-person162" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-person162" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-person162" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a watch maker and goldsmith; the prisoner at the bar came to me on Monday the 15th of June, between the hours of one and three, to pay me a small bill which she owed me, of 8 s. 6 d. then she said, she had got a watch to sell, that the person that did own it was dead; and the money to be divided amongst several, and it must be sold; there were two seals, and a locket to it; one of the seals was a coat of arors: she said that would be of no more service than the weight of the gold, and she would keep that for one that belonged to the family, who would be glad of it then they grew up; and she would keep the locket herself, as it would fetch but little; and she desired me to take it off. I bought the watch; it was a gold one, with one gold seal, and gold chain, for 19 l. [ produced in court. ] There was an advertisement in the papers sometime after that; I went with the watch to Mr. Dudley as directed, facing the New Buildings in the Strand; he and I went to Mrs. Hays's, and after describing the prisoner at the bar, she was brought to us; she confessed then in Mr. Dudley's, Mr. Wells's, Mrs. Hays's, and my hearing, that she had sold them to me; we asked her, what she had done with the money; she said, she had paid fifteen guineas, or pounds, to a brewer; and one guinea she had lent to one Mr. Smith; and the rest she had left. She owned also, she had taken the watch and things from Mrs. Hays's apartment, when she was there to see her; (Mrs. Hays is blind) the prisoner asked forgiveness; she said she took it the same day she sold it me; and after she had sold it to me, she went directly back to Mrs. Hays's again.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who appears to be the prosecutor of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Edwards. Mrs. Hays.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the money paid you again?</p>
               <p>Edwards. It was brought to me by the prisoner, and Mrs. Hays's servant, on the Saturday morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you take upon you to say whose property the watch was?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after this, was it, that the prisoner was prosecuted?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I believe it was about three weeks after.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Hays, who is husband to Mrs. Hays, declare he would not prosecute her?</p>
               <p>Edwards. There was an advertisement in the paper, something about the prisoner excusing herself: which put him upon doing as he did.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you known the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I had known her I believe about two years: she used to come to my shop; I had mended a gold watch for her, which came to the 8 s. 6 d. which she paid me, when she brought this.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-17-person163">
                  Robert 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17610916-17-person163" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-person163" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have the will in court [producing one.] In this will is left a gold watch to Mrs. Hays, for her life-time; and after that, to her daughter; and it is in the trust of Mr. 
               <persName id="t17610916-17-person164">
                  Ambrose 
                  Godfrey 
               <interp inst="t17610916-17-person164" type="surname" value="Godfrey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-person164" type="given" value="Ambrose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Mr. Butler, the duke of Bedford's steward; it is left by Mrs. 
               <persName id="t17610916-17-person165">
                  Catharine 
                  Leckup 
               <interp inst="t17610916-17-person165" type="surname" value="Leckup"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-person165" type="given" value="Catharine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-person165" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , who died the 30th of July, 1760. There is also an estate at the Bath, left to us in trust for Mrs. Hays; the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160018"></xptr> rents are regularly received for her. Mrs Hays had this watch in her possession, within three days after her mother's death.</p>
               <p>Q. Who delivered it to her?</p>
               <p>Brown. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever taken a probate of that will?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, we were told there would be no need of taking a probate, as the property was laid wrong in the indictment.</p>
               <p>She was <rs id="t17610916-17-verdict90" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-17-verdict90" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
