<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600416-20">
               <interp inst="t17600416-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-20" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600416"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600416-20" type="date" value="17600416"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600416-20-off131-c186" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-20-defend222 t17600416-20-off131 t17600416-20-verdict136"></join>
         
               <p>153. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600416-20-defend222" type="defendantName">
                     Patrick 
                     Shirlock 
                  <interp inst="t17600416-20-defend222" type="surname" value="Shirlock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-20-defend222" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-20-defend222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for that <rs id="t17600416-20-off131" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600416-20-off131" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-20-off131" type="offenceSubcategory" value="burglary"></interp>
               he, on the <rs id="t17600416-20-cd132" type="crimeDate">21st of March</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-20-off131 t17600416-20-cd132"></join>, about the hour of eight in the night of the same day, the dwelling house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17600416-20-victim224" type="victimName">
                           Jane 
                           Danson 
                        <interp inst="t17600416-20-victim224" type="surname" value="Danson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600416-20-victim224" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17600416-20-victim224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-20-off131 t17600416-20-victim224"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17600416-20-viclabel133" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-20-victim224 t17600416-20-viclabel133"></join>, did break and enter, and steal out from thence ten linen handkerchiefs, value 10 s. the goods of the said Jane
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Jane Danson. I live in <placeName id="t17600416-20-crimeloc134">Longacre</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600416-20-crimeloc134" type="placeName" value="Longacre"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600416-20-crimeloc134" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-20-off131 t17600416-20-crimeloc134"></join>, and <rs id="t17600416-20-viclabel135" type="occupation">keep a haberdasher's shop</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600416-20-victim224 t17600416-20-viclabel135"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a married woman?</p>
               <p>J. Danson. I never was married. On the 21st of March last I lost thirteen or fourteen handkerchiefs.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you lose them?</p>
               <p>J. Danson. I saw a young man with either a blue or blue grey coat break my window, and take the handkerchiefs out.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>J. Danson. This was between seven and eight o'clock in the evening, it was candle light. I first heard the window break, then I look'd and saw a hand take them out.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you got any of them again?</p>
               <p>J. Danson. I have got some of them, not all.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>J. Danson. I was so much frighted, I cannot swear to him.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you by some of them again?</p>
               <p>J. Danson. Mr. Fielding sent to me the very next night. and told me there were such handkerchiefs at his house; I went there and saw them, and believe them to be mine.</p>
               <p>Q. How many are there of them?</p>
               <p>J. Danson. Here are ten of them (produced in court) there are part of the handkerchiefs I lost that night.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the justice examine the prisoner?</p>
               <p>J. Danson. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-20-person225">
                  James 
                  Bradbroke 
               <interp inst="t17600416-20-person225" type="surname" value="Bradbroke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-20-person225" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-20-person225" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 27th of March last, I was going over More fields, where I saw two young chaps; I knew one of them had been committed two or three times. I knew him to be a thief. The prisoner was not along with them, but he walked behind them. On seeing me he turned his face back; they were in Chiswel-Street, coming towards me.</p>
               <p>Q. How old might the other lads be?</p>
               <p>Bradbroke. About sixteen or seventeen years old; the prisoner had a handkerchief, with something tied up in it, I judged he might be one of their party; the others made off over the paved stones; I call'd out, stop them, and catched hold of the prisoner, he said what do you want with me; I asked him what he had got in his handkerchief.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Bradbroke. No, not to my knowledge; he said what is that to you. I brought him down to the Ship alehouse, and untied his bundle, and there I found these handkerchiefs ( produced in court) I cut a piece off from one of the corners, so as to know them again (he compared the piece and it agreed) he told me he found them.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did he say he found them?</p>
               <p>Bradbroke. I think he said some-where towards Drury Lane; I asked him if he did not know the other two lads; he said he knew nothing of them; I said I shall take you before justice Fielding, and you shall there give an account how you came by them; he own'd nothing there, and Mr. Fielding committed him upon my oath.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-20-person226">
                  Margaret 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17600416-20-person226" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-20-person226" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-20-person226" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in Mrs. Danson's shop when the window was broke open; I saw a hand put in at the hole of the window, and the handkerchiefs taken out; I touched either the handkerchiefs or the hand as they went out of the window.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner's face?</p>
               <p>M. Richardson. No, I did not, so far as to swear to it; I was in the shop and he in the street, and it was candle light. He had a blue-grey coat on.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600416-20-person227">
                  Mary 
                  Dispaine 
               <interp inst="t17600416-20-person227" type="surname" value="Dispaine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-20-person227" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600416-20-person227" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the prosecutrix's shop when the window was broke, and the handkerchiefs drawn out, but I did not see the person that did it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was going home to my mother's house, about nine o'clock. At the corner of Long-Acre, going into Drury Lane, I trod upon these things; I found something soft under my feet; I gave them a kick and they flew open; I took them up and carried<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176004160026"></xptr> them home to my mother's house, in Mayner-Street, St. Giles's, and in the morning I look'd in the paper to see if there were any such things advertised, and I found there was not: About ten o'clock I thought I would go and leave them in pawn, instead of a furtout coat. As I was going to leave them I met that man, he stop'd me in the street; this was between ten and eleven the next day. He asked what I had got under my arm. I said what is that to you? He took the bundle from under my arm, and said he would know how I came by them; I said I found them, and told him the place where; he took me into an alehouse and examin'd me, and then he took me before Mr. Fielding.</p>
               <p>Q. to Bradbroke. Where did he say he found them before Mr. Fielding?</p>
               <p>Bradbroke. He said there he found them in Drury-Lane.</p>
               <p>He call'd three people to his character, one had known him from six years of age, the second had known him twelve months, and the third better than a year; they all gave him the character of an honest lad.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600416-20-verdict136" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600416-20-verdict136" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
