<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650710-28">
               <interp inst="t17650710-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650710-28" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650710-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650710"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650710-28" type="date" value="17650710"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650710-28-off148-c205" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-28-defend260 t17650710-28-off148 t17650710-28-verdict152"></join>
         
               <p>371. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650710-28-defend260" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Abbott 
                  <interp inst="t17650710-28-defend260" type="surname" value="Abbott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-defend260" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-defend260" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17650710-28-off148" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-off148" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-off148" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, in a certain park called Hyde-Park, near the King's high-way, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650710-28-victim262" type="victimName">
                           John Stuckley 
                           Somerset 
                        <interp inst="t17650710-28-victim262" type="surname" value="Somerset"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650710-28-victim262" type="given" value="John Stuckley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650710-28-victim262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-28-off148 t17650710-28-victim262"></join>
                     </persName>
                     
                  , <rs id="t17650710-28-viclabel149" type="occupation">Esq</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-28-victim262 t17650710-28-viclabel149"></join>; did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person one green silk purse, value 1 s. and 6 s. in money, numbered, the property of the said John, against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650710-28-cd150" type="crimeDate">June 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-28-off148 t17650710-28-cd150"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650710-28-person263">
                  John Stuckley 
                  Somerset 
               <interp inst="t17650710-28-person263" type="surname" value="Somerset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person263" type="given" value="John Stuckley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person263" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq, I was returning from Turnham-Green in a coach with Major Smith and three ladies on Saturday night, the 22d of June, a little before ten. Going through <placeName id="t17650710-28-crimeloc151">Hyde-Park</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650710-28-crimeloc151" type="placeName" value="Hyde-Park"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650710-28-crimeloc151" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-28-off148 t17650710-28-crimeloc151"></join>, not far from Grosvenor gate, we were overtaken by a highwayman on horseback, who rode up to the coach-door, and ordered the coachman to stop; upon which Major Smith, who sat near that side he came up on, shoved a large stick out at the window against the neck of the highway-man's horse, and ask'd him how he dar'd to stop the coach, and what he wanted. The man immediately came up a second time to the coach, presented a small pistol, and said he wanted our money. Major Smith, I believe, gave him some silver, and he collected money from two of the ladies, and a green purse, with about 6 s. 6 d. or 7 s. in it, from me. Among this money were three or four sixpences. One of the ladies delivered to him a green purse, and three or four shillings in it. After that he rode back. There was nothing over his face, as well as I could see at that time of night; and I have seen him several times since. I do believe the prisoner is the man. I don't swear positively he is the man. I gave a description of him before I saw the prisoner again, and that description answer'd.</p>
               <p>Major Smith. I can only confirm what Captain 
               <persName id="t17650710-28-person264">
                  Somerset
               <interp inst="t17650710-28-person264" type="given" value="Somerset"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person264" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             has said. The person was so close: to me, I can be as positive the prisoner is the man that robb'd us, as I can be positive to my own person. I talk'd with him: he told me, when leaving the coach, that distress drove him to do it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Major Smith. It was a very remarkable light evening; I believe the moon was just rising at the time; I could distinguish him or any body else; his head was close to me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176507100015"></xptr>Q. Were there any lamps near?</p>
               <p>Major Smith. No, there were not.</p>
               <p>Q. What colour was the horse?</p>
               <p>Major Smith. He was mounted, as I took it, on a black or dark brown horse; he had rode him very hard; he had a snuffle bridle; he behaved with a great deal of civility and politeness.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650710-28-person265">
                  Richard 
                  Wood 
               <interp inst="t17650710-28-person265" type="surname" value="Wood"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person265" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was by the barracks at Kensington-gate, and heard the cry Stop thief. This was on a Saturday night, about the hour of ten, the same night this robbery was committed. The prisoner came up on a gentle trot to the gate; he desired the man to open it; he did not open it immediately: there came two men galloping up the park, hallooing out Stop thief; I ran to meet them; the prisoner turned about, and I seiz'd his horse's bridle; he ask'd me what reason I had to stop him; I told him I thought he was a highwayman; he said, Let the horse go; I said I would not; he struck me several times with his whip: he finding I would not quit his horse, he jump'd down and left him, and ran away. I ran after him; he jump'd from the road to the greensward; I jump'd after him, and seiz'd him; then he said he would surrender to me.</p>

               <p>Q. What colour was the horse?</p>
               <p>Wood. The horse was a bright bay, with a small star in his forehead; he was very sweaty; he appeared to have been rode hard.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he appear to be in liquor?</p>
               <p>Wood. No, he did not. I was ordered to take him to Sir 
               <persName id="t17650710-28-person266">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650710-28-person266" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person266" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that night: I took those things out of his left-hand breeches-pocket (producing two green silk purses, with money in each); I have had them in my custody ever since. I found this cock of a pistol upon him (producing one).</p>
               <p>Capt. Somerset. (Takes one of them in his hand) Mine was an old green purse like this; I believe this to be mine (be turned out 6 s. 6 d. among which were three sixpences); the other purse we believe to belong to one of the ladies; but she is not here. There were two of my sixpences appeared to be pretty fresh; the impressions were very strong upon them; and so are two of these in the purse I believe to be mine.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650710-28-person267">
                  Robert 
                  Stoaks 
               <interp inst="t17650710-28-person267" type="surname" value="Stoaks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person267" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming from Kensington Gravel-pits. A little on this side Kensington, a gentleman on a black horse with a bald face told me there was a highwayman in the park.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Stoaks. I am servant to Mr. Hall the riding-master. The gentleman ordered me, and 
               <persName id="t17650710-28-person268">
                  John 
                  Dodd 
               <interp inst="t17650710-28-person268" type="surname" value="Dodd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person268" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             my fellow servant, to go in pursuit, and he would go along with us. We rode down Knights-bridge, and in at Hyde-Park Corner. The gentleman went no farther than the gate; my fellow-servant went in first; he said the man was coming from Kensington mounted. When he saw us, and heard us call a highwayman, he turn'd and went towards Kensington. I did not see him after till this light-horseman, Wood, was running after him. I met them both running on foot. I was close to them when the light-horseman took him. We went to Justice Fielding's with the prisoner, and saw the light-horseman take these things out of his pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650710-28-person269">
                  John 
                  Dodd 
               <interp inst="t17650710-28-person269" type="surname" value="Dodd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person269" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Hall, a riding-master. I was returning from Kensington Gravel-pits with Stoaks towards Knightsbridge. Kensington-gate was shut. There came a gentleman up with a black horse with a bald face from Kensington; he said he heard there was a highwayman in the park, and desired us to go with him. They would not let us go through Kensington gate. We both went with him: we rode on to Hyde-Park Corner gate, and bid the gate-man shut the gate, for there was a highwayman in the park. Just at that time the man came riding up from towards Grosvenor-gate upon a gallop. There was hallooing out towards Grosvenor gate of a highwayman; they halloo'd after him Stop thief. I and my fellow-servant went after him towards Kensington gate: we came up to him just as the light horseman took him on the greensward; they were both on foot. I rode first, and my fellow-servant after me.</p>
               <p>Capt. Somerset. We got out at Grosvenor gate, and desired the man at the gate to shut it, and told him what had happened. Whether he did or not, I don't know. Major Smith and I went for our horses, in order to pursue. We went towards Hyde-Park Corner in order for our horses; and ordered the coachman to drive the ladies home. As we were going towards our horses, we met a man mounted; we desired him to ride to Hyde-Park gate, and order the man to shut it, while we got our horses ready. As we were going down, we heard a man on the other side the park wall gallopping as hard as he could. We supposed he had been up to Grosvenor-gate, and could not get out. As soon as my horse was ready, I got upon him, and Major Smith wrote to Sir 
               <persName id="t17650710-28-person270">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650710-28-person270" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person270" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and described the highwayman's person. I rode found<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176507100016"></xptr> to Hyde-Park Corner gate; I found the alarm had been given; then I rode to Kensington gate thro' Knightsbridge. When I came there, I found they had just taken the prisoner; the officer ask'd me if I should know him if I saw him. I went into the guard-room, and said, I believed he was the man. The officer ask'd me if he had taken any thing particular from me; then I mentioned this old green purse. The prisoner said he had no purse about him, and said they might search him. They did not think it so proper to search him then: he was put into a coach, and carried to Sir 
               <persName id="t17650710-28-person271">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17650710-28-person271" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person271" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's. I came there just after they had search'd him, and they shewed me this purse.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I am very innocent of the thing.</p>
               <p>To his Character.</p>
               <p>Mr. Beaver. I have known him near three years; he has been a gentleman's servant, but lately buys and sells horses. I have had dealings with him; he paid me honestly.</p>
               <p>Mr. Kelly. I have known him about three years; I look upon him to be an honest, industrious, fair-dealing man. If he had wanted an hundred pounds, I would have lent it him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Peate. I have known him sixteen or seventeen months; he is a sober, honest, industrious man, and never quarrelsome. I think within myself, he is the least capable of going on the highway of any man I know. I take him to be a timorous man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Howell. I have known him between two and three years; I have had dealings with him, and never heard or saw any thing amiss by him.</p>
               <p>Mr. Reves. I have known him sixteen or seventeen months; I always took him to be a very honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Floodgate. I have known him eighteen months; he is an honest, industrious man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Jones. I have known him about twelve months; I always found him just and punctual in all his dealings.</p>
               <p>Mr. Carver. I have been acquainted with him upwards of twelve months, and have had dealings with him; he always behaved just and honest; I never heard any thing amiss of him in my life.</p>
               <p>Mr. Webb. I have known him between two and three years; I never heard a syllable amiss of him.</p>
               <p>Mr Draper. I have known him about eighteen or nineteen months; I have recommended him to sell horses; he is a very sober, honest man.</p>
               <p>Mr. Stevens. I have known him more than four months; his character is that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Elliot. I have known him going on four months, or better; he is a very honest, sober man. I never heard to the contrary.</p>
               <p>Q. to Wood. How was the prisoner dress'd when you took him?</p>
               <p>Wood. He had a plain hat, and a blue surtout coat.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650710-28-verdict152" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-verdict152" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17650710-28-punish153" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650710-28-punish153" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650710-28-defend260 t17650710-28-punish153"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
