<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650522-27">
               <interp inst="t17650522-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-27" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650522"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650522-27" type="date" value="17650522"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650522-27-off170-c298" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-27-defend352 t17650522-27-off170 t17650522-27-verdict175"></join>
         
               <p>325. (L.) 
               <persName id="t17650522-27-defend352" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Edmund 
                     Swinney 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17650522-27-alias-6" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-27-defend352 t17650522-27-alias-6"></join>McSwinney</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-defend352" type="surname" value="Swinney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-defend352" type="given" value="Edmund"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-defend352" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17650522-27-off170" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-off170" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-off170" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two hempen bags, value 2 d. one Jacobus, value 20 s. two silver dollars, and 30 l. in money numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650522-27-victim355" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Plummer 
                  <interp inst="t17650522-27-victim355" type="surname" value="Plummer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-victim355" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-victim355" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-27-off170 t17650522-27-victim355"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . <rs id="t17650522-27-cd171" type="crimeDate">May 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-27-off170 t17650522-27-cd171"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-27-person356">
                  William 
                  Plummer 
               <interp inst="t17650522-27-person356" type="surname" value="Plummer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-person356" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live within <placeName id="t17650522-27-crimeloc172">Aldgate</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-27-crimeloc172" type="placeName" value="Aldgate"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650522-27-crimeloc172" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-27-off170 t17650522-27-crimeloc172"></join>, and am an <rs id="t17650522-27-viclabel173" type="occupation">oil-man</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-27-victim355 t17650522-27-viclabel173"></join>; I found my desk broke open last Friday morning; and my man informed me that the prisoner, (who had lived <rs id="t17650522-27-deflabel174" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-27-defend352 t17650522-27-deflabel174"></join> with me) came into my shop on Thursday evening, between nine and ten o'clock, and took up a pot and went down and drawed himself some beer, without asking leave; at which time, I have great reason to believe he unbolted the cellar window; and came in at it in the night, and got to my desk: I missed the money mentioned in the indictment out of my desk: On Sunday morning he was taken up, and brought to me; I examined him in my compting-house; he was three parts drunk: he denied the charge: at last I got out of him; he lived in Wapping: he was carried to the compter, and the next morning before Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-27-person357">
                  Samuel 
                  Fludyer 
               <interp inst="t17650522-27-person357" type="surname" value="Fludyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-person357" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            : upon finding he was not at his lodgings that Thursday night, I got out of him that he was at Mr. Dowdall's, in King's-street, Wapping: I asked him if he staid there all night; he said, he went from thence to a club; but would not say where: I sent my kinsman to enquire, and found he had been at Mr. Breadey's, Montague-street, Whitechapel: and there he found two bags of money; upon which the prisoner was examined again before Sir 
               <persName id="t17650522-27-person358">
                  Samuel 
                  Fludyer 
               <interp inst="t17650522-27-person358" type="surname" value="Fludyer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-person358" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-person358" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; there he confessed that when he went into my cellar he 
               <persName id="t17650522-27-person359">
                  drew
               <interp inst="t17650522-27-person359" type="given" value="drew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-person359" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             some beer, he unbolted two bolts of my cellar window, and in the night got in, and so up into the kitchen; and took the key of the compting-house, and went and unbolted the door, and broke open my desk, and put the money into two bags; which he confessed to be my bags; and carried the money and left it in Mr. Breadey's hands: he begged for mercy, and proposed pleading guilty.</p>
               <p>Mr. Breadey. The prisoner was at my house last Saturday night; the first time I ever saw him; he had two bags with money tossing them about the table; there was another man with him; my wife thought the man might be a sharper; she asked him to leave his money till he was sober: he came to me and said, he worked very hard for it, and he intended to go home in a fortnight or three weeks: he put it on the table and reckoned it up; 35 l. 6 s. I observed a bad moidore; afterwards the money was sealed up: upon opening it I found a broad Jacobus; I did not see that; I imagine that was left in the bag, when we counted the money.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. There was in my money a bad<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176505220035"></xptr> moidore, and a broad Jacobus, (the money produced, he takes them in his hand); these I can swear are my property: there are two dollars amongst the money; I know I lost two: I lost a dish full of silver; and here is 19 l. all in silver amongst this: here is a smooth six-pence that has been gilded, which I have had some time.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650522-27-person360">
                  John 
                  Hoy 
               <interp inst="t17650522-27-person360" type="surname" value="Hoy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-person360" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-person360" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am porter to Mr. Plummer; yesterday was a week, at night, I was serving a customer; the prisoner came in, and said he was very bad and very dry; he took the pot without leave and went down into the cellar, and returned again in about five or six minutes: I had bolted the cellar window myself about three quarters of an hour before; I heard the prisoner confess he was guilty of the fact.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>They want to swear my life away upon a piece of money or two, that there is many more like them.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650522-27-verdict175" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-verdict175" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17650522-27-punish176" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650522-27-punish176" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650522-27-defend352 t17650522-27-punish176"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
