<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620421-35">
               <interp inst="t17620421-35" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-35" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-35" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620421"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620421-35" type="date" value="17620421"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620421-35-off186-c283" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-35-defend337 t17620421-35-off186 t17620421-35-verdict188"></join>
         
               <p>150. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620421-35-defend337" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Kite 
                  <interp inst="t17620421-35-defend337" type="surname" value="Kite"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-defend337" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-defend337" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17620421-35-off186" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-off186" type="offenceCategory" value="deception"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-off186" type="offenceSubcategory" value="perjury"></interp>
               wilful and corrupt perjury on a trial at Guild-hall
            </rs>, <rs id="t17620421-35-cd187" type="crimeDate">February 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-35-off186 t17620421-35-cd187"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-35-person338">
                  David 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person338" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person338" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person338" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I belong to the Custom-house; am a tidesman in see. I saw the prisoner come out of a Hamburgh vessel, lately arrived: she had landed upon the stairs. I went and told her I was a Custom-house-officer. I examined her bundle, and found about seven ells of holland, and three quarters of a yard of cambrick. I told her, I must seize them, and carry them to the warehouse. I walked with them: she followed me to the warehouse. When I came out, she followed, and asked me, which way she should get them again? I bid her go over to the George coffee-house, there is a man that writes petitions, and possibly, upon application to the honourable board, they may grant them you again. She went there. Then I went to the wharf. A soldier told an acquaintance of mine, that the waterman advised her not to land there, and that the woman had more goods about her. Then I went back to the coffee-house, and said to her, I have an information you have more goods about you. There were 
               <persName id="t17620421-35-person339">
                  Timothy 
                  Osmond 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person339" type="surname" value="Osmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person339" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Mr. Wingfield, 
               <persName id="t17620421-35-person340">
                  Richard 
                  Sewell 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person340" type="surname" value="Sewell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person340" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the waiter, and 
               <persName id="t17620421-35-person341">
                  Mary 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person341" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person341" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person341" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , by; it was just by the bar. I took and felt her arms, that is, on the outside her cloaths, and her cloaths down, by squeezing them. She said, be civil. I said, you may depend upon it, I shall do nothing indecent. I touched her pockets on the outside pretty hard; she did not complain of any indecency. About five or six weeks after I was indicted, and tried last sessions at Guild-hall. She swore on that trial, that</p>
               <p>"I took her behind the</p>
               <p>"yard-door at the George coffee-house, put my</p>
               <p>"hand up her petticoats, behaved very rudely to</p>
               <p>"her, and gave her a violent blow on her breast;</p>
               <p>"she cried out: Afterwards she complained to the</p>
               <p>"master of the house of my ill usuage." His name is 
               <persName id="t17620421-35-person342">
                  William 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person342" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person342" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person342" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q What did she say upon her cross-examination?</p>
               <p>Williams. She was asked by the court, whether Mr. Bland or Mr. Vincent asked her, whether she had declared to them that I had behaved no way indecent to her. She denied it, and declared she never said I behaved no way indecent to her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you take her behind the yard-door at the George coffee house?</p>
               <p>Williams. No.</p>
               <p>Q Did you put your hand up her petticoats?</p>
               <p>Williams. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you behave rudely to her?</p>
               <p>Williams. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give her a blow on the breast, or strike her?</p>
               <p>Williams. No: I did not strike her in no way whatsoever,</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner. Did you not take up every one of my petticoats, till you came to my shift?</p>
               <p>Williams. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-35-person343">
                  Timothy 
                  Osmond 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person343" type="surname" value="Osmond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person343" type="given" value="Timothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person343" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the George coffee-house when the prisoner was there. She was talking to me about the things being taken from her. She said, I should not mind it, if he had not used me so ill. I said, when? She said, now this minute; Mr. Wingfield was in the box with me. She said, he put his hand up her petticoats and down her bosom, and she stood very still, for she was frighted, and did not know what he was going to do with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her cry out?</p>
               <p>Osmond. No, I did not. I did not know that Mr. Williams was there.</p>
               <p>Oldfield Wingfield. I was in the coffee house at the same time that 
               <persName id="t17620421-35-person344">
                  David 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person344" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person344" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person344" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was searching the prisoner. I was in the same box with the last witness: She made no complaint, or cried out. She said, sir, I hope you will be civil to me. He said, I will not hurt you in any shape, or treat you with any indecency. I had my back towards them; but if what she swore to had been true, I must have heard it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-35-person345">
                  Richard 
                  Sewell 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person345" type="surname" value="Sewell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person345" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person345" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw 
               <persName id="t17620421-35-person346">
                  David 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person346" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person346" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person346" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             search the woman at the bar in our coffee-house. I did not see him use her with any indecency. I saw him handle her cloaths on the outside, but not up her petticoats. She did not complain at that time at all: This was in the open coffee-room. There was Mr. Wingfield, Mr. Osmond, the maid, and me, by. I am servant there.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner complain to your master?</p>
               <p>Sewell. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Williams strike her?</p>
               <p>Sewell. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-35-person347">
                  William 
                  Young 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person347" type="surname" value="Young"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person347" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person347" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was master of the George coffee-house. I was at breakfast when this happened. I saw nothing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner complain of any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Young. She complained to me and my spouse. she had lost a remnant of holland and a little bit of cambrick, but did not make any complaint of any blow, or any ill-usage, any farther than that of the taking her goods.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620421-35-person348">
                  Richard 
                  Vincent 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person348" type="surname" value="Vincent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person348" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person348" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the prisoner in the coffee-room<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176204210024"></xptr> several times. She applied to the board to have her linen again.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Vincent. I am inspector. I told her Williams was at Gravesend, and when he came home, I dare say he would do her all the service he could. I hope she knows me now. she swore at Guild-hall she did not know me. I told her, I heard she was going to prosecute Williams for ill-treating her. Mr. Blond and I were together in the coffee-room. She had applied several times to have them restored, and lodged a complaint against Williams for ill-treatment; but I never heard any thing about a blow. Mr. Blond and I were ordered to inquire into the state of it, whether Williams was guilty or not: I told her, I was very sorry to hear she was going to carry a prosecution on against Williams. She declared to me and Mr. Blond, 
               <persName id="t17620421-35-person349">
                  David 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person349" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person349" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person349" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had never used any indecency to her in the coffee-house.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I petitioned for my cloth, and could never get an answer. They all put me to defiance, because I had no witnesses. He said, he could have witnesses, and I could have none. I have no witnesses of the bad usage he gave me, but I had witnesses afterwards of the condition I was in, from the fright he put me in. I was a stranger, and did not know where I was. When I got into Tower-street, I miscarried. I was eleven weeks gone with child. They told me he was a waterman, and his name was Williams.</p>
               <p>Q. to Vincent. Had her charge been true, what would have been the consequence?</p>
               <p>Vincent. 
               <persName id="t17620421-35-person350">
                  David 
                  Williams 
               <interp inst="t17620421-35-person350" type="surname" value="Williams"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person350" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-person350" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             would have been discharged.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. I was advised to do this by Mr. Kelly, a lawyer.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620421-35-verdict188" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-verdict188" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17620421-35-punish189" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-punish189" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-punish189" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="pillory"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-35-defend337 t17620421-35-punish189"></join>
               P
            </rs>. 
<rs id="t17620421-35-punish190" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-punish190" type="punishmentCategory" value="imprison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-punish190" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="newgate"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-35-defend337 t17620421-35-punish190"></join>
               Im
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620421-35-punish191" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-punish191" type="punishmentCategory" value="miscPunish"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620421-35-punish191" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="fine"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620421-35-defend337 t17620421-35-punish191"></join>
               
                     <note>[Fine. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
