<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650918-29">
               <interp inst="t17650918-29" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-29" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-29" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650918"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-29" type="date" value="17650918"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650918-29-off158-c201" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-29-defend258 t17650918-29-off158 t17650918-29-verdict163"></join>
         
               <p>447. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650918-29-defend258" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     White 
                  <interp inst="t17650918-29-defend258" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-defend258" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-defend258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17650918-29-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape on the body of Mary, wife of 
                     <persName id="t17650918-29-person259">
                        John 
                        Oldner 
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-person259" type="surname" value="Oldner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-29-person259" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-29-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , against her will and consent
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650918-29-cd159" type="crimeDate">August 26</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-29-off158 t17650918-29-cd159"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
               
                  <persName id="t17650918-29-victim261" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Oldner 
                  <interp inst="t17650918-29-victim261" type="surname" value="Oldner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-victim261" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-victim261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-29-off158 t17650918-29-victim261"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . I am <rs id="t17650918-29-viclabel160" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-29-victim261 t17650918-29-viclabel160"></join> to 
               <persName id="t17650918-29-person262">
                  John 
                  Oldner 
               <interp inst="t17650918-29-person262" type="surname" value="Oldner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-person262" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , a Carpenter in <placeName id="t17650918-29-crimeloc161">Castle-street, Seven-dials</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-29-crimeloc161" type="placeName" value="Castle-street, Seven-dials"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-29-crimeloc161" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-29-off158 t17650918-29-crimeloc161"></join>. The prisoner is a <rs id="t17650918-29-deflabel162" type="occupation">journeyman baker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-29-defend258 t17650918-29-deflabel162"></join>; he was at our house on the 26th of August last, with bread, about six in the evening: according to custom, 
               <persName id="t17650918-29-person263">
                  Isabella 
                  Nemoe 
               <interp inst="t17650918-29-person263" type="surname" value="Nemoe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-person263" type="given" value="Isabella"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-person263" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sat in the room with me; he sat down upon a table for some time; I was very earnest at work. Nemoe was call'd out of the room: I was removed from the table: he fell upon me, with one arm before and the other behind, and with that behind me he put the sash down, which was his left hand, and dragg'd me to the bed from my chair: I had not time to say one word: the sash looked into the public street; it was a two pair of stairs room; the curtains to the window were open.</p>
               <p>Q. How far was the bed from the chair where you sat?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. The bed was not a yard from the place where I sat, but not in the same room; then he tripp'd up my heels; I fell upon the child's bed-feet: and with the blow hurting my back, I had not power to speak: he confined my hands down to the bed under my head: I lay on the child's bed, rather on my right side; so then he did what he could do: he did not do so much as he would have done; but he gave me the foul disease.</p>
               <p>Court. If it is disagreeable to you, you must give the court an account, in as decent words as you can, what he did to you.</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. I had a great deal of natural knowledge of his private parts in my body; he put his private part into mine.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this without your consent?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. It was; he never ask'd me whether he should or should not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you refuse or resist him?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. I did as much as I could.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the consequence of this?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. He did the same as my husband did; a great deal of moisture came from him; afterwards I was so sore I could hardly sit in my chair.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination:</p>
               <p>Q. When did you first complain of this usage?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. I complained to Isabella Nemoe immediately; she came to the door, and the door was lock'd and fastened unknown to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Who unlock'd it?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. The prisoner did: she finding me full of tears, insisted upon knowing what was the matter, and I told her before his face; said she to him. A heavy curse fall on you: and I said, My curse, and God's curse, fall upon you, for my sake and my family.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had he been in the room before this affair?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. I can't tell how long; not above a quarter of an hour. I told her every thing, as he sat in a chair, how he went on with me, and when he was gone, I told her over again.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you apply to a magistrate in order to take him up?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. He had told us before, he was going away: the very next day after this affair, Nemoe and I went down to his master's, to enquire for him; he was not at home; we were told he had been gone out with bread about an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you go to the Justice for a warrant?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. I went for a warrant a fortnight after.</p>
               <p>Q. How many days after the fact committed was it that you told your husband?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. That would have been a fortnight come the Monday night, and I told him the Saturday before.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to tell your husband of it?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. Because my husband found it out: I was very bad, and my husband took it from me; my husband charged me with giving him that distemper.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you tell your husband he gave it you?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. I was afraid of his knowing of it: to my knowledge I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you take the prisoner up?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. In the street near my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Before or after you told your husband of it?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. He was taken up the next morning after.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176509180020"></xptr>Q. Is not your house very public, what lodgers are there?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. There is a man and his wife, and three or four children, live in the room over me: the landlord lives in the shop.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was he in ravishing you?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. From the beginning to the end it might be a quarter of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was you upon the bed before he entered your body?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. Not many minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body confine your mouth?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. No; I cry'd out as well as ever I could, and desired he would not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you speak mighty civil to him?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. No, I did not; but told him I would not consent to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, if this misfortune had not happened to your husband, should you ever have taken notice of this insult upon you?</p>
               <p>M. Oldner. Yes, I should have complained; but it would not have been at present; I was ashamed.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650918-29-verdict163" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-29-verdict163" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
