<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620224-3">
               <interp inst="t17620224-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-3" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-3" type="date" value="17620224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620224-3-off14-c48" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-3-defend53 t17620224-3-off14 t17620224-3-verdict16"></join>
         
               <p>90. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620224-3-defend53" type="defendantName">
                     Morris 
                     Delaney 
                  <interp inst="t17620224-3-defend53" type="surname" value="Delaney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-defend53" type="given" value="Morris"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-defend53" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17620224-3-off14" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-off14" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-off14" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing, out of the house of Thomas Combe, one silver scollop waiter, value 5 l. one silver waiter stand, two silver sauce boats, two silver table spoons, a pair of gold studs, one silver pint mug, one silver sauce pan, three shirts, three dimity waistcoats
            </rs>, the property of the said 
               <persName id="t17620224-3-victim54" type="victimName">
                  Thomas 
                  Combe 
               <interp inst="t17620224-3-victim54" type="surname" value="Combe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-victim54" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-victim54" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-3-off14 t17620224-3-victim54"></join>
                  </persName>
              + .</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-3-person55">
                  Thomas 
                  Combe 
               <interp inst="t17620224-3-person55" type="surname" value="Combe"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person55" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person55" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17620224-3-crimeloc15">Tottenham Cross</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17620224-3-crimeloc15" type="placeName" value="Tottenham Cross"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17620224-3-crimeloc15" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-3-off14 t17620224-3-crimeloc15"></join>; and in the night, between the 12th and 13th instant, my house was broke open, and robbed of the several things mentioned in the indictment. When my maid got up in the morning, she found the parlour door and window shutter open, the drawers opened, and things all about the room. Upon that she came to acquaint me of it; my wife and I got up, and found the cupboard, where the plate principally was, broke open, the locks of the drawers forced open, and almost all the locks in the room opened, by a sort of instrument, we could not tell what. I sent for a carpenter in the neighbourhood, who said he thought it could not be done by any picklock keys; and upon inquiry in the neighbourhood, and of the watchman, if any-body had been seen about my house, I was told the prisoner at the bar had been lurking about the street; and, believing I had reasons sufficient to suspect him, I went to Sir 
               <persName id="t17620224-3-person56">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620224-3-person56" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person56" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person56" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             to get a warrant to search his house, and take him up. When I returned from Mr. Fielding's, I went to the constable's house, and he and I went to this man's lodgings with my wife, and found this instrument in his room, which we apprehend to be the very instrument that had forced or broke open the locks; which, upon bringing to my house and trying how it fitted the holes, we concluded it must be done by that, or some other such-like instrument. The constable afterwards took him; and had him to his house.</p>
               <p>Q. What passed there?</p>
               <p>Combes. He said he knew nothing of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he searched at the constable's house?</p>
               <p>Combes. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing of your property upon him?</p>
               <p>Combes. Nothing at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Then you charge him upon suspicion only?</p>
               <p>Combes. Yes, my lord.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you found any part of your goods?</p>
               <p>Combes. No, my lord.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-3-person57">
                  Margaret 
                  Combes 
               <interp inst="t17620224-3-person57" type="surname" value="Combes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person57" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person57" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , When Mr. Combes and I were informed the house was broke open, and there was some suspicion of the prisoner, my husband got a warrant to search his house, and I went with him; there was very little in the room, but a hammock put up in one corner of it, and this instrument lay in the window [holding it up]. I took it in my hand, and said, I think this very thing broke open my house; and, upon return home, we fitted it to several holes made in the drawers and cupboard doors.</p>
               <p>Q. What other reason have you to think it was done by that instrument?</p>
               <p>M. Combes. Any-body might see it was done by such an instrument, and this fitted the places.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Combes, in your presence, ask him any questions about that instrument?</p>
               <p>M. Combes. No; Mr. Combes asked him about it afterwards at Sir 
               <persName id="t17620224-3-person58">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17620224-3-person58" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person58" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person58" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's, and he said he had that and another screw and staple to fasten up his hammock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the hammock appear to be screwed up by such an instrument.</p>
               <p>Mr. Combes. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-3-person59">
                  Mary 
                  Waters 
               <interp inst="t17620224-3-person59" type="surname" value="Waters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person59" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person59" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Waters. In the house the prisoner lives at.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you know of this matter?</p>
               <p>M. Waters. Only this, that he keeps very bad hours; and the night before I saw another man with him about 10 o'clock in his room.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether the prisoner at the bar, or they, had been out that night?</p>
               <p>M. Waters. I cannot say; they appeared to be both just got up about 8 o'clock that morning.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-3-person60">
                  Henry 
                  Melling 
               <interp inst="t17620224-3-person60" type="surname" value="Melling"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person60" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person60" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Watchman.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you watch about the night of the 12th of February.</p>
               <p>H. Melling. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you watch near Mr. Combes's house?</p>
               <p>Melling. No, my stand is a good way from his house; but I was going my rounds, to the best of my knowledge about one, and I met this man.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the prisoner is the man you met?</p>
               <p>Melling. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you say?</p>
               <p>Melling. After one o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any-body with him?</p>
               <p>Melling. No, Sir.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any thing of a bundle with him?</p>
               <p>Melling. None that I saw.</p>
               <p>Q. Was all fast at Mr. Combes's about that time?</p>
               <p>Melling. Yes.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-3-person61">
                  William 
                  Rose 
               <interp inst="t17620224-3-person61" type="surname" value="Rose"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person61" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person61" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Watchman.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go your round?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176202240005"></xptr>Rose. At the hours of twelve, two, and four; and I saw all fast at Mr. Combes's.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you meet this man?</p>
               <p>Rose. Yes, about four.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any thing about him when you met him?</p>
               <p>Rose. No, nothing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go your rounds after four?</p>
               <p>Rose. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-3-person62">
                  Robert 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17620224-3-person62" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person62" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-person62" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , carpenter. I was sent for to Mr. Combes's, to see what kind of instrument had opened the shutter, cupboard-door, and drawers, and I said it was forced by some other instrument than common pick-lock tools; that I imagined that it was by a screw like what is called a cooper's vice. This is what is called so [holding it up.] When this instrument had been found in his room, I tried it, and I found it went in very easy; and that this instrument, or some other like it, must have opened the desk, the drawers, and cupboard.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure they were forced by a screw?</p>
               <p>Edwards. The desk was forced in the joint opposite to the lock.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the leaf of the desk much torn or not, or the drawers?</p>
               <p>Edwards. The holes made in the flap of the desk were pretty much torn, but the drawers were not.</p>
               <p>Q. So all we know from your evidence is, that this was done by that or some other instrument like it.</p>
               <p>Constable. They brought me a warrant to search this man's house, and to take him up. Upon searching his house, we found this screw; and when I met with the man afterwards, I told him he must go along with me. He asked for my authority. I said, Here it is; upon that he struck me with his fist; and I said he had better be easy, and go with me. He then took his knife, and threatened to rip me up; and he got away from me then, but I afterwards took him.</p>
               <p>Court to the Prisoner. Have you any questions to ask?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. No.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620224-3-verdict16" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-3-verdict16" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Detained upon another indictment.</p>
            </div1>
