<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611209-21">
               <interp inst="t17611209-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-21" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611209"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611209-21" type="date" value="17611209"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611209-21-off121-c220" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-defend257 t17611209-21-off121 t17611209-21-verdict125"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611209-21-off126-c220" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-defend257 t17611209-21-off126 t17611209-21-verdict125"></join>
         
               <p>22. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17611209-21-defend257" type="defendantName">
                     Christopher 
                     Flinn 
                  <interp inst="t17611209-21-defend257" type="surname" value="Flinn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-defend257" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-defend257" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted, for <rs id="t17611209-21-off121" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-off121" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-off121" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, together with 
                     <persName id="t17611209-21-person258">
                        Samuel 
                        Rolk 
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person258" type="surname" value="Rolk"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-person258" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-person258" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   and 
                     <persName id="t17611209-21-person259">
                        Patrick 
                        Surridon 
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person259" type="surname" value="Surridon"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-person259" type="given" value="Patrick"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-person259" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                   not taken, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17611209-21-victim261" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Rouce 
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-victim261" type="surname" value="Rouce"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-victim261" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-victim261" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17611209-21-viclabel122" type="occupation">Esquire</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-victim261 t17611209-21-viclabel122"></join>, did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and taking from his person two guineas and one half guinea, the money of the said 
                     <persName id="t17611209-21-person262">
                        Thomas 
                        Rouce 
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person262" type="surname" value="Rouce"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-person262" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-person262" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17611209-21-cd123" type="crimeDate">Oct. 18</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-off121 t17611209-21-cd123"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-off126 t17611209-21-cd123"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-21-person263">
                  Thomas 
                  Rouce 
               <interp inst="t17611209-21-person263" type="surname" value="Rouce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person263" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person263" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming from Hampstead in a post chaise with 
               <persName id="t17611209-21-person264">
                  George 
                  Seaton 
               <interp inst="t17611209-21-person264" type="surname" value="Seaton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person264" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esquire, on a Saturday in October, I cannot tell the day of the month. We were going to Hackney. When we were <placeName id="t17611209-21-crimeloc124">near the Angel Inn at Islington</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17611209-21-crimeloc124" type="placeName" value="near the Angel Inn at Islington"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17611209-21-crimeloc124" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-off121 t17611209-21-crimeloc124"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-off126 t17611209-21-crimeloc124"></join>, there came three men on horseback; one of them rode up to the postilion, and stopp'd him, the two others came up to us on each side, and, putting pistols to our breasts, with oaths demanded our money. I delivered two guineas and a half to one of them, and Mr. Seaton, I believe, gave six guineas and his watch to the other. Then they rode off the way that we came. This was before seven o'clock, and it was dark. I could not know their faces. The man that robb'd me had a brown coat on. I gave information of them, and a man immediately went after them; who can give a farther account. I cannot swear to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your money in a purse?</p>
               <p>Rouce. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Is Mr. Seaton here?</p>
               <p>Rouce. No, he is not.</p>
               <p>Jos. Dingley. Just after the gentlemen were robb'd they stopp'd at my door at the Angel Inn in Islington. They told me they had just been robb'd by three highwaymen near my house, and described their horses. I could not persuade any body to go with me in pursuit of them. I got a gun, and went to the turnpike myself, and found three had gone<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176112090019"></xptr> through towards Cold Bath Fields. I went there, and up into Grays Inn Lane; I heard nothing of them there; then I went to the Bull inn in Holborn, I heard nothing there; then I went to the Horse and Groom, and asked if there were any such people there; and told them there had been a robbery, and described the horses. The landlord said they had been in there, and were gone about 10 minutes, or a quarter of an hour. I asked him if he knew them? He said, they had had the horses a great many times. I asked him if he knew where to find them? He said, one day he was coming down Fleet Market, and they treated him with some rum and water; and he believed, by inquiring there, he could find them. Then I went home, and the next morning I went to see the gentlemen. We went to Mr. Fielding, and gave information; and, on the Tuesday after, the prisoner was taken in the Fleet Market; the robbery was on the Sunday evening.</p>
               <p>John Quiby. I keep the Horse and Groom, Holborn. I think it was on the 18th of October Mr. Dingly came to me: I had that day lett a horse to the prisoner, another to Rolk, and another to a person that called himself Smith, one was a grey, another a roan, and the other a dark brown.</p>
               <p>Q. What time that day did they take horse?</p>
               <p>Quiby. I think it was about 12 o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they all go out together?</p>
               <p>Quiby. They did, and returned about eight at night; I can't tell to half an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they all return together?</p>
               <p>Quiby. They did. I was before justice Fielding when the prisoner was there; he was searched, and there was a seal taken out of his pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Do you recollect what kind of horses the three men were on that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I cannot say to that.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-21-person265">
                  Thomas 
                  Wadington 
               <interp inst="t17611209-21-person265" type="surname" value="Wadington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person265" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Sunday the 18th of October I saw three horses that those men rode; they were lett out of the yard where I live: I saw them ride out of the yard between twelve and one o'clock. I went out for a walk into the fields, and I saw them again near four o'clock go through the turnpike by Sir John Oldcastle's, near Clerkenwell Green, that goes on through Blackmary's-hole, to the new road; they were going out of town.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner one of the three?</p>
               <p>Wadington. I am sure he was; he rode upon a tall roan gelding. They came galloping as fast as they could ride: I halloo'd to them; and said to one of them, You'll break your girth; to let them see I saw them.</p>
               <p>Dingly. It was the other gentleman that described the horses, who is not here.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-21-person266">
                  John 
                  Fitzpatrick 
               <interp inst="t17611209-21-person266" type="surname" value="Fitzpatrick"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person266" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lodged with me upwards of 12 months; he paid me very honestly 10 l, that I lent him when he went to Ireland.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611209-21-verdict125" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-verdict125" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>(M) He was a second time indicted, for <rs id="t17611209-21-off126" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-off126" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-off126" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17611209-21-victim268" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Yardley 
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-victim268" type="surname" value="Yardley"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-victim268" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611209-21-victim268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17611209-21-viclabel127" type="occupation">Clerk</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-victim268 t17611209-21-viclabel127"></join>, did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear, and danger of his life, and taking from his person one metal watch, val. 40 s. one gold seal, val. 30 s. and one half guinea, the property of the said Edward, and against his will
            </rs>, <rs id="t17611209-21-cd128" type="crimeDate">Oct. 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-off121 t17611209-21-cd128"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-off126 t17611209-21-cd128"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-21-person269">
                  Edward 
                  Yardley 
               <interp inst="t17611209-21-person269" type="surname" value="Yardley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person269" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 8th of Oct. about six in the evening, it was dark, I was coming up <placeName id="t17611209-21-crimeloc129">Highgate Hill</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17611209-21-crimeloc129" type="placeName" value="Highgate Hill"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17611209-21-crimeloc129" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-off121 t17611209-21-crimeloc129"></join>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611209-21-off126 t17611209-21-crimeloc129"></join> in my one horse chaise; two men came up to my chaise, one on each side, each of them put a pistol to my breast, and demanded my purse and my watch. They seemed to be in a pretty great hurry; they said, Make haste, make haste, make haste! your purse, your watch, make haste! I bid them be easy, and said they should have them.</p>

               <p>Q. Was any body with you?</p>
               <p>Yardley. No, I was alone; I was going to Highgate, and this was within a quarter of a mile of the houses. I gave them my purse, which had but half a guinea in it, and a metal watch with a shagreen case, and a white dial-plate; the maker's name Gray, no number (I believe); there was a common seal, and a cornelian seal set in gold, the seal was a greyhound on his master's monument, with a French motto to it; then they galloped away towards Highgate as hard as they could.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they their faces covered, or not?</p>
               <p>Yardley. It was too dark for me to see that: I cannot describe neither their persons or horses.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see your watch again?</p>
               <p>Yardley. Sir 
               <persName id="t17611209-21-person270">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17611209-21-person270" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person270" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sent for me, I having made an information before him of what I lost; I went there again; this was about a week or ten days after; then he shewed me my seal.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner by at the time?</p>
               <p>Yardley. He was. (Produced in court.) This is my property, and what I was robbed of that evening: I have had it 30 years; this is the seal of a dog sitting on a monument; I have an impression of it here, which I have had by me some time. [Produced, and the seal put upon it; they answered exactly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-21-person271">
                  James 
                  Steel 
               <interp inst="t17611209-21-person271" type="surname" value="Steel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person271" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person271" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . There was a report of a robbery being committed; I believe it was in October last.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Steel. I live upon Finchley common, at the Windmill and Fighting Cocks; there came two men to my house about five o'clock; they hung their horses at the door, and came in.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did they come?</p>
               <p>Steel. I was backwards when they came; I can't tell which way they came.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether the prisoner is one of them?</p>
               <p>Steel. I do not know; I made no remarks of them.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did they go away?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176112090020"></xptr>Steel. I believe they were gone before six; but I was backwards, and did not see them go away: I know one of the horses was a roan horse with a cut tail; the near eye was out, and a gaul on the shoulder.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-21-person272">
                  Mary 
                  Steel 
               <interp inst="t17611209-21-person272" type="surname" value="Steel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person272" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person272" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the last evidence; I remember two gentlemen coming to our house about five o'clock; they came in, and had something to eat, and left their horses at the door.</p>
               <p>Q. What coloured horses were they?</p>
               <p>M. Steel. I do not know; they went away before six o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Which way did they go?</p>
               <p>M. Steel. They went away towards London.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-21-person273">
                  John 
                  Quiby 
               <interp inst="t17611209-21-person273" type="surname" value="Quiby"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person273" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person273" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner and another had horses of me on the 8th of October, I verily believe, but I cannot be positive; I know they had on the 9th, because I have that set down. The prisoner had a horse of me seven times; he and Rolk went out together several times. I lett the prisoner a roan horse very often; he is blind of the near eye, and a cut tail, and gauled on his shoulder by running in a chaise. The seal that the prosecutor has sworn to is the seal that I saw taken out of the prisoner's pocket at justice Fielding's; that was, I think, on the 22d of Oct. I remember the prosecutor said it was a grey hound on a monument, before he saw it. The prisoner said, that Sheridan found it in Covent Garden, and gave it to him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-21-person274">
                  William 
                  Marsden 
               <interp inst="t17611209-21-person274" type="surname" value="Marsden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person274" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw this seal taken out of the prisoner's pocket when under examination on the 20th of October. The prisoner was examined different times, because we know the seal to be Mr. Yardley's seal, by his descriptions of it to us. I live with Mr. Fielding; the prisoner gave different accounts of it, first, he said a man gave it him that is gone to Ireland, another time he said he found it in Covent Garden, as he was walking there one morning.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I can contradict him in what he says. It was made a present of to me. The next time they examined me, they asked me if I heard the man say where he found it. I said he found it in Covent Garden; the young man is gone to Ireland short of money, and I made him a present of half a guinea, between me and another man; I gave him 5 s. 6 d. and the other 5 s. I never robbed a man in my life. I believed that was pinchbeck; I knew no other till it was taken from me.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611209-21-person275">
                  Arthur 
                  Foster 
               <interp inst="t17611209-21-person275" type="surname" value="Foster"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person275" type="given" value="Arthur"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner from his infancy. I was at the Blue Anchor, Russel-street, Covent Garden; I cannot say the day of the month, but I believe it was some time in October, it was on a Sunday, there was a young man going home to Ireland, named Sheridan; we thought proper to make a collection for him to carry him home, as he was a labouring man; Mr. Flinn said he would contribute, and pulled out 5 s. 6 d. and I pulled out 5 s. which was all the money I had upon earth. There were three or four more. The money was given him; this is a thing usual with our countrymen when they are going home. He put the money in his pocket, and pulled out a seal; I never had it in my hand, it was a yellow seal with a red stone in it. Said he to Mr. Flinn. I have a seal that I picked up, you have a watch, and I never a one, I'll give you this seal. There were many in company, wishing him a good journey; I did not hear him say where he found it. We staid and had some punch. I never saw Mr. Flinn since, till I heard he was taken into custody. I have known him from his infancy, his character was always a good one. I have worked with him here.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Foster. I am a Dyer; I worked for Mr Honor and Graham in Montague Close, on the other Side the Water.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611209-21-verdict130" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611209-21-verdict130" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
