<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17631207-32">
               <interp inst="t17631207-32" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-32" type="year" value="1763"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-32" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17631207"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17631207-32" type="date" value="17631207"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17631207-32-off177-c244" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-32-defend312 t17631207-32-off177 t17631207-32-verdict181"></join>
         
               <p>36. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17631207-32-defend312" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Armstrong 
                  <interp inst="t17631207-32-defend312" type="surname" value="Armstrong"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-32-defend312" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-32-defend312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17631207-32-off177" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-32-off177" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-32-off177" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's high-way, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17631207-32-victim314" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Derand 
                        <interp inst="t17631207-32-victim314" type="surname" value="Derand"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-32-victim314" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17631207-32-victim314" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-32-off177 t17631207-32-victim314"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life; and stealing from his person one hat, value 5 s. the property of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17631207-32-cd178" type="crimeDate">November 10</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-32-off177 t17631207-32-cd178"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-32-person315">
                  John 
                  Derand 
               <interp inst="t17631207-32-person315" type="surname" value="Derand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-32-person315" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-32-person315" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Bond's Stables; I am the <rs id="t17631207-32-viclabel179" type="occupation">keeper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-32-victim314 t17631207-32-viclabel179"></join> of them. I was coming from the Cross-keys in Long-acre, between seven and eight o'clock, on the 10th of November, in the evening: when I was near counsellor Willis's rails, in <placeName id="t17631207-32-crimeloc180">Lincoln's-inn Fields</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-32-crimeloc180" type="placeName" value="Lincoln's-inn Fields"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17631207-32-crimeloc180" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17631207-32-off177 t17631207-32-crimeloc180"></join>, there came the prisoner and two other men; Mr. Whitaker was with me; the other two went by Mr. Whitaker, and the prisoner went between the rails and me, and snatched my hat and wig off; I saved my wig, but my hat he ran away with. I said to Mr. Whitaker, I had lost my hat; we pursued, and one of the other men took hold on my coat, as I turned the corner, and turned me about to stop me: we called, stop the thief; at the corner of the market, we lost sight of him for not above a minute; he was taken near the Queen's Head, in Bear-street, Clare-market; he had a sailor's jacket on, and a pair of trowsers, without a hat; the other two had light coloured clothes on. I do not, by his face, swear positively to him, but, by his dress, he is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he, or they, say any thing to you?</p>
               <p>Derand. No, not a word.</p>
               <p>Q. Had they any weapons?</p>
               <p>Derand. No, they had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find the hat upon the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Derand. No, he flung that away, as he ran, near an oil-shop.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176312070030"></xptr>Q. What did the prisoner say when taken?</p>
               <p>Derand. He said he did not take my hat, but he knew who did; that it was one of his companions ( this was before the justice): he said there were eight of them in company. (The hat produced, and deposed to).</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17631207-32-person316">
                  Francis 
                  Whitaker 
               <interp inst="t17631207-32-person316" type="surname" value="Whitaker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-32-person316" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17631207-32-person316" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was with Mr. Derand, coming home, in Lincoln's-Inn-Fields: by Mr. Willis's we met three or four persons, but the act was so instantaneous, I cannot tell what sort of men they were, or whether this man was one of them; as I was pursuing, one of them ran against me, I believe with an intent to prevent my running.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>Coming from Crutched Friars, I met two of my ship-mates, who brought me to a house by Temple-Bar; after which, we were walking up Lincoln's-Inn-Fields, we met the gentleman; one of them snap'd his hat off; the gentleman ran after me, and had me taken up. I said I was not the man: said they, if you are not the man, you know who did it. I told them I never saw the man above twice before.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17631207-32-verdict181" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17631207-32-verdict181" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
