<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611021-19">
               <interp inst="t17611021-19" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-19" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-19" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-19" type="date" value="17611021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611021-19-off95-c93" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-19-defend126 t17611021-19-off95 t17611021-19-verdict98"></join>
         
               <p>303. (L) 
               
                  <persName id="t17611021-19-defend126" type="defendantName">
                     Jane 
                     Trueman 
                  <interp inst="t17611021-19-defend126" type="surname" value="Trueman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-defend126" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-defend126" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17611021-19-deflabel94" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-19-defend126 t17611021-19-deflabel94"></join>, was indicted, together with 
               <persName id="t17611021-19-person127">
                  Edward 
                  Leister 
               <interp inst="t17611021-19-person127" type="surname" value="Leister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-person127" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-person127" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , not taken, for <rs id="t17611021-19-off95" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-off95" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-off95" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 40 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17611021-19-victim129" type="victimName">
                           George 
                           Ennis 
                        <interp inst="t17611021-19-victim129" type="surname" value="Ennis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611021-19-victim129" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17611021-19-victim129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-19-off95 t17611021-19-victim129"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately and secretly from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17611021-19-cd96" type="crimeDate">October 13</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-19-off95 t17611021-19-cd96"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-19-person130">
                  George 
                  Ennis 
               <interp inst="t17611021-19-person130" type="surname" value="Ennis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-person130" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday was se'ennight at night, between the hours of 10 and 11, I was coming down <placeName id="t17611021-19-crimeloc97">Grace-church-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17611021-19-crimeloc97" type="placeName" value="Grace-church-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17611021-19-crimeloc97" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-19-off95 t17611021-19-crimeloc97"></join>, and met with the prisoner, and another woman younger than she; they ran against me, and picked me up. I felt the prisoner's hand at my fob, put my hand down, and missed my watch, and charged her with it. A man came up in a sailor's habit, and said, What business have you with my wife? Then came another man, I hear his name is 
               <persName id="t17611021-19-person131">
                  Edward 
                  Leister 
               <interp inst="t17611021-19-person131" type="surname" value="Leister"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-person131" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-person131" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and have been told my watch is in his possession. I never saw it since. There was nobody else near me when I missed the watch.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the other woman?</p>
               <p>Ennis. I had hold of both her hands at the time.</p>
               <p>Q. When had you seen the watch last?</p>

               <p>Ennis. I know I had it not five minutes before.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in liquor?</p>
               <p>Ennis. No, I was not at all.</p>
               <p>Q How did you hear Leister had the watch?</p>
               <p>Ennis. A woman that calls herself sister to the prisoner came and told me so, but I cannot as yet take him.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a sailor?</p>
               <p>Ennis. No, he is a Spital-fields weaver.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever advertised the watch?</p>
               <p>Ennis. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. from Prisoner. Did you feel me take the watch out?</p>
               <p>Ennis. I felt her hand at the waistband of my breeches, and I clapped my hand down.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Then why did you not stop me?</p>
               <p>Ennis. I asked her what she was doing.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you swear the prisoner is the person that took the watch from you?</p>
               <p>Ennis. I think she took it; I think to the bes t of my knowledge I had hold of both the other's hands.</p>
               <p>Q How long were you together before you missed your watch?</p>
               <p>Ennis. I had not hardly a minute's conversation before I missed it.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts was this?</p>
               <p>Ennis. Just at the corner of the Half-moon tavern, Gracechurch-street.</p>
               <p>Q. What could you have conversation with them about?</p>
               <p>Ennis. I cannot say but it was a little of the bad sort.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-19-person132">
                  Jacob 
                  Marks 
               <interp inst="t17611021-19-person132" type="surname" value="Marks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-person132" type="given" value="Jacob"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-person132" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Tuesday was se'ennight the prisoner and another woman, and a Portugal sailor, were both brought to the watch-house together; the prosecutor charged them all three. I said, What, 
               <persName id="t17611021-19-person133">
                  Jane 
                  Trueman 
               <interp inst="t17611021-19-person133" type="surname" value="Trueman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-person133" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-person133" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . are you come here again? She was in Newgate last sessions, but she generally gets off. The prosecutor said she took his watch out of his pocket, and the other woman was concerned, and the young fellow came up, and collared him. I sent them all three to the Compter. The prosecutor swore, the next day, the prisoner took his watch. She offered to be searched, but I knew she had got them about her that would soon take the watch out of his way.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was going to buy a bit of meat, and met a young woman going to buy a duck at Leadenhall market, for her husband's supper: Lord bless me, Betty, said I, how do you do? I have not seen you a long time. As we were talking, this gentleman came up, and put his hand under her petticoats, and then took and knocked both our heads together. She said, Are not you ashamed to serve us so. I was willing to go to the watch-house to be searched. The gentleman offered my sister three guineas if she would make it up, that he might have his watch again. I had no foul near me, but a young body, and she was sent down to Bridewell-precinct, and I was sent here.</p>

               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611021-19-verdict98" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-19-verdict98" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
