<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17621208-27">
               <interp inst="t17621208-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-27" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17621208"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17621208-27" type="date" value="17621208"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17621208-27-off145-c247" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-27-defend295 t17621208-27-off145 t17621208-27-verdict148"></join>
         
               <p>29. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17621208-27-defend295" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Samuel 
                  <interp inst="t17621208-27-defend295" type="surname" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-defend295" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-defend295" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17621208-27-deflabel144" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-27-defend295 t17621208-27-deflabel144"></join>, was indicted, for <rs id="t17621208-27-off145" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-off145" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-off145" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               the wilful murder of her male bastard child, in the same manner as the former; and she stood likewise charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder
            </rs>. <rs id="t17621208-27-cd146" type="crimeDate">Nov. 15</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-27-off145 t17621208-27-cd146"></join>. +.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-27-person296">
                  John 
                  Hall 
               <interp inst="t17621208-27-person296" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-person296" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-person296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Jewin-street. The prisoner lived <rs id="t17621208-27-deflabel147" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17621208-27-defend295 t17621208-27-deflabel147"></join> with me pretty near 2 years and a half; she went for a single woman. On the 15th of Nov. as soon as I got up in the morning, my wife said these words to me, She has thrown the child into the vault; my man was by, I said, Go and see if you can get the child out; he goes with a pair of tongs and a candle, (this was about 8 o'clock) he said he had got hold of it and it slipped away, and he could not come at it. I went and acquainted the nightman with it; he sent his men, one of them put his head down very low, and said he saw it; he directed one of the men to dig some mould away, and take away a plank, there lay the child; I saw it taken out; I saw a wound at the corner of the child's mouth, quite down towards the jaw, it seemed to go quite through, about an inch long; the man put it into a tub of water, and washed it, then it was laid on a table: it was a male child.</p>
               <p>Rose Hall. The prisoner was my servant. On Monday morning, about 7 o'clock, the 15th of Nov. I came out of my room, I was surprized seeing a great deal of blood upon the stairs a 2 pair of stairs that led to the prisoner's room, I went into the room, and said, Molly, how do you do? (she was then in bed, she had been not well over night, she said she believed she had got the cholick) she answered, Very bad, I believe I shall die. I said, I believe you are very bad indeed, I having seen blood from her room down into the yard. I looked round the room, and under the bed, and saw nothing: I said I believe I must go and fetch somebody: I went and fetched Mrs. Bickeridge, a midwife, she told the prisoner there had been a child born of the prisoner answered, There was a lump of something came from her; the midwife asked her what she had done with it; she said, she had put it down the vault. I lighted a candle, and looked down, and saw a child; then we bid a servant man, the man she lays it to, to go and get it out with a pair of tongs; it slipped away; after that it was taken out, and washed, and laid on a table, and Mr. Goodman and Mr. White came, I believe the forepart of that same day, and saw it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine the woman, to know whether there had been a child born?</p>
               <p>Rose Hall. No; Dr. White did, he his here; the prisoner had been complaining she was very ill, we took a great deal of pity on her, she complained<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176212080027"></xptr> of a dropsy; I hired people to do her business for her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say any thing about a child being till after the child was found?</p>
               <p>Rose Hall. No, she did not: then she said it dead, and she knew nothing of it till it dropt down on the boards, as she was sitting by her bed side, and she perceived no life in it.</p>
               <p>Q. her cross examination, she said, the prisoner was a good servant, and behaved well; that she was a very clean body, and she did look upon her character as undeniable: that she took the prisoner's key, and looked in her box, and there found some things proper for a child. She produced a gown, caps, blankets, and several things. (Produced in Court.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-27-person297">
                  George 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17621208-27-person297" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-person297" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-person297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a man-midwife. I was sent for to Mr. Hall's on the 15th of Nov. about 11 o'clock, to attend on a suspicion of murder. I was surprized, and sent for my friend Mr. Goodman, to go along with me We both went into the room to the child; I took a cursory view of the child, then being desired to go up to the poor creature, I found she had been newly delivered of a child, and I was obliged to do the requisites to the same. After which we went down stairs and examined the child; we found a wound on the right side of the jaw, and the jaw-bone broke on the same side.</p>
               <p>Q. What sort of a wound was it?</p>
               <p>White. It was a laceration, a tearing by force on the right side of the mouth, beginning at the mouth and extending almost to the ear.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the child full grown?</p>
               <p>White. It was a perfect full grown child, at its full time, a male infant.</p>
               <p>Q. By the appearance of this wound can you account how it might come?</p>
               <p>White. The poor creature, I doubt not, was in a great deal of distress, when the child's head might be born, and to extricate herself in that misery, she might introduce her fingers into the child's mouth, she might make use of this means to pull the child from her, which might break the jaw and tear the part. This I mention from my own observation and experience. I believe the child was still-born.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your reason for that?</p>
               <p>White. From the difficulty of the birth, and the ceration of herself. It is plain to me, no person would give themselves pain, if they could help or ease it; every body will try to ease themselves; and as the navel-string was broke before, death trust ensue before the child could be delivered. The lungs may be filled with air, and the child not been alive. I was present when the child was opened, and an experiment made upon the lungs swam upon the surface.</p>
               <p>Q. Is not that a circumstance to prove the child was born alive?</p>
               <p>White. It may be in some cases. but we have proof to the contrary. I was sent for, last Thursday was sennight, on the like occasion; there was another of the faculty that agreed with me in it. The lungs being inflated, and swimming, is not always a proof of a child's being born alive; that I have had a proof of within these ten days.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-27-person298">
                  Thomas 
                  Goodman 
               <interp inst="t17621208-27-person298" type="surname" value="Goodman"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-person298" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with Mr. White. There was a laceration on the cheek, and the jaw broke, as he has mentioned. The lungs may be inflated, and the child be born dead. I saw the experiment made on the lungs, and they swam. I apprehend, the child's head was born first, and it might be obstructed in the passage of the vagina, probably the woman put her fingers to the child's mouth, and her thumb on the outward part, and in endeavouring to separate the child from her, the jaw might give way, and without great force, so slender a subject as an infant is, that laceration might happen.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it your opinion, the child was born dead or alive?</p>
               <p>Goodman. In consideration of the difficulty of the labour, I apprehend it was born dead.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-27-person299">
                  John 
                  Chatress 
               <interp inst="t17621208-27-person299" type="surname" value="Chatress"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-person299" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am son-in-law to Mr. Hall. I do not usually lie there, but I happened accidentally to be there that night. All I know of the affair is this, There was only a small partition that intervened between my room and the prisoner's. That whole night I was exceeding restless through a disorder settled in my thigh; I heard her groan several times very distinctly, as a person in great distress. I was awake when the servant-man arose, about 4 o'clock, he went into her apartment, and according as the circumstance appeared afterwards, she was delivered a little after that time, so that if the child had been born alive, and had cryed, I don't question but I should have heard it.</p>
               <p>On his cross examination he said, It was a very thin partition, through which he could hear a person whisper, if such had been in her room; that he heard nothing but her groanings.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>When my mistress came up to me, I told her where I had put the child; it was born dead; I had no intention to destroy it, had it been born alive, for I had provided for it.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Hall. What was her character?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hall. She bore a very good character while she lived with me.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176212080028"></xptr>Q. How was her behaviour towards children, as to cruelty or otherwise?</p>
               <p>Mrs. Hall. I never saw any cruelty by her in the least.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17621208-27-person300">
                  Ann 
                  Cook 
               <interp inst="t17621208-27-person300" type="surname" value="Cook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-person300" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-person300" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am very often at Mr. Hall's, I have three children, they have been with me there, the prisoner used to take a deal of notice of them.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17621208-27-verdict148" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17621208-27-verdict148" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
