<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660903-38">
               <interp inst="t17660903-38" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-38" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-38" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-38" type="date" value="17660903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660903-38-off202-c251" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-38-defend328 t17660903-38-off202 t17660903-38-verdict206"></join>
         
               <p>435. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660903-38-defend328" type="defendantName">
                     Edward 
                     Brophy 
                  <interp inst="t17660903-38-defend328" type="surname" value="Brophy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-defend328" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-defend328" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660903-38-off202" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-off202" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-off202" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape on the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660903-38-victim330" type="victimName">
                           Phillis 
                           Holmes 
                        <interp inst="t17660903-38-victim330" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660903-38-victim330" type="given" value="Phillis"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660903-38-victim330" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-38-off202 t17660903-38-victim330"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17660903-38-viclabel203" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-38-victim330 t17660903-38-viclabel203"></join>, an infant under ten years of age, <rs id="t17660903-38-cd204" type="crimeDate">June 23</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-38-off202 t17660903-38-cd204"></join>. *</p>
               <p>(The witnesses were examined apart at the desire of the prisoner.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-38-person331">
                  Sarah 
                  Arey 
               <interp inst="t17660903-38-person331" type="surname" value="Arey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person331" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person331" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Mr. Walker keeps the New Goose and Gridiron in St. Paul's Church-yard, the prisoner was <rs id="t17660903-38-deflabel205" type="occupation">head waiter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-38-defend328 t17660903-38-deflabel205"></join> there. I was going to clean the child 
               <persName id="t17660903-38-person332">
                  Phillis 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17660903-38-person332" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person332" type="given" value="Phillis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person332" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             one Sunday morning. I stripped her, and had some water ready to wash her: she was not willing to pull her shift off, her excuse was that it was cold. I said she had not been half washed all the week; I took and stripped her shift over her head, and saw it was in a deplorable condition; it stood alone with nastiness, green, blue, yellow, and all colours. I said, my dear, you have not got botches or biles about you. She said, no, nurse, I all nothing. Mr. Walker rang the bell, he was impatient to have the child down; I dressed her, and let her go down, and flung her cloaths carelessly into the closet. Mrs. Walker was ill in the room in bed, and insensible of any thing then; I was her nurse to attend her; I could not help looking at the shift: I said to Mrs. Walker, are you awake; she said, I am. I said, here is such a shift of Phillis's, that I never saw the like, and shewed it her. After that, Mrs. Walker's sister-in-law came, named Askew; I told her all about it; I told her, I nursed a gentlewoman in Wells's-Row that had the foul disease, and this appears like it. She said she would go and tell her brother; she went down directly; he sent the child up, and followed her; I laid her down on the bed and looked at her; I never saw such a sight in my life; her womb was open as wide as mine, who have had nine children. I then thought she had been abused by a man; there was a deal of nastiness like thick milk and cream, that ran quite down to her ancles. I shewed Mr. Walker her shift; (he is a very passionate man) he said, O you b - h, you are poxed! Hussey, who has meddled with you. Nobody indeed, said she: he said, I insist upon knowing. She said, nobody indeed,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030026"></xptr> again. I kept her above stairs; he came up again after dinner, she still stood it out that nobody had meddled with her; he asked her how she got it; she said she got it that day she bought some cherries, when he kicked her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he beat her then?</p>
               <p>S. Arey. No, he did not, I took her from him; she kept it to herself all day, and lived all that day upon nothing but bread and water; she had lived upon nothing but bread and water before for almost a month, only I gave her something some-times by stealth; she had done something that she should not have done; she had given a shilling away one day, and three shillings another day. On the next morning, which was on a Monday. Mr. Bull the apothecary came, he attended my mistress; Mr. Walker acquainted him with it; he came up stairs and said, Phillis, what is the matter with you; she said, nothing, Sir. Mr. Bull said, bring her down, is there no privater room than this. Then I carried her down into the club-room, and laid her down on her back on the bed, and took up her cloaths; he looked at her and said, O my God! she is poxed! who has meddled with you, child? Nobody, said she; he said, don't tell me so, for I know somebody has as well as if I was between you both; he could not persuade her to tell: he said to me. Nurse, do not you know surgeon Pott? I will speak to the beadle of the hospital, and he is a severe man, I will have her cut to pieces; (this was to affright her, to make her tell;) he went down, and clapped the door too as if he was angry; the child was still obstinate; then the child and I went up to dinner; then I said, tell me, for you hear what he says, you will be cut to pieces; then she said it was Ned, (I only knew the prisoner by that name Ned;) I said, do not say so, I do not believe you; she said, yes indeed it was; I said, you mean Jem; (that is one James, another waiter, that was then bad) she said, no, indeed, it was Ned; I said, where was it; she said, in the cellar; I said, how came you to go into the cellar; she said her uncle (meaning Mr. Walker) sent her into the cellar to draw a pint of beer for Mr. Griffiths, and Ned was there, stirring the beer with a stick, and he came and put his hands under her cloaths, and put his finger into her private parts, and took her up and carried into the other cellar, which goes a great way under ground, where she might have been killed, and we not heard; that he put what he had in her, and hurt her terribly, and he could not get it in the first time; and he put his hand upon her mouth, and told her, if she told any body she would be killed and hanged. I said, did he meddle with you any more; she said, yes, nurse, two times more; once she said she was going to carry her uncle's wig into the club-room, and he was putting up the press-bed; that he took her up and laid her on the bed, and stopped her mouth that she could not cry; then he hurted her terribly, and when it was in a good way then it was easier to her after; and told her the same again, that if she told any body, her uncle would kill her, and she would be hanged; and yet all the time he used to be more angry with the girl than any body else. I asked her when was the next time; she said, on the free masons day (there is a club of free masons at the house) she said her uncle sent her up, and the prisoner was cleaning the glasses; that he took her up and flung her on the bed, and did the same again, and she felt it very warm within her, but it did not hurt her so much then as it had done before; and then he told her as he had before. I asked her what she felt warm within her; she said she did not know; at last she told me it was his cock; I went down immediately and told them below; then Mr. Bull, Mr. Walker, and others came up; then I went down and heard no more. As he was coming down stairs to go before the magistrate, I said to the prisoner, O Ned! how could you do this affair; he said, O nurse! the devil was in me, and I was devoid of my senses.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you before the magistrate?</p>
               <p>S. Arey. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing?</p>
               <p>S. Arey. He talked a deal of nonsense, and said he should be glad to be heard. When I came down stairs from Mr. Bull and Mr. Walker, the prisoner said, nurse, what, is there any thing the matter with my mistress; I said, no, but something is the matter with Phillis, and you will hear presently; he looked as white as death.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mr. Walker use to kick the child?</p>
               <p>S. Arey. He used to kick her backside; he never kicked her over that part.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. What time did this girl tell you the manner that I did this action, was it the day that I was taken into custody, I mean the transaction in the cellar?</p>
               <p>S. Arey. This was directly after Mr. Bull went down from examining her on the Monday.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the child kept in her business for that month, you say she lived on bread and water?</p>
               <p>S. Arey. No, her uncle would not let her come near the bar; she used to be in the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Who kept the bar at that time?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030027"></xptr>S. Arey. It was kept by several, Betty and others.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the girl say in common that her uncle had kicked her?</p>
               <p>S. Arey. She always said her uncle had kicked her, till she said it was done by Ned.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-38-person333">
                  Edward 
                  Bull 
               <interp inst="t17660903-38-person333" type="surname" value="Bull"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person333" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person333" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I am an apothecary, and live at Islington; I attended Mrs. Walker; I called there on the 23d of June, and was asked to examine the child, there was something the matter with her that they could not find out; she had informed them it was a kick; the nurse let me see the shift; I said it was something worse, which I was very sorry to see; I said I should be very glad to examine her; I did, and said I apprehended it was the venereal disease, and a very bad one; I examined the part and the linen, and said, I was very sure it proceeded from no kick; I asked her how she came to be so, who had meddled with her; she would not tell; I then threatened her, and mentioned Mr. Pott at the hospital, and said she should go there, and called for ink and paper, pretending to write a note that she should go under his care, and be cut and slashed as he thought proper; she still insisted no body had meddled with her; but at last she said she would tell the truth, if I would be favourable to her; I said I would; she said, one of the waiters, mentioning a name, had been concerned with her: upon which, the prisoner was called up; when he came first into the room, he looked a good deal confounded. I said to Mr. Walker, I am afraid this man is guilty of what the girl accuses him with; he looked at me, and said he was not; I said, my friend, your countenance betrays you; what makes you look so white; his answer was, I really am not guilty.</p>
               <p>Q. What had the child told you, keep to the words as near as you can?</p>
               <p>Bull. She said the man had been concerned with her, mentioning the name Brophy; upon which I asked her where; she said in the cellar; she told me the day, but I do not recollect it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she mention the day of the month?</p>
               <p>Bull. No, she mentioned the day of the week; upon her acknowledging that, I asked her why she made use of no means in order to alarm any of the family; she said, she was prevented by the man putting his hand to her mouth. She acknowledged he had been concerned with her two times after the first time, up stairs, on the bed in the club-room. When the prisoner came up, I asked him if he knew any thing of that girl being injured; he denied it; this he did twice over, when I told him his countenance betrayed him; I said, you had better tell the truth, for it lies in my power to be a friend to you; he did not then acknowledge it; then I was advised to take him into another room, and examine if he was foul. I did, and plainly saw he was not a sound man, he had the venereal disease upon him. I then desired him to tell the truth, as it was in my power to be of service to him, and said I wou'd do all in my power. He told me he had had that disease upon him in the month of August was twelve months: I asked him if he ever applied for relief to any apothecary; he said he never did; he said he had a circumstance to tell me, that was, about nine days before he was concerned with the girl, there was a person that wanted to lie with a person that was at his master's house; (I believe a lodger) he wanted to have to do with her himself; he pulled her by the gown, and told her he believed the man was not a sound man; and upon that he himself was concerned with her, and a little after that he found a running; and about a week or nine days after, he owned he was concerned with the girl Phillis. I asked him how often he was concerned with the girl; he said he was concerned with her once; I said, have you been concerned with her no more; he said no, he had not; I said, the girl tells me you have been concerned with her three times. I asked the girl very particular questions, if she was hurt, and found any great pain the first time; she said she did; I asked her if she was hurt the second time; she said she was hurt a good deal, but not so bad as the first; and the last time no pain at all, or very little.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your opinion now, as to the disorder the child had?</p>
               <p>Bull. I am now of opinion, that the child's disorder was venereal, and not proceeding from a kick; it is my opinion she had been laid with by a man; I gave her some physic, just to keep the disorder from getting a head; she was sent to St. Bartholomew's hospital, under the care of Mr. Pott.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words you made use of before the prisoner confessed?</p>
               <p>Bull. I told him it was in my power to be of service to him, and I would do him all the service in my power.</p>

               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether I had the foul disease, or whether it was a gleet or running?</p>
               <p>Bull. I asked him how long he had had it; he said, since August was twelve months, and he never had applied to any person whatsoever to get redress.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether an apothecary may not be deceived, and not know a strain from the foul disease?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030028"></xptr>Bull. I think there can be no infection given to another person from a strain.</p>
               <p>Court. The question is of a different tendency: the question is, whether a strain would not occasion the same appearance at first sight as the venereal disease?</p>
               <p>Bull. I think not, this strain was quite of a different colour: the running that I found upon his linen had a quite different appearance to me than that of a strain, both upon his linen and the girl's.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did you not tell me it was the only means of saving my life to own it?</p>
               <p>Bull. No, I said it might be in my power to be of service to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. When did the girl tell you the thing?</p>
               <p>Bull. She told me it the very day you was taken before Mr. Alderman Peers.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-38-person334">
                  Phillis 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17660903-38-person334" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person334" type="given" value="Phillis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person334" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             (not upon oath.)</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. I do not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what an oath is?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. I live with Mr. Walker.</p>
               <p>Q. How did you come by that illness you had some time ago, when the nurse found you was out of order?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. The first time was, I went down into the cellar to draw a pint of twopenny for Mr. Griffiths; Ned, the man that stands there, followed me down; he put his hands up my cloaths, and carried me to the farthest part of the cellar, and stopped my mouth, and pulled out what he had, and put it into my private parts.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever do so again?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. The next time I went into the cellar for a quart of beer for two carpenters, and he did the same.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever do so after that?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. Yes, he did so in the club-room.</p>
               <p>Q. How often in the club-room?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. Only once.</p>
               <p>Q. Have not you told some people he did so twice in the club-room?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. Is all that you have said true?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. It is.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say to you afterwards?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. He said I should be hanged if ever I spoke of it; he bid me say it was by a kick.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you begin to be ill?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. That was the second time.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was that time after the first?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. That was about a fortnight after the first.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was you cured?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. I was sent to the hospital to be cured.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you sent to be cured of?</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. To be cured of the pox.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever any acquaintance in that way with any body else but Ned.</p>
               <p>P. Holmes. No, I never had with any body else.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-38-person335">
                  Anne 
                  Bullock 
               <interp inst="t17660903-38-person335" type="surname" value="Bullock"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person335" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person335" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The child 
               <persName id="t17660903-38-person336">
                  Phillis 
                  Holmes 
               <interp inst="t17660903-38-person336" type="surname" value="Holmes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person336" type="given" value="Phillis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person336" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is my child; she was ten years of age the 20th of July last. I bore her of my own body.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-38-person337">
                  Edward 
                  Harding 
               <interp inst="t17660903-38-person337" type="surname" value="Harding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person337" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person337" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the prisoner's examination before Mr. Alderman Crosby and Mr. Alderman Peers; the second examination before Mr. Alderman Crosby was very extraordinary: (this was in Mr. Walker's house) I desired Mr. Bull to search if the prisoner was foul; he said he was foul: then the prisoner confessed the fact, and kneeled down on his knees, and said to Mr. Walker, what service will my life be to you. Mr. Alderman Crosby asked him if he had been concerned with the child once, twice, or three times; he answered three times.</p>
               <p>Q. What kind of concern?</p>
               <p>Harding. I imagine by lying with her; he was examined about that fact; he was examined first by Mr. Alderman Peers, and twice after that by Mr. Alderman Crosby; he asked the child how her breath was stopped; she said, by the prisoner's finger.</p>
               <p>Samuel Hall. I was present when the prisoner acknowledged the fact in his master's room.</p>
               <p>Mr. Daniel. I heard the prisoner confess at the same time.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Bullock produced a copy of the register of the birth of the child, which she brought up out of the conntry, but as she could not read, could not say it was a true copy, any farther than hear say; she deposed she put down the day of its birth in her Common Prayer book, which was July 20, 1756.</p>
               <p>Mr. Walker. I left this woman in the year 1756, in the country, she was then about six months gone with child: since I have been in London, I have had it more in my power to do for the child; I sent for it up to keep it as my own, as I thought it my duty so to do. I was by when Mr. Alderman Crosby examined the prisoner; there was but little said the first time, by reason we had not got the age of the child: then I wrote into the country for a copy of the register. On the second examination<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030029"></xptr> the prisoner equivocated, and said he should be glad to hear his first examination; then he did not deny the thing, he confessed he had had in some measure to do with the child; but as I am the prosecutor, I did not think I should be examined as an evidence; I came by the knowledge of it, by the nurse bringing the shift down to me in the bar, and said, O Lord, Sir, Phillis is ruined! she has either been concerned with a man, or you have given her some blow, her shift is as bad as if she had had the foul disease seven years; I was convinced upon seeing it, she had had to do with a man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>How is it possible to commit such an act in a public cellar, where are three waiters, and many going backwards and forwards, and her father was so impatient when she was out of the bar?</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-38-person338">
                  Mary 
                  Freeborn 
               <interp inst="t17660903-38-person338" type="surname" value="Freeborn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person338" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person338" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lived with me between nine and ten months when I was a widow; I have two young daughters, I never saw no ill by him; he is a very honest young lad.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is it since he lived with you?</p>
               <p>M. Freeborn. It is near two years ago.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-38-person339">
                  Hugh 
                  Macmann 
               <interp inst="t17660903-38-person339" type="surname" value="Macmann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person339" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person339" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about nine years; I never heard any ill of him in my life, but what was industrious and good; he had the best of characters I ever heard a poor boy have in my life time; he minded both God and his church every where.</p>
               <p>Q. What church?</p>
               <p>Macmann. The church of England.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you, and where do you live?</p>
               <p>Macmann. I am a salesman; I live within four doors of Holbourn, going out of Broad St. Giles's.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-38-person340">
                  Paul 
                  Scandler 
               <interp inst="t17660903-38-person340" type="surname" value="Scandler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person340" type="given" value="Paul"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person340" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 12 years; he always had a good character in all shapes that ever I could hear.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-38-person341">
                  Martin 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17660903-38-person341" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person341" type="given" value="Martin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-person341" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about nine or ten years; I never heard any thing to his discredit in my life; I always imagined him to be a good christian and an honest man, he always minded his church.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660903-38-verdict206" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-verdict206" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660903-38-punish207" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-38-punish207" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-38-defend328 t17660903-38-punish207"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
