<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650116-40">
               <interp inst="t17650116-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650116-40" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650116-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650116"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650116-40" type="date" value="17650116"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650116-40-off257-c333" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-40-defend423 t17650116-40-off257 t17650116-40-verdict261"></join>
         
               <p>145. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650116-40-defend423" type="defendantName">
                     James 
                     Tonkin 
                  <interp inst="t17650116-40-defend423" type="surname" value="Tonkin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-defend423" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-defend423" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-defend423" type="age" value="almost sixteen years of age"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17650116-40-off257" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-off257" type="offenceCategory" value="damage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-off257" type="offenceSubcategory" value="arson"></interp>
               unlawfully and feloniously setting fire to the dwelling-house of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650116-40-victim425" type="victimName">
                           Thomas 
                           Fenner 
                        <interp inst="t17650116-40-victim425" type="surname" value="Fenner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650116-40-victim425" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650116-40-victim425" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-40-off257 t17650116-40-victim425"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17650116-40-cd258" type="crimeDate">December 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-40-off257 t17650116-40-cd258"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-40-person426">
                  Thomas 
                  Fenner 
               <interp inst="t17650116-40-person426" type="surname" value="Fenner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person426" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person426" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in <placeName id="t17650116-40-crimeloc259">Salisbury-court, Fleet-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650116-40-crimeloc259" type="placeName" value="Salisbury-court, Fleet-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650116-40-crimeloc259" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-40-off257 t17650116-40-crimeloc259"></join>. The prisoner has been <rs id="t17650116-40-deflabel260" type="occupation">apprentice</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650116-40-defend423 t17650116-40-deflabel260"></join> to me four years and a half, or thereabouts: I have had the misfortune to have my house set on fire four times. On the 14th of September last, 
               <persName id="t17650116-40-person427">
                  Esther 
                  Harald 
               <interp inst="t17650116-40-person427" type="surname" value="Harald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person427" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person427" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was sent up to shut the shutters, and draw the curtains, by my wife, in my hearing; we were then in the back parlour.</p>
               <p>Q. Who is 
               <persName id="t17650116-40-person428">
                  Esther 
                  Harald 
               <interp inst="t17650116-40-person428" type="surname" value="Harald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person428" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person428" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>Fenner. She was my servant. After she had been down about twenty minutes, a neighbour knocked very hard at my door, and said, the room backwards was on fire: I ran up as hard as I could, and when the door was open, I saw the furniture of the bed on fire; the maid ran up after me: I turned to her, and desired she would go and bring me some water, for the curtains were on fire. Soon after that, the prisoner came down, out of the garret: he was ordered to go for water, but no water came up; that I did not know the meaning of. I burnt my hands on the occasion very much.</p>
               <p>Q. What was burnt?</p>
               <p>Fenner. The furniture of the bed; the bed, and the waistcoat of the room was damaged by the flames, which is to be seen now.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the wainscot on fire?</p>

               <p>Fenner. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. What family had you in the house?</p>
               <p>Fenner. There was nobody but my wife and I, two lodgers up two pair of stairs, the prisoner and the maid, at this time: nobody was up stairs, but the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What are your lodgers names?</p>
               <p>Fenner. They are a widow-woman, named Bolt, and her daughter.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Fenner. The alarm was given between nine and ten at night. It was with some difficulty put out. On the 11th of December last, there was another alarm of fire, in the morning, about ten minutes after seven o'clock: I dressed myself, in order to go to Chelsea, in the room where the fire was after I was gone. I believe I was gone about four hours; the apprentice was at work when I went out: I left him and the maid in the house by themselves.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Fenner. I am a taylor.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you and your apprentice the prisoner, any difference?</p>
               <p>Fenner. We had, the night before, about a trifling affair; it was about a piece of work.</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you come home from Chelsea?</p>
               <p>Fenner. I came home between ten and eleven; then I found my house had been set on fire in two places: the wainscot and bed in the room where I lie, were burnt; this was my own bed: the first was a lodger's bed. My bed was on the ground floor, in a black room; all the furniture and bedcloaths were burnt almost to ashes, and the wainscot damaged very much. It may be seen now,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176501160035"></xptr> so that in one place you may push your thumb through it.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Counsel. You say on the 14th of September, you sent Esther up stairs to shut the window; was that up one pair of stairs, or two?</p>
               <p>Fenner. That is up one pair of stairs.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was your wife?</p>
               <p>Fenner. She was with me in the room.</p>
               <p>Q. How is your wife for understanding?</p>
               <p>Fenner. She is not right in her senses.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has she been out of her senses?</p>
               <p>Fenner. It may be three or four months.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she out of her senses at that time?</p>
               <p>Fenner. I believe she was.</p>
               <p>Q. How old is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Fenner. His mother says he is almost sixteen years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she in your company the time this alarm was given, on the 14th of September?</p>
               <p>Fenner. She was with me two hours before.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-40-person429">
                  Esther 
                  Harald 
               <interp inst="t17650116-40-person429" type="surname" value="Harald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person429" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person429" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was servant with Mr. Fenner, in Salisbury-court on the 14th of September last; there were two women lodged over the room where the fire was, and a gentleman lodged in the room where the fire was; his name is Pickard, but he was not at home at the time.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was at home at the time of the fire?</p>
               <p>Harald. There were my master, mistress, myself, and the prisoner. I then went up to Mr. Pickard's room, to shut the shutters, and draw the curtains, and turn the bed down; this was, I believe, a little after nine o'clock: the prisoner was with me, and held the candle. After I had done, I went down stairs, into the back parlour, to my master and mistress: then he told me he would take the candle, and go to bed with it, but instead of that, he went down into the cellar, to clean some shoes; and I take it to be about half an hour after, I heard him go by the parlour door, to go up stairs; it must be him, for there was nobody to go up but him, we being all in the back parlour. About five minutes after I heard him go up, I heard somebody knock at the door, and say the house was on fire, up one pair of stairs backwards: my master and I went up stairs together, and a little after I came down for water, I saw the prisoner come down behind me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see him in the room where the fire was?</p>
               <p>Harald. No, I did not. He came down from above the room where the fire was.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any candle with him?</p>
               <p>Harald. I did not see a candle. I went through a stone-yard, into the kitchen: there was a water in a tub.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner help you to carry water?</p>
               <p>Harald. I can't say he did. I thought he rather hindered me.</p>
               <p>Q. How hindered you?</p>
               <p>Harald. Through confusion: the spiggot was lost some how; I don't know how.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he carry up any water?</p>
               <p>Harald. I don't know that he did.</p>
               <p>Q. How many pails had you?</p>
               <p>Harald. There was but one of ours; but there were a great many of other people's, in a very little time.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thing on fire?</p>
               <p>Harald. When I was up stairs, I saw the curtains of the bed on fire.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Where were the gentlewomen that lived over the room where the fire was?</p>

               <p>Harald. They were both out.</p>
               <p>Q. After you had shut the window, and put the bed to rights, what became of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Harald. He and I came down stairs together.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was the prisoner you heard go up, after you was below?</p>
               <p>Harald. I am pretty sure it was, because nobody else could: there was nobody there besides him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner appear frighted?</p>
               <p>Harald. He did not appear much frighted.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-40-person430">
                  William 
                  Boddington 
               <interp inst="t17650116-40-person430" type="surname" value="Boddington"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person430" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person430" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a baker, and live in Salisbury-court. I was coming from the Lyon in the Wood, about half an hour after nine o'clock: I live about ten doors below where the fire was; as I was turning the corner, a person came and said, I have been knocking at the door, just at the corner of the square; there has been a fire: said I, there has been a fire there three times, within these three or four months; they must do it on purpose. I went in, and ran up stairs, and saw the bed curtains all in a flame, and the room in a smother.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Boddington. This was on the 14th of September: there were two lads went in with me. We got to tearing all the valence down, and I had my right hand much burnt: I took and threw the bed up, and brought down the posts of the bed together. We called for water, but there was no pail to be found: when we got the bed down, the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176501160036"></xptr> corner of the room was on fire. I went down, and found the spiggot out of the tub, and the water running about: I called out, for God's sake, where are the pails? there were none to be found: after that, the cork-cutter's boy came with one full of water: I ran up with that pail, thinking the engines were coming, and quenched the curtains; then more pails came, which we threw about the wainscot; the engine came and played in at the window, and got it down. After that, it seemed to smoke very much behind the wainscot, and we pulled out a pannel, and saw that all was safe: the cornice of the room and the bed were very much burnt.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not the prisoner come up into the room, to assist in putting it out?</p>
               <p>Boddington. No, he did not, as I know of. I saw him below, where the water-tub was, but no where else.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-40-person431">
                  Mary 
                  Crab 
               <interp inst="t17650116-40-person431" type="surname" value="Crab"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person431" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person431" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 11th of December, I lived with Mr. Fenner: that morning I came down, and lighted my fire in the back parlour. I turned the bed up, and by and by, there came a great smoke: I wondered what was the matter; my master was gone to Chelsea; I said, where can this smoak come from Jemmy I went to the entry, and there was such a smoke, I could not see the door. I went into the other room, and coming back again, I heard something crack: I went down into the kitchen, and under the stairs, was a fire on some chips, which we had to light the fire: the prisoner helped to put it out.</p>

               <p>Q. What time was this?</p>
               <p>Crab. This might be betwixt eight and nine o'clock: then we came both up into the back-parlour again. There three times he said to me, why don't you go down, and see if the fire is safe below: I went down, and felt all round, and found it all cold: I was below I believe three minutes: I came up again, and came into the parlour, and my master's bed that I had just turned up, was all on fire.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was the prisoner when you went down?</p>
               <p>Crab. He was standing just at the parlour door.</p>
               <p>Q. Could there be any connection with the fire on the chips, and the bed?</p>
               <p>Crab. No, there could not: it did not get hold of the posts. When I saw the bed on fire, I called out, Jem, Jem, Jem, come, the bed is all on fire; he came down, and we put it out: the curtains were burnt all to pieces; the bedding, blankets, pillows, and bolsters, were burnt; the bedstead was burnt, the bed was half burnt, and the flame had just catched the wainscot: there was one pannel damaged, just behind the middle of the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you lived in that house?</p>
               <p>Crab. I came in the room of the other servant, the evidence, when she was turned away.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your mistress at the home at the time of the fire?</p>
               <p>Crab. No, she was not. (The bolster produced in court, very much burnt).</p>
               <p>Q. Could you form any judgment, how it came?</p>
               <p>Crab. No, I could not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any dog, or cat, or animal in the room?</p>
               <p>Crab. No, I did not.</p>

               <p>Q. What became of the prisoner, after you had put the fire out?</p>
               <p>Crab. He went up stairs, and after that, Mr. Dutton came in.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you a cat in the house?</p>
               <p>Crab. We have a cat in the house, but I did not see her there, when the bed was on fire.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Who gets up first in the morning, the prisoner, or you?</p>
               <p>Crab. The prisoner is up before me.</p>

               <p>Q. What did you light the fire with that morning?</p>
               <p>Crab. I lighted it with some of the chips out of that hole where I saw some on fire.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you carry the candle in your hand, when you went for them?</p>
               <p>Crab. I did; but I set the candle on the outside of the hole: I always am fearful of fire.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-40-person432">
                  Robert 
                  Dutton 
               <interp inst="t17650116-40-person432" type="surname" value="Dutton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person432" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person432" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Fenner. On the 11th of December, I came to work in the morning, about a quarter before nine, and was let in by Mrs. Crab. I had not gone above half the length of the passage, before I saw a large quantity of dirty water and feathers, floating upon the floor. I said to her, pray what has been the matter? she said in a sorrowful manner, a fire had happened: I said, I hoped not a fire again? she said, yes indeed there has. I said, pray how did it happen? she declared she did not know; that she had been down stairs but a few minutes, and when she returned, she saw the bed all on fire. I went to the parlour door, to see what damage was done: the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176501160037"></xptr> prisoner opened the door: I said, do you know how this happened? he said, no. I asked him where his master was? he said, he was gone to Chelsea; that he went between six and seven. I said, had you any engines? he said no, Mrs. Crab and he put it out: but he was surprized how they did it, there being so much of it. I then directed my discourse to Mrs. Crab. I went up into the garret, and found one of the casements open, and wondered what could be the cause of it: I went down again, to assist in putting the things to rights: I found a quantity of chips among the things in the bed: I could not help observing the behaviour of the prisoner, who seemed to behave more by way of diversion rather than otherwise: I took these chips up; some were burnt to cinders, and some half burnt: I began to suspect something wrong. When we had taken up all the pieces of bed furniture, and cleared away the water out of the room, I began to observe the wainscot, and found one part of it exceedingly burnt, more than the rest; I believe it was three parts through; I think I could have pushed my thumb through it: the door was pretty much burnt: Mrs. Crab said the middle of the bedstead turned up against that part that was much burnt, I said it was very odd which way fire could come between the bedstead and the wainscot; I am afraid fire has been put there, on some bad design. The prisoner immediately answered in a very surly manner, No, the middle was not in that place. Observing him so surly, I said no more, but thought to take another opportunity to talk to him, when working by ourselves. Then the next day, I said there was a great deal of mischief done below, it is very odd to me a great deal of smoke did not come up stairs: said he, there was a great deal, and I was obliged to open the casement, to let it out. I said, it is very odd you did not go down stairs: no, said he, I did not; but soon after Mrs. Crab called me down. I said, I would have gone down to have seen what was the matter; for you knew very well, that chimney never used to smoke, and there was but one fire, from whence you must conclude the smoke must come; and you must open the window and stay till you are called: said he, what do you think I would sit here to be stifled with smoke, and not open the window to let it out? there is a person below, able to take care of the house, and I thought I had no business with it. The next day I said, was you down stairs, James, when the fire was, before you was called? he said, yes, I was. What did you go down for? I went down to desire Mrs. Crab to save me a bason of tea, for he knew his master would not be back soon. What, said I, was this silly old woman, Mrs. Crab doing, when you went down stairs? he said, blowing the fire. I said, in what position was the bed? he said, turned up, as usual. How long did you stay below? he said, about four or five minutes, and he left her blowing the fire. How long might it be before you was called down, after that? he said, about twenty minutes. Was there a great deal of smoke came up? yes, a great deal; and the first thing he did when he went down, he said, was, he pulled the bedstead from the wainscot, and got a knife, and cut some of the bed-cords. and pulled the bed on the floor; then he got a pail of water, and threw into the middle of the bed. I asked him some time after, which way he supposed this could happen? his reply was, you are to understand, Mrs. Crab is blind on one eye, and I imagine she had gone too near the bed with a candle, and set the curtain on fire. Then I pressed the matter pretty hard upon him: he at first denied it very strongly, and resented it very much. At last he began to be very silent: then I was so too. On the afternoon, on the Saturday, I began again, in the mildest and softest terms, relative to the heinousness of the crime, and the punishment I thought due to such a person that could be guilty of doing such a thing; and that his master had told me he would have him before a magistrate: he seemed very much concerned, and tears came. I told him there was but one way to escape the danger, and that was to confess the fact, and beg pardon for it; and if he could not speak to his master himself, I would solicit for him. I pressed him with such like arguments, but to no purpose, till about 8 or 9 o'clock: he said, you know we have a strange cat in the house; said I, I know it: said he, that morning, I chanced to go into the back parlour, and there was nobody there: I saw this strange cat sitting under the stove, and I frighted her away, or pulled her away, and she ran into the bed: there was a red hot poker in the fire; I took that, and threw into the bed after her, and that was the way that it happened; and he left the poker there. I asked him the reason for leaving it, and he said he forgot it, and that was the way it happened. But James, said I, this red hot poker could not set the house in such a flame, in such a time; because when you saw the cat run away, you would naturally take the poker out again: he said, no; I did not take it out again. I said, what, and did you leave it there? he said, yes, I did. I said, what could be your reason for that? he said, I don't know; I forgot it. Said I, I am<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176501160038"></xptr> afraid you have not told me the right of it: he said, yes, I have; and if you don't chuse to believe it, you may let it alone.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen a strange cat there?</p>
               <p>Dutton. I have; a sort of a tabby cat, a strange cat: she was a very familiar one.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you never heard him say this cat had stole his victuals?</p>
               <p>Dutton. No, I never have heard him say such thing.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner, as to his capacity?</p>
               <p>Dutton. He is a lad of a common capacity, considering he has had no education.</p>
               <p>Q. How old do you take him to be?</p>
               <p>Dutton. He is about 16 years of age.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never perceive he was a weak lad?</p>
               <p>Dutton. I never perceived any uncommon weakness in him.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Crab. Did you leave a poker in the fire that morning?</p>
               <p>Crab. If I did, I do not recollect it.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-40-person433">
                  John 
                  Veal 
               <interp inst="t17650116-40-person433" type="surname" value="Veal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person433" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person433" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about five or six years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he, as to understanding?</p>
               <p>Veal. He is a simple lad, but I believe very honest. He is rather weak than sharp.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-40-person434">
                  John 
                  Tompkins 
               <interp inst="t17650116-40-person434" type="surname" value="Tompkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person434" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person434" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him 16 years; ever since he was born.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was he born?</p>
               <p>Tompkins. He was born in Bristol.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has he been in London?</p>
               <p>Tompkins. He has been in London about twelve or fourteen years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Tompkins. Always just and honest.</p>
               <p>Q. How is he, as to capacity?</p>
               <p>Tompkins. He is rather an ignorant boy, not over sharp.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Veal. I have known him about three or four years.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his general character?</p>
               <p>Veal. He is a very honest lad, but very ignorant; not so sharp as some people are.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650116-40-person435">
                  John 
                  Morgan 
               <interp inst="t17650116-40-person435" type="surname" value="Morgan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person435" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-person435" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about four years; his mother lives in an apartment of mine. I have seen him come backwards and forwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you conversed with him?</p>
               <p>Morgan. I have: he always behaved very civil and sober; he has a very honest character.</p>
               <p>Q. How is he for understanding?</p>
               <p>Morgan. He is childish and simple. I have asked him several questions; sometimes he has given me no answer, but smiled, and turned away from me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650116-40-verdict261" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650116-40-verdict261" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
