<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640222-71">
               <interp inst="t17640222-71" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-71" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-71" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-71" type="date" value="17640222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640222-71-off383-c523" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-71-defend675 t17640222-71-off383 t17640222-71-verdict385"></join>
         
               <p>212. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17640222-71-defend675" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Robert 
                     Welch 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17640222-71-alias-11" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-71-defend675 t17640222-71-alias-11"></join>William Young</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-defend675" type="surname" value="Welch"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-defend675" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-defend675" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted, for <rs id="t17640222-71-off383" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-off383" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-off383" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, on the king's highway, on Esther, wife of 
                     <persName id="t17640222-71-person677">
                        James 
                        Green 
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-person677" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-71-person677" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640222-71-person677" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  , did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear and danger of her life, and violently taking from her person one silver watch, value 4 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17640222-71-victim679" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Jones 
                  <interp inst="t17640222-71-victim679" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-victim679" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-victim679" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17640222-71-cd384" type="crimeDate">February 8</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-71-off383 t17640222-71-cd384"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-71-victim680" type="victimName">
                  Esther 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17640222-71-victim680" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-victim680" type="given" value="Esther"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-victim680" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             . My husband's name is James. Katharine Adams came to me on the 8th of this instant, about 10 at night, (this was in the street) and said, Mr. Jones had given his watch to her to pawn for half-a-guinea till the morning. I said, I had not so much money about me; that if I saw the owner, I would get him half-a-guinea on it. She said, do you dispute that I did not come honestly by it? You may see the owner tomorrow. I said, Where is the watch? She put her hand into her bosom, and took it out. The prisoner came up, and gave me a blow under my right breast, (I did not fall) and snatched the watch out of my right hand; and, with an oath, said, if I made any words, he would stab me. We cry'd, Stop thief; he turned back, and said, he would run me through.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he strike you before, or after he took the watch?</p>
               <p>Green. That was after he had taken it. He made his escape.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any instrument in his hand?</p>
               <p>Green. He had a knife in his hand when he turned back.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you put in fear when he took the watch from you?</p>
               <p>Green. I was not frighted.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Green It was so light that I could take particular notice of him, and there was a lamp just by. He was pursued directly, and in better than half an hour he was taken; it was under an hour. The watch was found upon him. They sent for me. 
               <persName id="t17640222-71-person681">
                  John 
                  Molten 
               <interp inst="t17640222-71-person681" type="surname" value="Molten"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-person681" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-person681" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took him.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>Green. I take in washing. My husband is a whitesmith.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Katharine Adams?</p>
               <p>Green. She deals in Rosemary-lane, in buying and selling old cloaths.</p>
               <p>Katharine Adams. I never saw the prisoner but one night in my life; that was, I believe, about 10 o'clock. 
               <persName id="t17640222-71-person682">
                  Robert 
                  Jones 
               <interp inst="t17640222-71-person682" type="surname" value="Jones"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-person682" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-person682" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             trusted me to pawn his watch. I went to the pawnbrokers, there were none up. I came and brought it him again. He then asked me, if I would lend him half-a-guinea on it? Then Elizabeth Wall, who was in the house, said, Go up to Mrs. Green; if she has not the money, she will get it for you. I was going up to her, and met her as I was going. I asked her to go and pawn this watch for me for half-a-guinea. She asked me where the owner was; I said, at Mrs. Cook's.</p>
               <p>Q. What is Mrs. Cook?</p>
               <p>Adams. She deals in Rag-fair. Said Mrs. Green, let me see the man. Said I, you may go and pawn the watch, and come down and see him. Upon that, she and another woman were going a little way together; saying, she was going to a<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176402220050"></xptr> woman. Then I thought I would go and do it myself.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you the watch then?</p>
               <p>Adams. I had. I was going up Church-lane to a woman where she intended to pawn it. I met the prisoner, and a man that I knew; he ask'd me if I would go and drink a pint of beer.</p>
               <p>Q. And had you never seen the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Adams. No, I never did see him before.</p>
               <p>The Court ordered Esther Green, and all the other evidences out of court, in order to be separately examined.</p>
               <p>Q. What alehouse did you drink at?</p>
               <p>Adams. The King and Queen in Cable-street, almost opposite Church-lane.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did you stay in that house with the prisoner and other man?</p>
               <p>Adams. I did not stay with them above ten minutes; I left them, and was going up Church-lane, and Mrs. Green called to me, and said, Kitty; I did not answer the first time; Kitty, said she again. Now, said she, I will go and do it for you. I gave it her out of my bosom. The prisoner came up, and said, Let me look at that watch? She gave it him out of her hand into his to look at, and he made his escape with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he and you go out of the house together?</p>
               <p>Adams. He followed me out.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Mrs. Green see you and the prisoner, and the other man, go together to the alehouse?</p>
               <p>Adams. I cannot say whether she did or no.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he take the watch from her, or did she give it him?</p>
               <p>Adams. I will not swear; but to the best of my knowledge she gave it him out of her hand. She said, Why should I let you look at it? and to the best of my knowledge she gave it him.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you be sure she gave it him, or that he took it out of her hand?</p>
               <p>Adams. I cannot say, indeed.</p>
               <p>Q. How near to you was he, when you took it out of your bosom to give it to her?</p>
               <p>Adams. He was just by. - Why should I go to swear against a man?</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-71-person683">
                  John 
                  Molton 
               <interp inst="t17640222-71-person683" type="surname" value="Molton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-person683" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-person683" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a sea-faring man.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you follow no other employ?</p>
               <p>Molton. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you follow that of a thief-catcher?</p>
               <p>Molton. I sometimes follow taking these sort of people that rob folks. On the 18th of February I was at the horns and horseshoe, in Rosemary-lane.</p>
               <p>Is not that the house where your sort of people have a club?</p>
               <p>Molton. It is. Katharine Adams came and called me down stairs twice. She said, she had been defrauded, or robbed of a watch, which she had from a man to deliver to Esther Green, and the man met her in the street, and struck her, and robbed her of it. She described the man to me, and said he was there, and was going to kill some people. While I was there, 
               <persName id="t17640222-71-person684">
                  Henry 
                  Hethorn 
               <interp inst="t17640222-71-person684" type="surname" value="Hethorn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-person684" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-person684" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             said, he saw the prisoner take the watch out of his pocket, and throw it into a muscle basket. I took the prisoner at the corner of Mill-yard, Rosemary-lane. There was a cry of, Stop thief.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner running?</p>
               <p>Molton. He was standing there talking with some women; I struck him and brought him into the house. I took him at the door where the club is kept, the Horns and Horseshoe.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he readily submit?</p>
               <p>Molton. He seemed as if he would get away, but I would not let him.</p>
               <p>Q. Was Hethorn with you at the club?</p>
               <p>Molton. He was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-71-person685">
                  Henry 
                  Hethorn 
               <interp inst="t17640222-71-person685" type="surname" value="Hethorn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-person685" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-person685" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a sea-faring man, and follow rigging of ships.</p>
               <p>Q. Nothing else?</p>
               <p>Hethorn. No, nothing else.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you never engage in the business of thief-taking?</p>
               <p>Hethorn. No, never in my life. I was up at the club that night.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Molton?</p>
               <p>Hethorn. I have known him some years at sea. Katharine Adams came in and said, she had been robbed of a watch; and said, for God's sake, come, for she should be blamed for it. Molton ran down from the club, and took hold of the prisoner by Mill-yard, and struck him; and as he was hawling of him in doors, the prisoner took and threw the watch in a muscle basket.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640222-71-verdict385" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-71-verdict385" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
