<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680413-70">
               <interp inst="t17680413-70" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-70" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-70" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680413"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-70" type="date" value="17680413"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680413-70-off385-c478" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-70-defend621 t17680413-70-off385 t17680413-70-verdict388"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680413-70-off385-c479" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-70-defend623 t17680413-70-off385 t17680413-70-verdict388"></join>
         
               <p>331, 332. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680413-70-defend621" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17680413-70-defend621" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-defend621" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-defend621" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17680413-70-defend623" type="defendantName">
                     Anne 
                     King 
                  <interp inst="t17680413-70-defend623" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-defend623" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-defend623" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17680413-70-deflabel384" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-70-defend623 t17680413-70-deflabel384"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17680413-70-off385" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-off385" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-off385" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a chrystal stone stock-buckle set in silver, value 5 s. a pair of silver knee-buckles, value 3 s. a pair of silver shoe-buckles,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176804130038"></xptr> value 7 s. one guinea, and 5 s. in money numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17680413-70-victim625" type="victimName">
                     Thomas 
                     Pressey 
                  <interp inst="t17680413-70-victim625" type="surname" value="Pressey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-victim625" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-victim625" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-70-off385 t17680413-70-victim625"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17680413-70-cd386" type="crimeDate">April 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-70-off385 t17680413-70-cd386"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-70-person626">
                  Thomas 
                  Pressey 
               <interp inst="t17680413-70-person626" type="surname" value="Pressey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person626" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person626" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17680413-70-viclabel387" type="occupation">waiter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-70-victim625 t17680413-70-viclabel387"></join> out of place, I lodged at the Noah's Ark, by Well-close-square; on the first of April, in the evening, between nine and ten o'clock, I was going from the Noah's Ark, when in East Smithfield I met 
               <persName id="t17680413-70-person627">
                  Anne 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17680413-70-person627" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person627" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person627" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17680413-70-person628">
                  Margaret 
                  Bulge 
               <interp inst="t17680413-70-person628" type="surname" value="Bulge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person628" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person628" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; they got me to go into a public-house in Parrot-alley, there I treated them with liquor, and staid with them two hours; after they had had liquor, 
               <persName id="t17680413-70-person629">
                  Anne 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17680413-70-person629" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person629" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person629" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I went to bed together; this was on the ground floor; Bulge went out, I fell asleep; after which, in about two hours, there came a man and pulled me out of bed, and swore at me, and asked me what business I had there; I was frighted, I saw only a little bit of a fire, I saw a woman sitting by it; she begged she might not be used ill on the account of my being there; I missed my knee and shoe-buckles; I begged of the man to give me a bit of candle, that I might get my clothes, then I said I would be gone; he would not bring a candle, but brought a little bit of a match; I missed 26 s. in gold and silver; I had got a guinea and a half when I went in, and the girls got me to change the half guinea; we had 18 d. in liquor, King had I think a shilling, and Bulge two sixpences; when I got out at the door, I called for a watchman; the man and woman followed me out, so I was afraid to stay, she was a lustyish woman; she asked me what business I had to call the watch to her house, they bid me go about my business; I went away for fear of being ill used; I met a young woman, she asked me what was the matter, I told her I had lost my knee and shoe-buckles; I asked her to mark the house; she said young man do not be afraid, I have a clean bed, go and lie down on my bed; I went with her and undressed myself, and went into bed, and she lay down by me with her clothes on, and in the morning she and every morsel of my things were gone; I lay some time, and did not know what to do; at last I sent for the man at the Noah's Ark, and he brought me some clothes, and took me to his house; after that, I gave one James Salmon a guinea, which I was forced to borrow, to take all the parties up; I could not be sure of the man that pulled me off the bed, the man at the bar seems to be him by his voice; I never got my money or clothes again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-70-person630">
                  Margaret 
                  Bulge 
               <interp inst="t17680413-70-person630" type="surname" value="Bulge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person630" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person630" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . Last Friday night was a week, Anne King brought this man into the house of Mary Hall, in Parrots-alley, in East Smithfield; he sent for a shilling in brandy and water, and wanted change for a guinea; I went and got change for it; after that he had six pence in brandy and water; after that they both went to bed together; after they had been in bed some time, he wanted some beer, I got some; after that they both lay down to sleep; after that 
               <persName id="t17680413-70-person631">
                  Anne 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17680413-70-person631" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person631" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person631" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             got up, and said she was very ill; 
               <persName id="t17680413-70-person632">
                  Anne 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17680413-70-person632" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person632" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person632" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took the buckles out of his shoes, I was in the room all the time; then she went out and sent 
               <persName id="t17680413-70-person633">
                  John 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17680413-70-person633" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person633" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person633" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             in; he took the man's breeches, and took the knee-buckles out; then he made a wrangle, and said, the bed belonged to him, and desired to know what the man did there with his wife, and insisted upon his getting out of bed, and going out of the room; after that Smith walked out, and left his own buckles in the man's shoes; I saw no money at all; he never talked of losing any money before now; for my part, I never got the value of a snuff of a candle by it, only two six pences, which he gave me for fetching liquor.</p>
               <p>King's defence.</p>
               <p>This man spoke to me first of all, I did not chuse to go into a public-house, I chose to go home, he went with me; 
               <persName id="t17680413-70-person634">
                  Margaret 
                  Bulge 
               <interp inst="t17680413-70-person634" type="surname" value="Bulge"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person634" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-person634" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             unlocked the door for me, the lower floor belongs to us both; he sent for a shilling in rum and water, we cannot have less than a shilling's worth; I sent Bulge for it, after that we had another, and after that another; then we were going to have another, he wanted change; he said he did not chuse to send out a guinea; a servant brought the change and a shilling in rum and water, I told the change into his hand; after that Bulge made him pay for the rum and water again; he was very kind and good natured, he would send for another shilling's worth; when she brought that, she said he had not paid for that, though she carried the money, she made him pay for that again; then I asked for a little bit of supper; he sent out a 5 s. and 3 d. for supper, Bulge kept that and brought nothing; I said never mind it, she will come by and by; I locked the doors, and we went to bed, he gave me what he and I agreed for; I gave it Bulge to keep for me, he fell asleep, and I was in a sort of a dose; she came and opened the door, and awaked me, (a little matter awakes me) in came a lusty sort of brewer's servant with her; they sat down by the fire-side; said Bulge, here is an acquaintance wants you at the public-house; said I, if they want me, I have engaged myself to this young man to night; she said it was an acquaintance of her's wanted me, get up and speak to him; I said, I was afraid the young man would be angry; she said he is asleep, and will not miss<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176804130039"></xptr> you; I got up, and went to the public house, there was no body wanted me; when I came back the house was shut; I knocked at the door, she said I cannot let you in just now; she said I should not live with her any longer; I peeped through the key-hole, and saw the brewer's servant have the young man's shoes in his hand, and she had his breeches in her hand, they were talking together; the next morning I asked her for the 3 s. the man gave me for going to bed with him; she would not give it me; I said I saw through the key-hole what you did, and I will let people know of it; said she, you dirty hussey, and threatened me, and said, you watch me. I'll hang an hundred such as you for my breakfast in a morning; the night before that there was a man that had fifty guineas in his pocket, I would not go to bed with him; she said, go to bed, I will take care you shall not come to any damage.</p>
               <p>Smith's defence.</p>
               <p>I think it is very hard a common prostitute should take a man's life away, I had not been in London above a week.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17680413-70-verdict388" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-70-verdict388" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
