<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640502-63">
               <interp inst="t17640502-63" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-63" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-63" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640502"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640502-63" type="date" value="17640502"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640502-63-off368-c470" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-63-defend600 t17640502-63-off368 t17640502-63-verdict370"></join>
         
               <p>297. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640502-63-defend600" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Larey 
                  <interp inst="t17640502-63-defend600" type="surname" value="Larey"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-defend600" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-defend600" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17640502-63-off368" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-off368" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-off368" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the king's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640502-63-victim602" type="victimName">
                           David 
                           Ross 
                        <interp inst="t17640502-63-victim602" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640502-63-victim602" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640502-63-victim602" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-63-off368 t17640502-63-victim602"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking from his person one pair of silver shoe-buckles, value 10 s. a pair of leather shoes, value 2 s. one hat, covered with oil skin, value 2 s. one perriwig, value 5 s. and two guineas, the property of the said David
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640502-63-cd369" type="crimeDate">April 9</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-63-off368 t17640502-63-cd369"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-63-person603">
                  David 
                  Ross 
               <interp inst="t17640502-63-person603" type="surname" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-person603" type="given" value="David"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-person603" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going home from the custom-house, rather better than half an hour after 11 o'clock at night, on the 9th of April: there came four or five men; one of them had a clasp knife: he took hold of me by my two arms, while<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176405020037"></xptr> the others took off my shoes from my feet: I felt a hand in my pocket; they took out two guineas and some silver, and then my hat and wig; they then knocked me down with my own stick. I went to the watch-house in that condition, and alarmed the watchmen; there was the prisoner and two others taken that night: I had a great suspicion of the other two; but as the knife was held to my throat, and I durst not move my head, I cannot sware to their faces: I can swear the prisoner is the man that held the knife to my throat.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. This man came into the watch-house drunk, and said this man robbed him, then that man; and the next morning, he said the other two robbed him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-63-person604">
                  George 
                  Burasdale 
               <interp inst="t17640502-63-person604" type="surname" value="Burasdale"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-person604" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-person604" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was the officer of the night: the prisoner was brought into the watch-house, with two others, and I had charge given of them by the prosecutor.</p>
               <p>John Hall. I am a watchman. Mr. Ross's wife left the key with the beadle: he came to the watch-house bare-headed and footed, and said he had been robbed: the prisoner and two other men were taken coming out of an alehouse, with half a gallon of beer. Mr. Ross said the prisoner was the man that held the knife to his throat.</p>
               <p>Q. In what condition was the prosecutor for liquor?</p>
               <p>Hall. He was not drunk, but was in a flurry, and complained of the side of his face having been beat with a stick.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-63-person605">
                  John 
                  Spicer 
               <interp inst="t17640502-63-person605" type="surname" value="Spicer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-person605" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-person605" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard Mr. 
               <persName id="t17640502-63-person606">
                  Ross
               <interp inst="t17640502-63-person606" type="given" value="Ross"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-person606" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             that night, charge the prisoner with being one of the men that robbed him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>When they took me, I had the beer in my hand: they took me to the watch-house, and searched me: they found nothing but 3 d. upon me. He swore the next day he would hang me, if there was no other man living: his wife was as willing to swear as he, though she was not there.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-63-person607">
                  William 
                  Flin 
               <interp inst="t17640502-63-person607" type="surname" value="Flin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-person607" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-person607" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was in my company in my house: there were two men fell out: I was in my bed. I hearing a noise, got up to make peace between them: we went out, in order to call the watch: one of the men owed me a little money; then I thought it would be better to make it up, than call the watch. The prisoner eat his supper about 9 o'clock that night, in my house; he went out, and came in again about eleven: then directly we went out to call the watch; they told me it was about 10 minutes after eleven: we went for a gallon of beer, and I was taken up with the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640502-63-person608">
                  Christopher 
                  Henle 
               <interp inst="t17640502-63-person608" type="surname" value="Henle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-person608" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-person608" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             y. The prisoner has been a lodger in the house where I do: I never saw any harm of him in all my days. That night, he eat his supper, and went out, and came in again about eleven: a man came in, and made some disturbance; it began about one asking what it was a clock; the other called him Son of a B - h, and would not tell him: we went out to call the watch.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. Was it light or dark?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. It was moon-light, and there was a lamp by my side. I am positive to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640502-63-verdict370" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-verdict370" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640502-63-punish371" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640502-63-punish371" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640502-63-defend600 t17640502-63-punish371"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. </p>
            </div1>
