<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640222-25">
               <interp inst="t17640222-25" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-25" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-25" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640222"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640222-25" type="date" value="17640222"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640222-25-off135-c160" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-25-defend213 t17640222-25-off135 t17640222-25-verdict138"></join>
         
               <p>155. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640222-25-defend213" type="defendantName">
                     Benjamin 
                     March 
                  <interp inst="t17640222-25-defend213" type="surname" value="March"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-25-defend213" type="given" value="Benjamin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-25-defend213" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17640222-25-off135" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-25-off135" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-25-off135" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing four guineas
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17640222-25-victim215" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Carren 
                  <interp inst="t17640222-25-victim215" type="surname" value="Carren"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-25-victim215" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-25-victim215" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-25-off135 t17640222-25-victim215"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17640222-25-cd136" type="crimeDate">January 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-25-off135 t17640222-25-cd136"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640222-25-person216">
                  John 
                  Carren 
               <interp inst="t17640222-25-person216" type="surname" value="Carren"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-25-person216" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640222-25-person216" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17640222-25-viclabel137" type="occupation">peruke-maker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640222-25-victim215 t17640222-25-viclabel137"></join>: The prisoner worked journey-work with me. On the 28th of January I went out among my customers, and left him at work in the shop; when I returned he told me he was taken ill and must go home to bed; after he was gone I began to recollect I had left my key in my cupboard of drawers in the shop; I went to look at my money, and out of twelve guineas which were there in a purse, I miss'd four of them. I went to justice Manley and got a warrant, and took the prisoner up upon suspicion in his mother's room: The constable told him he must come along with us directly to justice Manley's; the prisoner said, Step down stairs, I will come to you presently; I said I would not trust him out of my sight; he then arose from his chair, and begged to speak with me; he and I went into an adjacent room, he shut the door, and said, pray, Sir, don't expose me; I said, Ben, You know very well you have robbed me this morning of four guineas, deliver it up, and no creature shall know of it; he then put his hand into his pocket and pulled out a handkerchief, and delivered it to me, saying, There; It is there: I untied it, and there found four guineas: He said necessity forced him to it: His landlady threatened to turn him out of doors, and take his bed from under him: I promised not to expose him: I went into the other room and said to the constable, There is nothing in it, you may go home. The constable said, no; I must execute my warrant, you must go before the justice: When we came there, the justice said, Is this the man? I said, Yes. The justice said, How long have you left your master? he answered, About an hour: I then interrupted, and said, He has confessed the money; the prisoner fell on his knees and begged of me and the justice to forgive him; I also begged of the justice to forgive him, but he said he could not.</p>
               <p>As his confession was drawn out of him with a promise of forgiveness, he was <rs id="t17640222-25-verdict138" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640222-25-verdict138" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
