<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650227-21">
               <interp inst="t17650227-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-21" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-21" type="date" value="17650227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650227-21-off113-c151" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-21-defend199 t17650227-21-off113 t17650227-21-verdict116"></join>
         
               <p>177. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650227-21-defend199" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Ogden 
                  <interp inst="t17650227-21-defend199" type="surname" value="Ogden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-defend199" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-defend199" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17650227-21-off113" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-off113" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-off113" type="offenceSubcategory" value="animalTheft"></interp>
               stealing six live hogs, value 6 l.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650227-21-victim201" type="victimName">
                     Francis 
                     Evans 
                  <interp inst="t17650227-21-victim201" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-victim201" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-victim201" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-21-off113 t17650227-21-victim201"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17650227-21-cd114" type="crimeDate">February 11</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-21-off113 t17650227-21-cd114"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-21-person202">
                  Francis 
                  Evans 
               <interp inst="t17650227-21-person202" type="surname" value="Evans"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-person202" type="given" value="Francis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-person202" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Barnsley: I am a farmer: I lost six hogs on the 11th of this instant February, from out of my father's yard at <placeName id="t17650227-21-crimeloc115">Drayton</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650227-21-crimeloc115" type="placeName" value="Drayton"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650227-21-crimeloc115" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-21-off113 t17650227-21-crimeloc115"></join>, about a mile from my house: I took my horse and went after them: I heard of them first at Smallbury-green turnpike; then at Kew-bridge; then I went to Mortlake, and heard of them there; after that I heard of them at Putney; I rode on to the farther end of Wandsworth, there I heard of them again: when I came to the Three Goat's-heads, at Battersea, a man came out of the house, and said the pigs were stopped there; there I saw them, and the prisoner: I charged the constable with him, and the next morning I took him before Justice Miller; the justice asked him why he stole the hogs; he said for distress of money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Evans. He comes out of Northamptonshire: he mowed at my father's last harvest, and has lived two years in our neighbourhood.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-21-person203">
                  John 
                  Legg 
               <interp inst="t17650227-21-person203" type="surname" value="Legg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-person203" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-person203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming from Putney Bowling-green, and overtook the prisoner, driving the six hogs, last Monday was fortnight: I first saw him just above Putney: I went down into the town, and staid some time, and overtook him again beyond the Three Goat's-heads: I asked him, where he was going with them? he said, to sell them; and that he brought them out of Berkshire: I said, it was a wonder he did not go to Smithfield with them; he said, he should be too late there, and he was going into the Borough with them. I asked the price of the best of them; he said 25 s. at last he would have sold it me for 18 s. then he said, he wished he could sell them all together: I said, what will be the price, to take them all together; he said 15 s. apiece: I said, I did not know but I could help him to a chap, if he would sell them worth the money, then he came to thirteen shillings apiece: then I went on to the Three Goat's-heads, and said to Mr. Johnson, here is a man coming along with a parcel of hogs; I am satisfied he has stole them, for they are worth as much more as he asks for them; so he let the man put them into his stable: I went on, and when I came to the Goat's-head again, the owner of the hogs came: when the prisoner saw him, he begged for mercy.</p>
               <p>William Hill. I live at Drayton: I saw the hogs on Sunday night, and they were missing on the Monday morning: I know them to be the property of the prosecutor.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-21-person204">
                  John 
                  Johnson 
               <interp inst="t17650227-21-person204" type="surname" value="Johnson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-person204" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-person204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a constable, and live at Nine Elms, in Battersea parish: the prisoner was at my house with the hogs; they were put into my yard: the prisoner was there three hours, or more, before Mr. Evans came; when he came, he owned the hogs: the prisoner told me he had bought them at Reading. when he first came in; but after Mr. Evans came in he held his head down, and did not care to say any thing.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was out of business, and had been at Windsor, to a brewer; I heard he wanted a man: coming back again over Hounslow-heath, I overtook a man, just before I ca me to Cranford-bridge, with these hogs: he ask'd me, where I was bound? I said to London: he said, I shall be too late; if you'll be so good as to drive these hogs to town for me, I'll give you a couple of shillings: he desired me to go over Kew-bridge, and so to Vaux-hall; and, if I could light of a chap, to sell them, as money would be of more service to him than the hogs. I drove them along; this farmer was coming, he went with me a mile or two: I partly bargained with him for thirteen shillings apiece. The man that I drove them for, told me his name was 
               <persName id="t17650227-21-person205">
                  John 
                  Wright 
               <interp inst="t17650227-21-person205" type="surname" value="Wright"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-person205" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and that he came from somewhere near Reading; he was to have met me near Vauxhall.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650227-21-verdict116" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-verdict116" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17650227-21-punish117" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-21-punish117" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-21-defend199 t17650227-21-punish117"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
