<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17611021-23">
               <interp inst="t17611021-23" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-23" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-23" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17611021"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17611021-23" type="date" value="17611021"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17611021-23-off116-c238" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-23-defend277 t17611021-23-off116 t17611021-23-verdict119"></join>
         
               <p>307. (M) 
               
                  <persName id="t17611021-23-defend277" type="defendantName">
                     Frances 
                     Whaley 
                  <interp inst="t17611021-23-defend277" type="surname" value="Whaley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-defend277" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-defend277" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for that <rs id="t17611021-23-off116" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-off116" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-off116" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               she being big with a certain male child, on the <rs id="t17611021-23-cd117" type="crimeDate">29th of September</rs>
                     <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-23-off116 t17611021-23-cd117"></join>, and the same day the said male child privately and secretly from her body did bring forth alive, the said male child by the laws of this realm being a bastard; and that the said Frances, not having the fear of God before her eyes; but being moved by the instigation of the devil, as soon as the said male child was brought forth, feloniously, wilfully, and of malice afore-thought, did strangle, whereof the said child instantly died
            </rs>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-23-person278">
                  Hannah 
                  Ambler 
               <interp inst="t17611021-23-person278" type="surname" value="Ambler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person278" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person278" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner lived <rs id="t17611021-23-deflabel118" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17611021-23-defend277 t17611021-23-deflabel118"></join> in the house where I lodge.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe her to grow big?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. No, I did not, 'till I found the child.</p>
               <p>Q. Give an account of what you know.</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. I only went to live there last quarter day. On the Friday before quarter day, I put some empty bottles, and lumber, into a closet. I had no occasion to go into that closet any more 'till the Tuesday following, then I went for a tub of coals; I could not find the coal-shovel; I opened the closet-door to see if it was there. I did not see it; but looking upon a shelf, I saw a band-box, which I knew was not mine. I pulled it to see what was in it, and found it heavy. I touched it with my finger, and imagined it was a dead child. I went down stairs, and told some people in the house, and they came up with me. We opened it, and found a dead child. Then I went down stairs, and told the landlord of the house.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. His name is Kent.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a boy or a girl?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. It was a boy.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who was the mother of the child?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. I do not know of my own knowledge that it was born of the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you acquainted with her before?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. No, I was not?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear her examined?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. I did before the justice; there she confessed that the child was born of her, in my hearing. This was the second time she was there. I was not there the first time she was carried there.</p>
               <p>Q. What justice was this before?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. Justice Welch in Long-acre.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the words she made use of?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. The justice asked her how she came to hide the child? She said, she did not know.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say the child was born alive, or dead?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. She said the child was born dead.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine the child?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. I looked at it, but never touched it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you observe any marks of violence upon it?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it seem to have gone it's time?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. It did.</p>
               <p>Q. Were any experiments made by the lungs in water?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. I saw none.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Whether when you was before the justice there were any linnen produced there?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210037"></xptr>H. Ambler. There were some child-bed linnen brought there; it was said it belonged to the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there provision for a young child?</p>
               <p>H. Ambler. There was.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-23-person279">
                  Samuel 
                  Clay 
               <interp inst="t17611021-23-person279" type="surname" value="Clay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person279" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 29th of September, I was informed by some of the neighbours there was a child found in the house of Mr. Kent, in Eagle-street, in the parish of St. George, the martyr. I went there, and was shewed a dead child in a hand-box in the back-kitchen. I asked who found it. They said one that was a lodger in the house. I asked where that lodger was. I was told she was not in the way. Then I asked where the maid was. They said she was gone out. I then asked Mr. Kent if he knew how the child came there.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know whether the child was born dead, or alive?</p>
               <p>Clay. I do not know that.</p>
               <p>Q. Had it gone its full time?</p>
               <p>Clay. I am not a judge of that; I took the prisoner in custody about four o'clock in the afternoon, being told it must be her child. I asked her if she knew any thing of that child. She said she did not, and any body might search her. I repeated it over again several times. She still denied knowing any thing of it; but after some people had talked to her, she owned her master that morning had given her 3 s. 6 d. to buy a coffin to bury the child.</p>

               <p>Q. Did she own the child to be hers?</p>
               <p>Clay. No, she still denied that; then I asked her again, in the passage, if she knew any thing of the child, and begged she would tell me, if she knew whose it was. She said she did not know whose it was, except it was one Jenny's, that lay up stairs with her master's nephew the night before. I took her before the justice; he examined her. She denied it being her child. She was ordered to be searched. She was searched, and there was milk found in her breasts in my presence. The justice charged her closely, and desired her to tell the truth, whether it was her child, or not, Then she said it was her child, and that she was delivered of that child, the Friday before, by herself, in the back-room in her master's house. Mr. Welch asked her if she had acquainted any bedy of her being with child. She said she had acquainted one Mrs. Franket with it, about two months before. Mrs. Franket was sent for, and Mr. Welch gave her her oath. She said she knew nothing of it. Mr. Welch then asked the prisoner how she came to say she knew it. Then the prisoner said that was false, for she never told her. Mr. Welch asked the prisoner if she had made any provision for the child. She said she had, and they were in her box in her master's house up stairs, and the key was in the drawer in the kitchen. Mr. Welch ordered me to go, and take the keys, and examine the box. I did, and could not find any key to the trunk; I found a trunk with drawers in it; it was locked; I could find no key, so I forced it. There was nothing at all in it of wearing-apparel of any consideration, but two little things; here they be. [Producing two small pieces of linnen, about two inches wide, and six long.] Then I went to Mr. Kent, her master, and desired him to let me look into all the drawers in the apartment. The boy brought me two drawers; I could find nothing in them, but some caps of her own. There were none found by me that day. I was going to attend the jury, but was sent for by Mr. Kent, to let me know he had found some things. I went there, and he delivered them to me. [Producing some child-bed linnen, such as caps, a shirt, and a waistcoat.]</p>

               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Clay. I am a constable.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was the coroner?</p>
               <p>Clay. Mr Grew was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there a jury?</p>
               <p>Clay. There was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the child opened before the jury?</p>
               <p>Clay. No, it was not; it lay in the room all the time the jury sat.</p>
               <p>Q. Was a surgeon sent for?</p>
               <p>Clay. No, there was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the jury make an inquisition?</p>
               <p>Clay. They did.</p>
               <p>Q. to Clerk of the Arraigns. Is there an inquisition returned here?</p>
               <p>Clerk of the Arraigns. No, there is not.</p>
               <p>Q. to Clay. Have you seen the coroner here to-day.</p>
               <p>Clay. No, I have not.</p>
               <p>Q. What is his name?</p>
               <p>Clay. It is 
               <persName id="t17611021-23-person280">
                  George 
                  Grew 
               <interp inst="t17611021-23-person280" type="surname" value="Grew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person280" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq;</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-23-person281">
                  George 
                  Grew 
               <interp inst="t17611021-23-person281" type="surname" value="Grew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person281" type="given" value="George"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , Esq; was three times called, as coroner for the county of Middlesex, to appear, and return all inquisitions found by him; he did not appear, and the court set a fine upon him of 50 l. for not appearing.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-23-person282">
                  Thomas 
                  Kent 
               <interp inst="t17611021-23-person282" type="surname" value="Kent"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person282" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person282" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was my servant; I am a bricklayer, and live in Eagle-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of the child, or how it came by its death?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176110210038"></xptr>Kent. No, I did not; I was not at home when the child was born, and did not hear of it till Tuesday after; it was found in a closet in my cellar next to my coal hole.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you heard the prisoner say any thing about it?</p>
               <p>Kent. The prisoner has said since, that the child was still born.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to give her 3 s. 6 d. to buy a coffin?</p>
               <p>Kent. That was false evidence; I gave her money when she went to market; but I gave her no money to buy a coffin.</p>
               <p>Q. to Clay. Was this evidence by, when the the prisoner said, he gave her 3 s. 6 d. to buy a coffin?</p>
               <p>Clay. He was, and made answer, it was but half a crown.</p>
               <p>Kent. I gave her half a crown to go and buy some meat for dinner, I did not mention a coffin; I had no notion of buying a coffin.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know she was with child before?</p>
               <p>Kent. I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-23-person283">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Franket 
               <interp inst="t17611021-23-person283" type="surname" value="Franket"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person283" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person283" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to me on Friday morning, and told me her master had a child dropt in the cellar. I went to see it, and a very fine child it was. I returned home again about my business; there was a great stir to know who was the mother of it. After that, the prisoner was taken at our house, and carried before justice Welch; there she did say, she had told me she was with child, but she never did tell me, neither did I ever think it before the child was found.</p>
               <p>Q. Had it gone its full time?</p>
               <p>E. Franket. I believe it had?</p>
               <p>Q. Was it born alive or dead?</p>
               <p>E. Franket. My judgment cannot know that.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any marks of violence upon it?</p>
               <p>E. Franket. No, there was not, it was a neat child, I never saw a finer in my life, so clear a one.</p>
               <p>Q. to Kent. Upon your oath, where did you find these child bed things, which you delivered to 
               <persName id="t17611021-23-person284">
                  Clay
               <interp inst="t17611021-23-person284" type="given" value="Clay"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person284" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the constable?</p>
               <p>Kent. I found them in my drawer, a drawer that I did not use; there were table-linnen, and this childbed-linnen I found among it, between the other linnen. The prisoner used to sit and work in the parlour, and she had an opportunity of putting the linnen there.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you believe the childbed-linnen belonged to her?</p>
               <p>Kent. I am sure it did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17611021-23-person285">
                  Jane 
                  Miner 
               <interp inst="t17611021-23-person285" type="surname" value="Miner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person285" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-person285" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Kent's house on Monday, and lay there on Monday night.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know who the child belonged to?</p>
               <p>J. Miner. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see it after it was found?</p>
               <p>J. Miner. Yes, I did; after the jury had set upon it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever hear the prisoner say any thing about the child?</p>
               <p>J. Miner. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you a single, or married woman?</p>
               <p>J. Miner. I am a single woman.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell whether the child was born dead or alive?</p>
               <p>J. Miner. No, I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. to Kent. How long had the prisoner lived with you?</p>
               <p>Kent. She had lived seven years with me.</p>
               <p>Q. How did she behave?</p>
               <p>Kent. As good a servant as ever lived at a house; towards the latter end, she took to drinking a little.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in her defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17611021-23-verdict119" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17611021-23-verdict119" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
