<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600910-5">
               <interp inst="t17600910-5" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-5" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-5" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600910"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600910-5" type="date" value="17600910"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600910-5-off23-c58" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-5-defend78 t17600910-5-off23 t17600910-5-verdict28"></join>
         
               <p>247. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600910-5-defend78" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Dennison 
                  <interp inst="t17600910-5-defend78" type="surname" value="Dennison"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-defend78" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-defend78" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17600910-5-off23" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-off23" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-off23" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing 2 linnen sheets, value 5 s. 2 blankets, value 10 s. one quilt, value 4 s. one linnen counterpane, value 1 s. one silk gown, value 30 s. one callico gown, value 15 s. 2 dimity petticoats, value 10 s. one silk cardinal, value 20 s. one silk bonnet, one waistcoat, 2 callico window curtains
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17600910-5-victim80" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Sibley 
                  <interp inst="t17600910-5-victim80" type="surname" value="Sibley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-victim80" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-victim80" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-5-off23 t17600910-5-victim80"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17600910-5-viclabel24" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-5-victim80 t17600910-5-viclabel24"></join>, <rs id="t17600910-5-cd25" type="crimeDate">July 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-5-off23 t17600910-5-cd25"></join>.*</p>
               <p>Mary Sibley. I live at <placeName id="t17600910-5-crimeloc26">Waltham cross , in the parish of Chesson</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600910-5-crimeloc26" type="placeName" value="Waltham cross , in the parish of Chesson"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600910-5-crimeloc26" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-5-off23 t17600910-5-crimeloc26"></join>; the prisoner lodg'd one night in my house.</p>
               <p>Q What house do you keep?</p>
               <p>M. Sibley. <rs id="t17600910-5-viclabel27" type="occupation">I keep a public house</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-5-victim80 t17600910-5-viclabel27"></join>; the next morning he was gone, and I miss'd 2 silk gowns, a callico gown, 2 dimity petticoats, a flower'd or stripe cardinal, a bonnet, a red and white stripe flannel waistcoat, a pair of sheets, a pair of blankets, a quilt, and a counterpane.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you lose them from?</p>
               <p>M. Sibley. From out of the room the prisoner lay in.</p>
               <p>Q. When did you miss them?</p>

               <p>M. Sibley. I miss'd them on the 12th of July in the morning.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you seen any of your goods since?</p>
               <p>M. Sibley. I saw them since at a public house at Newington; there they had secur'd the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. What did the prisoner say?</p>
               <p>M. Sibley. He said nothing, but hop'd I would be favourable to him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he own that he took the things?</p>
               <p>M. Sibley. He did not deny it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you charge him with taking them?</p>
               <p>M. Sibley. I did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-5-person81">
                  Elisha 
                  Webb 
               <interp inst="t17600910-5-person81" type="surname" value="Webb"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person81" type="given" value="Elisha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person81" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am an officer at Newington; 
               <persName id="t17600910-5-person82">
                  John 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17600910-5-person82" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person82" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person82" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             called me up, and said a person had been robb'd, and that they believed they had got the person that did the robbery in hold; I went with him; he gave me charge of the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Webb. This was rather before 6 in the morning on the last day of the last sessions at Hicks's hall; I do not know the day of the month; the things were in a cart when he was detected; the prisoner said they were his property; they also were delivered into my care; he was ask'd where he came from; he said, he lodg'd at Mrs. Sibley's. (The goods produc'd in court, and depos'd to by the prosecutrix.</p>
               <p>Prisoner. He says, I said they were mine; I did not know any thing of them, till they were found upon a country cart.</p>
               <p>Q. to Webb. Did you hear the prisoner say the goods were his?</p>
               <p>Webb. I did; he said several times they were his.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-5-person83">
                  John 
                  Glass 
               <interp inst="t17600910-5-person83" type="surname" value="Glass"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person83" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person83" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . A man came and told me, a Man had had some stakes at Waltham cross, and had gone away and robb'd his lodgings of things of great value, and described him; he had not been gone many minutes before a cart came up to the door, and the prisoner came from under the tilt of the cart, and went up in a corner to make water. I followed him into the house, he call'd for a pennyworth of beer; I said to the man of the house, according to the description just given, this is the man that has done this robbery; he said, perhaps he belongs to the cart; we ask'd the man that drove the cart, if he knew any thing of him; he said, he was to bring him to London for six pence; I said, have you got any bundle of his? he said he had; then we took him upon suspicion of this robbery; then I went to fetch a constable.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>Glass. This was at the White Hart, just on this side Newington, in Hornsey parish, we took the bundle from off the cart.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear him say any thing about the goods?</p>
               <p>Glass. I, going for the constable, did not hear what he said.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600910-5-person84">
                  Tho 
                  Boote 
               <interp inst="t17600910-5-person84" type="surname" value="Boote"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person84" type="given" value="Tho"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person84" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was by when the prisoner was seized, and I took care of him while Mr. Glass went for a constable. As soon as the bundle was brought into the house, and pitch'd down, the prisoner said it was his bundle. I ask'd him in particular if it was his; he said it was. After he was secur'd, he then own'd he had robb'd his lodgings. I ask'd him, if any others were concerned with him; he said there were two men, but he did not know their names.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he say where his lodgings were?</p>
               <p>Boote. He said they were at Waltham.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176009100005"></xptr>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was going a harvesting; I call'd in at the prosecutrix's house with a bit of beef stake, to have a sup of beer, and to dine; the woman dress'd my stake, and the people were playing at skettles, and two men were going to play at backsword; there was a corporal that drank with me till between twelve and one; I was so much in liquor I could not go up to bed; they got me to bed, and there was somebody with me, who it was I don't know; how these things were taken away I don't know; I did not know they were there, or that I had any hand in it, till I came before the justice.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600910-5-verdict28" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-verdict28" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600910-5-punish29" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-punish29" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600910-5-defend78 t17600910-5-punish29"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
               <p>This is the same person who was admitted an evidence by the name of 
               <persName id="t17600910-5-person85">
                  John 
                  Child 
               <interp inst="t17600910-5-person85" type="surname" value="Child"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person85" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person85" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , against 
               <persName id="t17600910-5-person86">
                  John 
                  Guest 
               <interp inst="t17600910-5-person86" type="surname" value="Guest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person86" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person86" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17600910-5-person87">
                  Peter 
                  Mason 
               <interp inst="t17600910-5-person87" type="surname" value="Mason"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person87" type="given" value="Peter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person87" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and 
               <persName id="t17600910-5-person88">
                  Thomas 
                  Henfield 
               <interp inst="t17600910-5-person88" type="surname" value="Henfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person88" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person88" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , for stealing lead from off of Stepney church. See No. 195, 196, 197, in Sir 
               <persName id="t17600910-5-person89">
                  Richard 
                  Glyn 
               <interp inst="t17600910-5-person89" type="surname" value="Glyn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person89" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600910-5-person89" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's mayoralty. He was since convicted at Stafford.</p>
            </div1>
