<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-21">
               <interp inst="t17661217-21" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-21" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-21" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-21" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-21-off104-c171" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-21-defend218 t17661217-21-off104 t17661217-21-verdict109"></join>
         
               <p>27. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-21-defend218" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Bradley 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-21-defend218" type="surname" value="Bradley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-defend218" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-defend218" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661217-21-off104" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-off104" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-off104" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a man's hat, value 3 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-21-victim220" type="victimName">
                     Robert 
                     Brown 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-21-victim220" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-victim220" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-victim220" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-21-off104 t17661217-21-victim220"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17661217-21-cd105" type="crimeDate">Nov. 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-21-off104 t17661217-21-cd105"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>At the desire of the prisoner the witnesses were examined apart.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-21-person221">
                  Robert 
                  Brown 
               <interp inst="t17661217-21-person221" type="surname" value="Brown"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-person221" type="given" value="Robert"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-person221" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17661217-21-viclabel106" type="occupation">carpenter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-21-victim220 t17661217-21-viclabel106"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17661217-21-crimeloc107">Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-21-crimeloc107" type="placeName" value="Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-21-crimeloc107" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-21-off104 t17661217-21-crimeloc107"></join>. On the 17th of November the prisoner and three others came past me, as I was at the bottom of Holbourn-hill, going home, about eleven at night; the prisoner took my hat from my head, and threw it to another man; I ran after the other man, the prisoner after me, and knocked me down; I got up again immediately; seeing my hat lying by the side of a house, I made to it; he came again a second time, and threw me down in the channel; there came three gentlemen and took him; the watch was charged with him; he said to the watchman, don't hold me, I'll go with you quietly; he let him go; he got from him and ran through Fleet-market, and up some high steps; they followed and took him there; then he was carried to Wood-street Compter; I never saw my hat since.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Was you drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Brown. I was neither; I had had a little liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did I demand any thing of you, or put you in bodily fear?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, you did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober or drunk the next morning before the Alderman?</p>
               <p>Brown. I was a little troubled about the affair, by being confined all night in the Compter.</p>
               <p>Q. How happened that?</p>
               <p>Prisoner. Because I charged him with an assault first of all.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether you did not say if I would give you 6 s. for the hat, you would not prosecute me?</p>
               <p>Brown. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-21-person222">
                  Samuel 
                  Hughes 
               <interp inst="t17661217-21-person222" type="surname" value="Hughes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-person222" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-person222" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of November I was turning down Fleet market from Holbourn-hill, I perceived Mr. Brown running down Holbourn-hill after one of these chimney-sweepers, (the prisoner is a chimney-sweeper) and the prisoner was running after Mr. Brown; he overtook him just opposite the Fleet-market, there he knocked Mr. Brown down; I went to see what was the matter;<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170015"></xptr> a chimney-sweeper took up a hat and ran up the hill.</p>
               <p>Q. Had that man a hat on his head at the same time?</p>
               <p>Hughes. He had a sort of hat on; I called to a watchman who turned him; then he ran down and through the Fleet-market; by that time Mr. Brown had recovered himself, then I told him where to find me, if I should be wanted to give evidence.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-21-person223">
                  John 
                  Cowell 
               <interp inst="t17661217-21-person223" type="surname" value="Cowell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-person223" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-person223" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 17th of November, about a quarter before twelve at night, I saw Brown knocked down by some person, I know not who; I went up; Mr. Hughes was there; he told me Mr. Brown had lost his hat; I saw a hat thrown to another person; Mr. Hughes shewed me the person that did it; I seized the prisoner; taking him along by St. Andrew's watch-house, he made his escape; I ran after him, he ran down Fleet-market; one of his accomplices I believe joined him at the top of Turnagain-lane; coming upon Snow-hill, there I took him; the other man was I believe five feet ten inches high; he was a chimney-sweeper; he went off as soon as the prisoner was taken; after that I learned by the people at the watch-house, he came several times and peeped in at the window.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I am a <rs id="t17661217-21-deflabel108" type="occupation">chimney-sweeper</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-21-defend218 t17661217-21-deflabel108"></join> by trade, and had that night been at work with a night cart; coming along I met the prosecutor running after three or four men in the highway, as if they were at football; he was challenging one and another with having his hat; he came to me and said, have you got my hat, and laid hold on my collar; I said, let me alone, I have not got it; he was going to strike me; I first charged the watch with him for striking me, and he after that charged me with this robbery; they took me towards the watch-house; I said, where is my antagonist; they said, never mind that, so long as we have you; I said, I will not go without him; I ran away down Fleet-market and up Turnagain-lane; they call'd, stop thief: a man came, I said I am the man they mean, I am your prisoner; there came my antagonist; we were both carried to the Compter, and the next day before Mr. Alderman Crosby; the Alderman asked him if he was drunk or sober; he owned he was in liquor. I am as innocent as the child unborn.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661217-21-verdict109" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-verdict109" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17661217-21-punish110" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-21-punish110" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-21-defend218 t17661217-21-punish110"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
