<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650227-28">
               <interp inst="t17650227-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-28" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650227"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650227-28" type="date" value="17650227"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650227-28-off164-c212" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-28-defend278 t17650227-28-off164 t17650227-28-verdict168"></join>
         
               <p>189. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17650227-28-defend278" type="defendantName">
                  John 
                  Hall 
               <interp inst="t17650227-28-defend278" type="surname" value="Hall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-defend278" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-defend278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-defend278" type="age" value="fourteen"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted for <rs id="t17650227-28-off164" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-off164" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-off164" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing nine guineas, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17650227-28-victim280" type="victimName">
                           John 
                           Tyner 
                        <interp inst="t17650227-28-victim280" type="surname" value="Tyner"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650227-28-victim280" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650227-28-victim280" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-28-off164 t17650227-28-victim280"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in the dwelling-house of the said John
            </rs>, <rs id="t17650227-28-cd165" type="crimeDate">February 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-28-off164 t17650227-28-cd165"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176502270024"></xptr>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-28-person281">
                  John 
                  Tyner 
               <interp inst="t17650227-28-person281" type="surname" value="Tyner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-person281" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-person281" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at <placeName id="t17650227-28-crimeloc166">the Red Lion, Grosvenor-meuse</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650227-28-crimeloc166" type="placeName" value="the Red Lion, Grosvenor-meuse"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650227-28-crimeloc166" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-28-off164 t17650227-28-crimeloc166"></join>, a public house: the prisoner was my <rs id="t17650227-28-deflabel167" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-28-defend278 t17650227-28-deflabel167"></join> a month, on the Sunday, and he left me the Tuesday after, being the 12th of February.</p>
               <p>Q. In what capacity was he?</p>
               <p>Tyner. He drawed beer for me: on the Tuesday morning, about a quarter after six, I was dressing myself in my own room; the boy at the bar was coming down stairs: we burning a rush-light, lighted a candle, and bid him light a fire in the p-room, and said I would be down presently: when I came down, the candle was standing on the table, and the tap-room door open and no fire, and the boy was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. How soon did you go down after him?</p>
               <p>Tyner. I believe I went down in about five minutes after him; I found the bar-door unlocked; my wife had put nine guineas in the drawer, over night, at about half an hour after eleven o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her put it in?</p>
               <p>Tyner. I did: on the next day, being Wednesday, I was riding after him for Essex, and heard of him in Whitechapel, and found him in the custody of a constable, who had taken him on suspicion.</p>
               <p>Q. How could that lad get at your money?</p>
               <p>Tyner. I had pulled my key out of my pocket, and gave it to my wife, to put the money into the till, and she left the key in the bar: we found it, with others, upon the prisoner: the boy told me he found it in the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any money found upon the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Tyner. There was a silver watch, and some money found upon him; he had no watch when he was with me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-28-person282">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Tyner 
               <interp inst="t17650227-28-person282" type="surname" value="Tyner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-person282" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-person282" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am wife to the prosecutor: the lad at the bar was our servant: I put nine guineas into a bladder, in the till in the bar, on Monday, the 12th of January, at night, and locked the door with the key that locks my husband's bureau: I was the last person up that night; the boy saw me put the guineas in that my husband gave me. When my husband went down, and miss'd the boy, he came up, and ask'd me where I put the money: I told him I had locked it up in the cupboard: he said, give me the key, that I may see; he went down, and found the door locked, but the money was gone.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650227-28-person283">
                  John 
                  Galatley 
               <interp inst="t17650227-28-person283" type="surname" value="Galatley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-person283" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-person283" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . ( Produced a parcel of keys) These I found upon the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Tyner. This is the key of the cupboard, (taking one of them in her hand.)</p>
               <p>Galatley. I am a headborough, at Mile-end; the first time I saw the prisoner, was on Tuesday morning, I believe the 13th of January, at the White Hart, at Mile-end; my brother officer had him, on suspicion of robbing somebody; and was going, before the justice with him: the boy told the justice, he had an uncle lived at such a place in Westminster, named 
               <persName id="t17650227-28-person284">
                  John 
                  Sebrook 
               <interp inst="t17650227-28-person284" type="surname" value="Sebrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-person284" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-person284" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; my brother officer desired I would go with the boy, and see if it was true: going along Cheapside, something hit against me in the prisoner's pocket: I felt in his pocket, and found this bunch of keys, here produced, and likewise this bladder, (producing it.)</p>

               <p>Prosecutor. This is the bladder I put my money in.</p>
               <p>Galatley. I could find no such person as he mentioned: the prisoner said he had bought a watch at the Cross Keys, a sale-shop in High Holbourn: I went there, to inquire the truth of that; I found he had bought it there: I asked the man what he gave for it; he said that was nothing at all to me, the boy had paid for it; he took it out of my hand and gave it to the boy, and desired him to keep it: I was afraid the boy might throw it away, and I begged of the man to ask the boy for it: when he found I was a peace officer he was sorry for what he had done; he got it again of the boy, and delivered it to me: it seemed to be a good watch.</p>
               <p>Mr. Segwick. I am a constable at Mile-end: on Tuesday the 12th of February instant -</p>
               <p>Q. Are you certain that was the day?</p>
               <p>Segwick. I am; that day the boy at the bar, and two men, came in at the White Hart, and called for six-pennyworth of warm brandy and water; when they had drank it, the boy pulled out this bladder, and laid down a 5 s. 3 d. piece, and desired change for it; they then ordered another six-pennyworth: one of the men said, landlady, bring us a glass, that we may all drink alike: I said, you don't use the boy well, to make him drink as you do; it will be time enough for that ten years hence: I asked that man if the boy was any relation of his: the man said he was the boy's uncle: I asked the boy if he was his uncle; the boy said no, and winked, as though he wanted to speak with me; I went out of the box I was sitting in, and took him into the next room; I asked him how he came by that money, and how much he had got: he said he had lived three years in service, in Essex, and that he had three pounds a year at each place: I asked him who found him cloaths all the time; he said his father: I asked him to let me look at the money, what he had left, there was 2 l. 17 s. 9 d. as he was putting the money in his pocket I saw a seal hang down; I asked him if he had a watch? he said,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176502270025"></xptr> Yes, He said, he had been changing watches with one of the two men: then we went into the room again, where the two men were sitting. I I asked the man, (not him that said he was the boy's uncle) if he had changed watches with the boy? he said, What was that to me; but when he found I was a peace officer, he said he had: I asked him if he gave the boy any thing in exchange? the boy said he had given the man two guineas and a crown. It was an old watch that belonged to the man. I desired him to return the money and take his watch; he refused it: then I said I should take him before a magistrate, and let him decide it. I then took them all three before Justice Darling: they had made the boy drunk: the boy then told me he had an uncle at Hyde-Park Corner, and after that he said he had not: the Justice ordered him to give the money to me, and the man to refund the two guineas and a crown. After they had been examined, the Justice desired me to go and see whether he had an uncle at Hyde-Park Corner, or whether he had bought that watch, as he had said. I begg'd the favour of his worship (the next day being execution day at Tyburn, and I was to attend) that he would let the headborough go with the boy: so Mr. Galatley went.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did take the money.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650227-28-verdict168" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-verdict168" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-verdict168" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Recommended to Mercy, being but fourteen years old.</p>
               <p>Note. The last evidence put it beyond all doubt, that the robbery was committed on Tuesday morning the 12th of February, as the prosecutor had before said; for the last execution was on Wednesday the 13th. His wife mistakes Monday night the 12th of January, instead of Monday night the 11th of February. 
               <persName id="t17650227-28-person285">
                  John 
                  Galatley 
               <interp inst="t17650227-28-person285" type="surname" value="Galatley"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-person285" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-person285" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , instead of the 13th of January, should have said, Tuesday the 12th of February. Mistakes of this sort happen very often on trials.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650227-28-punish169" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650227-28-punish169" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650227-28-defend278 t17650227-28-punish169"></join>
               
                     <note>[Death. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
