<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17601022-7">
               <interp inst="t17601022-7" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-7" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-7" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17601022"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17601022-7" type="date" value="17601022"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17601022-7-off43-c93" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-7-defend108 t17601022-7-off43 t17601022-7-verdict45"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17601022-7-off43-c94" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-7-defend110 t17601022-7-off43 t17601022-7-verdict47"></join>
         
               <p>296, 297. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17601022-7-defend108" type="defendantName">
                     Mary 
                     Fagan 
                  <interp inst="t17601022-7-defend108" type="surname" value="Fagan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-defend108" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-defend108" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , and 
               
                  <persName id="t17601022-7-defend110" type="defendantName">
                     Hannah 
                     Saunders 
                  <interp inst="t17601022-7-defend110" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-defend110" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-defend110" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17601022-7-deflabel42" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-7-defend108 t17601022-7-deflabel42"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-7-defend110 t17601022-7-deflabel42"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17601022-7-off43" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-off43" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-off43" type="offenceSubcategory" value="pocketpicking"></interp>
               stealing 16 guineas, 2 half guineas, and 12 s. and 6 d. in money, numbered, the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17601022-7-victim112" type="victimName">
                           James 
                           Shoosmith 
                        <interp inst="t17601022-7-victim112" type="surname" value="Shoosmith"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-7-victim112" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17601022-7-victim112" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-7-off43 t17601022-7-victim112"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , privately and secretly from his person
            </rs>, <rs id="t17601022-7-cd44" type="crimeDate">Sept. 24</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-7-off43 t17601022-7-cd44"></join>. *</p>
               <p>James Shoosmith. I met with the two prisoners at the Adam and Eve, hard by Pancras churchyard; Fagan was carrying a pot of beer out, to carry to two men that were cleaning a moat out; the two men ask'd me, if I wanted a jobb? I said, I did not care if I had a jobb.</p>
               <p>Q. When was this?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. This was on a wednesday, three weeks, or near a month ago; the two women at the bar were there; I went to help them, and was to have a shilling for half a day's work.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was to give you the shilling?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. The man at the Adam and Eve was to give it me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you help them?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. I did for three hours and a half; I had not had much victuals, and I found myself failing; I told the men I could not stand it, and I went out of the mud, and left my shoes in the mud, and could not get them out; I went and thought to go and buy myself a pair of shoes at St. Gyles's. I went down the fields about forty poles from the house, and lay down to rest me. Fagan followed me, and the other came just after her; they were soon both about me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you asleep?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Then how can you tell what was done?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. I felt Fagan's hand in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you speak to her?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Could you feel her hand in your pocket, and say nothing to her?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. Yes, Sir, I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Which pocket was it?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. It was my right-hand pocket, as I was laying down.</p>
               <p>Q. What was 
               <persName id="t17601022-7-person113">
                  Hannah 
                  Saunders 
               <interp inst="t17601022-7-person113" type="surname" value="Saunders"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-person113" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-person113" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             doing at that time?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. She stood about a pole off, when this money was taken from me; Fagan took it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she take any?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. No, she did not. I was not quite fast asleep, but I was doasing, then I awaked.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you any commerce with either of the women?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. No, I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lose?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. I lost in all, to tell the plain truth, upwards of 30 guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose money was it?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. It was my own money.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to have so much money about you?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. I had had it seven years in my pocket. I have been earning of it ever since I was a little boy; I can bring farmers to witness it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been asleep?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. I had slept I believe not quite two hours; when I got up, I felt in my pocket, and my money was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. How could you sleep quietly two hours, when you felt the woman's hand in your pocket?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. I did not sleep after I found her hand in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you then charge them with it?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. No; I got up, but could not tell which way they went, and I had no shoes to follow them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you drunk?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. No, I was not; I was taken not over and above well.</p>
               <p>Q. Where did you meet with the prisoners again?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. I found Fagan at the black horse in Dyer's street accidentally, as I was going by the door; then I charg'd her with taking my money.</p>
               <p>Q. And do you swear she took it from you?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. I do swear she did; they left two half crowns and a shilling in my pocket; she own'd to that going before the justice, just before we came to his house.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176010220011"></xptr>Q. What were her words, as near as you can recollect?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. Said she, I did not leave the rogue desolate, he had no occasion to swear against me; I left him two half crowns and a shilling in his pocket, and I had that left in my pocket.</p>
               <p>Q. Did either of them know that you had money about you?</p>
               <p>Shoothsmith. They both clean'd me when I came out of the mud, and by scraping my breeches my money stuck out; they might perceive it: I bid them keep away, and said, I had no business for them.</p>
               <p>Q. Was your money loose in your pocket, or in a purse?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. It was in two parcels, in a purse tied up, and in a bag, or linnen cloth.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you ever your money again?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. No, I never had.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you say against Saunders?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. I know she had part of my money.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you know that?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. We took 17 guineas from her after she was taken; 16 old ones, and 2 half guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was that?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. In the constable's house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find any thing upon Fagan?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. We found 12 s. and 6 d. upon her.</p>
               <p>Q. Did Saunders say which way she came by that money you found upon her?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. She said, she found it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after you lost your money was it, that this money was found on Saunders?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. It was found the next day.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find either of your bags again?</p>
               <p>Shoosmith. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Jos. Mackdaniel. I am a constable; I search'd the prisoner by order of justice Welch, and found 16 guineas, and two half guineas on Saunders; it was in a little bit of a cloth. (he produc'd the money in a cloth) I am not certain that this cloth is it.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. This is not my cloath.</p>
               <p>Q. Look at the money: can you tell whether any part of it is your's?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. There is nothing particular on any of them.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mackdaniel. How did Saunders say she came by the money?</p>
               <p>Mackdaniel. She said, she found it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17601022-7-person114">
                  Hugh 
                  Fagan 
               <interp inst="t17601022-7-person114" type="surname" value="Fagan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-person114" type="given" value="Hugh"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-person114" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             I took the two prisoners. I took Fagan at the Noah's-ark in Dyer's-street; the other I took at the Turk's-head in the same street. When Fagan was my prisoner, she said to me, a lousy country dog, he had no occasion to swear against her, for she left him two half crowns and a shilling in his pocket; in searching her, I found 12 s. and 6 d. in silver, and a few half-pence ( produc'd in court.)</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutor. What money did you find in your pocket after you had been robb'd?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. There was left two half crowns and a shilling.</p>
               <p>Fagan's Defence.</p>
               <p>My fellow prisoner and I went out a gathering of black-berries; going by the church we met two men in the moat; they as'd me, if I would give them any beer; I said, with all pleasure; one of the men said, I will be 3 d to your 3 d. I said, with all my heart; he said, do you go to the Adam and Eve and order it; I did. I happen'd to meet a woman, she ask'd me, what brought me there, and desired me to go to her home with her; I said, another woman was come along with me to go a black-berrying. This man (the prosecutor) was standing by the other men, he stripp'd stark naked to go to fight with the men in the mud. he had not a bit of shirt to his back; he said he was out of work; he was so much in liquor, they help'd him out of the moat; one said, I'll be 6 d. and the other I'll be 6 d. will not you be 6 d. they said to us, we willingly was 6 d. The prosecutor had a pennyworth of bread and cheese, and paid for two pots of beer; he said, he would fight any of them, and stripp'd in the publick house to fight them; I said to them, sie for shame, how could you make the poor creature so in liquor? they said, what is that to you; I said, he will be drown'd if he goes in the water; then he went into the water, they stood on each side and he in the middle; he fell down; I begg'd for God's sake that they would help him out When he got out, he begg'd of me to go and have a pint of beer with him; I said, I will not drink with you; he said, I have money; he put his hand in his pocket, there was a shilling and a half a crown. This woman by me went from me, and she found that money, where she found it I do not know.</p>
               <p>Saunders's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was in the field, this man wanted me to go<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176010220012"></xptr> and drink with him, I would not; he said, I should; we went and drank at the Adam and Eve; then he went to go to work, and fell down on his back in the mud and mire; we cry'd out shame; he call'd for help; the water was as high as his middle; the two men draw'd him out, and he lost both his shoes; I saw only half a crown and a shilling he had about him, upon my word; I found 12 guineas in the field.</p>
               <p>Fagan <rs id="t17601022-7-verdict45" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-verdict45" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               guilty
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17601022-7-punish46" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-punish46" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-7-defend108 t17601022-7-punish46"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Saunders <rs id="t17601022-7-verdict47" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-verdict47" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-verdict47" type="verdictSubcategory" value="lesserOffence"></interp>
               guilty of felony only
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17601022-7-punish48" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17601022-7-punish48" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17601022-7-defend110 t17601022-7-punish48"></join>
               
                     <note>[Transportation. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
