<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640113-33">
               <interp inst="t17640113-33" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-33" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-33" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640113"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640113-33" type="date" value="17640113"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640113-33-off173-c246" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-33-defend306 t17640113-33-off173 t17640113-33-verdict176"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176401130025"></xptr>102. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17640113-33-defend306" type="defendantName">
                     Richard 
                     Jewes 
                  <interp inst="t17640113-33-defend306" type="surname" value="Jewes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-defend306" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-defend306" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17640113-33-off173" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-off173" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-off173" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing a silver tankard, value 4 l. 10 s. the property of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640113-33-victim308" type="victimName">
                           Edward 
                           Lloyd 
                        <interp inst="t17640113-33-victim308" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-33-victim308" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640113-33-victim308" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-33-off173 t17640113-33-victim308"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , in his dwelling-house
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640113-33-cd174" type="crimeDate">January 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-33-off173 t17640113-33-cd174"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-33-person309">
                  Edward 
                  Lloyd 
               <interp inst="t17640113-33-person309" type="surname" value="Lloyd"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-person309" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-person309" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at the <placeName id="t17640113-33-crimeloc175">Green-Dragon, in Bishopsgate-street</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-33-crimeloc175" type="placeName" value="Green-Dragon, in Bishopsgate-street"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640113-33-crimeloc175" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-33-off173 t17640113-33-crimeloc175"></join>. The prisoner used to come to my house to drink; he behaved very well. I stood at the farther end of the house, on Wednesday the 5th instant, about 7 in the evening: the prisoner came into the tap-room, and stood against the fire. My servant and he had some words together; I saw the prisoner go towards the door, with a tankard by his side; it was without a lid. My servant followed him out at the door; in a little time he returned to me, and said, I have let the tankard go to Mr. Marshall's shop (Mr. Marshall is a barber); I said, it is very well; no more passed that night. The next morning, going there, and not finding my tankard, I then suspected it was lost. I made the best enquiry I could, about the prisoner and tankard; I found the prisoner at the Crooked Billet, in Kingsland-road, about four or five days following: I told him, there was something betwixt him and I, and desired to speak to him on one side; he said, he knew there was something. A man in company looked me in the face, and asked what I wanted with the man? I said, unless you behave yourself well, I shall take you along with him. I told the prisoner, if he would tell me where my tankard was, or if he had pawned it, I would pay the money, and take no farther notice of it, and it will be the better for you. He said, he had carried it into Hounsditch, and met a Jew, and the Jew gave him a guinea, and a bad shilling for it: he produced the shilling immediately: we removed him from that public-house to another, and talked to him in the same manner; he persisted in it he could say no more. I asked him, did the Jew ply you, or did you call to him? he said, he was drunk, and could not well tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever meet with your tankard again?</p>
               <p>Lloyd. No, I never heard any thing more of it; the prisoner was carried to New Prison, and afterwards he had a hearing before a magistrate, and he was committed to Newgate.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-33-person310">
                  John 
                  Barrett 
               <interp inst="t17640113-33-person310" type="surname" value="Barrett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-person310" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-person310" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am Mr. Lloyd's servant. The prisoner at the bar came into the house, and called for a tankard of beer: I drawed it in a silver tankard; he stood with his back to the fire, and bid me put it on the bar; I did, and went about my business directly. I came out of the cellar, and saw him take it from the bar, and go to the door; I followed him: he said, I am going to the barber's with the tankard; I stood at my master's door and saw him go in at the barber's shop, with the beer. In the morning, I went to the barber's for the tankard, and it was not there; they said, the young man came in with a tankard, almost full of beer, and he brought it back again, as the person was not there, which he said he brought it to drink with. I never saw him since he took the tankard from the bar, till to-day; he had used our house once or twice a day, for about two months.</p>
               <p>Q. from the Prisoner. Whether did you give me the tankard, or I took it from the bar?</p>
               <p>Barrett. The prisoner took it from the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body else see me take it from the bar?</p>
               <p>Barrett. Yes, 
               <persName id="t17640113-33-person311">
                  William 
                  Barrett 
               <interp inst="t17640113-33-person311" type="surname" value="Barrett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-person311" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-person311" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the coachman did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640113-33-person312">
                  William 
                  Barrett 
               <interp inst="t17640113-33-person312" type="surname" value="Barrett"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-person312" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-person312" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I heard the prisoner bid the evidence draw a tankard of beer, and saw him take the tankard from the bar, just as I came into the house, and go out at the door with it.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was born at Highgate: I work for Mr. Miles, a coachmaker, in cammomile-street.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640113-33-verdict176" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-verdict176" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640113-33-punish177" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640113-33-punish177" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640113-33-defend306 t17640113-33-punish177"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
