<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680413-69">
               <interp inst="t17680413-69" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-69" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-69" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680413"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-69" type="date" value="17680413"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680413-69-off378-c471" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-69-defend612 t17680413-69-off378 t17680413-69-verdict382"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680413-69-off378-c472" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-69-person613 t17680413-69-off378 t17680413-69-verdict382"></join>
         
               <p>330. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17680413-69-defend612" type="defendantName">
                  Margaret, <rs id="t17680413-69-alias-5" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-69-defend612 t17680413-69-alias-5"></join>wife</rs> of 
                     <persName id="t17680413-69-person613" type="defendantName">
                        John 
                        Watts 
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-person613" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680413-69-person613" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680413-69-person613" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-defend612" type="surname" value="Watts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-defend612" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-defend612" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17680413-69-off378" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-off378" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-off378" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing five women's silk sacks and petticoats, value 11 l. 10 s. two other women's silk sacks, with aprons of the same, value 4 l. one woman's bombasine sack and coat, value 30 s. and one woman's black amozeen sack and coat, value 4 l.
            </rs> the property of <rs id="t17680413-69-viclabel379" type="occupation">Dame</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-69-victim615 t17680413-69-viclabel379"></join> 
            
               
                  <persName id="t17680413-69-victim615" type="victimName">
                     Elizabeth Valicar 
                     Sambrook 
                  <interp inst="t17680413-69-victim615" type="surname" value="Sambrook"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-victim615" type="given" value="Elizabeth Valicar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-victim615" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-69-off378 t17680413-69-victim615"></join>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17680413-69-cd380" type="crimeDate">March 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-69-off378 t17680413-69-cd380"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-69-person616">
                  Mary 
                  Gifford 
               <interp inst="t17680413-69-person616" type="surname" value="Gifford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-person616" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-person616" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have lived with Lady Sambrook five years, the prisoner was my Lady's own <rs id="t17680413-69-deflabel381" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-69-defend612 t17680413-69-deflabel381"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-69-person613 t17680413-69-deflabel381"></join>, and has been her dressing-maid about three years; there was a little argument with my Lady and me -</p>
               <p>Q. How old is Lady Sambrook?</p>
               <p>M. Gifford. I believe she is eighty-seven years of age, her memory is much impaired; my Lady said she had no yellow gown; to convince her she had, I called to the prisoner to bring my Lady's sattin gown; she came to the door, and put her head in, and said there was no such thing, or my Lady had no such thing; at night my Lady and I had a few more arguments about it; going to bed,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176804130037"></xptr> I said to the prisoner, I never was more surprized than when you said my Lady had no such gown; her answer was, my Lady knows what she has done with it, she gave it me last August was twelve months; I said, I believe you mistake the time, Mrs. Watts, I wonder I never saw you wear it; she said my Lady did not give it her to wear, she gave it her for her children, and she sent it to them; the next day my Lady told me again she had no such gown; I then endeavoured in my mind to give over trying to convince her; she came into my chamber, and said, you will be obstinate, I am come to tell you you are mistaken; I could not bear it; I clapped hold of her hand, and said, my dear Lady, do not be deceived by that wretch, believe me she deceives you, I am your friend; she said what would you have me to do; I said, let me call her, and confront her before you; I called her; I then repeated to her the conversation she and I had had the night before; she acknowledged she had said to me my Lady had given her the gown; I asked her where was my Lady's brown damask gown; she said it was gone to the mantua-maker's to be let out; I asked my Lady if she had given orders for it to be sent there; my Lady said she had no such gown; I seized the prisoner by the shoulder, and said, art thou not a vile wretch, down on your knees this minute; I desired her to deliver up the keys, she gave me them; I bid her confess what she had done with the things, or I would charge a constable with her; she went on her knees, and confessed she had been very vile, but all my Lady's things should be returned; then my Lady bid her go out of the house, she went immediately away; on the Sunday after we opened the press where my Lady's clothes were, and missed fourteen gowns; then it was concluded to search for the prisoner, and take her up; she was taken, and brought to the house on Monday about noon; she brought papers, on which were set down every gown that I had missed; she confessed she had stolen them at different times out of my Lady's house, and said they were in pawn, and gave Mr. Spinnage the pawnbrokers duplicates, to go to the different pawnbrokers for them; there was one I was a little doubtful of; she told me, if I went to such a drawer in my Lady's house, there was the stomacher that belonged to it, which would convince me it was my Lady's gown; the stomacher was sent for to Mr. Spinnage's, then it appeared to be my Lady's; Mrs. Crawley, my Lady's daughter, asked the prisoner if what she was charged with was truth; she answered, all I had said was truth, and I gave the same account as now.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-69-person617">
                  Christopher 
                  Wallis 
               <interp inst="t17680413-69-person617" type="surname" value="Wallis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-person617" type="given" value="Christopher"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-person617" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to Mr. Fryer, a pawnbroker in Wych-street; I was present at the taking in of the prisoner at the bar, 1st, a gray tabby, 2d, a flowered silk, 3d, a striped lutestring; (the three sacks or gowns produced) she brought the two first on the 2d and 18th of January, and the other the 20th of March; I was with her before the Justice, she there said they were Lady Sambrook's property.</p>
               <p>M. Gifford. These are my Lady Sambrook's property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-69-person618">
                  Joseph 
                  Wassel 
               <interp inst="t17680413-69-person618" type="surname" value="Wassel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-person618" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-person618" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am servant to Mr. Brooks, a pawnbroker in the Strand; (be produced four sacks and coats) I was present at the taking these in; the prisoner brought the black silk and flowered silk the 28th of March, I lent her a guinea and half on each; there was a guinea lent upon one of the other, and three guineas on the other; I was before the magistrate when she was examined, she owned to the taking them out of Lady Sambrook's house without the Lady's leave.</p>
               <p>M. Gifford. These four are Lady Sambrook's property.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-69-person619">
                  Thomas 
                  Nash 
               <interp inst="t17680413-69-person619" type="surname" value="Nash"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-person619" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-person619" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live with Mr. Spires, a pawnbroker in Clare-market; (he produced two sacks) one of these was brought by the prisoner at the bar, and the other by Mrs. Thacker; the prisoner and she were at our house together several times; I lent two guineas and a half upon the blue tissue the 19th of December.</p>
               <p>M. Gifford. These are my Lady Sambrook's property.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Crawley. I am daughter to Lady Sambrook; I was at both the examinations of the prisoner at my Lady's, and also at Mr. Spinnage's; she owned they were Lady Sambrook's property; she told where they were pawned, and for what; the Major asked her if she did steal them; she said she did; he asked her if she took them out of the house privately; she said she did, privately, and without Lady Sambrook's consent; I wish I could say any thing for the prisoner, but it is out of my power.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in her defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680413-69-verdict382" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-verdict382" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>, <rs id="t17680413-69-punish383" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-punish383" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-69-punish383" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="respitedForPregnancy"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-69-defend612 t17680413-69-punish383"></join>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-69-person613 t17680413-69-punish383"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
