<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680114-3">
               <interp inst="t17680114-3" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-3" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-3" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680114"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680114-3" type="date" value="17680114"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680114-3-off25-c65" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-3-defend72 t17680114-3-off25 t17680114-3-verdict30"></join>
         
               <p>104. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680114-3-defend72" type="defendantName">
                     Luke 
                     Ranger 
                  <interp inst="t17680114-3-defend72" type="surname" value="Ranger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-defend72" type="given" value="Luke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-defend72" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17680114-3-off25" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-off25" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-off25" type="offenceSubcategory" value="theftFromPlace"></interp>
               stealing nine pair of men's silk hose, value 3 l. seventy-six pair of other silk hose, value 15 l. nine pieces of wove silk for breeches, value 5 l. the property of 
                     <persName id="t17680114-3-victim73" type="victimName">
                        Israel 
                        Eltington 
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-victim73" type="surname" value="Eltington"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-3-victim73" type="given" value="Israel"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680114-3-victim73" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-3-off25 t17680114-3-victim73"></join>
                     </persName>
                   , in the dwelling-house of the said Israel
            </rs>, <rs id="t17680114-3-cd26" type="crimeDate">Oct. 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-3-off25 t17680114-3-cd26"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>Israel Eltington. I am a <rs id="t17680114-3-viclabel27" type="occupation">hosier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-3-victim73 t17680114-3-viclabel27"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17680114-3-crimeloc28">Cheapside</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680114-3-crimeloc28" type="placeName" value="Cheapside"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680114-3-crimeloc28" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-3-off25 t17680114-3-crimeloc28"></join>; the prisoner was my <rs id="t17680114-3-deflabel29" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-3-defend72 t17680114-3-deflabel29"></join> for upwards of seven years, in the capacity of a porter; he has robbed me of sundry parcels of goods, more than I shall now mention; I had information of his extravagant life about the middle of October; having missed goods at sundry times I suspected him, but never could charge him. I took a search warrant the last day of last sessions, and went to his dwelling; I found nothing in his apartment, but I found nine pair of silk stockings in his landlady's apartment, where his wife lodged in Warwick-lane, all of my own manufactory; I know every workman's goods as well as I know my right hand.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say those goods were never sold out of your shop?</p>
               <p>Eltington. That I cannot say; I know they are such goods that I had missed, this led me to farther enquiry. I found his wife's brother, a seafaring man, had a considerable quantity of goods out with him; he was on board a ship bound for Jamaica; she was gone down the river. I sent one Collins down to Portmouth; he sent me up two parcels of goods which I can swear to; one of the papers they were in, had my writing on it. I received the invoice in 
               <persName id="t17680114-3-person74">
                  Luke 
                  Ranger 
               <interp inst="t17680114-3-person74" type="surname" value="Ranger"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-person74" type="given" value="Luke"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-person74" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            's hand-writing, to the amount of 64 l. consisting of stocking and breeches pieces, all of my own manufactory; the invoice was made to his brother-in-law; (the invoice produced in court;) at that time the ship lay at Mother-Bank (the invoice read in court) directed to Mr. 
               <persName id="t17680114-3-person75">
                  Ebenezer 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17680114-3-person75" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-person75" type="given" value="Ebenezer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-person75" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , on board the ship Lenton, 
               <persName id="t17680114-3-person76">
                  Isaac 
                  Corland 
               <interp inst="t17680114-3-person76" type="surname" value="Corland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-person76" type="given" value="Isaac"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-person76" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             commander, dated October 25th, 1767. I received these the 14th of November from Portsmouth; the prisoner was in Newgate at the time. Here is a letter which I received from him in Newgate, which agrees with the invoice, except in three or four pair of stockings short. I know the letter to be the prisoner's handwriting; (the letter read)</p>
               <p>"wherein he acknowledged</p>
               <p>"he had wronged the prosecutor; begs for</p>
               <p>"mercy, and says if the ship is not gone off, he</p>
               <p>"makes no doubt but the goods will be delivered</p>
               <p>"up to him again, and hopes his brother-in-law</p>
               <p>"will not be punished; and acknowledged himself</p>
               <p>"to be the only transgressor, signed Luke</p>
               <p>"Ranger." I received 27 l. after his commitment, for an adventure the prisoner sent out under the care of 
               <persName id="t17680114-3-person77">
                  Ebenezer 
                  Read 
               <interp inst="t17680114-3-person77" type="surname" value="Read"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-person77" type="given" value="Ebenezer"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-person77" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , to the Granades.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell the time they were taken out of your shop?</p>
               <p>Eltington. No, I cannot.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell what quantity were taken at one time?</p>
               <p>Eltington. No, I cannot; I know I have missed tot he value of 5 l. at a time; I missed two or three parcels very considerable.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680114-3-person78">
                  Judith 
                  Walters 
               <interp inst="t17680114-3-person78" type="surname" value="Walters"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-person78" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-person78" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Warwick-lane, the prisoner's wife and mother lodged at my house, the prisoner lived at his master's; he told me he dealt for himself; he brought a parcel of stockings to my apartment, in the beginning of last summer; he asked me if I could dispose of a few pair for him. I sold some, and what I sold I had a shop price for them; some at seven shillings, some at nine shillings, and some at half a guinea a pair; I paid 6 l. 17 s. 6 d. with my own hand, to a gentleman that was with Mr. Eltington, for he would<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176801140007"></xptr> not take it himself; he seemed much confused, to think the prisoner had robbed him.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the prisoner's wife lived at your house?</p>
               <p>J. Walters. About nine months; the man behaved very well when at my house.</p>
               <p>The prisoner said nothing in his defence.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680114-3-verdict30" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-verdict30" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-verdict30" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder40s"></interp>
               Guilty 39 s.
            </rs> 
                  <rs id="t17680114-3-punish31" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680114-3-punish31" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680114-3-defend72 t17680114-3-punish31"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
