<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660514-20">
               <interp inst="t17660514-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-20" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660514"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660514-20" type="date" value="17660514"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660514-20-off119-c160" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-20-defend203 t17660514-20-off119 t17660514-20-verdict123"></join>
         
               <p>304. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-20-defend203" type="defendantName">
                     Henry 
                     Shields 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-20-defend203" type="surname" value="Shields"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-defend203" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-defend203" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17660514-20-off119" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-off119" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-off119" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a wicker bread-basket, value 4 s. one half peck loaf of wheaten bread, value 1 s. and nine quartern loaves, value 4 s 6 d.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660514-20-victim205" type="victimName">
                     Alexander 
                     Lylle 
                  <interp inst="t17660514-20-victim205" type="surname" value="Lylle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-victim205" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-victim205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-20-off119 t17660514-20-victim205"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660514-20-cd120" type="crimeDate">April 17</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-20-off119 t17660514-20-cd120"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-20-person206">
                  William 
                  Mather 
               <interp inst="t17660514-20-person206" type="surname" value="Mather"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-person206" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17660514-20-person207">
                  Alexander 
                  Lylle 
               <interp inst="t17660514-20-person207" type="surname" value="Lylle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-person207" type="given" value="Alexander"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is my master, he lives in Hyde-street, Bloomsbury-market; he is a <rs id="t17660514-20-viclabel121" type="occupation">baker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-20-victim205 t17660514-20-viclabel121"></join>; I pitched my basket on the 17th of April, about ten o'clock, in <placeName id="t17660514-20-crimeloc122">High Holbourn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-20-crimeloc122" type="placeName" value="High Holbourn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660514-20-crimeloc122" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-20-off119 t17660514-20-crimeloc122"></join>, by the Coack and Horses, a public-house, and went up into Hatton garden with two loaves; when I came back, my basket was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. What had you left in it?</p>
               <p>Mather. I left one half peck loaf, and nine quartern loaves; I was obliged to go home for another basket of bread to serve my customers; after that I went to Rag-fair, thinking it the best place to find it; going along Cheapside, I met the prisoner with the basket, a little on the other side Bow-church; I was coming from Newgate-street way; this was betwixt five and six in the afternoon; the man that was carrying it, said he had it of the prisoner: there was a half peck loaf in it, but that was none of my master's; I got a constable, and took the prisoner and the other man to Wood-street Compter; the prisoner seemed to be in liquor when I took him.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-20-person208">
                  Charles 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17660514-20-person208" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-person208" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-person208" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a baker, and live in Blackman-street; my master sent me with a half peck loaf to Bishopsgate-street; I met with the prisoner on St. Margaret's-hill; I never saw him before; he was disguised in liquor, and had a parcel of people about him; he asked me to see after his basket; the people had hid it, and would not let him have it without a gallon of beer; this is the basket here (produced and deposed to by Mather as the property of his master) I got it for him, and being going over London-bridge, he being in liquor, I carried it for him, and put my loaf into it; he said he lived in Holbourn with one Mrs. Clark; I carried it to near Bow-church, Cheapside, then Mather came and took us both up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any loaves in the basket?</p>
               <p>Hall. No; there was none till I put mine in.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660514-20-person209">
                  Joseph 
                  Hazard 
               <interp inst="t17660514-20-person209" type="surname" value="Hazard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-person209" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-person209" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was going up Holbourn-hill; I saw Mather go down Hatton-garden with two loaves; I turn'd and saw the prisoner on the other side the way watching him; I went to serve the Bell in Holbourn, and saw the prisoner come and take the basket from the pitching-place, and run up Fetter-lane with it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Hazard. I have known him three quarters of a year; I had once taken him before the Justice.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I never took the basket; I happened to go along the Borough; I met a young fellow out of place; I asked him where he was going, and which way he came by the basket; he asked me to drink a pint of beer; there were four loaves in the basket; we had three or four pots of beer at the Green Dragon; he asked me to go and fetch the basket, and when I came it was gone; I being in liquor, the people made game of me; and while I went to a public-house, the basket was hid, and this young man spoke to the people and got the basket again; I had not the basket on my shoulder.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660514-20-verdict123" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-verdict123" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17660514-20-punish124" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660514-20-punish124" type="punishmentCategory" value="transport"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660514-20-defend203 t17660514-20-punish124"></join>
               T
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
