<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17610916-20">
               <interp inst="t17610916-20" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-20" type="year" value="1761"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-20" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17610916"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17610916-20" type="date" value="17610916"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17610916-20-off103-c148" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-20-defend178 t17610916-20-off103 t17610916-20-verdict106"></join>
         
               <p>239. (M) 
               <persName id="t17610916-20-defend178" type="defendantName">
                  Mary, <rs id="t17610916-20-deflabel102" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-20-defend178 t17610916-20-deflabel102"></join> of James Tickner<interp inst="t17610916-20-defend178" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-defend178" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17610916-20-off103" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-off103" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-off103" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing two linen shifts, value 3 s. two childrens shirts, value 2 s. five white linnen aprons, value 5 s. four linnen handkerchiefs, two linnen caps, thirteen linnen clouts, and two silver tea-spoons
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17610916-20-victim180" type="victimName">
                     Mary 
                     Dunning 
                  <interp inst="t17610916-20-victim180" type="surname" value="Dunning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-victim180" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-victim180" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-20-off103 t17610916-20-victim180"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17610916-20-cd104" type="crimeDate">September 2</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-20-off103 t17610916-20-cd104"></join>..~</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-20-person181">
                  Mary 
                  Dunning 
               <interp inst="t17610916-20-person181" type="surname" value="Dunning"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-person181" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-person181" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 2d. of this month I went out and left my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>M. Dunning. I live at <placeName id="t17610916-20-crimeloc105">Twickenham</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-20-crimeloc105" type="placeName" value="Twickenham"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17610916-20-crimeloc105" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-20-off103 t17610916-20-crimeloc105"></join>, when I returned I found my house broke open, and missed the things mentioned in the indictment. [ Mentioning them by name.]</p>
               <p>Q. What time did you go out?</p>
               <p>M. Dunning. I went out abot ten in the forenoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know the prisoner at the bar before?</p>
               <p>M. Dunning. She was a neighbour, I know nothing of her taking them.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17610916-20-person182">
                  Mary 
                  Deschampes 
               <interp inst="t17610916-20-person182" type="surname" value="Deschampes"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-person182" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-person182" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was enquiring about the prosecutrix's things, a neighbour said she believed she could tell me who took the things. She took me a back-way to the prisoner's apartment. I said to her, Have you seen any body go a back-way to Mrs. Dunning's, she has lost a good many things? She said, She was very sorry to hear it, she had not seen any body go that way. I looked into a room belonging to the prisoner, there I saw such cloaths hanging.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body else live in that house besides the prisoner?</p>
               <p>M. Deschampes. No, there was nobody else, and I saw the things, like the other things that are missing, taken out of the prisoner's drawers, by the woman that went with me; this was the room where the prisoner's bed is.</p>
               <p>Q. Where is that woman that took them out?</p>
               <p>M. Deschampes. She is not here; the prisoner wanted her to take them home to the prosecutrix; I saw the spoons lying in particular, and one apron.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176109160020"></xptr>Q. Where are the things?</p>
               <p>M. Deschampes. None of them are here.</p>
               <p>Q. What became of them?</p>
               <p>M. Deschampes. We went away, and left them; and after that they were throwed over into Mrs. Dunning's yard in the evening.</p>
               <p>Q to Prosecutrix. Where did you miss them from?</p>

               <p>Prosecutrix. I missed them from out of my house; I found them again in my yard.</p>
               <p>Q. What part of the yard were they found in?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. They were lying loose; the prisoner's house join to my yard.</p>
               <p>Q. Are any other peoples house's joining your yard, besides the prisoner's?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. Yes there are.</p>
               <p>Q. Whose premisses were the things lying nearest to?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. They were rather nearer the prisoner's, than any other.</p>
               <p>Q. Did they lie so that it was possible they might be thrown over from any other person's yard?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. It is possible they might.</p>
               <p>Q. to Deschampes. Are you able to say that the cloaths you saw were the prosecutrix's property?</p>
               <p>M Deschampes. No, I am not, nor the spoons neither.</p>
               <p>Q. How many spoons did you see?</p>
               <p>M. Deschampes. I saw two.</p>
               <p>Q. to Prosecutrix. How many spoons were thrown over into your yard?</p>
               <p>Prosecutrix. There were two.</p>
               <p>M. Deschampes. I believe the things did belong to Mrs. Dunning.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your reason for believing it?</p>
               <p>M. Deschampes. The prisoner herself owned she throwed the things over the pales before the justice, in my hearing.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say how she came by them?</p>
               <p>M. Deschampes. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>Q. What things did she say she threw over?</p>
               <p>M. Deschampes. The things that I saw in her room.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I did not throw them over, nor did I own it before the justice; my husband threw them over a soon as he came home, as I lay on the bed; I have been very often at Mrs. Dunning's before this.</p>
               <p>Mrs Dunning. So she has, and I never missed any thing to my knowledge before that, that I could lay to her charge.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-20-verdict106" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-verdict106" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-verdict106" type="verdictSubcategory" value="theftunder1s"></interp>
               Guilty 10 d.
            </rs>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17610916-20-punish107" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-punish107" type="punishmentCategory" value="corporal"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17610916-20-punish107" type="punishmentSubcategory" value="whipping"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17610916-20-defend178 t17610916-20-punish107"></join>
               
                     <note>[Whipping. See summary.]</note>
               
                  </rs>
               </p>
            </div1>
