<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17670715-16">
               <interp inst="t17670715-16" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-16" type="year" value="1767"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-16" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17670715"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17670715-16" type="date" value="17670715"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17670715-16-off91-c110" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-16-defend142 t17670715-16-off91 t17670715-16-verdict93"></join>
         
               <p>351. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17670715-16-defend142" type="defendantName">
                     Eleanor 
                     Carrol 
                  <interp inst="t17670715-16-defend142" type="surname" value="Carrol"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-defend142" type="given" value="Eleanor"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-defend142" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17670715-16-deflabel90" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-16-defend142 t17670715-16-deflabel90"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17670715-16-off91" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-off91" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-off91" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a cloth coat, value 20 s. a cloth waistcoat, value 10 s. and a linen handkerchief, value 1 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17670715-16-victim144" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Mills 
                  <interp inst="t17670715-16-victim144" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-victim144" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-victim144" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-16-off91 t17670715-16-victim144"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17670715-16-cd92" type="crimeDate">June 1</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17670715-16-off91 t17670715-16-cd92"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-16-person145">
                  William 
                  Mills 
               <interp inst="t17670715-16-person145" type="surname" value="Mills"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person145" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person145" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Crown-court, Fleet-street; I never saw the prisoner till I saw her before Sir 
               <persName id="t17670715-16-person146">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670715-16-person146" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person146" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person146" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; I lost a brown cloth coat and waistcoat with metal buttons, on the 1st of June, there was a red and white handkerchief in the pocket. On the Thursday evening I sent to borrow the Gazetteer of the day before, in which paper I saw the coat and handkerchief advertised, stopped, supposed to be stolen, to go to see it at Justice Fielding's; I went on the Friday morning; I was desired to go to the beadle of St. Clement's parish, in whose hands the clothes were; I went; Mr. 
               <persName id="t17670715-16-person147">
                  Bond
               <interp inst="t17670715-16-person147" type="given" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person147" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the beadle, told me there were a pair of gloves in the pocket; I described them, being doe-skin, and the fingers cut part off on the left-hand glove; he shewed them me, they were my property; I went to the Justice the next day, being<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176707150010"></xptr> Saturday; he examined her; she said she bought the things of a woman in Holbourn.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-16-person148">
                  William 
                  Wooler 
               <interp inst="t17670715-16-person148" type="surname" value="Wooler"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person148" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person148" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Monday the 1st of June, about eight in the evening, this woman at the bar was detained in my house; I live in St. Clement Danes, and am a perriwig maker; she was taken in my lodger's room; she had these clothes and a hat, and other things with her; I asked her how she came by these clothes; she said she never saw them till she saw them in my house; we had a suspicion she wanted to pilser something, she being a stranger; I got a constable, and took her before Sir 
               <persName id="t17670715-16-person149">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670715-16-person149" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person149" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person149" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ; the clothes were put into the custody of the beadle; she said she bought them in Holbourn; she would have left the clothes with me, if I would have let her go.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Did I not ask for Dr. Carrol?</p>
               <p>Wooler. I know no such Doctor; she did say she wanted a Doctor of that name, and said, she was recommended to him at my house.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-16-person150">
                  William 
                  Barker 
               <interp inst="t17670715-16-person150" type="surname" value="Barker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person150" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person150" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner came to my master's shop about four o'clock the 1st of June; she looked earnestly in at the window; after which, my master's kinswoman rapped hard under where I sat; I went into the passage, and going up stairs, I met the prisoner coming down; I saw these clothes in her apron; I took them out, she had other things; I asked her how she came by them; she said she bought them in Westminster; I took the coat and waistcoat to be my master's kinsman's property, being much the colour: I said, if she came again the next day at such a time, if they were her property, she should have them again; she very willingly gave them to me, and went away: it was thought she might have been in a room backwards; then I went and found her, and brought her back, and asked her where she got the clothes; she said, from St. James's street, by St. James's-gate; after that, she said she bought them in Pall-mall; she was very much in liquor; I detained her; then my master came in; he asked her several times where she got them; she varied every time; she said she got them in the Strand; then she said a woman gave them to her in Arundel-street.</p>

               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-16-person151">
                  James 
                  Bond 
               <interp inst="t17670715-16-person151" type="surname" value="Bond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person151" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person151" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the officer; the clothes were delivered into my custody, and they were advertised, by which means the prosecutor found them.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I bought the clothes that afternoon.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-16-person152">
                  Judith 
                  Layton 
               <interp inst="t17670715-16-person152" type="surname" value="Layton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person152" type="given" value="Judith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person152" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I held the prisoner's child while she paid some money for some clothes, which woman seemed to be an old clothes woman; it was that day in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know her before?</p>
               <p>J. Layton. No, I did not, I never saw her before.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to know of coming here?</p>
               <p>J. Layton. She sent for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go before Sir 
               <persName id="t17670715-16-person153">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17670715-16-person153" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person153" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            ?</p>
               <p>J. Layton. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you tell this story there?</p>
               <p>J. Layton. I never told it to Sir John, nor no body else; I was too late.</p>
               <p>Q. Whereabouts in Holbourn did she pay the money you mentioned?</p>
               <p>J. Layton. It was just a little on this side the One Tun.</p>
               <p>Q. What is your business?</p>
               <p>J. Layton. I work at washing and scouring.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-16-person154">
                  Margaret 
                  Doyle 
               <interp inst="t17670715-16-person154" type="surname" value="Doyle"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person154" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner was a lodger of mine twelve months; I have lent her half a guinea and a guinea at a time, to buy old clothes; she never wronged me of a farthing; I have known her two years.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever heard her mention such a name as Dr. Carrol?</p>
               <p>M. Doyle. I have.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17670715-16-person155">
                  Mary 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17670715-16-person155" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person155" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-person155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . She lived with me six months in Poppin's-court, Fleet-street.</p>
               <p>Q. Is the prisoner a single or a married woman?</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. She is a married woman; her husband is a paviour.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Do you know whether she has a husband?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. She said she was not married when she was taken up.</p>
               <p>M. Kelly. I do not know whether she has a husband or not, I know she buys rags and old clothes; I am in the same way myself.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17670715-16-verdict93" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17670715-16-verdict93" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
