<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660903-71">
               <interp inst="t17660903-71" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-71" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-71" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660903"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660903-71" type="date" value="17660903"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660903-71-off383-c509" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-71-defend655 t17660903-71-off383 t17660903-71-verdict386"></join>
         
               <p>470. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17660903-71-defend655" type="defendantName">
                  
                     Thomas 
                     Jacocks 
                  , otherwise <rs id="t17660903-71-alias-7" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-71-defend655 t17660903-71-alias-7"></join>Gecox</rs>, otherwise <rs id="t17660903-71-alias-8" type="alias">
                        <join result="nameAlias" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-71-defend655 t17660903-71-alias-8"></join>Jecox</rs>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-defend655" type="surname" value="Jacocks"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-defend655" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-defend655" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17660903-71-off383" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-off383" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-off383" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               robbing 
                     
                        <persName id="t17660903-71-victim658" type="victimName">
                           Charles 
                           White 
                        <interp inst="t17660903-71-victim658" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660903-71-victim658" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17660903-71-victim658" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-71-off383 t17660903-71-victim658"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   on the king's highway, of a 36 shilling piece
            </rs>, <rs id="t17660903-71-cd384" type="crimeDate">September 4</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-71-off383 t17660903-71-cd384"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-71-person659">
                  Charles 
                  White 
               <interp inst="t17660903-71-person659" type="surname" value="White"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person659" type="given" value="Charles"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person659" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming upon <placeName id="t17660903-71-crimeloc385">Finchley common</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660903-71-crimeloc385" type="placeName" value="Finchley common"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660903-71-crimeloc385" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-71-off383 t17660903-71-crimeloc385"></join>, my wife and a journeyman of mine were with me; this was last Thursday night; I was stopped by a young man; he was very drunk, and I had drank a little; it was near Whetstone turnpike.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was that young man?</p>
               <p>White. I believe it was the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath is the prisoner the man?</p>
               <p>White. I believe he is; he was taken in at the Fighting Cocks.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you drunk all the while you was there, and before the Justice?</p>
               <p>White. He is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say when he stopped you?</p>
               <p>White. I can't remember what he said more than taking my money.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he get any money, and what money?</p>
               <p>White. I gave him a 36 shillings piece and a halfpenny.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you present at his being searched?</p>
               <p>White. I believe I was in the house, but did not see him searched.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you find your 36 s. piece?</p>
               <p>White. They said they had taken a piece of gold and some silver out of his pocket.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-71-person660">
                  Henry 
                  Gotobed 
               <interp inst="t17660903-71-person660" type="surname" value="Gotobed"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person660" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person660" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a butcher, and live in Cold Bath-fields, and work in Clare-market; last Thursday night between seven and eight o'clock, I and 
               <persName id="t17660903-71-person661">
                  John 
                  Caverly 
               <interp inst="t17660903-71-person661" type="surname" value="Caverly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person661" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person661" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             were coming from Barnet, we saw the prisoner by the side of Mr. White's chaise, almost by the two Fighting Cocks on Finchley-common; Mr. White called, Butcher, give me assistance; the prisoner was robbing him and his lady in the chaise.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see the prisoner take any thing?</p>
               <p>Gotobed. No; I came up to him and hove him from his horse along-side the chaise; he had a pistol in his hand, which we found afterwards to be loaded; he was very much in liquor; we took him in at the two Fighting-cocks; he was charged with robbing Mr. White of a 36 s. piece. The prisoner could not tell what to say; I held the candle while others searched him; I saw a 36 s. piece laid down upon the floor by, I believe, the constable; Mr. White and his lady challenged the 36 s. piece; the prisoner said nothing to it but cried.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say for himself?</p>
               <p>Gotobed. He had nothing to say, he was quite intirely in liquor; we left him there all night in the care of the constable, and the man of the house, but they are not here.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner very much in liquor?</p>
               <p>Gotobed. He was quite stupid, I hardly think he knew what he did.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-71-person662">
                  John 
                  Caverly 
               <interp inst="t17660903-71-person662" type="surname" value="Caverly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person662" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person662" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in company with the last witness coming from Barnet, last Thursday night; we saw the prisoner close by the chaise; I believe his hand was in the chaise, and a pistol in it; when we came up to them, Mrs. White said they had been robbed of a 36 s. piece and a halfpenny; the prisoner was very fuddled, he could hardly speak at all.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he make any resistance when you went to take him?</p>
               <p>Caverly. No, he did not; my companion shoved him from his horse, and I got hold of his collar; we carried him in at the two Fighting Cocks; he was searched; there was a 36 s. piece and some<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030056"></xptr> silver and halfpence found upon him; I saw the constable and another man search him; I saw the 30 s. after they had flung it down, upon a handkerchief that was spread on the ground; I saw him the next day when he was before the Justice, he would not own any thing.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he very much in liquor?</p>
               <p>Caverly. He was very much, he could hardly speak.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he any thing of value about him?</p>
               <p>Caverly. No, not as I saw; he cried very much when before Justice Palmer, and said but very little.</p>
               <p>Q. What was he charged with?</p>
               <p>Caverly. He was charged with robbing Mr. White.</p>
               <p>Q. How many pistols had he about him?</p>
               <p>Caverly. He had two.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they both loaded?</p>
               <p>Caverly. They were.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I was fuddled, or I had never done such a thing.</p>
               <p>To his character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-71-person663">
                  Thompson 
                  Payter 
               <interp inst="t17660903-71-person663" type="surname" value="Payter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person663" type="given" value="Thompson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person663" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Newport Pagnel in the county of Bucks, I have known the prisoner from about a week old; I know his father, and all the family; his father is a dealer in lace, the prisoner was brought up in the lace way; he was with his father all his life time, only when at the boarding school; he came to town about his father's business; he comes once a fortnight. I have known him trusted with two thousand pounds worth of lace at a time. I am in the lace trade.</p>
               <p>Q. Is it usual in your way to carry arms?</p>
               <p>Payter. It is; I never go a journey without arms, when I am making up money in my circuit, sometimes one pistol, sometimes two; there are very few in the lace business but what carry arms, because our stock lies in a little compass, and is very valuable.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner's character?</p>
               <p>Payter. He is a very sober steady lad, I never heard one misbehaviour of him before this in all my life; this was not for the want of money; he might have had 500 l. had he asked it; I would let him have 500 l. had I it, upon his own note; he was in great business and had great credit; he did not stand in need of thirty-six score such pieces; I heard of this at St. Alban's, and came to town but last night.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-71-person664">
                  Jeremiah 
                  Worlings 
               <interp inst="t17660903-71-person664" type="surname" value="Worlings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person664" type="given" value="Jeremiah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person664" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I keep the Bear and Ragged-staff in Smithfield; I have known the prisoner between two and three years, he is a lace-man; his father and he deal very largely; he did business for his father, latterly he has done it for himself.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a man of property?</p>
               <p>Worlings. His father is for what I heard, a man that can have money upon his own credit at any time. I would have lent the prisoner any thing that was in my power upon his own note.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharpling. I am a clockmaker, and live in Duck-lane; I have been acquainted with the prisoner about two or three years; last Thursday was with him between four and five o'clock, he was very much in liquor, this was at the Bear and Ragged staff; I was looking over the newspaper, he insisted on my drinking a glass of wine with him; I said, you had better go and lie down; he said to me you shall drink a glass, and then you and I will go and take a ride for six or seven miles.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any thing of his circumstances?</p>
               <p>Sharpling. Yes, his father is in good circumstances; I never heard of the prisoner's being short of money; had he wanted 20 l. at any time I would let him have it; I never heard the least blemish of his character in my life.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-71-person665">
                  Samuel 
                  Payter 
               <interp inst="t17660903-71-person665" type="surname" value="Payter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person665" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person665" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Noble-street; I have known him about fourteen years, he has a very good character as ever I heard; he lived in good credit; had he wanted 40 or 50 l. at any time, I would have let him have it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-71-person666">
                  Anne 
                  Hardy 
               <interp inst="t17660903-71-person666" type="surname" value="Hardy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person666" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person666" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him pretty near three years, he has a very good character; I belive his circumstances are very good.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Scott. I have known him three years, he has an extraordinary good character, and in very good circumstances. I live with my brother in Smithfield.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-71-person667">
                  Edward 
                  Scott 
               <interp inst="t17660903-71-person667" type="surname" value="Scott"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person667" type="given" value="Edward"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person667" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a perriwigmaker, and live in Smithfield; I have known him about three years; he is a very honest just man, and his circumstances very good; I don't know but many people would have given him 20, 30 or 100 l. credit in the way of trade.</p>
               <p>John Hall. I keep the Oxford-arms in Warwick-lane, I have known him above four years; his father and he quartered at my house best part of twelve months; I have said to the old man, I thought him very happy in a son; I always took him to be very sober, and I always took the old man to be in middling circumstances.</p>
               <p>Q. to Gotobed. What sort of a horse did the prisoner ride?</p>
               <p>Gotobed. He rode a grey horse.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660903-71-person668">
                  Thomas 
                  Worlings 
               <interp inst="t17660903-71-person668" type="surname" value="Worlings"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person668" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-person668" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him upwards of two years; I never heard any thing amiss of<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176609030057"></xptr> him in my life. I am book-keeper at the Bear and Ragged staff, I always understood his father and he were in exceeding good credit.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660903-71-verdict386" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-verdict386" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-verdict386" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17660903-71-punish387" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660903-71-punish387" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660903-71-defend655 t17660903-71-punish387"></join>
               Death
            </rs>. Recommended.</p>
            </div1>
