<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17641212-30">
               <interp inst="t17641212-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-30" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17641212"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17641212-30" type="date" value="17641212"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17641212-30-off156-c192" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-30-defend254 t17641212-30-off156 t17641212-30-verdict163"></join>
         
               <p>32. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17641212-30-defend254" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Dunn 
                  <interp inst="t17641212-30-defend254" type="surname" value="Dunn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-defend254" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-defend254" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted, for <rs id="t17641212-30-off156" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-off156" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-off156" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               that he, in a certain court and open place, near the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17641212-30-victim256" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Colwell 
                        <interp inst="t17641212-30-victim256" type="surname" value="Colwell"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-30-victim256" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17641212-30-victim256" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                     </persName>
                      
                  , <rs id="t17641212-30-viclabel157" type="occupation">Spinster</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-30-victim256 t17641212-30-viclabel157"></join>, did make an assault, putting her in corporal fear<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176412120017"></xptr> and danger of her life, and violently taking from her person two quarter guineas, and five shillings and six-pence in money, numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17641212-30-victim258" type="victimName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Baudouin 
                  <interp inst="t17641212-30-victim258" type="surname" value="Baudouin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-victim258" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-victim258" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17641212-30-viclabel158" type="occupation">widow</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-30-victim258 t17641212-30-viclabel158"></join>, <rs id="t17641212-30-cd159" type="crimeDate">October 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-30-off156 t17641212-30-cd159"></join>. *</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-30-person259">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Baudouin 
               <interp inst="t17641212-30-person259" type="surname" value="Baudouin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person259" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person259" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . 
               <persName id="t17641212-30-person260">
                  Mary 
                  Colwell 
               <interp inst="t17641212-30-person260" type="surname" value="Colwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person260" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person260" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             is my <rs id="t17641212-30-viclabel160" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-30-victim256 t17641212-30-viclabel160"></join>: On the 22d of October, between six and seven at night, a man came to order four bottles of cappillaire, to be carried to Mr. Crisp's, in Catherine Court.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Baudouin. I am a <rs id="t17641212-30-viclabel161" type="occupation">perfumer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-30-victim258 t17641212-30-viclabel161"></join>, and live in Seething-lane; I said he might have four bottles for half a crown; he said he would go and ask his mistress: he said I must send it, with a change for a 36 s. piece: I said I could not; then he said, send change for a guinea.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that the prisoner at the bar?</p>
               <p>Baudouin. No, it was not. Then I sent 
               <persName id="t17641212-30-person261">
                  Mary 
                  Colwell 
               <interp inst="t17641212-30-person261" type="surname" value="Colwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person261" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person261" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             with the cappillaire, and two five and three-penny piece: five shillings in silver, and a six-pence: she came back again crying, in less than half a quarter of an hour, and said she had been robbed: upon that I ran out to meet her; and people brought the prisoner in less than a quarter of an hour: there were Mr. Dixon and Mr. Pierpoint; then the girl ran out, and said the prisoner was the man that had robbed her, and that she would swear it: he pulled out about five shillings; we found none of the quarter-guineas upon him: I thought I did know one of the shillings; but I don't take upon me to swear it: he said he was coming from the Crooked Billet cross the hill, and was going to one Bell, a lifeguard man, and not meeting with him he was returning to that place; and then begged I would let him go, and that he was not guilty of it, and said the people had made a mistake.</p>
               <p>Q. Was it a dark or light night?</p>
               <p>Baudouin. It was not a very dark night, nor a very light night; but there are lamps at the doors all lighted: the shops were shut up.</p>
               <p>Q. to 
               <persName id="t17641212-30-person262">
                  Mary 
                  Colwell 
               <interp inst="t17641212-30-person262" type="surname" value="Colwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person262" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person262" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . How old are you?</p>
               <p>Colwell. If I live till the 11th of June, I shall be twenty years of age. I was not at home when the man came to order the cappillaire; my mistress sent me to go to Mr. Crisp's in Catherine Court.</p>
               <p>Q. to Mrs. Baudouin. How long after the man had ordered the cappillaire was it, that you sent this witness?</p>
               <p>Baudouin. She was out on an errand, but soon came home: I sent her about six minutes after he had ordered it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-30-person263">
                  Mary 
                  Colwell 
               <interp inst="t17641212-30-person263" type="surname" value="Colwell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person263" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person263" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The man met me about the middle of <placeName id="t17641212-30-crimeloc162">Catherine Court</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-30-crimeloc162" type="placeName" value="Catherine Court"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17641212-30-crimeloc162" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-30-off156 t17641212-30-crimeloc162"></join>, and asked me whether I had got the cappillaire? I said, Yes: he said, Zounds! where have you been all this while? I said I had been at the other end of the town, and I came as soon as I came home: he asked me to give him the change; I told him I would not; he would not touch the cappillaire: the change was in my left hand, two five and three-penny pieces, and six shillings and six-pence: he took hold of my hand, and found it shut, with the change in it; he twisted my hand round, and broke my fingers open, and took it away from me; then he ran, and I ran after him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say when he took the money?</p>
               <p>Colwell. He said nothing to me: there is an iron gate; he could not get through without going side-ways: I almost got to him: there was a black boy on the out-side of the gate; he said, What has he done? I said (in my hurry) he has taken a guinea: the boy said he would follow him and would not leave him: he ran after him, and I ran home and told my mistress.</p>
               <p>Q. What is that black boy's name?</p>
               <p>Colwell. His name is Guardaloup.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you light enough to see the man's person?</p>
               <p>Colwell. Every door has a lamp; and that door where I stood upon the steps. (Mr. Crisp's) had two lamps: the man stood before me there when he got the money out of my hand; he walked with me to that door; I asked him whether he lived there? he said, Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. How far did he walk with you?</p>
               <p>Colwell. He walked with me from the middle of the court; that is not above twenty yards; he did not take hold of my arm till I got to the door; the lamp shone upon him; his face was white all over.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you mean?</p>
               <p>Colwell. His face was quite pale.</p>
               <p>Court. Look at the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Colwell. I am sure that is the man that took the money from me; he had then a black coat on.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever see the prisoner before?</p>
               <p>Colwell. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you not frighted?</p>
               <p>Colwell. I was, when he took the money, not before; then I cry'd, Stop thief; the man has taken my money out of my hand.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176412120018"></xptr>Q. How long after you lost the money was it, that you saw the prisoner brought to your mistress's house?</p>
               <p>Colwell. It was not above half a quarter of an hour; they ran and brought him back.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he searched?</p>
               <p>Colwell. They pull'd off his shoes and stockings to search him; he said he would leave his holland shirt with my mistress; and if my mistress would let him send home to his wife, he would send for the money that I lost.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he not say it was a mistake, he was not the man?</p>
               <p>Colwell. At first he did; after that, he desired they would let him have a coach, for he would not go without.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he ever say he was the man that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Colwell. No, he did not; he wanted sadly to get away, but we kept the door pretty fast.</p>
               <p>Q. Is that man that you saw go side-ways thro' the gate, the man that robbed you?</p>
               <p>Colwell. That was the man.</p>
               <p>Q. to Guardaloup. What is your other name?</p>
               <p>Guardaloup. They call me Guardaloup, Guardey.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you been in England?</p>
               <p>Guardaloup. I have been in England three years.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you been taught any principles of religion?</p>
               <p>Guardaloup. No; I know nothing of religion.</p>
               <p>He was not sworn.</p>
               <p>Q. to Colwell. Is this the lad that was on the out-side of the gate?</p>
               <p>Colwell. This is the person.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-30-person264">
                  John 
                  Dixon 
               <interp inst="t17641212-30-person264" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person264" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person264" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I work at the Custom-house; I was going home over Tower-Hill, about a quarter after seven; a young man crossed the hill, towards Crutched Fryars; his name is Pierpoint; I had got almost over the hill; I heard somebody scream out, and then the cry, Stop thief; I went on pretty fast; I heard Stop thief very much; I saw some people running over the hill; the prisoner ran betwixt the young man and I; Pierpoint was coming one way, and I another; he directly turned short round, and pursued, and I directly after, into George Yard: when the prisoner came to the bars in the yard, he turned round; and Pierpoint catched him in his arms; and I took him by the collar: the prisoner directly said, I am not the man, or I am innocent, I can't tell which; there were a great croud of people after him; they said, here is the gi rl on the other side, that has been robbed: Pierpoint had hold of one side, and I the other; coming over the hill, I had my left hand on his right side; he put his hand into his left hand breeche's pocket, and stooped down, with his hand below the calf of his leg; I made an observation of it, and said, Stop, he has pulled something out of his pocket, and dropt it; but the people hurried him on as fast as they could; so we did not stay to see what he had dropt; when we were come to Seething-lane, the girl came and said, O! mistress, here is the man; they have got him between them two men.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go back to search on the hill?</p>
               <p>Dixon. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see that black boy?</p>
               <p>Dixon. He was in George Yard, but I did not see him till I had hold of the prisoner; then he was close at my heels.</p>
               <p>Q. How far is George Yard from the end of Catherine Court?</p>
               <p>Dixon. It is about 200 yards.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear any thing drop when the prisoner stooped down.</p>
               <p>Dixon. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any thing in his hand?</p>
               <p>Dixon. No.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-30-person265">
                  James 
                  Pierpoint 
               <interp inst="t17641212-30-person265" type="surname" value="Pierpoint"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person265" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was coming from Thames-street, cross the hill, going towards Crutched Fryars; about the middle of the hill I heard stop thief; the prisoner was then about my arm's length from my breast, running as hard as he could from Catherine Court to George Yard; he ran cross me; as he pass'd me. I turned short about, and pursued directly; I perceived a black boy at my heels; he ran as hard as I did, for what I know; he called stop thief; he might be three or four yards from me, and I the same length from the prisoner; I pursued him into George Yard, and in the entrance of the yard I called out the same; there was an obstruction in the passage, and people coming, the prisoner was stopp'd; he turned round, and came on the other side of the way; I had an adz in my hand; I took him between my arms; he said he was not the man; he was innocent: said I, You must go to the gentlewoman, or the girl that you are accused of robbing: 
               <persName id="t17641212-30-person266">
                  John 
                  Dixon 
               <interp inst="t17641212-30-person266" type="surname" value="Dixon"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person266" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person266" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             and I brought him cross the hill into Catherine Court; the girl met him about the middle of the court, and said, That was the man that took the money from her: I observed<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176412120019"></xptr> his motion in stooping; he leaned on one side; but I did not see him drop any thing; when we got him to the house, he was sometimes willing to be searched, and sometimes unwilling: he said he was in so bad a garb, he did not care to shew himself: the knees of his breeches were torn, and he had bad shoes on: he pulled out of his pocket four or five shillings.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-30-person267">
                  Joseph 
                  Richards 
               <interp inst="t17641212-30-person267" type="surname" value="Richards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person267" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I had the prisoner in charge; I asked the maid her age: she said she was nineteen; I took the prisoner to the Compter; he said he was not the man.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was running over Tower-Hill; I heard the cry Stop thief; I did not think they were running after me; as soon as I thought they meant me, I turned immediately back: I was going to meet an acquaintance of mine at the Crooked Billet; one of the men took hold of me, and said, I was the man that stole the girl's money, or robb'd her: I said, Shew me the house, I am very willing to go there: I asked the woman if I was the man that was there before? she said, No, I was not: I was willing to be searched: they made me pull off my shoes, and unbutton my breeches; they took off my garters: they asked me what money I had? I took out all I had, which was four or five shillings; the gentlewoman said, give me the money, and you shall go about your business; saying, she was sure I had it about me: when they sent for the constable, I said, if she would give me my liberty, I would give her the money, not knowing but they would swear my life away.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-30-person268">
                  Thomas 
                  English 
               <interp inst="t17641212-30-person268" type="surname" value="English"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person268" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a linen-draper and haberdasher; I live in Whitechapel: I have known the prisoner and his family from my infancy; his father is a bricklayer, and keeps a great many men at work in Yorkshire; I never heard but that the prisoner bore a very fair, honest character.</p>

               <p>Q. Have you known him much in town?</p>
               <p>English. I have seen him in town about a year ago, in a working dress; he is a bricklayer also.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know any master he has worked with here?</p>
               <p>English. No, I do not, since he left Easinwold.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17641212-30-person269">
                  William 
                  Edwards 
               <interp inst="t17641212-30-person269" type="surname" value="Edwards"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person269" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him between six and seven years; last summer he worked in the same house where I did; I always took him for an industrious man; he always bore a very good character.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Edwards. I am a master painter, and live in the Strand.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17641212-30-verdict163" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-verdict163" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-verdict163" type="verdictSubcategory" value="withRecommendation"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17641212-30-punish164" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17641212-30-punish164" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17641212-30-defend254 t17641212-30-punish164"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>Recommended to mercy, being young.</p>
            </div1>
