<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650918-40">
               <interp inst="t17650918-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-40" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650918"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650918-40" type="date" value="17650918"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650918-40-off212-c272" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-40-defend350 t17650918-40-off212 t17650918-40-verdict215"></join>
         
               <p>459. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650918-40-defend350" type="defendantName">
                     Maria 
                     Jenkins 
                  <interp inst="t17650918-40-defend350" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-defend350" type="given" value="Maria"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-defend350" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for the <rs id="t17650918-40-off212" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-off212" type="offenceCategory" value="kill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-off212" type="offenceSubcategory" value="infanticide"></interp>
               wilful murder of her male bastard-child
            </rs>. She stood charged on the coroner's inquest for the said murder, <rs id="t17650918-40-cd213" type="crimeDate">August 25</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-40-off212 t17650918-40-cd213"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-40-person351">
                  Mary 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person351" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person351" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person351" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner at the bar lived <rs id="t17650918-40-deflabel214" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-40-defend350 t17650918-40-deflabel214"></join> with Mr. Fisher, an attorney at law in the Minories, about four months: I went to Mr. Fisher's on the 25th of August; I was told the servant was taken very ill; I am a relation of Mr. Fisher's; they sent for me; the prisoner's sister was there shutting up the windows; she seemed to be in a great confusion; I ask'd her what was the matter with her sister; she said she had been very bad, but was then better; then one of the women came that was to wash the next morning, had the maid been well; but as she was ill, they could not wash: the woman said there was a child, she was certain; I did not know what they meant; I had no suspicion; Mrs. Davis took a stick, and went to the necessary, and put it down, and said, there it was; I said, For God's sake send for a midwife; they sent for Mr. Complin, who came immediately; he went up stairs to Maria: I had not seen the prisoner, but I saw the child taken out of the necessary by Mrs. Davis's husband: Mr. Complin came down; this was before the child was found; and after it was found, he was sent for a second time; he ordered it to be wash'd; I saw it afterwards; it was a male child; there appeared no marks of violence upon it; it was a fine baby.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had children?</p>
               <p>M. Clark. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it appear to have come to its full birth?</p>
               <p>M. Clark. It did; the prisoner appeared always to me to be a very clever, decent person; I never suspected her.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-40-person352">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Davis 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person352" type="surname" value="Davis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person352" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person352" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about five months; she lived all that time at Mr. Fisher's. Miss Shoreditch, Mr. Fisher's niece, sent for me about nine o'clock on Sunday night, the 25th of August; I went; she told me the prisoner was taken very bad, and I must sit up with her all night; I went up immediately to her bedside, and said, Maria, how do you do? she said she was much better, and much easier: I ask'd her if I should get her any thing; her sister made answer, she was going to get her something; I told her I was sent for to sit up with her all night; she told me I had no occasion for that, for she should; I came down stairs, and her sister with me; her sister carried her something up; after that the sister came down, and said she would go home and ask her master to let her sit up all night, and desired nobody to go up stairs, for Maria was much easier, and believed she would go to sleep. While her sister was gone, Mr. Complin was sent for by Mr. Fisher's niece; he went up to her, came down again, and said he saw nothing at all; that if she had had any thing, she denied it; then there was orders given to search the house. I, 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person353">
                  Martha 
                  Sharpham 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person353" type="surname" value="Sharpham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person353" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person353" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and Mrs. Clark's maid, who is not here, went up stairs, and first went into Mrs. Fisher's room; we saw the floor sadly daubed over with blood at the foot of the bed.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever had a child?</p>
               <p>E. Davis. I am a married woman, but never had a child, nor was ever with any at a labour. We came down stairs, and told them what we saw, but could find nothing at all; then they desired us to look out backwards; we opened the back-door; there was the track of blood from the back-door to the necessary; I had a long stick; I put it down the necessary, and 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person354">
                  drew
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person354" type="given" value="drew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person354" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             the child up; I fetch'd my husband, and he took it out; Mr. Complin was sent for again, and he went up to her.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you tell which way the track went, whether from the back-door to the necessary, or from the necessary to the back-door?</p>
               <p>E. Davis. I cannot.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-40-person355">
                  Martha 
                  Sharpham 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person355" type="surname" value="Sharpham"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person355" type="given" value="Martha"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person355" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I knew the prisoner four months at Mr. Fisher's; the maid was so very bad, she could not wash; I wash'd for Mr. Fisher every month; I went that night a little before dark, time enough to have filled my tubs and copper; I saw Maria walking about in the kitchen, and her sister with her; she had her hands by her sides; she was not very well; her sister said she had got the piles; I saw some stuff in a pot on the dresser; then I went away for an hour. When I returned, the house was all in a confusion; she was gone to bed; Mrs. Clark was there; I went down into the kitchen, and they up stairs; I staid till Mrs. Davis and the sister came down; I said, What is the matter? I found they had seen some marks upon the stones in the yard. (I had had a mistrust she was with child two months before).</p>
               <p>Q. Did you ever tell her of it?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176509180024"></xptr>M. Sharpham. No, I never did, nor any body else, as I know of. Her bigness appeared most on her sides: they search'd, and found the child in the necessary; I held the candle while it was taken up.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you had children?</p>
               <p>M. Sharpham. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Did it appear to have come to its full birth?</p>
               <p>M. Sharpham. It did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see any marks of violence upon it?</p>
               <p>M. Sharpham. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine it?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharpham. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you ever seen any still-born children?</p>
               <p>M. Sharpham. I have.</p>
               <p>Q. Can you say it was a still-born child?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharpham. I cannot; it was not quite cold; from thence is all my suspicion; it was the proper warmth of flesh and blood, I think. Towards the morning. I said to the prisoner, there was a fine baby below; she said nothing to it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you examine her linen and sheets?</p>
               <p>M. Sharpham. I did; they appeared like that of a woman brought to bed, stained in that manner.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you hear the prisoner say any thing after this?</p>
               <p>M. Sharpham. She said it was too late to repent, she could not call it back: she was sorry for it.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you imagine she was delivered?</p>
               <p>Mr. Sharpham. We imagined she was delivered in her mistress's room.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Q. Don't sometimes pains of a woman in labour come upon them when they can't help themselves?</p>
               <p>M. Sharpham. Yes, sometimes.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose a pain should take them when on the necessary, can they help themselves?</p>
               <p>M. Sharpham. I don't suppose they could.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the woman perfectly delivered at the time you saw her?</p>
               <p>M. Sharpham. She was not; there was something came from her a great while after.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not the violence of her pains discharge the child while she was sitting on the vault?</p>
               <p>M. Sharpham. It might.</p>
               <p>Q. When you say she said she was sorry for what she had done, might not that be applied to letting a man get her with child?</p>
               <p>M. Sharpham. That might be the case.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-40-person356">
                  William 
                  Complin 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person356" type="surname" value="Complin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person356" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person356" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon and man-midwife. I was sent for to Mr. Fisher's on the 25th of August, a little after nine o'clock; Mrs. Clark told me she believed there had been an unlucky accident; the maid had miscarried; that her sister had emptied something down the necessary; I said, I would go up and speak to her: I went up, and said, Maria, what is the matter with you? she said, I am better than I was: I said, I heard that you had something came from you; that you had miscarried: No, said she, I have not: I have been out of order two months, and now there has been rather too great a quantity than what naturally is: I asked her if I could do any thing for her; she said, No. I had another patient waiting for me; I went down, and said they must search the necessary house, and if they found any thing, they must send for me again: I went away, and about eleven o'clock they came and told me the child was found, and desired I would come directly. When I came, the child was lying on the ground, taken out of the necessary: I desired them to wash it, and bring it into the parlour; then I sent for Maria's sister down stairs, who was up with Maria: I asked what that was that she heaved down the necessary; she said it was water; I went up again to Maria, and asked her if she had not been brought to bed; she denied it; I said, You have no occasion to deny it now, for there was a child found that had not long been born; she still said it was not her's; I said, Considering the condition you are in, every body is convinced it is your's; then the lay still, and made no answer at all: I went down, and looked at the child, and found no marks of violence upon it: I told them they must let somebody take care of her that night, and I would come again in the morning: and I dar'd say every thing would come out: when I went in the morning. they shewed me what had come from her since I went away; then, upon my charging her with having had a child, she owned it; then I went away. I was ordered by the coroner the next evening, to open the body in the presence of another surgeon. We tried the usual experiment to know whether the child was born alive, that is, upon the lungs; if the lungs have imbibed the air. if the child has breathed, they will swim upon the surface of the water; if not, they will sink: we gave it as our opinion, that the child had breathed.</p>
         
               <p>N. B. The LAST PART of these PROCEEDINGS will be published in a few days.</p>
         
               <div1 type="frontMatter" id="t17650918-40">
                  <interp inst="t17650918-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-40" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650918"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650918-40" type="date" value="17650918"></interp>
            
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176509180025"></xptr>THE WHOLE PROCEEDINGS ON THE King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol-Delivery FOR THE CITY of LONDON; And also the Gaol-Delivery for the County of MIDDLESEX, HELD AT JUSTICE-HALL in the OLD-BAILEY, On Wednesday the 18th, Thursday the 19th, Friday the 20th, Saturday the 21st, Monday the 23d, and Tuesday the 24th of September.</p>
                  <p>In the Fifth Year of His MAJESTY's Reign. Being the Seventh SESSION in the MAYORALTY of The Right Honble Sir 
                  <persName id="t17650918-40-person357">
                     William 
                     Stephenson 
                  <interp inst="t17650918-40-person357" type="surname" value="Stephenson"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-40-person357" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17650918-40-person357" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
               , Knt. LORD-MAYOR of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
                  <p>NUMBER VII. PART II, for the YEAR 1765.</p>
                  <p>LONDON:</p>
                  <p>Sold by W. NICOLL, in St. Paul's Church-yard.</p>
                  <p>[Price SIX-PENCE.]</p>
                  <p>
                     <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176509180026"></xptr>THE PROCEEDINGS ON THE</p>
                  <p>King's Commission of the Peace, Oyer and Terminer, and Gaol-Delivery, held for the City of LONDON, &amp; c.</p>
               </div1>
               <p>[Continuation of the Trial of 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person358">
                  Maria 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person358" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person358" type="given" value="Maria"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person358" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .]</p>
               <p>Q. IF the child was born alive, and thrown into the little house, and drowned there, will the lungs always swim?</p>
               <p>Complin. Yes; if it was killed any way they would swim; besides, the soil was thick and stiff, and none of the water or nastiness was in its stomach; some might get up its nose.</p>
               <p>Q. How do you apprehend it was killed?</p>
               <p>Complin. It appeared to me it was stifled in the necessary.</p>
               <p>Q. Do not you think such a child as that might make a great noise, in being brought down stairs, if it was born alive?</p>
               <p>Complin. I think it might.</p>
               <p>Cross Examination.</p>
               <p>Counsel. Then this experiment is entirely from the inflation of the lungs?</p>
               <p>Complin. It is.</p>
               <p>Q. Suppose the child's head was to come into the open air, don't you think the child's lungs would be instantly inflated?</p>
               <p>Complin. Yes, if it gives but two gasps; if it cries, the child was born alive.</p>
               <p>Q. If a woman be upon the necessary, and was delivered there, in the agonies that come near the critical time, can she help herself?</p>
               <p>Complin. No, she cannot; she then requires all the help they can. Sometimes twenty minutes is taken up in the delivery of a woman. In the course of that time, the head of the child being discharged from the mother, when the mouth is in the open air, then the inflation commences: when the child opens its mouth, and the lungs are once inflated, they never afterwards become dense, till some time after death.</p>
               <p>Q. Might not that accident happen to a woman that finds pains upon her different from what she may think the pains of labour, and be taken in labour on the necessary, and be delivered of a child?</p>
               <p>Complin. Yes, that may be the case.</p>
               <p>Q. May not a child falling in the soil have the same appearance as this child?</p>
               <p>Complin. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. to Sharpham. Did you see the after-burden?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176509180027"></xptr>Sharpham. That was put upon a street, and I put it in the pot; then the prisoner was in bed; this was some hours after the child was found.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I was taken very ill, I went out into the yard; Mrs. Davis promised to come to me, and never came nigh me; I had occasion to go to the necessary, and the child dropped from me there.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-40-person359">
                  Mary 
                  Donnival 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person359" type="surname" value="Donnival"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person359" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person359" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner three years. I had some child bed linen that was my mother's; and I live with Mrs. Hucherson. I had lent them to her, and she said I might have them when I pleased to come for them. The prisoner came one time to see me; I thought she was with child; I said, I fancy you have stole a wedding; she said, When you see Mrs. Hucherson, I should be obliged to you, if you will get your child-bed linen. The last time she asked about it was the Sunday fortnight before she was delivered: the first time was three months before she was delivered.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she tell you she was with child?</p>
               <p>M. Donnival. No, she did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-40-person360">
                  Mary 
                  Hucherson 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person360" type="surname" value="Hucherson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person360" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person360" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Lemon-street. The last witness was my servant, in August; (
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person361">
                  Maria 
                  Jenkins 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person361" type="surname" value="Jenkins"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person361" type="given" value="Maria"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person361" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             had lived with me). Donnival made application to me about some child-bed linen belonging to her, that was her mother's. I don't know who she wanted it for. Maria was very fond of my child, when she lived with me.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650918-40-person362">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Jasper 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person362" type="surname" value="Jasper"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person362" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person362" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person363">
                  Catherine 
                  Hagers 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person363" type="surname" value="Hagers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person363" type="given" value="Catherine"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person363" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person364">
                  Mary 
                  Hess 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person364" type="surname" value="Hess"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person364" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person364" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person365">
                  Ruth 
                  Beck 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person365" type="surname" value="Beck"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person365" type="given" value="Ruth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person365" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person366">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Walker 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person366" type="surname" value="Walker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person366" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person366" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person367">
                  Frances 
                  Egars 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person367" type="surname" value="Egars"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person367" type="given" value="Frances"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person367" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person368">
                  John 
                  Garth 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person368" type="surname" value="Garth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person368" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person368" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person369">
                  Joseph 
                  Hess 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person369" type="surname" value="Hess"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person369" type="given" value="Joseph"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person369" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person370">
                  Andrew 
                  Neese 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person370" type="surname" value="Neese"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person370" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person370" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person371">
                  John 
                  Arney 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person371" type="surname" value="Arney"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person371" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person371" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17650918-40-person372">
                  Kesia 
                  Allen 
               <interp inst="t17650918-40-person372" type="surname" value="Allen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person372" type="given" value="Kesia"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-person372" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , all gave her a good character, and one that was very fond of young children.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650918-40-verdict215" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-verdict215" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17650918-40-punish216" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650918-40-punish216" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650918-40-defend350 t17650918-40-punish216"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
