<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17660702-24">
               <interp inst="t17660702-24" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-24" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-24" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17660702"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17660702-24" type="date" value="17660702"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-24-off136-c177" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-24-defend222 t17660702-24-off136 t17660702-24-verdict139"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17660702-24-off136-c178" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-24-defend224 t17660702-24-off136 t17660702-24-verdict139"></join>
         
               <p>357, 358. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-24-defend222" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Richardson 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-24-defend222" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-defend222" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-defend222" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-24-defend224" type="defendantName">
                     Susannah 
                     Bourn 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-24-defend224" type="surname" value="Bourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-defend224" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-defend224" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660702-24-deflabel135" type="occupation">spinsters</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-24-defend222 t17660702-24-deflabel135"></join>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-24-defend224 t17660702-24-deflabel135"></join>, were indicted for <rs id="t17660702-24-off136" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-off136" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-off136" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a cloth coat, value 4 s. a pair of everlasting breeches, and a man's hat
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17660702-24-victim226" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Campbell 
                  <interp inst="t17660702-24-victim226" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-victim226" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-victim226" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-24-off136 t17660702-24-victim226"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17660702-24-cd137" type="crimeDate">May 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-24-off136 t17660702-24-cd137"></join>. ||</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-24-person227">
                  William 
                  Campbell 
               <interp inst="t17660702-24-person227" type="surname" value="Campbell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person227" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person227" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 12th of May I was drinking in the morning early, at the Fountain in the Minories; there I met with Richardson in the house; she called for a brush, to brush my coat and hat.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she live there?</p>
               <p>Campbell. No, she did not; I drank some beer in her company, and went home along with her to her own room, in <placeName id="t17660702-24-crimeloc138">Parrot-alley in East Smithfield</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-24-crimeloc138" type="placeName" value="Parrot-alley in East Smithfield"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17660702-24-crimeloc138" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17660702-24-off136 t17660702-24-crimeloc138"></join>; it was in the house of 
               <persName id="t17660702-24-person228">
                  Susanna 
                  Bourn 
               <interp inst="t17660702-24-person228" type="surname" value="Bourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person228" type="given" value="Susanna"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person228" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I went to bed there with Richardson; when I awaked I found she was gone, and Bourn was helping to put on me some other beeeches; I looked about, and found all my cloaths were gone; Bourn<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176607020018"></xptr> said, come, let us go and see for the girl that has got your cloaths; so we went to an ale-house.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do for cloaths to go in?</p>
               <p>Campbell. Bourn brought me some rags to put on, (producing an old ragged piece of a banyan, a pair of cloth breeches, ragged and full of holes) these are they; I put them on as well as I could make them hang on me; and when at that ale-house I was telling the landlord what I had lost, in the mean time Bourn slipped away. I went back to to the Fountain, and a man let me into the light where I must go to enquire after them. I went and found 
               <persName id="t17660702-24-person229">
                  Elizabeth 
                  Richardson 
               <interp inst="t17660702-24-person229" type="surname" value="Richardson"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person229" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person229" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             on the top of Houndsditch; she owned she had been along with me, but did not take my cloaths; but said, the woman of the house said she would have either money, or value, for my being there, and so she took my cloaths; and that she had been along with her to sell them. She asked me to go along with her, and have a pint of beer; so I went with her to the house where I first saw her, and the people of the house knew that was the woman that took me out of that house. Then I got a watchman, and gave him charge of her; she was brought before the Justice; she said there, she did not sell the cloaths, but the people where I had been insisted upon either money or goods for the use of the room: she said she went with Bourn when my cloaths were sold, and got half a crown of the money; that the coat was sold to Mr. Fitzgerald, and the hat and breeches to Mrs. Clark, where I found them.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you give to Richardson.?</p>
               <p>Campbell. I gave her nothing; I had no money to give her; I gave the landlady of the house my scissars, till I went home to bring some money.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>Campbell. I am a taylor.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know they had put on things that were not your own?</p>
               <p>Campbell. I was not long before I found it out.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-24-person230">
                  John 
                  Fitzgerald 
               <interp inst="t17660702-24-person230" type="surname" value="Fitzgerald"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person230" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person230" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The two women at the bar came, Bourn had the coat on her arm; she asked 3 s. 6 d. for it; I bought it for half a crown ( produced and deposed to)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-24-person231">
                  Dorothy 
                  Clark 
               <interp inst="t17660702-24-person231" type="surname" value="Clark"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person231" type="given" value="Dorothy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person231" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I bought a hat and a pair of breeches of Richardson for 3 s. 8 d. the other prisoner was with her at the time; (produced and deposed to.)</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-24-person232">
                  Andrew 
                  Popard 
               <interp inst="t17660702-24-person232" type="surname" value="Popard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person232" type="given" value="Andrew"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person232" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The two prisoners at the bar came into my shop together; Bourn had a coat, which she offered to pledge to me; she said it was one of her lodger's.</p>
               <p>John Hall. I am one of the headboroughs of St. John's, Wapping, there are seven of us, so one attends every night; on Friday the 16th of May, about one in the morning, Campbell came to me, and gave me charge of Richardson; he said he had lost his coat, hat, and breeches, and had spent what money he had at the Fountain, and she took him down to another house, and he went to bed, but did not know whether he was stripped or not; and when he awaked, the girl and his cloaths, were gone. I asked Richardson if that was true; she said it was, but she did not take the cloaths; but Mrs. Bourn took them, as she found he had no money; that she went and sold the things, and gave her half a crown of the money, and she spent a shilling out of it; I took charge of her, and of the prosecutor also, as he was a stranger to me; I carried them before Justice Hodgson; the Justice asked what sort of a house Bourn kept; she answered, it was a bawdy-house, which she swore to, and that she, that day, gave her 18 d. for the use of the bed. The Justice granted a warrant to apprehend Bourn; we went and found her at the Fountain in the Minories; they both accused each other before the Justice; then I was sent to Mrs. Clark, Mr. Fitzgerald, and Mr. Popard, who gave the same account they have here. The prisoners were committed to New Prison.</p>
               <p>Q. from Richardson to prosecutor. Did I take your cloaths from you without your consent?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. How could I give you leave while I was asleep?</p>
               <p>Q. Did you give them liberty to raise money upon them?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I had spent three or four shillings on Richardson in the public-house; but the liquor was free for any body there, I had no money left.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know you had no money left when you went with Richardson to her lodgings?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I did not; I did not know that I had left my scissars for money, till I was told of it afterwards.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been acquainted with Richardson before?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had you been at the Fountain before you went to her lodging?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I imagine I had been there three or four hours.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober when you went in at the Fountain?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, I went there in liquor.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176607020019"></xptr>Q. from Richardson. Did you not give me the things to let you lie with me?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No; I neither gave you them, nor promised you them.</p>
               <p>Richardson's defence.</p>
               <p>I was in the public-house, the prosecutor happened to come in, his cloaths were very much dirty; he asked to sit down by me; another woman came in, he arose up, and asked her to drink part of a pint of twopenny; the landlord said he was very quarrelsome when in liquor, and would use women very ill; he came up to me and asked me to drink; he took his coat off his back, and asked me to dry it; he had been down in the dirt; the landlord would not let me, so I gave him it again; then he wanted a brush, the landlord would not lend him one. I was coming out to go home about five o'clock. he asked me where I was going, and said, my dear, shall I go with you? I said, I have no home to go to but to my sister's room, and I must go by myself; he said, why may not I go with you as well as another man? I said, I was a disorderly woman, but I thought he was not fit for me; he would go with me, and told me he had no money, but he had things that would make money; he went with me, and stripped the things off, and bid me go and pawn them. I went to Mr. Popard's and offered the coat to pawn, but he not taking it in, I carried it back to him again; then he said, you may go and sell them for something, and buy some other things to wear in their room; saying, he did not care what they were, for he had better at home. After he had got the other things on, he went to bed with me; he not using me well, I got up and dressed myself, and two days after he took me up for a robbery, and after that he wanted to make up the felony for 12 s.</p>
               <p>Bourn's defence.</p>
               <p>They came home together, he told me he had no money; she said she would not go to bed without he would make her a present; he pulled off his cloaths and gave them to her; she went to the pawnbroker's, and he would lend but 2 s. on the coat; then he desired us to go and sell them, which we did, and bought some old cloaths as he had desired us, then they went to bed.</p>
               <p>For the prisoners.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-24-person233">
                  Jane 
                  Horn 
               <interp inst="t17660702-24-person233" type="surname" value="Horn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person233" type="given" value="Jane"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person233" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The man offered to make it up for 12 s. and all expences, at the Noah's Ark, the day they were committed.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you there?</p>
               <p>J. Horn. 
               <persName id="t17660702-24-person234">
                  Susannah 
                  Bourn 
               <interp inst="t17660702-24-person234" type="surname" value="Bourn"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person234" type="given" value="Susannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person234" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             sent for me; I am a neighbour.</p>
               <p>Q. What was you to do?</p>
               <p>J. Horn. The Justice was there; but this was in the tap-room, he was not in that room when the man said he would make it up for 12 s. I said, what for an old turned coat; the prisoner said before the Justice, he gave her the cloaths to lie with her, and she would not make it up.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17660702-24-person235">
                  Mary 
                  Brand 
               <interp inst="t17660702-24-person235" type="surname" value="Brand"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person235" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-person235" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner Richardson sent for me to the Noah's Ark; she told me the man had given her the things to lie with her; we had a pot of beer; the man said he would make it up for 12 s. I took her on one side, and said she had better make it up, it was but a trifle she said she would not, because he had given them to her.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Did you offer to make it up with the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, they proposed to make it up with me; she never said I gave her the cloaths, before she said it here in court.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17660702-24-verdict139" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17660702-24-verdict139" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
