<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17620224-11">
               <interp inst="t17620224-11" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-11" type="year" value="1762"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-11" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17620224"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17620224-11" type="date" value="17620224"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620224-11-off57-c134" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-11-defend150 t17620224-11-off57 t17620224-11-verdict59"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17620224-11-off60-c134" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-11-defend150 t17620224-11-off60 t17620224-11-verdict59"></join>
         
               <p>98. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-defend150" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Morring 
                  <interp inst="t17620224-11-defend150" type="surname" value="Morring"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-defend150" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-defend150" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , <rs id="t17620224-11-deflabel56" type="occupation">spinster</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-11-defend150 t17620224-11-deflabel56"></join>, was indicted for <rs id="t17620224-11-off57" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-off57" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-off57" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing three silver spoons, value 16 s. and three pair of laced ruffles, value 10 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-victim152" type="victimName">
                     Stephen 
                     Dalton 
                  <interp inst="t17620224-11-victim152" type="surname" value="Dalton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-victim152" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-victim152" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-11-off57 t17620224-11-victim152"></join>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-11-off60 t17620224-11-victim152"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            . <rs id="t17620224-11-cd58" type="crimeDate">February 8, 1762</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-11-off57 t17620224-11-cd58"></join>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17620224-11-off60 t17620224-11-cd58"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-person153">
                  Stephen 
                  Dalton 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person153" type="surname" value="Dalton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person153" type="given" value="Stephen"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person153" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On Wednesday the 10th of February, between six and seven in the evening, as I was sitting in the parlour behind the tap-room, a woman in the fore room picked up a black silk apron that lay on the floor; she called out to my wife to know if she had lost any thing, and my wife went and took it of her. On her returning to me, she said, the Lord bless me, how came this apron out of my drawers? I said, you must take more care of your things. The maid (the prisoner at the bar) went up stairs some little time before, and my wife going up stairs, I immediately heard her talk something about fire; then I went up stairs, and casting my eye to the bed I found the bed cloaths a fire, and my wife turned about, and said, O! Lord, Sall, what have you done! I turned about as she was going out of the room, and gave her two or three kicks as she went down; she ran out of the house, and I went back immediately to put the fire out, not seeking at all after her. Some people in the tap-room seeing a smoke, came up stairs, and one of them seeing smoke come out of the drawers in the same room, we opened the drawers and found some part of them on fire, with some things in them. After the fire was extinguished, we began to examine what things were missing out of the drawers. About this time a girl came in and picked up a muslin double ruffle at the door, which the maid had dropped.</p>
               <p>Q. Who saw her drop it?</p>
               <p>S. Dalton. 
               <persName id="t17620224-11-person154">
                  Hannah 
                  Abram 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person154" type="surname" value="Abram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person154" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person154" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. Might not the things that were missing out of the drawers be burnt?</p>
               <p>S. Dalton. No; there were three silver spoons and other things.</p>
               <p>Q. How long had the prisoner lived with you?</p>
               <p>S. Dalton. Three months.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you put them in the indictment?</p>
               <p>S. Dalton. Because they were in the house that afternoon, and never found since.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you a suspicion of her dishonesty when you kicked her down stairs?</p>
               <p>S. Dalton. Only that she had carelessly set the bed on fire.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-person155">
                  Ann 
                  Dalton 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person155" type="surname" value="Dalton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person155" type="given" value="Ann"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person155" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . As I and my husband were sitting in the back room, some person said, Mrs. Dalton what have you lost? I said, I don't know that I have lost any thing; they said I had; and with that I went to them and found a black silk apron: I went into the next room, and said to my husband, Lord have mercy upon me, how came this apron here? And my husband said, It is carelessness in you not to keep your drawers fast; upon that I went up stairs, and pulled the latch of the door, but could not readily get it open. When I did, the candle was out, and I said; Who is there? what is the matter? And the maid answered, Nobody but me, Madam. Then said I, What have you done? what is the matter? there is fire in the room. And I said, For God's sake, go down and light the candle as quick as possible; but, she staying some time, I called out for somebody to come up stairs; which they did, and went to the bed side, and the bed was tucked in very close; and we pulled off the sheets and blankets, and found it all on fire; and one of the men looked at the drawers, and saw they were in a smoke, and took out one of the drawers, and turned out the things, and they were on fire; here are the remains of several things that were on fire; and there were in the drawers before, three pair of double ruffles, a gauze handkerchief, one black silk handkerchief, one flowered linen one, and three large silver table<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176202240012"></xptr> spoons; so looking over the things that were left, I said, Lord have mercy upon me, what signifies what is left, so many things are lost! At this juncture, Mr. Bradfield, sitting in the house, said, here is something pick'd up since you went up stairs; that was one pair of ruffles and one yard of plain muslin.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do upon this?</p>
               <p>A. Dalton. I was quite unhappy about it, finding my sheets and linen burnt, and many things lost, and I could not hear where the girl was, till my husband, by much inquiry, found her, and took her before Justice Fielding for examination.</p>
               <p>Q. In the course of that examination, did you find out any of the other things you lost?</p>
               <p>A. Dalton. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was the person who told you a little girl had picked up some things at the door?</p>
               <p>A. Dalton. Mr. Bradfield.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you know where the prisoner's father lived?</p>
               <p>A. Dalton. I did not at that time; I took her upon her uncle's account.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go to Mr. Kelley's to inquire for her that night?</p>
               <p>A. Dalton. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray now, good woman, when you heard where the father's house was, why did not you search his house next morning?</p>
               <p>A. Dalton. I really did not know; I believe her father's house was searched some time the next day.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-person156">
                  Hannah 
                  Abram 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person156" type="surname" value="Abram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person156" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person156" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            .</p>
               <p>Q. How old are you?</p>
               <p>H. Abram. Turned of fourteen.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the nature of an oath?</p>
               <p>H. Abram. I believe I shall be punished in another world, if I don't speak the truth. I was going of an errand, and I saw a girl coming out of Mr. Dalton's, who dropt a yard of new muslin and a plain double ruffle.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know the person who dropt it?</p>
               <p>H. Abram. No, I do not.</p>
               <p>Q. Was she coming out in a hurry, or leisurely.</p>

               <p>H. Abram. She came out hastily.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you offer to stop her, or ask her any questions?</p>
               <p>H. Abram. No.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you do with the things she dropt, and you pick'd up?</p>
               <p>H. Abram. I carried them into the house, and gave them to Mr. Bradfield.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known Mr. Dalton?</p>
               <p>H. Abram. Very lately.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-person157">
                  Samuel 
                  Bradfield 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person157" type="surname" value="Bradfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person157" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person157" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at Mr. Dalton's the 10th of February in the evening, and I heard a tumult in the tap-room; and this girl, coming in, asked for the mistress, and she said a young woman that went out had dropt some things.</p>
               <p>Q. Pray, Mrs. Dalton, when did you see the things, and where, the last time before that?</p>
               <p>A. Dalton. In my upper drawer.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-person158">
                  Samuel 
                  Bradfield 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person158" type="surname" value="Bradfield"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person158" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person158" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             cross-examined.</p>
               <p>When 
               <persName id="t17620224-11-person159">
                  Hannah 
                  Abram 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person159" type="surname" value="Abram"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person159" type="given" value="Hannah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person159" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
             asked for the mistress, and said a young woman that went out had dropt some things, did you see a young woman go out?</p>
               <p>Bradfield. I heard her go out.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure it was her?</p>
               <p>Bradfield. No, I am not.</p>
               <p>- Brenton. I was at Mr. Dalton's about six or seven o'clock, sitting in the tap-room, and I heard an uncommon noise of the girl's running down stairs, and she ran through the tap-room with something in her apron.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you see her.</p>
               <p>Brenton. I saw her running by me out of the door, my Lord, and just after she had ran by me a man pick'd up a black silk apron; soon after that I heard Mrs. Dalton cry out, that the house was on fire: then I ran up stairs in order to put it out. When I came there I found three upper drawers on fire, and Mr. Dalton putting it out in the bedcloaths. One of the witnesses ran and fetched some water, and we took the things out of the drawers, and dipt them in it, in order to put out the fire.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the prisoner in the house?</p>
               <p>Brenton. No, she was gone about three minutes before, and never came back any more till she was brought back.</p>
               <p>Q. When was it the black silk apron was found? Was it before or after the girl came running down?</p>

               <p>Brenton. Upon her running down, she dropt it going out of the door.</p>
               <p>Q. Are you sure the black silk apron was not found before she came running down stairs?</p>
               <p>Brenton. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you remember any thing being said to Mrs. Dalton about the apron?</p>
               <p>Brenton. Not till after the girl was out of the house?</p>
               <p>Q. Upon what occasion did Mrs. Dalton go up stairs?</p>
               <p>Brenton. Mrs. Dalton called to the girl, and she made no answer; then she went up stairs, and found the room on fire.</p>
               <p>Q. Just after the girl was gone, and the apron found, did any-body call in, saying, I saw a ruffle drop'd, and I pick'd it up.</p>
               <p>Brenton. Yes.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you in the room when it was delivered?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176202240013"></xptr>Brenton. I was.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober at that time?</p>

               <p>Brenton. As sober as a judge.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you up in the room at all?</p>
               <p>Brenton. Yes, and assisted at putting the fire out.</p>
               <p>Q. Was the discovery made by the girl after the fire was put out or before?</p>
               <p>Brenton. The apron was before; but I cannot say whether the ruffle was found before or not.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the first alarm?</p>
               <p>Brenton. The girl's coming down stairs in a great hurry, and dropping something which appeared to be this apron; and soon after a girl brought in the muslin ruffle and some muslin.</p>
               <p>[Court observed this witness plainly mistook in giving his evidence].</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-person160">
                  William 
                  Belton 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person160" type="surname" value="Belton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person160" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person160" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I saw the apron dropt at the foot of the stairs. I was in the tap-room at the time, and I called out, that I had found a black apron.</p>
               <p>Q. Was there any alarm of fire just at that time?</p>
               <p>Belton. Yes, and I went up to put it out; and when I came up the master shoved the girl down stairs.</p>
               <p>Court. If I understand you right, you found the black apron dropt at the foot of the stairs before the girl, being shoved by the master, came running down stairs and ran out of doors.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I never stole any thing from them.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>Mrs. Osborn. I have known her about eight years; she was always a very honest girl, for any thing I knew, and I would take her into my house as a servant to-morrow if I wanted one.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-person161">
                  Rowland 
                  Wenfleet 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person161" type="surname" value="Wenfleet"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person161" type="given" value="Rowland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person161" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have know her many years; she was in my house three years, and was intrusted with every thing there, and I never found her dishonest.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-person162">
                  Margaret 
                  Cowlin 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person162" type="surname" value="Cowlin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person162" type="given" value="Margaret"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person162" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known her ever since she was born; she had very honest parents, and she always bore a good character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-person163">
                  John 
                  Mering 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person163" type="surname" value="Mering"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person163" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person163" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             deposed to the same effect.</p>
               <p>Mr. Kelley said, she resided at his house when out of place, and he had not the least doubt of her honesty.</p>
               <p>- Kelly deposed, that, when his house was searched and she not there, she went and surrendered herself, and readily went before the Justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-person164">
                  William 
                  Cowlin 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person164" type="surname" value="Cowlin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person164" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person164" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             also said, that he had known her these ten years, that she was a very honest girl to the best of his knowledge; and that, when she was inquired after on account of this charge, she was not at all averse to going before the Justice.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17620224-11-person165">
                  William 
                  Kegin 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person165" type="surname" value="Kegin"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person165" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person165" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17620224-11-person166">
                  Mary 
                  Hayden 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person166" type="surname" value="Hayden"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person166" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person166" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , 
               <persName id="t17620224-11-person167">
                  Mary 
                  Peachy 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person167" type="surname" value="Peachy"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person167" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person167" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and 
               <persName id="t17620224-11-person168">
                  Mary 
                  Skiers 
               <interp inst="t17620224-11-person168" type="surname" value="Skiers"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person168" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-person168" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , likewise appeared on her behalf, and gave her a good character.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17620224-11-verdict59" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-verdict59" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>The prisoner was farther arraigned for <rs id="t17620224-11-off60" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-off60" type="offenceCategory" value="damage"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-off60" type="offenceSubcategory" value="arson"></interp>
               setting fire to a part of the house
            </rs>; but as neither Mr. Dalton, nor any other evidence, gave any proof of any part of the house being burned, the Court was of opinion that she should be acquitted of that indictment, and she was thereupon <rs id="t17620224-11-verdict61" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17620224-11-verdict61" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               acquitted
            </rs>. Then the Judge reprehended her conduct, and recommended it to her relations to take better care of her.</p>
            </div1>
