<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680413-30">
               <interp inst="t17680413-30" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-30" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-30" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680413"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-30" type="date" value="17680413"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680413-30-off158-c212" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-30-defend270 t17680413-30-off158 t17680413-30-verdict163"></join>
         
               <p>284. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680413-30-defend270" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Sheridan 
                  <interp inst="t17680413-30-defend270" type="surname" value="Sheridan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-defend270" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-defend270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17680413-30-off158" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-off158" type="offenceCategory" value="sexual"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-off158" type="offenceSubcategory" value="rape"></interp>
               committing a rape on the body of 
                     
                        <persName id="t17680413-30-victim272" type="victimName">
                           Mary 
                           Brickinshaw 
                        <interp inst="t17680413-30-victim272" type="surname" value="Brickinshaw"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680413-30-victim272" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680413-30-victim272" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-30-off158 t17680413-30-victim272"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                  
               
                  </rs>, <rs id="t17680413-30-cd159" type="crimeDate">March 22</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-30-off158 t17680413-30-cd159"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-30-person273">
                  Mary 
                  Brickinshaw 
               <interp inst="t17680413-30-person273" type="surname" value="Brickinshaw"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person273" type="given" value="Mary"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person273" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am not quite twenty years of age; I am <rs id="t17680413-30-viclabel160" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-30-victim272 t17680413-30-viclabel160"></join> to Mr. Roberts, he keeps an inn at Hammersmith.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you lived with him?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. A little better than half a year.</p>
               <p>Q. How long have you known the prisoner?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. I have known him ever since I have been there; he lived next door to where I live.</p>
               <p>Q. What is he?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. He is a <rs id="t17680413-30-deflabel161" type="occupation">journeyman baker</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-30-defend270 t17680413-30-deflabel161"></join>.</p>
               <p>Q. Is he a single or a married man?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. He is a single man for what I know.</p>
               <p>Court. Give an account of what you have to say against him.</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. I was going out with a pot of beer one Tuesday night about a month ago, about eight o'clock; I did not know the house or the person to whom I was carrying it; I met the prisoner and said, I am going to such a place, can you tell where it is; he said no, the best way will be to go to such a shop and ask; I did, and was directed, and went and delivered the beer; coming back, the prisoner came and catched me round my waist, and pulled me down a lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Where was this?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. This was in the town of <placeName id="t17680413-30-crimeloc162">Hammersmith</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680413-30-crimeloc162" type="placeName" value="Hammersmith"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680413-30-crimeloc162" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-30-off158 t17680413-30-crimeloc162"></join>; I went to cry out; he put his hand on my mouth, and took me half way down the lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any houses down the lane?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176804130016"></xptr>M. Brickinshaw. No, there were not; then he insisted on lying with me; I told him he should not; he said he would; he put his legs between mine, and threw me down, and lay with me.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he his clothes on?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. He had.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you your petticoats on?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. I had.</p>
               <p>Court. You must be a little more particular.</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. He drawed my petticoats up.</p>
               <p>Q. What more did he do?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. He put his thing into me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you consent to that?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. I endeavoured to prevent him as much as I could.</p>
               <p>Q. How long did he keep it in you?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. It might be two or three minutes.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you feel any thing come from him?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, there was blood came from me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you cry out?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. I made as much noise as I could.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body come by, or pull him up?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, he got up of himself, he lay with me after that.</p>
               <p>Q. How long after?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. It may be a quarter of an hour, or half an hour; he dragged me out of that lane into another.</p>
               <p>Q. Was that nearer the town, or farther off?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. It was nearer the town.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any houses there?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No.</p>
               <p>Q. Did no body come by all the time?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No; when in that lane, he insisted upon lying with me again; I had not strength left to struggle as before.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you coment?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. How did he get you down, or did you lie down?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. Then he put his legs between mine, and put me down as before; after that he got up, and helped me up in his arms; he asked me then if I would forgive him; I said no, I would not; he asked me if I would kiss him; I said no, I would not kiss him nor forgive him.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he say to that?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. He said then he could not help it; he turned down the lane, and I came home; I found our house full of people; I could not tell my mistress directly, but I told her as soon as the company was gone.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the evening was that?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. That was I believe after nine o'clock.</p>
               <p>Q. Did your mistress ask you where you had been at your coming home?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. She did, and what was the occasion of my staying so long; I told her I could not find the house, because I was ashamed to tell what had happened then, but I told her as soon as the company was gone, which was before ten o'clock; then she and I went to the prisoner's master's house; we saw the master and mistress, they said he was gone to bed; I went for a warrant the next morning to Sir 
               <persName id="t17680413-30-person274">
                  John 
                  Fielding 
               <interp inst="t17680413-30-person274" type="surname" value="Fielding"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person274" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person274" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , and the prisoner was taken up that day, which was the Wednesday in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. When did your master know of it?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. He knew of it the night it was done, my mistress told him.</p>
               <p>Cross examination.</p>
               <p>Q. What time was it you met the prisoner in the street?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. About half an hour after seven o'clock, but I cannot say exactly.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might you be out of your master's house?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. It might be three quarters of an hour.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you never been with beer to that house before?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, I never had.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not desire the prisoner to shew you the lane?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, I did not, the house I was going to was in a little passage.</p>
               <p>Q. Which side of the way is that passage?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. It is on the same side the way the lane is on.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you go by yourself with the beer?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. I did.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not go willingly down the lane?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, he laid hold round my waist, and turned me towards the lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Were not you and he intimate before?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. I never had any thing to say to him in my life, I knew him very well.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to make some noise?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. I did, and he clapped his hand before my mouth directly, and kept it so till half way down the lane; it is a little bye-lane, it was a good distance down the lane.</p>
               <p>Q. Was his hand on your mouth when he declared he would lie with you?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, it was not.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176804130017"></xptr>Q. Why did you not call out then?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. If I had, no body could hear me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might you converse together before he tripped up your heels?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. A good while, for I refused, and would not let him.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the conversation not hold near a quarter of an hour?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, It did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not a person come by, upon which you both started up?</p>
               <p>M. Brackish. No, no body came by.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you make any resistance while you were going to the other lane?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. I did; I did not know what to do, he cursed and swore enough to fright me out of my wits; he told me if I called out, people would hear me; it was by his persuasion I did not call out.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was it between the first and second time?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. It might be a quarter of an hour or more.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to tell your mistress of this?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. When the people were gone away, one Mr. Banks, a customer, was the last in the house; going out he attempted to kiss me, I would not let him; my mistress said to me, what makes you look so scornful; then after he was gone I told her of it.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not made declaration, that you should not have told it to your master or mistress, had they not taxed you with staying out so long?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, I never did say so.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not declared you would not have prosecuted, had it not been for your master and mistress?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, I never did.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you not been to see the prisoner since he was in confinement?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. I went to him yesterday morning in prison.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you to go?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. He sent for me, and that he wanted to speak to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Did any body go with you?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No.</p>
               <p>Court. Were there people in the room with him?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. There were.</p>
               <p>Court. Upon your oath tell what passed between you and him.</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. He said to me, will you swear my life away; and said if I would take what money he offered me I should have it.</p>
               <p>Q. What did he offer you?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. He offered me five guineas.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he the money in his hand?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, he said it should be put into a person's hand for me.</p>
               <p>Q. Was any thing else said?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. He said he would have me if I would have him, and he would use me well; as to having him, I said I never will.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you not say you was afraid of marrying him, on the account of having sworn against him?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you or did you not at that time say, you never intended to hurt a hair of his head, and hoped you should not?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, I never did; he said he hoped I would not take his life away; I told him I would not spare him an inch, if I knew it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-30-person275">
                  Thomas 
                  Roberts 
               <interp inst="t17680413-30-person275" type="surname" value="Roberts"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person275" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person275" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am master to the young woman; I first heard of her being ill used by the prisoner at almost ten o'clock that night; she confessed, as soon as the house was clear, what had happened; I had sent her to Mrs. Bevan's with beer, between seven and eight I believe in the evening; I believe she might be out half an hour or three quarters; when she came back, we asked her where she had been so long; she made some little slow answer, I think she said she could not readily find the place; as soon as the company was all gone out of the house but me and my wife, while I went into the cellar she fell a crying, and told my wife what had happened; when I came up I was informed of it, she then gave us the same account as she has now.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say he had twice lain with her?</p>
               <p>Roberts. She did, that he threw her down in both the lanes, and lay with her.</p>
               <p>Q. Are there any houses in the lanes?</p>
               <p>Roberts. No, there are not, and in the night-time there are very few people go through them; the prisoner lives next door to me.</p>
               <p>Q. How long has the girl lived with you?</p>
               <p>Roberts. A little above half a year.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, during the time she has lived with you, have you perceived any thing loose in her behaviour, have you any reason to suspect she would suffer people to lie with her?</p>
               <p>Roberts. No, I never had a suspicion of her, I look upon her to be a sober honest girl as any is; I never believed she would condescend to any body.</p>
               <p>Q. Have you any reason to believe this man at the bar used any familiarity with her, so as to kiss her?</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176804130018"></xptr>Roberts. No, I never had any reason to believe it in my life.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he used to come to your house often?</p>
               <p>Roberts. He has come once or twice a day sometimes; I never saw nothing between them.</p>
               <p>Q. Were there any quarrel between you and him?</p>
               <p>Roberts. No, I never had any quarrel with him or his master.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you advise the girl to prosecute?</p>
               <p>Roberts. It was her own doing; she went in the morning of her own will for the warrant, I did not discourage her in doing it; she was willing and desirous to prosecute him; if she had not of her own accord, I should have advised her to do it; I should not have been willing to have put up with them things in my house.</p>
               <p>Q. Did not you threaten her if she did not prosecute?</p>
               <p>Roberts. No, I did not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-30-person276">
                  Thomas 
                  Harvest 
               <interp inst="t17680413-30-person276" type="surname" value="Harvest"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person276" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person276" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a surgeon, and live at Hammersmith; I was sent for to the Justice, the day following the act, to look at this young girl; I searched her, I did not see any particular act of violence; there was some little laceration, and some hemorrhage, that might be from coition, this I believe proceeded from the laceration; I believe he had entered the vagina; I believe from the straitness of the passage, and the violence that had been used, the hemorrhage might ensue.</p>
               <p>Q. Could these appearances be on a woman that had been lain with before?</p>
               <p>Harvest. They might; we could not expect to see any great marks of violence upon a person of her age.</p>
               <p>Q. May not the hymen be broke of a woman that has not been lain with?</p>
               <p>Harvest. I believe it may, and often has been, by a great many circumstances.</p>
               <p>Q. Supposing that had been broke, could you discover whether it had been lately, or of any time standing before?</p>
               <p>Harvest. I believe that could not be discovered, the passage was very small; I really believe she had not been lain with by any man before; I was desired to examine the prisoner before the Justice, he had got the lues upon him to a high degree.</p>
               <p>Q. Had the girl any appearance of it?</p>
               <p>Harvest. No, she had not; I believe he has had the disease upon him a considerable time; I have some reason to think, by taking medicines, in some measure the violence was taken off, it was quite a pox; he had had a gonorrhoea before, but that was entirely stopt, it was only the external virus that he complained of; some time a man may have a lues upon him, and not communicate the disease; it might, or it might not.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-30-person277">
                  Thomas 
                  Daniel 
               <interp inst="t17680413-30-person277" type="surname" value="Daniel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person277" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person277" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was along with Mr. Harvest before the Justice; we examined the prisoner first, and found several little waits upon him; we acquainted the Justice with our opinions; at that time we examined the girl and found -</p>
               <p>Q. You have heard the account the other surgeon has given?</p>
               <p>Daniel. I have; he has given the just account, as to the prisoner and the girl; the girl made some little complaint after that, and did not walk so well as usual; I gave her some medicine, by way of prevention, but there was no appearance that the distemper had communicated.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>Betwixt seven and eight I met with the girl, with a pot of beer; she asked where the person lived; I said I did not know: she said, if you will come with me I'll come home with you; I went with her, and desired her to enquire the house at the farrier's shop; we walked together; when we came to the end of the lane, I asked her to come down the lane; when we came down the lane, I asked her to do so and so; she said I should not till we came to the corner; I said this is the best place; I laid her down, she never said a word against it, and after that I shook the dust off her gown and cloak; when we came to another place, I laid her down again, and did the same; she never said a word, nor cried; there was a person ran by, who it was I do not know; here is another person here, that was concerned with her as well as I.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-30-person278">
                  John 
                  Gregory 
               <interp inst="t17680413-30-person278" type="surname" value="Gregory"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person278" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person278" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was in the Bail-dock to see the prisoner.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you the person that went for the girl?</p>
               <p>Gregory. No, I was not.</p>
               <p>Q. Do you know what character the prisoner bears at Hammersmith?</p>
               <p>Gregory. I never heard any thing against him; he bears a general good character, as far as ever I heard.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-30-person279">
                  Thomas 
                  Cumerford 
               <interp inst="t17680413-30-person279" type="surname" value="Cumerford"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person279" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-person279" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have been to the girl's master, and I spoke to the girl; she said she did not want to hurt a hair of his head, it was what she was encouraged to do.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say by who?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. Who was by at the time?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. There was no body hearing our discourse but myself.</p>
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176804130019"></xptr>Q. What did you go to her for?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. I spoke to her, to see if she would make it up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he desire you to make it up?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. No, I never saw him at that time; I spoke to the girl, and asked her if she would let the young man out, and make it up.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she tell you she would?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. This was entirely to ask her how much money she would take.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you the money?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. I had not.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she consent to make it up?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. She said she did not want to hurt a hair of his head.</p>
               <p>Q. What day was this?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. This was the day of the election at Brentford.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she say she was willing to make it up?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. She did not.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not you offer her some money?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. I had none.</p>
               <p>Q. Was this application to her from humanity, or by the desire of the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. No, I had not seen him; I wanted to see if she was willing to make it up, that other people might do it.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she appear willing?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. I thought she did.</p>
               <p>Q. Then who did you apply to?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. To them that had no more money than myself.</p>
               <p>Q. What countryman are you?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. I am an Irishman.</p>
               <p>Q. What country is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. An Irishman.</p>
               <p>Q. Had he no money?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. I cannot tell.</p>
               <p>Q. What were the first words you said to her?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. I cannot tell indeed; the master came in the way, and she got out of the way when he was coming; we had not two words at a time; the girl was not willing to be seen speaking to me.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did you not ask her how much money she would take?</p>
               <p>Cumerford. I did not think about making it up, I did not ask her any such thing; and another thing was, I had no money.</p>
               <p>Q. to Breckinshaw. What conversation passed between you and this witness, in regard to this affair?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. I never saw this man till he came to our house the day of the election, he was drinking there; I was not very well, and could not go down into the cellar to draw any beer all the day, I sat in the kitchen with my cloak on; this man was in the parlour, he asked where Sheridan was, that was all that past.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. Yes, upon my oath.</p>
               <p>Q. Did you say to him, you did not desire to hurt a hair of the prisoner's head?</p>
               <p>M. Brickinshaw. No, I did not; I went into the room where he was but once all the time he was there.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680413-30-verdict163" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-verdict163" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17680413-30-punish164" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-30-punish164" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-30-defend270 t17680413-30-punish164"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
