<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17661217-48">
               <interp inst="t17661217-48" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-48" type="year" value="1766"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-48" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17661217"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17661217-48" type="date" value="17661217"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17661217-48-off245-c378" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-48-defend487 t17661217-48-off245 t17661217-48-verdict249"></join>
         
               <p>61. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-48-defend487" type="defendantName">
                     William 
                     Hern 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-48-defend487" type="surname" value="Hern"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-defend487" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-defend487" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17661217-48-off245" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-off245" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-off245" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a copper vessel, value 18 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17661217-48-victim489" type="victimName">
                     John 
                     Wolgar 
                  <interp inst="t17661217-48-victim489" type="surname" value="Wolgar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-victim489" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-victim489" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-48-off245 t17661217-48-victim489"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17661217-48-cd246" type="crimeDate">Dec. 16</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-48-off245 t17661217-48-cd246"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-48-person490">
                  John 
                  Wolgar 
               <interp inst="t17661217-48-person490" type="surname" value="Wolgar"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-person490" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-person490" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17661217-48-viclabel247" type="occupation">brazier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-48-victim489 t17661217-48-viclabel247"></join>, and live in <placeName id="t17661217-48-crimeloc248">the Minories</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-48-crimeloc248" type="placeName" value="the Minories"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17661217-48-crimeloc248" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17661217-48-off245 t17661217-48-crimeloc248"></join>; I lost a copper vessel last Saturday from my shop; I found it again at Mr. Wooden's, in Whitechapel; (produced in court and deposed to.) I asked him where he got it; he told me, of the prisoner at the bar.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wooden. I am a brazier; I bought this copper of the prisoner at the bar, Dec. 16. about three o'clock in the afternoon; I gave him 30 s. for it; I had known him four or five years.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>I have a mother lives at Mile-end; she was dying; I was going to see her last Saturday, about three o'clock; I met a man and a woman facing the New-road; the man asked me, if I could tell him where lived a coppersmith or a brasier; I told him, there was one just by, and I went with him to Mr. Wooden's; he asked me, if I would take and sell it for him, as I knew the man, I took and sold it; and when so done, I laid part of the money out in some things as he desired; I bought two pair of candlesticks, a candle-box, and a coffee-pot: I was to meet the man in Bell-yard, Whitechapel, or at the sign of the Halfmoon, if he was gone; I went and met him and his wife, and carried the things and the remainder of the money, which I believe were three half-crowns, and gave them to him; the man asked me where I lived; I told him in Spital-fields,<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176612170039"></xptr> but was going to Mile-end to see my mother; he said, he was going there too; we went to the Black-boy; he treated me there with two pints of beer; he told me, if I would meet him there, on the Tuesday following, he had some other things; I went, thinking to meet the man, and the gentleman came and told me, the copper he had bought of me was stolen. I went with his servant to the Black-boy, to meet the man, and asked at the house if such a man had been there, and I was told, no; we had a pint of beer there, and waited, expecting the man would come, but he never came near the place.</p>
               <p>For the prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-48-person491">
                  Samuel 
                  Cope 
               <interp inst="t17661217-48-person491" type="surname" value="Cope"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-person491" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-person491" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live at Mr. Garsed's, in Wood-street; the prisoner works for him, and has for some time past, as a gauze-weaver; we always looked upon him as a very honest man; he brought his work home very constantly.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17661217-48-person492">
                  James Lewis 
                  Dissemore 
               <interp inst="t17661217-48-person492" type="surname" value="Dissemore"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-person492" type="given" value="James Lewis"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-person492" type="gender" value="indeterminate"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . The prisoner is a tenant under my father; he is a very honest man, as far as we have heard of him; he has three or four children.</p>
               <p>Q. What can he get a week by his business?</p>
               <p>Cope. He can get 14 or 16 s. a week.</p>
               <p>Mr. Wooden. I apprehended him on the Tuesday, almost by my house; I charged him with the copper being stolen, and stopped him; the man was very willing to go with me to see for the man that he pretends stole the copper, if he could have found him; I sent my man with him to Mile-end.</p>
               <p>Q. What do you say to his character.</p>
               <p>Wooden. I never knew any thing dishonest of him; I have known him four or five years.</p>
               <p>Mr. Thompson. I live next door to the prisoner. I have known him twelve months; I never knew any harm of him; he is a sober man for any thing I ever saw.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17661217-48-verdict249" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17661217-48-verdict249" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
