<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17640912-28">
               <interp inst="t17640912-28" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-28" type="year" value="1764"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-28" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17640912"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17640912-28" type="date" value="17640912"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17640912-28-off154-c214" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-28-defend265 t17640912-28-off154 t17640912-28-verdict159"></join>
         
               <p>506. (M.) 
               <persName id="t17640912-28-defend265" type="defendantName">
                  William 
                  Hill 
               <interp inst="t17640912-28-defend265" type="surname" value="Hill"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-defend265" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-defend265" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             was indicted, for that <rs id="t17640912-28-off154" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-off154" type="offenceCategory" value="violentTheft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-off154" type="offenceSubcategory" value="highwayRobbery"></interp>
               he, on the King's highway, on 
                     
                        <persName id="t17640912-28-victim267" type="victimName">
                           William 
                           King 
                        <interp inst="t17640912-28-victim267" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-28-victim267" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17640912-28-victim267" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                        <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-28-off154 t17640912-28-victim267"></join>
                     </persName>
                      
                   did make an assault, putting him in corporal fear and danger of his life, and violently taking 2 s. in money numbered, from his person, his property
            </rs>, <rs id="t17640912-28-cd155" type="crimeDate">July 29</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-28-off154 t17640912-28-cd155"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-28-person268">
                  William 
                  King 
               <interp inst="t17640912-28-person268" type="surname" value="King"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-person268" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-person268" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 29th of July, I was going to the Duke of Leeds's; and between Kitt's End and <placeName id="t17640912-28-crimeloc156">Mim's Wash</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-28-crimeloc156" type="placeName" value="Mim's Wash"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17640912-28-crimeloc156" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-28-off154 t17640912-28-crimeloc156"></join>, the prisoner was going the same way as I was, down the hill to the Wash: we were talking about the weather; I would fain have gone from him, not liking his appearance. When we got to the Wash, he turned quick upon me, got before me, and drew a knife, collared me, and demanded my money; he swore he would murder me, if I did not give him all my money. I said I had but two shillings, and that I would give him as soon as I could: I took two shillings out of my pocket and gave him: then he said, You have more. I said, I have no more, but a few halfpence; and took them out, which were four; he would not take them; then he swore he would cut my throat, if I did not give him my watch. I told him I never travelled with one; then he swore he would murder me, if I did not go back; and shortened his arm, in which he held his knife, as if he was going to stab me. I said, Why should you make me go back? let me go on my journey; I have given you all my money. He said, Go back, that I may go by. I understood by that, that he might go, and I not see him: so I turned my back, and he went away: then I went on to a little ale-house at the farther end of the Wash, and called for a pennyworth of beer. While I was standing at the door, the prisoner came by; he looked me in the face, and said, Come along, come along; as if we had been acquainted: I did not know but he might be before me, till I saw him; I was more frighted then, by seeing him so audacious; and was afraid to take notice that I had been robbed there, because I saw only a little slight man and an old woman: I then waited till there came a post chaise, and people in it: I ran down the road, and desired they would let me go in it to near the turnpike: when I got in the chaise, I told them I had been robbed, and described the person: they said they were certain they should know him by my description; they put me down short of the turnpike, and went on a little farther in the town, and there took him, and sent for me: as soon as I heard his voice, I knew him; I am certain the prisoner is the man.</p>
               <p>Q. What time of the day was you robbed?</p>
               <p>King. It was between 6 and 7 in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>Q. What are you?</p>
               <p>King. I am a <rs id="t17640912-28-viclabel157" type="occupation">limner</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-28-victim267 t17640912-28-viclabel157"></join>, and live at Totteridge.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-28-person269">
                  Thomas 
                  Gayton 
               <interp inst="t17640912-28-person269" type="surname" value="Gayton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-person269" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-person269" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the driver of the post-chaise, and took Mr. King up at the farther end of Mims-wash; he said he had been robbed by a person, in a grey coat, black waistcoat, a clean pair of breeches, a soldier's hat cocked up, a tall young fellow in his own hair, pitted with the small-pox: I set Mr. King down by the turnpike, and found the prisoner at the Green Dragon door. He was in the house, hanging over the hatch; I said to the person in the chaise, this is the man: I went to him, and asked how far he was going? he said to Hatfield: I said, that is not the way. He said, will you drink? and gave me the mug in my hand: I got a constable, and he came and took the prisoner. He was searched, and 2 s. and this knife found in his pocket, (Producing a clasp knife.)</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I believe this is the knife the prisoner held to me.</p>
               <p>Mr. Gidens. I am a constable. I searched the prisoner, and found 2 s. and this knife upon him: when Mr. King came, and said the prisoner was the man that robbed him, the prisoner did not deny it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17640912-28-person270">
                  Henry 
                  Ansell 
               <interp inst="t17640912-28-person270" type="surname" value="Ansell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-person270" type="given" value="Henry"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-person270" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I was at the taking the prisoner: I saw him searched, and two shillings and this knife were found upon him.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>It is very false. I met the man that I believe did rob him. He asked me if I would change<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176409120020"></xptr> cloaths with him, and he would give me 2 s. to boot; so I changed. I am a <rs id="t17640912-28-deflabel158" type="occupation">soldier</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-28-defend265 t17640912-28-deflabel158"></join>, and my friends live in Yorkshire; so I have nobody to appear for me.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17640912-28-verdict159" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-verdict159" type="verdictCategory" value="guilty"></interp>
               Guilty
            </rs>. <rs id="t17640912-28-punish160" type="punishmentDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17640912-28-punish160" type="punishmentCategory" value="death"></interp>
                     <join result="defendantPunishment" targOrder="Y" targets="t17640912-28-defend265 t17640912-28-punish160"></join>
               Death
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
