<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17600521-27">
               <interp inst="t17600521-27" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-27" type="year" value="1760"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-27" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17600521"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17600521-27" type="date" value="17600521"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17600521-27-off136-c241" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-27-defend296 t17600521-27-off136 t17600521-27-verdict140"></join>
         
               <p>204. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17600521-27-defend296" type="defendantName">
                     Thomas 
                     Powell 
                  <interp inst="t17600521-27-defend296" type="surname" value="Powell"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-defend296" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-defend296" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17600521-27-off136" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-off136" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-off136" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one silver watch, value 20 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               <persName id="t17600521-27-victim297" type="victimName">
                  Thomas 
                  Green 
               <interp inst="t17600521-27-victim297" type="surname" value="Green"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-victim297" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-victim297" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-27-off136 t17600521-27-victim297"></join>
                  </persName>
             , <rs id="t17600521-27-cd137" type="crimeDate">April 28</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-27-off136 t17600521-27-cd137"></join>.*</p> 
               <p>Thomas Green. On a saturday, a month or 5 weeks ago, I lay at <placeName id="t17600521-27-crimeloc138">the George in Holborn</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17600521-27-crimeloc138" type="placeName" value="the George in Holborn"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17600521-27-crimeloc138" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-27-off136 t17600521-27-crimeloc138"></join>, along with a young man, my acquaintance; when I went to bed I put my watch under the bed, and when I got up in the morning it was gone, there was another bed in the room; when I said it was gone, a person in that other bed, name Learner, said to me, if you have lost a watch, starting up in the bed, then I can tell you the man that has got it; he got up, and when we were below stairs, he said, it was the prisoner at the bar; we took him before justice Welch, but there he denied it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Green. He is <rs id="t17600521-27-deflabel139" type="occupation">waiter</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17600521-27-defend296 t17600521-27-deflabel139"></join>; the George is a nighthouse; I know no more than what that evidence told me; I never found it again.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-27-person298">
                  William 
                  Learner 
               <interp inst="t17600521-27-person298" type="surname" value="Learner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-person298" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-person298" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a journeyman baker, I came out of the country to seek for business, and had been in London but 5 days; I had been at the 3 compasses, a house of call, one 
               <persName id="t17600521-27-person299">
                  Thomas 
                  Parker 
               <interp inst="t17600521-27-person299" type="surname" value="Parker"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-person299" type="given" value="Thomas"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-person299" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
             took me to the green Dragon in York Buildings to lie there; but we staid till half an hour after eleven and I could not have a bed there, I was forced to look farther; then he brought me to the George in Holborn, there I went to bed about 2 o'clock; the prosecutor and his friend came to bed about half an hour after, and lay in another bed in the same room; I was very uneasy, and could not sleep; after they were in bed, I heard them talk; in the morning when they got up, Mr. Green said to his friend he had lost his watch; I said then I know who has got it, for I saw the<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176005210035"></xptr> drawer, that is the prisoner at the bar, stoop at the feet of the bed, he took up something, I did not see what, but if it was a watch it had got a chain to it, for I heard a chain rattle; this was between 3 and 4 o'clock, when he came up to put another man to bed.</p>
               <p>Q. to Green. What part of the bed did you put your watch under?</p>
               <p>Green. Under the foot of the bed, quite close to the wall.</p>
               <p>Q. Did the prisoner ever confess any thing?</p>
               <p>Green. No.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>I lighted the evidence to bed, and left the light along with him; some considerable time afterwards came Mr. Green and his friend, they ask'd master for a bed; I lighted them up to bed, the other gentleman ask'd me if I could let him have a cap, I said it was not a customary thing in a night-house, I said I would go down and see; he said you need not to give yourself the trouble, I have a handkerchief, he pull'd one out; he had been at the play and it was wetted, he having had a bottle of wine or punch which broke in his pockets; said he lend me your's; I said I had lent 2 and lost them both; said he if I lose it I'll give you 15 s. for it; I lent it him and went down, wishing him a good repose; I saw no watch then, nor in the morning; there was a man came that frequently lies at our house; he said he belonged to the militia, he ask'd for a light to go to bed, and he went up stairs, and came down in about 15 minutes, and said, your beds are all full; I said there is half a bed in the garret; I lighted him up, and he made some objections there and would not stay; I am a Herefordshire man.</p>
               <p>For the Prisoner.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-27-person300">
                  James 
                  Swindall 
               <interp inst="t17600521-27-person300" type="surname" value="Swindall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-person300" type="given" value="James"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-person300" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known the prisoner about 3 months, he is now my servant, I never knew any thing of him but that of an honest man, he has behav'd honest and diligent.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-27-person301">
                  Wm 
                  Lorg 
               <interp inst="t17600521-27-person301" type="surname" value="Lorg"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-person301" type="given" value="Wm"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-person301" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about 3 months, I never heard any thing of him but what was good.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17600521-27-person302">
                  Robt 
                  Turner 
               <interp inst="t17600521-27-person302" type="surname" value="Turner"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-person302" type="given" value="Robt"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-person302" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I have known him about three months, I never heard any otherwise of him but that of an honest man.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17600521-27-verdict140" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17600521-27-verdict140" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
