<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17650417-40">
               <interp inst="t17650417-40" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-40" type="year" value="1765"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-40" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17650417"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17650417-40" type="date" value="17650417"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17650417-40-off226-c283" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-40-defend364 t17650417-40-off226 t17650417-40-verdict230"></join>
         
               <p>260. (M.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-40-defend364" type="defendantName">
                     John 
                     Bryan 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-40-defend364" type="surname" value="Bryan"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-40-defend364" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-40-defend364" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
               
             was indicted for <rs id="t17650417-40-off226" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-40-off226" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-40-off226" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing one hundred pounds weight of iron, value 4 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17650417-40-victim366" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Smith 
                  <interp inst="t17650417-40-victim366" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-40-victim366" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-40-victim366" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-40-off226 t17650417-40-victim366"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17650417-40-cd227" type="crimeDate">January 20</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-40-off226 t17650417-40-cd227"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17650417-40-person367">
                  William 
                  Smith 
               <interp inst="t17650417-40-person367" type="surname" value="Smith"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-40-person367" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17650417-40-person367" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17650417-40-viclabel228" type="occupation">bricklayer</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-40-victim366 t17650417-40-viclabel228"></join>; about the latter end of November was twelvemonth the prisoner came to my house and asked for a lodging: I granted him one; he said he had but twopence in the world: I gave him a bit of victuals for his supper: he said he was very willing to go to work, being just come from on board a ship, and had money due, but no credit. I trusted him with my keys, and he looked after my horses: I believe, about the 25th of January, my wife and he had a few words; she said he should not be in the house any longer. The second day after he was gone I went to look into a chest, in which were old iron, spike nails and other things; all was gone, a large quantity.</p>
               <p>Q. Where do you live?</p>
               <p>Smith. I live in <placeName id="t17650417-40-crimeloc229">Shoreditch</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17650417-40-crimeloc229" type="placeName" value="Shoreditch"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17650417-40-crimeloc229" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17650417-40-off226 t17650417-40-crimeloc229"></join>: I went to look about among the brokers, and saw a pair of steelyards at Mr. Sage's, near Holloway-mount; there were also some small spikes, and other things; he told me what sort of a man he bought them of, which description answered to the prisoner. I got a warrant of suspicion against him; as soon as he saw me he ran like a race-horse; we have seen him run five or six miles round Hackney-fields: we were after him a great many times. An<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176504170024"></xptr> officer that had a writ against another man said, I can take your man, if you can let me have his name with the other man in a writ: I'll soon catch him: this was last November or October; he was put into a writ and taken, and put into Whitechapel gaol. I got him discharged, not wanting the debt so much as I wanted him; they turned him out before the constable could come with the warrant, so I lost him again: I was at Guild-hall last Tuesday was three weeks; he was brought there by the city constables; he said, God bless you, Mr. Smith, do not say any thing: I went before the sitting alderman, and charged him with stealing my iron; he owned to it all.</p>
               <p>Q. What were his words?</p>
               <p>Smith. He said he did not deny it; but I had made a debt of it.</p>
               <p>Mr. Sage. I am a broker in Shoreditch: I bought these steelyards of the prisoner, about a year ago, (produced in court, and deposed to by the prosecutor.)</p>
               <p>Prisoner's Defence.</p>
               <p>He desired me to give him a note of hand for forty-three shillings, and said he would make it up with me; he sent me to Whitechapel gaol, and kept me there seven weeks: then I sued for my groats; he desired me to give him a fresh note of hand; I did, and he let me out of gaol; he arrested me upon the first note a little before last Michaelmas; the fresh note was for 3 l. 19 s. 9 d. I was to pay him at a shilling a week.</p>
               <p>Q. to prosecutor. Is this truth, that the prisoner has been saying?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I never had a first note of him: I did not arrest him upon a note.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he seven weeks in prison?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. No, he was not upon my suit; he never gave me any notice for the groats.</p>
               <p>Q. Did he give you any note?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. He gave me a note when he came out.</p>
               <p>Q. How long was he in gaol on your suit?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. They had him in gaol some time before I knew of it; as soon as I knew he was in gaol I went to him.</p>
               <p>Court. That is not answering the question.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I will not take upon me to say how long he was in gaol.</p>
               <p>Q. Tell as near as you can?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I believe it was not quite a month: we could not find the warrant, was the reason he lay in gaol so long.</p>
               <p>Q. What was the note for?</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. The note was for 3 l. the lawyer desired me not to turn him out without a fresh note.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17650417-40-verdict230" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17650417-40-verdict230" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
