<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680413-22">
               <interp inst="t17680413-22" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-22" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-22" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680413"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-22" type="date" value="17680413"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680413-22-off119-c160" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-22-defend200 t17680413-22-off119 t17680413-22-verdict123"></join>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680413-22-off119-c161" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-22-defend202 t17680413-22-off119 t17680413-22-verdict123"></join>
         
               <p>275, 276. (L.) 
               
                  <persName id="t17680413-22-defend200" type="defendantName">
                     Sarah 
                     Pummall 
                  <interp inst="t17680413-22-defend200" type="surname" value="Pummall"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-defend200" type="given" value="Sarah"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-defend200" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             and 
               
                  <persName id="t17680413-22-defend202" type="defendantName">
                     Elizabeth 
                     Vantandilo 
                  <interp inst="t17680413-22-defend202" type="surname" value="Vantandilo"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-defend202" type="given" value="Elizabeth"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-defend202" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
                
             were indicted for <rs id="t17680413-22-off119" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-off119" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-off119" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a cornelian seal set in silver, value 4 s. a quarter guinea, and 5 s. in money numbered
            </rs>, the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17680413-22-victim204" type="victimName">
                     Samuel 
                     Raymond 
                  <interp inst="t17680413-22-victim204" type="surname" value="Raymond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-victim204" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-victim204" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-22-off119 t17680413-22-victim204"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17680413-22-cd120" type="crimeDate">March 27</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-22-off119 t17680413-22-cd120"></join>. ++</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-22-person205">
                  Samuel 
                  Raymond 
               <interp inst="t17680413-22-person205" type="surname" value="Raymond"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-person205" type="given" value="Samuel"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-person205" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a <rs id="t17680413-22-viclabel121" type="occupation">journeyman barber</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-22-victim204 t17680413-22-viclabel121"></join>. On a Sunday evening, better than a fortnight ago, pretty near twelve at night, I was going home to my lodging in Flower and Dean-street, Spital-fields; I had a friend with me when we were in Cornhill; my friend went up <placeName id="t17680413-22-crimeloc122">St. Michael's-alley</placeName>
                  <interp inst="t17680413-22-crimeloc122" type="placeName" value="St. Michael's-alley"></interp>
                  <interp inst="t17680413-22-crimeloc122" type="type" value="crimeLocation"></interp>
                  <join result="offencePlace" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-22-off119 t17680413-22-crimeloc122"></join>, I stopped for him; then these girls at the bar came to me, they were very fond; one of them kissed me, and put her hand into my breeches; I observed one of them snatch at the chain of my watch; I found the chain gone, with a cornelian seal to it; I clapped my hand to my pocket, and found Vantandilo's hand in it, with my money in her hand; I saw her give it to the other prisoner; I held them, they wanted to get from me; I called the watch, he came; the prisoners fought me all the time, there was no body else near me; we<xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176804130012"></xptr> took them to the watch-house at the 'Change, they fought the watchman as well as me; as we went we were forced to call another watchman to assist.</p>
               <p>Q. Were they searched?</p>
               <p>Raymond. No, neither of them were, I never found my seal or money again; they took from me a quarter guinea and 5 s. in silver; the cornelian seal cost me 5 s.</p>
               <p>Q. Was you sober?</p>
               <p>Raymond. I was as sober as I am now.</p>
               <p>Q. Why did not your friend assist you?</p>
               <p>Raymond. He went up the alley, and out into Gracechurch-street, I saw no more of him.</p>
               <p>Q. Had you been drinking?</p>
               <p>Raymond. I had, but no ways disguised in liquor; I had been to see a friend in Upper Thames-street, at the house of Mr. Jenkins.</p>
               <p>Q. How long might you continue there?</p>
               <p>Raymond. I believe much about two hours; we had been up at St. Giles's in the afternoon.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-22-person206">
                  William 
                  Geter 
               <interp inst="t17680413-22-person206" type="surname" value="Geter"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-person206" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-person206" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am the constable, I was in the watch-house; the charge was given of the two prisoners by the prosecutor; he said he had lost 5 s. and after all, he said he had a lost 5 s. 3 d. there was nothing at all mentioned about the seal.</p>
               <p>Q. Was he drunk or sober?</p>
               <p>Geter. In short, he was rather in liquor.</p>
               <p>Q. How came you not to have the prisoners searched?</p>
               <p>Geter. I asked him if I should search them; he said no, it did not signify.</p>
               <p>Raymond. The constable never talked of searching them.</p>
               <p>Geter. When we were before the magistrate, he talked of losing his seal, but he said nothing of that before me.</p>
               <p>Pummall's defence.</p>
               <p>I had been at Vinegar-yard; coming home a little later than ordinary, that gentleman stopped me; he came running, and struck me with his cane, and used me very ill, and said I had robbed him of some money; he let me pass till I came to the end of Cornhill, then he laid hold of this lady, (meaning her fellow prisoner) she was coming past us; I never knew her before I was in trouble.</p>
               <p>To her character.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-22-person207">
                  John 
                  Kelly 
               <interp inst="t17680413-22-person207" type="surname" value="Kelly"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-person207" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-person207" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am a weaver in Rose and Crown-court, Whitechapel; Pummall is an engine winder, my wife employed her; when she was with me, no honester woman I could have; it is six months since she left me.</p>
               <p>Q. Is she a married woman, or single?</p>
               <p>Kelly. She is a married woman.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-22-person208">
                  Anne 
                  Jeggot 
               <interp inst="t17680413-22-person208" type="surname" value="Jeggot"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-person208" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-person208" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I live in Gravel-lane, Houndsditch; she is a clean industrious woman; I lived two years and a half in the house she lived in.</p>
               <p>Vantandilo's defence.</p>
               <p>I had been a little way to see a person that has my child of three months old; as I came back, this woman (meaning Pummall) was stopped as I was going by, the gentleman had knocked her down; he said, you robbed me, to me, and gave it to this girl; I never saw him, as God is my judge.</p>
               <p>Both <rs id="t17680413-22-verdict123" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-22-verdict123" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
               <p>There was another indictment against them for assaulting the prosecutor.</p>
            </div1>
