<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div1 type="trialAccount" id="t17680413-13">
               <interp inst="t17680413-13" type="collection" value="BAILEY"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-13" type="year" value="1768"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-13" type="uri" value="sessionsPapers/17680413"></interp>
               <interp inst="t17680413-13" type="date" value="17680413"></interp>
               <join result="criminalCharge" id="t17680413-13-off73-c102" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-13-defend125 t17680413-13-off73 t17680413-13-verdict76"></join>
         
               <p>
                  <xptr type="pageFacsimile" doc="176804130007"></xptr>264. (M) 
               <persName id="t17680413-13-defend125" type="defendantName">
                  Anne, <rs id="t17680413-13-deflabel72" type="occupation">wife</rs>
                     <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-13-defend125 t17680413-13-deflabel72"></join> of 
                     <persName id="t17680413-13-person126">
                        John 
                        Pearce 
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-person126" type="surname" value="Pearce"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680413-13-person126" type="given" value="John"></interp>
                        <interp inst="t17680413-13-person126" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     </persName>
                  
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-defend125" type="surname" value="Pearce"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-defend125" type="given" value="Anne"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-defend125" type="gender" value="female"></interp>
                  </persName>
            , was indicted for <rs id="t17680413-13-off73" type="offenceDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-off73" type="offenceCategory" value="theft"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-off73" type="offenceSubcategory" value="grandLarceny"></interp>
               stealing a silver watch, value 30 s.
            </rs> the property of 
               
                  <persName id="t17680413-13-victim128" type="victimName">
                     William 
                     Eastland 
                  <interp inst="t17680413-13-victim128" type="surname" value="Eastland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-victim128" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-victim128" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                     <join result="offenceVictim" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-13-off73 t17680413-13-victim128"></join>
                  </persName>
                
            , <rs id="t17680413-13-cd74" type="crimeDate">March 12</rs>
                  <join result="offenceCrimeDate" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-13-off73 t17680413-13-cd74"></join>. +</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-13-person129">
                  William 
                  Eastland 
               <interp inst="t17680413-13-person129" type="surname" value="Eastland"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-person129" type="given" value="William"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-person129" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . On the 12th of March the prisoner had some linen to wash for me, she did not bring them according to time; I desired her to go about her business, but she said before I go I will make your bed; my watch was hanging by my bed-side; soon after she was gone I missed it; after that, on Monday the 14th, I was informed it was pawned at the bottom of Benjamin-street; there I went and found it.</p>
               <p>Q. What is the prisoner?</p>
               <p>Eastland. She had been <rs id="t17680413-13-deflabel75" type="occupation">servant</rs>
                  <join result="persNameOccupation" targOrder="Y" targets="t17680413-13-defend125 t17680413-13-deflabel75"></join> to me formerly; I got a warrant from Justice Fielding; on Monday night she came into a public-house where I was, and abused me, and used me very ill, and all my neighbours said I ought to prosecute her, so I took her up.</p>
               <p>Q. from prisoner. Whether you did not give me leave to pawn your watch as usual?</p>
               <p>Eastland. I believe she did once pawn my watch before; she was always wanting money, and I made her believe I had none, and then she did pawn it.</p>
               <p>Q. How long is that ago?</p>
               <p>Eastland. That is six or seven months ago.</p>
               <p>Q. Upon your oath, did you, or did you not, give her leave to pawn it on the 12th of March?</p>
               <p>Eastland. Upon my oath I did not, neither did I think she would have been so base as to have taken it.</p>
               <p>
            
                  <persName id="t17680413-13-person130">
                  Richard 
                  Newton 
               <interp inst="t17680413-13-person130" type="surname" value="Newton"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-person130" type="given" value="Richard"></interp>
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-person130" type="gender" value="male"></interp>
                  </persName>
            . I am apprentice to a pawnbroker; the last time the prisoner pledged this watch to me was the 12th of March.</p>
               <p>Q. How often had she pledged it before?</p>
               <p>Newton. She pledged it the 1st of Dec. 1766, and had it out again on the 5th; she brought it the 29th of December, and it was taken out the 30th of January, 1767.</p>
               <p>Q. Did she tell you whose watch it was?</p>
               <p>Newton. She said it was Mr. Eastland's.</p>
               <p>Q. What did you lend her upon it the last time?</p>
               <p>Newton. I lent her 25 s. upon it; it was enquired after on the Tuesday.</p>
               <p>Prosecutor. I do not remember I gave her leave to pawn it above once before.</p>
               <p>Prisoner's defence.</p>
               <p>When I went up stairs to make his bed, he said to me, Nancy, my dear, take and put your child on a clean shift, it is one of the children I had by him; I said I will do it directly; said he, be as quick as you can, for I am obliged to go out; then he said, my dear, will you make my bed; after I had done it, I said now, Billy, consider my husband is very poor, and out of business through you, I want some money to fetch some things out of pawn; he said, my dear, cash runs very short, I cannot; I said, my dear, you must do as before, lend me the watch; he said, my dear, then take it; I did, and went and pawned it, and took my apron and cardinal out of pawn; then I went to him; he desired me not to tell my husband, he said he would give me a guinea; he has arrested my husband out of spite, because I will not leave my husband to go to live with him again; I have had as good as three children by my prosecutor.</p>
               <p>
                  <rs id="t17680413-13-verdict76" type="verdictDescription">
                     <interp inst="t17680413-13-verdict76" type="verdictCategory" value="notGuilty"></interp>
               Acquitted
            </rs>.</p>
            </div1>
